Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we have a great lesson for all our upper intermediate students
that's right we're talking about airplane travel today
airplane travel, alright so we're going to be in an airplane
yes and we're going to be listening to some of the common things you might hear on an announcement in the airplane
yeah usually the flight attendant or the captain will come on and say something and
well usually it's in English so we got to understand what they're saying
that's right and we'll also learn some great phrases that you can use when you want to describe flights to your friends when you talk to them
yeah that always happens you arrive somewhere and people are like hey how was your flight now you know how to answer it
exactly okay so why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview
very vocabulary preview
well we've got three words for you here in vocabulary preview all about flying
okay so what's our first one turbulence turbulence turbulence turbulence turbulence
so turbulence how can we describe this well turbulence when you're in an airplane basically is air
that is moving in all directions really fast okay so what happens so the airplane will start to shake
okay right yeah it's the same thing if you're flying a kite and maybe some turbulence is in the air your kite will maybe fall to the ground
oh yeah so it's air that's moving in all directions it's really turbulent
alright well we'll hear how this word is used in the dialogue but another airplane word we hear a lot
um crew crew flight crew yes CREW crew so the flight crew is basically the team yes
right yep it's all the people that are in the airplane so it's basically the captain
and the co-pilot and all the flight attendants right exactly yep that's the flight crew yes
okay and what about our last word bumpy ride bumpy ride bumpy ride bumpy not smooth not smooth
yeah so what would be an example of a bumpy ride okay imagine if you're driving in your car
and you're driving on a dirt road like with many holes in it and everything rocks and everything
you're driving on that road and it would be really really bumpy right so your car will be moving a lot
yeah so a bumpy ride is a trip where you move and shake a lot it's kind of uncomfortable
so you can say that is a bumpy road or it was a bumpy ride
it was a bumpy ride okay so now let's listen to our dialogue we're going to be listening to these people on an airplane
and the captain is going to give some instructions
and the next thing you know we're running towards the oh did you feel that?
yeah don't worry about it we're just going through a bit of turbulence
lighten gentlemen this is your captain speaking it looks like we've hit a patch of rough air
so we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes and this is why I hate flying
at this time I'd like to remind of our passengers to fasten their seat belts and remain seated
until the fasten seat belts are turned off
please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stood under the seat in front of you I'll be back to update you in a minute
did you hear that? oh my god brunt don't worry about it this is totally normal it happens all that
uh... late in jumbun this is your captain again we've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us
and so we're safe we will be suspending in flight service
I would ask all the inflate crew to return to the seat at this time
I would also ask that all our passengers are afraid for using the laboratory until the seat belt flight hasn't switched off
we can expect
well here we are with another dramatic dialogue another explosion in English fog what's happening
um... i don't know a lot of adventure is going on so we'll see what happens but i'm sure there are right don't worry everyone
hope so it's kind of making me nervous for my next flight
alright so let's take a look at some of the words that the captain used in language takeaway
language takeaway
all right all of these words you'll hear really really often when you're flying
um and the first one we have for you is fasten fasten fasten fasten your seat belt
mm-hmm now this is a great word fasten means to do up do up or put on or connect
connect connect right so usually it'll be with a seat belt or a belt or something like that right
yeah no the pronunciation here is interesting yes it's felt F a s t e n right so it would be fast
and no no right fasten fasten the key kind of becomes silent so it's fasten yeah okay let's look at our next word
lavatory lavatory lavatory lavatory okay so what is lavatory exactly because i'm always confused what's the difference between
bathroom restroom washroom wc lavatory i know so many words for bathroom um lavatory is a room
with a toilet and sink only only a toilet and sink so no bathtub no no shower either no shower so it's very very common to find a lavatory in boat
uh-huh airplanes or and trains yep but never in your house never in your house even if your room in your house is only a sink in a toilet it's still not a lavatory
it's uh a bathroom yeah okay i don't know why that's just the way it is in English and something interesting that you told me today
double you see uh-huh right that's a common thing that you'll see on a bathroom yep what is that stand for water closet water closet
yeah wow i didn't know that yeah water closet okay anyways let's take a look at our next word
stow stow stow stow yes stow your luggage so if i stow my luggage it means you put it in a place where you can get it easily but it is very safe
and maybe it's not even visible right yeah so you put it away in a safe spot okay so usually in airplanes they will tell you to stow your luggage under your seat
yes or stow your luggage in the overhead bin overhead compartment yes okay and our last word refrain refrain refrain refrain
refrain from doing something mm-hmm so this is a verb meaning avoid doing avoid doing do not do exactly
something interesting about this grammar wise is it's usually followed by from yeah refrain from and the verb that follows is always a jaren right
yeah so refrain from i and g right refrain from using the lavatory yes refrain from smoking refrain from smoking okay so refrain from
alright so some really great examples in language takeaway yeah and well now let's take a look at fluency builder and see some of these great phrases
fluency builder alright three phrases we have for you here and the first one remain seated remain seated remains seated
so to remain seated really simple to stay sitting to stay on your seat don't stand up yes this is really important in airplanes right
yeah because otherwise if there's turbulence you could you know end up flying around airplane
or fall exactly in hurt yourself hmm remains seated now one of the reasons they had to remain seated was because they were going to go through a patch of rough air patch of rough air
so patch now interesting okay so patch is a small area right yeah so a small area of turbulence a small area of turbulence now what would be another example of patch
maybe a patch of strawberries so it's like a little strawberry garden yes or a patch of grass patch of grass usually in front of your house you have a little patch of grass yep okay so patch of and now our last phrase
suspend suspend suspend in flight service yeah so stop for a short time stop for a short time so you could suspend your work yeah and if you're going on vacation you could suspend your subscription to the newspaper
okay so suspend to temporarily stop yes okay so we've covered a lot of vocabulary and some great phrases so why don't we listen to our dialogue one more time and we'll come back and talk about line
and the next thing you know we're running towards the oh did you feel that yeah don't worry about it we're just going through a bit of turbulence
like in gentlemen this is your captain speaking it looks like we've hit a patch of rough air so we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes and this is why I hate flying
at this time I'd like to remind of our passengers to fasten their seat belts and remain seated until the fasten seat belts are just turned off
please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stood under the seat in front of you I'll be back to update you in a minute
did you hear that oh my god brunt don't worry about it this is totally normal it happens all that
late in gentlemen this is your captain again we've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us and so for your safety we will be suspending
in flight service I would ask all the inflate crew to return to the seat at this time I would also ask that all our passengers are
in front using the laboratory until the seat belt flight has its switch stop we can expect
back
Erica have you ever had a turbulent flight like this no no never this bad a little bit of turbulence
actually kind of like turbulent flight flight it's sort of like I don't know it's kind of fine you get shaking around
you're like stomach moves up and down you don't like nervous no I get I get a little excited
well it is true that flying is actually very very safe right yeah I know we all hear that like more people are killed in car accidents than a flight accidents
so it's very very safe so yeah I don't worry about the turbulence not on wood
yeah so flying is really safe and you know as long as you remain seated you're fast in your seat building you know you follow the instructions you
shouldn't have any problems yeah yeah actually that's a really good point because actually when I was reading about flight turbulence for this dialogue
I kept reading all these stories about these people who you know when they got into some turbulence air were you know knocked over
or they ended up like actually literally flying through the cabin and getting really badly hurt
yeah everyone you got to fasten your seat yes remains seated yeah flying tips here at English
flying tips at English pod we don't want you to get hurt and we know that you travel that's so be safe right
yeah and use this language to describe your flight okay so come to our website English pod dot com or you can leave
questions you can also leave your comments yeah mark when I are always there and actually in fact we have to go check this
right now so yeah we're out of time so we'll see you guys next time thanks for listening bye