Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we're in the mood to read something today so we're going to play
called the library, right? That's right. We're going to go to the library and we're going to get
some books. But before we do that let's take a look at a word in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview. All right so today's vocabulary preview word is a thing that you use
when you go to the library to take that book home. You don't have to pay for the book. You use your
library card to borrow it. That's right so this is something that you need when you want to get books
at the library. You need a library card. So we're going to talk about this and how you get a library card.
So let's listen to the dialogue.
Wow look at all these books. I bet I can find a book about anything here.
Please keep your voice down. There are people reading and studying here.
Okay I'm sorry. Are you the librarian? Maybe you can help me. I am looking for a book.
Yes I am. You can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the
genre title or if you know the author I can point you towards the right direction.
I'm looking for a book that has nursery rhymes. That would be in our children's section. That
book shelf there on the right.
Okay I would like to check out these books. Do you have a library card? No how do I get one?
I just need to see a drive as license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident of this
state. Here you go. So you're all set. You can have these books for two weeks. If you need to have
them longer you can bring them here to renew them. If you don't you get charged 10 cents a day for
each book. Okay thanks.
Alright we're back so now let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright we have a lot of great things for you today in language takeaway. The first is actually
a job. This is a person who works at a library. What's that person called?
He or she is called a librarian.
Alright so someone who works at a library is a librarian. That's right. So this person
organizes the books. Know about all the books that are there and basically takes care of the
library. That's right. So if you need help in the library it's probably a good idea to ask the librarian
where the book you're looking for is. That's right and today we went in looking for a specific type of
book. We wanted a book that had nursery rhymes. Alright nursery rhymes. Now these are kind of like
songs or poems. Things that we tell little children and babies. So Mary had a little and little
them. That is a nursery rhyme. It's a playful poem for children. That's right. So obviously since we
are looking for nursery rhyme books the librarian told us that we need to go to the children section.
That's right but before we get to borrow this book there are a couple of things we need because the
person doesn't have a library card. Now the question is how do I get a library card and what
was the librarians response Marco? Well it was pretty simple. All we needed was to see that person's
driver's license or a utility bill. Alright so a driver's license is an ID card and identification
card that you get that allows you to drive a car. Now each state has a different kind of
driver's license and different rules for how to get one but this is a very common, almost the most
common kind of identification in America. That's right. So basically you show them your driver's license
and it has a picture of you there, your telephone number and even your address. That's right but not
everybody has a driver's license. Some people don't drive, some people don't want to drive. So
they would have to show something else and a good way to show that you live somewhere is to show your
utility bill. That's right so a utility is basically water, electricity, gas or your telephone bill
and it arrives to your house and that's where it's well obviously it says your address there and
who the bill is directed to so you can prove that you live there. That's right because why would
somebody else pay for the water at that house? It's obviously you. So these are a couple kinds of
identification you can use to get a library card. All right and well we're taking the books we can
borrow them for two weeks but if we need to have them for a longer period of time we can take them
back to the library and have them renewed. So to renew something renew means to continue to borrow
what you have to rebaro. But we don't say rebaro we say renews that means we get it for another two weeks.
That's right. So things that expire usually you need to renew like for example your driver's
license usually it will last maybe five years but then you need to renew your driver's license.
And if you don't renew it if you forget to renew something maybe there'll be a problem like in the
case of the library you have to pay for the late fees your book is overdue you have to pay for it
or in the case of a driver's license if your driver's license is overdue. Well you probably
have to get a new one. That's right. Okay so a lot of vocab there why don't we review everything
and we'll be right back.
Wow look at all these books I bet I can find a book about anything here.
Please keep your voice down there people reading and studying here.
Okay I'm sorry are you the librarian maybe you can help me I am looking for a book. Yes I am.
You can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the genre title or if
you know the author I can point you towards the right direction. I am looking for a book that has
nursery rhymes that would be in our children's section that bookshelf there on the right.
Okay I would like to check out these books. Do you have a library card? No how do I get one?
I just need to see a driver's license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident of this
state. Here you go. So you're all set you can have these books for two weeks. If you need to have
them longer you can bring them here to renew them. If you don't you get charged 10 cents a day for each
book. Okay thanks. All right so now we have three key phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So Marko what are librarians famous for? Well librarians are always telling you to
please keep your voice down. All right so libraries are quiet places there places where people
like to go and read and think and study. So oftentimes when people are talking they're being loud
the librarian will say hey keep your voice down or be quiet. That's right so another way of saying
be quiet is keep your voice down and it's a little bit more polite please keep your voice down.
Keep your voice down or if there's two people or three people you'd say keep your voices down.
So the librarian tells us to keep our voice down and well now we can get some help from the librarian
and he says that you know if you know the title of the book or the genre or the name of the author
the librarian can point you towards the right direction. Now to point someone in the right direction
or point someone towards the right direction means to help them understand where to go. Maybe they
don't know exactly the title of the book or the author but in this case the librarian can help
put the person in the right place so I can point you in the right direction or point you towards
the right direction. Exactly even maybe you're lost in a town and you stop and ask someone for
directions because you don't know how to get there and that person can help you by pointing you
towards the right direction. All right so this means I can help you. And basically okay and now what we
want it to do was we want it to borrow books from the library. We want it to get books from the library
but we have another way of saying this we can say we want to check out some books. All right so to
check out a book means to borrow it like you say but this is also a noun check out that's the place where
you scan something so maybe there's a bar or a black bar on the back of the book beep when you
scan it it scans out that means that you're borrowing it you get it for two weeks and you bring it back
to check out okay so a lot of great stuff in this dialogue today learning about libraries and how to
get a library card why don't we review everything one last time. Wow look at all these books I
bet I can find a book about anything here please keep your voice down there people reading and
studying here okay I'm sorry are you the librarian maybe you can help me I am looking for a book yes
I am you can check our online catalog to search for the book you want based on the genre title or if
you know the author I can point you towards the right direction I am looking for a book that has nursery
rhymes that would be in our children's section that bookshelf there on the right
okay I would like to check out these books do you have a library card no how do I get one
I just need to see a drive as license or utility bill to prove that you are a resident of this
state here you go so you're all set you can have these books for two weeks if you need to have
them longer you can bring them here to renew them if you don't you get charged ten cents a day
for each book okay thanks all right so barring books in a library seems pretty simple and
you don't really have to leave a deposit or something just in case you steal the book or you damage
it what how do you how do you deal with this no well libraries are a wonderful part of well
least American culture I'm not really sure how they work in other places but in America there's
a lot of federal money in libraries in fact I think it was Franklin Roosevelt who really helps
get a library system in place in America so they're they're a part of this system of kind of
community sharing and information you can go to the library and look for jobs they have computers
many have DVD and video sections many have very wonderful CD sections so basically it's a community
center for information knowledge and it's almost a relationship with trust I trust that the library
will provide for me and the library will will trust that I don't destroy a book of course if you do
you have to pay we have to pay so is it a federal offense to steal a book from a library I don't know
but it's pretty big deal this steal a book from the library they certainly will know who you are
because they have your information your driver's license right okay so it's actually pretty
especially because as you said library there's a lot of money put into library so it's all
communities have them as you say DVDs or movies or a lot of different types of books and in
other countries like maybe in Latin America it's not as popular to have a community library
can go and check things out because you know there's not that much money involved as well so
but we would be curious to know how it works in your country maybe your country has some
beautiful or extensive libraries yeah I'm very curious as well so public libraries do you have them
and if you don't do you also have university libraries you can go to let us know our website is
english.com all right guys we'll see you there bye