Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about something we talk about every year.
Every year after Christmas or while during the Christmas holidays we talk about new years,
new years day and a very important topic, new years resolutions.
All right so we're not going to preview anything today. It's all in the dialogue but when we come back
we'll be talking more about what you hear and something great phrases you can use at the new year.
Did you read this? It says that the number one new year resolution people make is to spend more
time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it. We're a society that
is always on the go. Not because we have to but because we want to. Why? We work hard and spend
less time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with goods and services that are usually
unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should start thinking even new years resolution
yourself. But it's the point we always make new years resolutions and by February we will have forgotten about
them. It's pointless. Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your goals and objectives.
What about you? Your gym bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new running shoes
that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the gym with me every
day. Yeah yeah whatever. All right great work back so this is very typical a new year's resolution
that you make but then people don't really stick to it etc. It don't. Usually they don't.
All right but you're probably wondering what is a new year's resolution so why don't we take a look at
this word and many more on language takeaway? Language takeaway. Okay so new year's resolution
let's break this phrase down the first phrase is new years so the new year is January 1st in the
West and it is celebrated on the 31st of December of the at night when the clock changes to the new
year and a new year's resolution remember that S there is something that you want to do or to change
in the new year. It's a fresh start. Okay so you pretty much the verb that you use there is to resolve
to do something so my new year's resolution is to you know go to the gym every day. It's like a promise
to yourself. Right so and this is very common right among Americans they try and because it's a
new year it's a fresh start so they want to start doing something great. Exactly we can talk about
this at the end but a lot of companies try to use this to sell Americans stupid things so we'll get
there in a minute but the two people in this dialogue are talking about the idea of spending more
time with friends and family and the other person says well sometimes it's hard to do that because
you have to provide your family with goods and services. All right so this phrase goods and services
is very common especially in economics and sociology so what does this mean? And they go to
together right so goods are tangible items things that you buy you know like food or you know
clothes, clothes, a TV etc stuff stuff and services of course are other things like for example
going to the doctor or the dentist or any other service you get. So service usually includes
another person doing something for you but you might not actually get something physical like a TV
for it. So goods and services it's included in this phrase always goods and services. Very good
and well moving on as we mentioned with the new year's resolution we had that verb there to resolve
so what does it mean if I want to resolve? Okay well to resolve as we said is to decide or to
promise yourself to do something so it's a decision that you don't want to change your mind about
for example I this year I've resolved to quit smoking that means I've made a decision for myself
and I'm going to do it. Okay very good. Very strong and not to be confused with like to solve right
it has no no real relation there right? No resolve to resolve to do something is to have a strong
passion or interest in doing something for yourself or changing an action. Very good and well
our last word for language takeaway is brand new a brand new something that's brand new. brand new.
So by a brand new car come down to Captain's car a lot. So brand new is something we hear a lot of
marketing it's also something that that well these words just go together very often and something
is new okay you just bought it or it just came out but something that's brand new is really fresh
really new. So brand new a brand new car a brand new watch etc a brand new movie a brand new movie or brand
yeah brand new cereal how do you have for try to very good so a great phrases there very good so great
words there why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with three phrases.
Did you read this? It says that the number one new year resolution people make is to spend more
time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it we're a society that
is always on the go not because we have to but because we want to why we work hard and spend less
time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with goods and services that are usually
unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should start thinking the new year's resolution
yourself. What's the point? We always make new year's resolutions and by February we will have
forgotten about them it's pointless. Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your goals and
objectives. What about you? Your Jim bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new running shoes
that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the gym with me every
day. Yeah yeah whatever. All right we're back so now let's take a look at these three phrases on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase is very common at gas stations and food like fast
food chains and we can say on the go. All right so he mentioned that we are a society that is
always on the go. It means we're always moving. Exactly so you're always going to work going home
from work going to the store going to the school to get the kids always moving moving moving so that
that kind of action that kind of life is on the go. You can also say eat on the go. That means I eat
while I'm going somewhere while I'm doing something I don't sit down. Okay so on the go and we're
talking about New Year's resolution and we say that well many people resolve to do something but they
don't really do it and we have a phrase that is used here to stick to something, stick to your
resolution. To stick to it so you think of tape or glue these things that help things stick together.
Okay so in that sense it's kind of it's a way for you to describe continuing to do something or
not stopping not quitting not ending it and so I could say remember how I said I wanted to
quit smoking? Well I'm really going to stick to this resolution because I think it's important.
That means I'm not going to give up. Right very good so you're going to stay with it. You're not
going to give up. All right so stick to something like for example our English learners they'll
stick to learning English. And we could say as a word of as words of encouragement he stick to it.
Stick to it don't give up. Don't give up. All right and well finally they were discussing
more more arguing about the gym membership and everything and he mentioned that the gym bag is gathering
dust. All right this is a very nice phrase I think because it's very visual I like I like phrases where
you can see what's happening. So gathering means collecting that means that the dust in the air it's
building on this bag and something is gathering dust if we don't use it. So we haven't gone to the gym
because our bag is in the corner and it's just filled with dust. Exactly we could also say this about
the computer. Why should I buy you a new computer Marco if you never use the old one that's just
sitting in the house gathering dust. Very good okay so it's another way of saying you never use it
you never do it. Etc. It's for an object though you can't say you are gathering. No we'll have you a
little weird you might be that or. All right great phrases so why don't we listen to this dialogue one last time.
Did you read this? It says that the number one New Year resolution people make is to spend more
time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it. We are society that
is always on the go. Not because we have to but because we want to. Why? We work hard and spend
less time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with goods and services that are
usually unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should start thinking of a New Year's resolution
yourself. But it's the point we always make New Year's resolutions and by February we will have
forgotten about them. It's pointless. Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your
goals and objectives. What about you? Your Jim bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new
running shoes that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to
Jim with me every day. Yeah yeah whatever. All right we're back and well as you mentioned there
are some interesting things about this dialogue especially when they talked about a society that's
always on the go and you mentioned that well sometimes you eat on the go and I've seen people in
the United States that are actually eating while driving. I'm guilty of doing that. Yeah you have no
time to actually sit down for like 15 minutes and eat. Now I remember being in high school at home and
you know you just have so much stuff to do you have a school then after school there's like
you know soccer practice after that there's music lessons and you never have time to eat
so you have to grab food in the car and then on the way home you're picking things up and you
get home and you get home and you get your homework or whatever there's so much stuff to do and it
doesn't stop. It doesn't stop and you grow up. It doesn't stop if you're an older person it's just
the way life is in America. Wow yeah that's that's really interesting because I think many of
our listeners that are in other countries would find that a little bit peculiar if they actually
went to the United States and saw somebody in their car you know like having a hamburger while
driving you know and sipping on their soda. Yeah it's kind of sad. Well that's the thing you don't
have much time but actually this is based on true events kind of on the fact that many Americans
do want to spend more time at home with their friends with their family because as you say you're
always so busy and I think it's a nice resolution to to resolve to have dinner with your family
once or twice a week at home where you sit down and you talk about your lives it's nice because
you get to share and you get to know each other better and you know otherwise you're always just
on the go in different places. Yeah exactly so we want to hear your comments in your opinions about
this topic so why don't you visit our website EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there. Don't
forget to share with us your new years resolutions everyone's got one so I'm very excited to hear those
all right until next time everyone bye.