Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a special dialogue for you all about this important
test that you need for going to graduate school.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about the famous or very scary g-met.
Alright so the g-met g-met is the test that students will take when they want to go to graduate
school for business management. So an MBA program.
That's right and it's pretty much a standard test that you have to take as you say to
get into one of these programs. And so today we're going to talk a little bit about the
sections of the test and more or less how it's structured but not too much in depth.
That's right. So let's take a listen to our dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
I come seem to progress up the creyolated no matter how hard I try.
And I have been here for two years already.
Well have you thought of getting an MBA? I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
An MBA hey well my degree wasn't in business. The business schools won't be interested in me.
nonsense. The business schools measure your ability through a test called g-met.
G-met what does that stand for and what will the test contain?
Graduate management admission test. It contains three parts.
Analytical writing assessment. The quantitative section and the verbal section.
Not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered but also on the difficulty.
Okay this sounds a little tough. How am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you. You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions.
You can also use free or private computer software.
Going to church might help as well.
No matter what I do I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cap.
That's the spirit.
Alright we're back so now let's talk about some of the language we found on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright so there's a lot of great stuff here. The first one we've got is actually more about
a job than school. This is the career ladder.
That's right. Ash is complaining how he can't seem to make any progress in the career ladder.
So what is a career ladder?
We know what a ladder is. A ladder is a tool that you use to climb from a low place to a high
place. So for example if you want to go on the roof of your house you have to use a ladder.
A career ladder is it's like an analogy. When you start a career you start at the bottom
and you climb up up to the top. So going from the bottom to maybe the president of an organization.
So that's called the career ladder.
Yeah climbing from the bottom of a career area like for example being the male man at an office
building to being the president of that office. Okay so this is what Ash is complaining about
that it's hard or he can't really seem to go up the career ladder.
And so Mindy suggests that he should take the GMAT and go into graduate school. So as we said
the GMAT is a test that you take but what is it's stand for? What is GMAT?
GMAT stands for graduate management admission test. Okay so that's the test that you take when you
want to go to school. So you have to send your scores to the admissions office of the school you
want to go to and they will decide if they're high enough or not. Okay very good. So
not everyone can go to graduate school and you have to take this test and pass it basically.
Well there's no pass fail but certain schools will say that a score is high enough and other
schools will say that a higher score is more important. So you can maybe go to a better school if
you have a better score. Okay and well Mindy went on to explain the three parts of this test.
The first one she said is analytical writing. All right so analytical writing is a very common
part of a test. For example I think the SAT also has analytical writing and basically you're asked
to read something and then write about it and analytical means that you have to really use your
mind to make an argument. It's not just read and repeat, read and repeat. Right so basically
comes from analyzing, you analyze what you read and then you write about it. That's right you have to
think and you have to make you have to understand what you read and then you have to write something
that makes you know make sense it's logical. Do you put your opinion in analytical writing? No.
No so it's all based on facts. Based on facts and logic and argument. Uh huh okay. So you have this
part of analytical writing and then Mindy talks about the quantitative section of the test. So what is
this? So the quantitative section you think of the word quantify, quantity, quantitative has to
deal with numbers. Okay. Basically so you have to be able to understand basic math, some algebra,
some arithmetic, some statistics for example. So quantitative sections on tests are the math sections.
Now from my understanding even though it is a math section it's not really like they give you a
problem in equation and you have to solve it. It's more like analysis right they give you some
information and you have to use math to solve it. That's right so there are a number of different
parts. One of them is like what you say it's kind of a it's about logic while using algebra to solve
these problems. I think the other part of it has to do with statistics and being able to understand
trends graphs. Things like that. So this is the math section of the exam so not only do you have to
be able to read understand and analyze what you're reading you have to be able to be good at math
and then finally we have a verbal section. What is this all about? This is about your English
language and grammar skills and so the verbal section will test your vocabulary knowledge. Do you
understand what a big word's mean? Also will test your ability to read passages and analyze them.
So I guess this part is the most important one of the most important parts for foreign students
obviously don't speak English as their first language that this makes sure that you have a good
enough English level to be able to take a graduate program in English right? Part of it's that there's
a special test that will test your English abilities but this is absolutely an important part for
a non-native English speaker on the GMAT. It's hard for English speakers who are born speaking
English. In native English speakers yeah so it's something that really you should do about your
time too if you are a non-native English speaker because there will be some very challenging words
okay so those are the three sections of the GMAT and so to finish off language take away Ash said
that he's going to take this test because he wants to become a corporate fat cat. All right now this
is an interesting term with this is not something we talk about in the office. This is something
we talk with friends. So a corporate fat cat you think corporate corporation has has to do
business. So basically we're talking about very important businessmen but fat cats not a good thing
no it's not really you refer to a fat cat a corporate fat cat is a businessman who you consider to
have a lot of money but obviously you make the analogy that they're fat because they have so much
money and it's kind of a way of saying that the businessmen are not the corporate fat cats are not
the best people around. No you're basically saying that these guys these men on top they're rich
but they're kind of lazy and so you he wants to be a corporate fat cat he wants to be very rich and
powerful and not have to work so hard. Which obviously is not really the case always but
this is a common term that as you said you wouldn't really mention it in the office but it's more of a
a of a satirical way of speaking about businessmen. All right so now let's finish off language take away
and move on to some phrases on fluency builder. I come seem to progress up the career ladder no
matter how hard I try and I have been here for two years already. Well have you thought of
getting an MBA? I heard it does wonders and getting you to the top. An MBA hey well my degree wasn't
in business the business schools won't be interested in me. nonsense the business schools measure
your ability through a test called GMAT. GMAT what does that stand for and what will the test contain?
Graduate management admission test it contains three parts analytical writing assessment the
quantitative section and the verbal section not only does the test score you on the number of
questions answered but also on the difficulty. Okay this sounds a little tough how my
supposed to practice for this. Up to you you could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group
sessions you can also use free or private computer software going to church might help as well.
No matter what I do I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cap.
That's the spirit.
All right in fluency builder today we have a number of really great phrases you can use the first.
The first one is from Mindy she says I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
Right she suggests getting an MBA I heard it does wonders to you know improve your career.
All right this is actually something that you might hear in a commercial so it does wonders
means it really helps it's really beneficial to you. Right you might hear in a commercial for example
with a face cream it does wonders you know to your skin it really makes your skin looks
good. So you by using this phrase it does wonders you're basically saying it's fast
defective it's almost a miracle of how much it can improve your career or in this case of the
cream how it can improve your face. That's right so the MBA does wonders it's almost miraculous
how positive and effective will have on your career. Exactly. Okay it does wonders and then
Ash was asking that how he's supposed to study for this and Mindy answered well you know what it's
up to you you have a lot of options so up to you up to you this means it's your decision.
Okay so we can use this in normal life you know you know you and I are out Marco and I say well
I don't know what to eat what do you want to eat like I say whatever it's up to you up to me that
means I get to decide what we eat and I want pizza okay very good. All right so up to you is a way to say
no you decide it's up to you it's your decision okay and for our next phrase Ash was saying
that he's going to study really hard and he's going to ace the test. All right now to ace a test this
is a this is a phrase that we use we can use it in high school and college as well not just MBA programs
and to ace a test means to do perfectly on it okay okay that means to get an A or even 100%
so it's important to remember that we have this grading system A, B, C, D, F, A is the top all right and so
you ace it means you don't make any mistakes and remember that A for ace okay so you can even use it
if it's not really a test like a job interview you say I ace that job interview I ace it and
in sports oftentimes we we see this tennis it's a sports analogy tennis when someone serves
a ball and the other player is can't even hit the ball back it's an ace you get a point that's right so
it's a ace for for that or even good sports athletes do you call them A's is so after a
job interview I can say you know wow Marco I really ace that interview like ace it okay and Mindy says well
you know what that's really good that's the spirit that's the spirit now this is something you say
to someone when you like their attitude okay so if I say oh man I did really bad this is stupid
I don't want to study you say well that's the bad attitude right but if I say you know what I'm
going to do awesome this is great I'm so I'm going to kill this I'm going to ace it now you can say
that's the spirit that means good attitude that's the right way to think about this so you're
kind of even encouraging that person you're saying you know what I really like your attitude that's
the good way of thinking exactly so if you want to if you want to push someone and say you know
good for you this is a good way to approach it you say that's the spirit okay awesome so
this is all the language that we have for fluency builder when we take a break and we'll be right back
I come seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try and I have been here for
two years already well have you thought of getting an MBA I heard it does wonders and getting you to the top
an MBA hey well my degree wasn't in business the business schools weren't being trusted in me
nonsense the business schools measure your ability through a test called GMAT GMAT what does that stand for
and what will the test contain graduate management admission test it contains three parts analytical
writing assessment the quantitative section and the verbal section not only does the test score you on the
number of questions answered but also on the difficulty okay this sounds a little tough how
am I supposed to practice for this up to you you could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group
sessions you can also use free or private computer software going to church might help as well
no matter what I do I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cap
uh that's the spirit all right we're back so now talking about the GMAT and then MBA this seems to be
a very popular topic nowadays everyone wants to get obviously a good education and go to graduate school
which means getting your master's degree or your doctoral degree um what do you think about the GMAT
and the MBA is it is it a miracle worker like this girl says she does wow it does wonders for
your career do you think that's really the case I don't know you know maybe if you asked me five
years ago I would say yes but I really believe that it depends on the person nothing is a miracle
cure I do think that if you if you really have a good attitude and you work hard you'll get a lot
out of it but if you think it's going to get you a job you're wrong because you you have to get yourself
a job so I think it depends on the person now obviously also it depends on the country right now how
popular or how important is it for people to have a let's say an MBA to get ahead and business
in the United States I'd say it's pretty important you don't have to have an MBA I mean you can
start your own business and if you're successful you'll probably start more businesses but getting
an MBA is also a very good opportunity to network to meet people to find out more about the industry
that you want to start out in and so I think in that sense it's pretty important because it's a
way to start making contacts mm-hmm yeah it you definitely meet a lot of people uh with work
experience from different backgrounds international students so it's obviously a great thing but
obviously to be able to do one of these uh programs like a get an MBA you have to take these tests
which I understand are very very difficult they are very difficult and it can be very expensive I mean
graduate school itself is $100 200 thousand dollars and uh then to prepare for the tests you could
spend another thousand dollars just getting classes or tutoring so I do think that uh it can it can
be a lot of uh it can be a lot of money upfront but there are there are places that you can go to the
study and um you could even study on your own using your computer so yeah exactly I think this is
a very interesting topic because in many different cultures in many different places education or
for example higher learning like getting an MBA is has different levels of importance like in Europe
a lot of Europeans maybe don't really even pay too much attention to getting an MBA whereas in
other countries they might really emphasize like you have to have an MBA it's really good it's
going to be good for your career so it's very interesting to see how in different places they handle it
it is interesting and I'm actually very curious to hear from our users have you ever thought about
getting an MBA our MBA is important to do business in your country but let us know our website is
all right we'll see you guys there bye