Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we've got an
upper intermediate level lesson for you guys today. This one is all about a crime scene. That's right.
So we are going to be at a crime scene. We are with the police officers and we're going to take a look at
some very, very interesting and specific vocab to like police and a crime in all that. That's right. So if you're
a fan of, so if you're a fan of the TV shows CSI or you like some of these
investigation police work TV shows, this is a lesson for you. That's right. So why don't we go and
listen to the dialogue for the first time?
Alright officer McGraw, give it to me straight. What are we looking at here?
Detective McGee, glad to see you. We could sure use your expertise on this one. It's a
break-in but nothing seems to have been stolen. I'm going to send a call from the bear family at around
10 30 this morning. They'd gone out for a walk before breakfast and came home to this mess.
Broken chairs and porridge all over the place. Apparently mama bear had made the porridge a little too hot
you see. They were waiting for it to cool down. Okay then let's start examining the evidence.
Have the friends X team been in yet? Yes sir. They found some fingerprints on the bowls and
are analyzing them back at the lab as we speak. Hopefully they will be able to identify the
burglar soon. Hmm. Aha! What's this? A strand of golden hair. This is a very important
piece of trace evidence, McGraw. It tells me the suspect has long golden hair and very few men
have long golden hair. So our criminal could be a woman. A woman was she working alone? Did she have
an accomplice? In a complice? No. No McGraw. She was definitely working alone. See here there
are footprints in the porridge. Here on the floor, small footprints. This tells me that our suspect is
small and could possibly be a child. A child? Surely not sir. We must follow the clues McGraw.
The evidence doesn't lie. Now let's reconstruct the crime. The suspect came in,
set an each chair breaking the smallest one into little pieces. Next the porridge.
She obviously tried to eat it because it was so hot she dropped it on the floor.
Making this mess. Hmm. Interesting. These footprints seem to lead upstairs. McGraw.
Did your officers clear the scene? Well there was no one down here. Maybe we forgot to check
upstairs. Hey, what's with all the noise? I'm trying to sleep up here. There she is. Get her.
All right we're back. So a lot of interesting phrases there. They are obviously
investigating a break-in. Okay, a break-in. Yeah, so someone broke into this family's house.
So they have to investigate the evidence and some of the things that were left behind.
So now why don't we take a look on language takeaways. Some of the specific words they used.
Language takeaway. All right. The first word that we have is forensics. The forensics team.
Forensics team. So a forensics team is a team at a police department or police station
that studies the things that are left behind after a crime. All right. So that team
goes and collects the evidence. So you could look at hair or fingerprints or foot prints.
Things like that. A forensics team is kind of like a team that puts together puzzle pieces trying to
figure out what the story was. So as you said, the TV show CSI, the whole show revolves around
the follows a group of forensic scientists who go to crime scenes and look at blood and different
at pieces of evidence that are left behind. Very cool. So one piece of evidence that a forensic
team might look at is a fingerprint. That's right. A fingerprint or in the dialogue we found
fingerprints the plural form. Okay, so for example, if you go to a police station because
the police think that you have committed a crime, the police will take your fingerprints.
Mm-hmm. I mean, so I'll put your finger. I mean, so I'll put your fingers into ink and they will
make you push your fingers onto a piece of paper to see what your fingers look like. That's right.
So our fingerprints have a unique pattern. Everyone has different fingerprints. They are no
two fingerprints alike in the world, right? Right. So it's kind of like a form of identification.
Mm-hmm. Very good. That's right. So that is your fingerprint. So moving on, we talked about
fingerprints now and the scientists who are investigating the crime scene and they are talking
about a very important piece of trace evidence. Okay. Well, let's look first at the second word.
There we've got the word evidence. So evidence is something that is usually physical, like a piece
of clothing or hair, that can be used against someone when we're trying to prove that they have
committed a crime. Right. So for example, a weapon or fingerprints, all that is evidence.
Okay. So Marko, what's the difference between evidence and trace evidence? Well, as you
notice, you have the specific word, their trace and to trace means to to follow or connect maybe.
To connect, right? So what you're doing here is you are taking this evidence to follow or connect
the person that committed the crime. So for example, fingerprints, let's you know who committed the
crime. Oh, okay. Or maybe if you have blood, you can find out who did this crime. Right. But what about
like a broken window? Well, that's just evidence. That just lets you know how the the crime was
committed. Maybe how they got into the house. But not who did it. But not who did it. Okay. So
trace evidence helps you connect the crime to the person who committed the crime. Mm-hmm.
And well, moving on, we found that very important piece of trace evidence, which was a piece of
or a strand of golden hair. And the police officer said, well, this tells me that the suspect
has long golden hair. So a suspect. Okay. This word is, it looks exactly the same as the word to
suspect. Mm-hmm. But be careful because we say these two words in a different and different ways.
So two suspect. That's a verb. That's right. So I suspect Marko did it. Mm-hmm. So that means I
think or I imagine. Right. Whereas a suspect, a noun, a suspect, is a person. So the person who we think
or the person who the police think committed a crime. Okay. Okay. So for example, we're talking about
some trace evidence like a long blonde hair. That means the suspect is probably a woman and
is probably blonde. Very good. And it's interesting that you use the verb to suspect and a suspect
all because you're not sure yet. So this person may have committed the crime or may not.
That's right. So we have to wait until the trial. We have to wait until we prove this person is
guilty before we can say that they actually committed the crime. Very good. Okay. And well, you
have a suspect. And usually you also have somebody who is in a complist to the crime or to the suspect.
Okay. So a suspect, as we said, is a person and it's a noun. So it's an accomplice.
So a complist is a suspect's helper. Right. So basically, if you're robbing a bank and I wait outside
in the car, right, while you're robbing the bank, then I am in a complist. That's right. And under
most laws, you could be sentenced to jail. Right. So the a complist usually doesn't commit the crime.
Right. You rob the bank, but I just waited outside in the car to drive you out. So I didn't rob the
bank. Right. But sometimes the complist is do also have guns and shoot people or knives. So
an accomplice is basically just the helper of the criminal, but they can get in trouble too.
Right. So basically, it's a person that helps out and knows about the crime, but didn't tell the police
about it. Exactly. That's a really important aspect. Okay. So a lot of interesting words there,
all related to crimes. Why don't we move on now to a couple of different phrases that we have prepared
for you on fluency builder? Fluency builder. Okay. I like this first phrase. It's a phrase you might
hear a lot actually in police shows. Mm-hmm. Give it to me straight. Give it to me straight.
Actually, also you can use it when you're just talking to someone and they're like,
hesitant, right? I don't know how to tell you this, but uh... Not so sure. I don't think you're
going to like what I have to say. So I can just say, okay, come on. Just give it to me straight.
Okay. I don't like your shirt. No, I'm just kidding. That's a nice shirt.
But what you're basically asking for is the person to say, be honest with me. Be direct. Be direct.
Straight can mean both of those things. Mm-hmm. Honest or straightforward or quick.
Um, you don't want someone to go around and around and say lots of different things. So I guess
yeah, that does make sense. Give it to me straight. Maybe comes from straight forward. So to be
straightforward is to not hesitate to just say something directly and honestly.
Exactly. Okay. So moving on to our next phrase, a McGraw is talking about the bowls.
And he said, well, they are analyzing them back at the lab as we speak.
As we speak, okay. So this is actually a phrase that refers to time. Mm-hmm.
So in this instance, what he's basically saying is, right now, they're being analyzed right now
or in this moment. So it's a way of indicating that something is happening at this very moment.
Exactly. So I could say, did you know that the president is giving a speech? As we speak?
Okay. So that means the president is talking right now. Exactly. As we speak. Mm-hmm.
Okay. Very good phrase. Now moving on to our third phrase, uh, detective McGee was talking about
reconstructing the crime. He said, let's reconstruct the crime. Okay. So I don't know if any of you
watch these crime TV shows like Dexter or CSI. This is my favorite part, right? Because they tell
you exactly what they believe happened. Mm-hmm. So to reconstruct means to build again or to
recreate, to create again. So basically they started the beginning and they pretend to follow
what happened during the crime. Mm-hmm. So that's basically the verb to reconstruct, to rebuild,
recreate. Mm-hmm. Okay. Reconstruct the crime. Very good. And what about our last phrase?
Okay. So our last phrase is again a very typical police phrase. Are you hear this a lot when there's
been a crime or on TV when they're talking about the scene of the crime? That means the place
where the crime happened. Mm-hmm. And the police say we need to clear the scene or did the officers
clear the scene? Mm-hmm. So to clear means to empty out. Right. But they're not talking about
emptying out the evidence or removing everything from the house. They're just saying to remove people,
right? Right. For obstructions. Exactly. And why is it that a police officer would want to
make all the people go away? Well, because you don't want people stepping on the evidence or
maybe putting their fingerprints all over the place. Right. So it's very important that the
officers, the police officers, clear the scene so that they can start their investigation. Right.
Very good. A lot of interesting phrases there. I think we should go back.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll come back and talk a little bit
more of this clip. And we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this really interesting topic.
All right, officer McGraw. Give it to me straight. What are we looking at here?
Detective McGee, glad to see you. We could sure use your expertise on this one.
It's a break-in, but nothing seems to have been stolen. We were sending the calls from the
bear family at around 10-30 this morning. They'd gone out for a walk before breakfast and came home
to this mess. Broken chairs and porridge all over the place. Apparently Mama Bear had made the
porridge a little too hot. You see, they were waiting for it to cool down.
Okay, then let's start examining the evidence. Have the friends' team been in yet?
Yes, sir. They found some fingerprints on the bowls and are analyzing them back at the lab as we speak.
Hopefully they will be able to identify the burglar soon.
What's this? A strand of gold in here. This is a very important piece of trace evidence, McGraw.
It tells me the suspect has long golden hair and very few men have long golden hair.
So our criminal could be a woman. A woman? Was she working alone? Did she have an accomplice?
In a complice, no, no McGraw. She was definitely working alone. See here, there are footprints in
the porridge. Here on the floor, small footprints. This tells me that our suspect is small and
could possibly be a child. A child? Surely not, sir. We must follow the clues, McGraw.
The evidence doesn't lie. Now, let's reconstruct the crime. The suspect came in,
set in each chair breaking the smallest one into little pieces. Next, the porridge,
she obviously tried to eat it because it was so hot. She dropped it on the floor,
making this mess. Hmm, interesting. This footprint seemed to lead upstairs.
McGraw, did your officers clear the scene? Well, there was no one down here. Maybe we forgot to
check upstairs. Hey, what's with all the noise? I'm trying to sleep up here. There she is. Get her!
So you mentioned a couple of different shows such as Dexter and CSID who do you watch any of these shows?
I do. I'm a big fan of Dexter. Dexter. And Dexter, as you know, works at a police station in Miami.
And his character is in forensics. He analyzes blood. He's like a blood expert. Yes.
And, but it's interesting because he is actually, he commits crimes himself. So he uses his knowledge
to help him to not get caught. Right. So he's both a criminal and he's a police officer. But he's
kind of like a superhero criminal, right? Because he doesn't kill for a fun or pleasure. He just
takes out people who kind of deserve it, right? Yes, but he does kind of do it for pleasure because
he he's obsessed. He can't not kill. So instead of killing good people, he decides he will only
ever kill bad people. Mm-hmm. It's a really good show. I've watched a couple of of episodes
that are in this very, very good. The same as CSID. There are a couple of different versions. There's
CSID Miami, New York, and Las Vegas. But my favorite is Las Vegas. It's very, very good. And also
law and order. I've watched a couple of episodes of line orders pretty good. Yeah, they often talk
about forensics because they have both parts. They have the police part and the law part with the
lawyers who have to use the evidence in court. Mm-hmm. Very interesting. And there's also, well,
forensic scientists, they take a look at the evidence. But I think also they examine the body
back at the, at the, at the more, right? That's right. They look at the body to find out what
happened to the body. This is all a part of reconstructing the crime. So this person is also sometimes
called a coroner, right? Okay. The person who analyzes the body. It's pretty scary though. I
feel if you think about having to, you know, to analyze the body. Mm-hmm. Yeah, I don't know.
It's, yeah. I think you have to be very experienced. It's a very interesting. I don't know. I
don't even know how somebody becomes a forensic scientist, for example. Do you study this this
course? Yeah. They have lots of forensic programs. I think I saw in Discovery Channel, they have
a reality TV show about, you know, students, forensic students and they're actually taking
three of crime scenes and then they get eliminated one by one. I'll have to look at that. Well,
I'm curious to know, have you ever heard of this before forensic science or forensic anthropology?
There are lots of people who study this and who do this as a job. And if you're not interested in
that, maybe you could tell us about what kind of crime drama TV shows you like, because we certainly
love them here. Our website is EnglishPod.com. All right. We'll see everyone there. Bye.