Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very very useful intermediate level lesson for you all about the weather.
That's right so obviously we have seen the news and sometimes on the news we have the weather report.
So today we're going to learn all about that weather report in English.
So let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about the words and phrases that those weather forecasters used.
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers?
I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend Mary. There's a storm system moving through the east coast.
It will be drizzling all day today and there's a 60% chance of thunderstorms this evening.
It will be warm and humid all weekend in the Midwest. Expect strong winds and a low over on 40 degrees.
That's pretty chilly for the summer. Will it rain on Saturday?
Unfortunately yes. It will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a high chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day.
There is a severe thunderstorm warning for some parts of the southeast.
Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding especially in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfall.
That certainly sounds like a jury Saturday.
It gets better on Sunday though. The storm systems move east and the skies will clear up at night.
It will still be rather cool with highs in the low 50s. The west coast will be experiencing some unusually chilly weather.
But at least the sun will come out. I advise weekend travelers to be careful especially while driving.
Back to you Mary. Thanks John and there you have it.
Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right we're back so apparently they're not going to have great weather this weekend and they actually started with an interesting word.
And actually the commentator started with asking the weatherman John what does the forecast look like for our weekend?
Okay so the word here forecast is very very important because it describes this part of the newscast.
A forecast is basically a prediction or a description of the future weather situation.
That's right so we're talking about the weather forecast.
Now it's very interesting because we can also use that in business for example in budgets.
You can say what is the financial forecast of the company?
All right so you can't know what will happen but you can predict it and that's what a forecast is.
That's right so we're talking about the weather forecast and the weatherman said that well
there are some storms coming and it will be drizzling all day.
Okay so to drizzle is a verb and it's like the verb terrain except it's less by degree so
very light rain. Yeah it's kind of like if I spray you with with water,
not a spray can or something it's like drizzle. It's just little dots of water.
It's not like you're getting wet. You don't really have the normal heavy rain drops.
You just have a little bit of water coming down. But it's annoying because do you bring your umbrella?
Do you believe your umbrella? So drizzling is a kind of rain that's very very light.
That's right. All right so it's going to drizzle all day and the weatherman also said that we
might have some thunderstorms. Okay so thunderstorms are very different. Thunderstorms are kind of
storm where there is thunder so thunder is the loud noises when there's lightning.
lightning okay so lightning is like the flash that you get from the sky and thunder is the
hard sound that comes after the boom that's right. Yeah so remember light lightning.
Light is the light that comes down from the sky lightning and thunder storms are just those loud
noises that the lightning makes. So usually with thunder storms we have very heavy rain. That's
right and that's why it's different from drizzling which is very light. Okay now we're talking
about water we have drizzle we have thunder storm. Now what about a shower because the weatherman said
there is a high chance of showers. Well yes there's a high chance of showers I take showers every
day thank you very much but this is not the kind of shower we're talking about here is it? That's right.
Think about it though it's similar. A shower when you wash yourself is water coming down on top of
you. Well in this case it's a rain shower so it's rain that's happening. Okay so it's rain water
that's coming down very similar to the shower that you take in the morning. The difference though
is that a shower is a noun and terrain is a verb so it will rain tomorrow or we expect showers
tomorrow both mean the same thing. All right very good and well talking about showers and thunder storms
there's also another type of water that falls from the sky this is called hail. Okay so hail is
difficult to describe because it's like ice but it's not really it's just usually hard almost like
marbles like hard balls of rain that come down so it's not snow that's right. It hurts when it
hits you sometimes it's very big sometimes it's very small but it's heavy hard things that come out
of the clouds. Yeah so just think about it it's very very similar to ice it's the small pieces of ice
coming down from the from the sky. So that's hail but obviously very different from snow because as we
said it's hard snow is very soft. Yes and well with this type of weather going on on the weekend
the commentator said wow that certainly sounds like a dreary saturday. Okay dreary is a great
word to describe it so as you can tell it's gonna rain it's dreary is not a good thing it's not a happy
thing. Okay so something is dreary when it's not very exciting it looks like it'll be dull or
sad or boring or dark. Now can you describe a person like this as well? Yes he's a very dreary person.
He's never optimistic he's always down and yeah kind of quiet and sad and down. boring. Yeah.
Okay so that's what it means something that's a boring not very exciting or very calm.
But also dark there's a dark element too because it's dreary you know there's no sunshine there's no
light there's no optimism. But you can say it's a dreary day. Yeah very dreary day today no light no sunshine
okay very good. We've taken a look at a lot of vocab there why don't we review what we've just
learned and listened to the dialogue again.
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers? I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend
Mary. There's a storm system moving through the east coast. It will be drizzling all day today and
there's a 60% chance of thunderstorms this evening. It will be warm and humid all weekend
in the Midwest expect strong winds and a low around 40 degrees. That's pretty chilly for the summer
will it rain on Saturday? Unfortunately yes it will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a
high chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day. There is a severe thunderstorm
warning for some parts of the southeast. Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding
especially in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfalls. That certainly sounds
like a dreary Saturday. It gets better on sunday though the storm systems movies
and the skies will clear up at night. It will still be rather cool with highs in the low
50s. The west coast will be experiencing some unusually chilly weather but at least the sun will
come out. I advise weekend travelers to be careful especially while driving back to you Mary.
Thanks John and there you have it. Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right we're back so now we're going to talk a little bit about some phrases that we've
chosen for you on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder So when we're talking about forecasts
remember that we're talking about things that aren't certain we have to explain that there is
a possibility of rain or a possibility of sunshine and usually in the weather report they will
use percentages to describe how likely something is to happen. That's right the weatherman said
there is a 60% chance of thunderstorms. 60% is not very likely but it's also not unlikely.
It means that it might happen that it rains. That's right so as you said it's a way to measure
what the probabilities are because you imagine if the weatherman says it might rain tomorrow you're
like well maybe it really will or maybe it's very unlikely that it won't or we don't really know.
Exactly so for example if the weatherman says there's a 95% chance of rain tomorrow do you bring
your umbrella? Yes. What if he says there's a 5% chance of rain tomorrow now? No so you have to
think about the probability. 60% it's maybe half and half but 95% it's very likely to happen.
That's right and he also mentioned that there's a high chance of thunderstorms or maybe you
can say there's a low chance of hail. Right so he's basically saying he or she is basically saying
you know it's possible it's not likely it's not likely it's not happened they're trying to
help you out they can't say this will happen because they don't know. Okay so the word for probability
here the key word is chance there is a good chance that it will rain so chance is probability.
Right so for example what's the chance it will rain tomorrow? Well there's a high chance.
Okay very good okay and now when we talk about the degrees or the how warm or cold it is
so we express it in Fahrenheit in some countries or in other countries in centigrade here we
talk about 40 degrees Fahrenheit but the weatherman also says highs and lows there's a a low of around
40 degrees what does he mean at low? This is a really important part of the forecast because you need
to know what you have to bring a coat tomorrow is it going to be hot or cold and so you think about
a day usually during the day at noon or one o'clock in the afternoon it's the hottest but at night
it's the coldest and so the low refers to the lowest temperature and the high refers to the highest
temperature so for example in the fall maybe the highs are 60 degrees but the lows are 40 so you
should bring a coat. Okay means at night it'll be 40 during the day it'll be 60. Okay so we're talking
about the highs or the highest temperatures or the highest number that we'll get and the lows is the
lowest so the weatherman will commonly say tomorrow we'll experience a high of 32 degrees and a low of
25. Right so it's very easy to understand that the temperature during the day will be between these
two-nong right. Very good. Okay and for our last phrase the weatherman also said that there is a
severe thunderstorm warning for some parts of the southeast. All right so Marko this is a really
key phrase because it is it's telling people about potential danger you know a thunderstorm can be
very dangerous so you want to stay inside so a severe thunderstorm warning severe means very
very serious it's something you should pay attention to. That's right but now the interesting thing
is that we can change the noun in this case thunderstorm and we can talk about for example a severe
tornado warning. All right so if there's a severe tornado warning then I really have to pay attention
to the weather and be careful not to go outside or even a severe flood warning. You need to know that
the streets might become flooded and prepare. So they're saying that there's a very high probability
that this might happen so they're warning you to take precaution. All right so pay attention to that
and we're going to listen to today's dialogue one more time we'll be back in a moment to talk a
little bit more about the weather.
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers? I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend
Mary. There's a storm system moving through the east coast. It will be drizzling all day today
and there's a 60% chance of thunderstorms this evening. It will be warm and humid all weekend
in the Midwest expect strong winds and a low around 40 degrees. That's pretty chilly for the summer.
Will it rain on Saturday? Unfortunately yes it will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a
high chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day. There is a severe thunderstorm warning
for some parts of the southeast. Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding especially
in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfalls. That certainly sounds like a jewelry
Saturday. It gets better on Sunday though the storm systems move east and the skies will clear
up at night. It will still be rather cool with highs in the low 50s. The west coast will be
experiencing some unusually chilly weather but at least the sun will come out. I advise weekend
travelers to be careful especially while driving back to you Mary. Thanks John and there you have it.
Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right so talking about the weather it always seems like the weatherman is always wrong.
Always it's like the opposite of what should happen. That's right. But you know you can't blame
them because all they have is the computer and some sensors and they have to guess about the weather
and help people to do. Have you ever experienced anything severe like a like a hard thunder storm
or maybe a tornado or something like this? I have actually because I'm from Chicago and in America
the middle of the country is called the tornado belt. That means it's a piece of land where
tornadoes are very common. And so in the fall and in the spring we often have tornadoes and I've been
in a couple tornadoes myself. All right have you seen them? Yes. There is an amazing to see.
They're very scary. You're always running inside and locking yourself in the basement. It's very
important to protect yourself in a tornado because it's it's very dangerous around the area of the
tornado because the wind is so strong that trucks and cars and telephone poles and big big heavy
objects can fly through the air and hurt people and that's how most of the damage happens.
Okay so this is interesting because a tornado is also considered a natural disaster. Yes it is.
But it is a it's some it's a weather phenomenon. Whereas earthquakes are a natural disaster but it's not
part of the weather. Now yeah you're right it's not something that it sweeps in and it leaves like a flood
for example all of the rain will come down and it will create a flood and earthquake is an
natural disaster that's not weather related. That's right. Okay interesting things though maybe some of
listeners that live in a very cold area have experienced the heavy snowstorm like a blizzard like a
blizzard or maybe people in a tropical area have experienced a hurricane so let us know if you've
ever been in one of these weather related phenomena and also if you have any comments or questions
we're always at EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there. All right bye.
you