Hello English learners. Welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marko.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about something very, very important in the computer age internet internet and internet connections.
Right, I think well so many people use the internet now and have it but it's sometimes a little bit complicated to maybe get a plan or maybe if you're not too familiar with the terms
Um, that's what we're going to be looking at today. So listen out for some of these words today. We're talking on the phone with someone who's going to help us get a plan
When we come back we're talking all about what some of these words and phrases mean so if you're confused just wait a couple seconds and we'll be back
Welcome to Gallinet. How can I help you? Hi. I would like to get an internet plan for my house. Of course
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from. The first one is the cheapest but most basic plan
Which is $30 a month. This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps
I have no idea what kbps means. I just want to be able to get online play games and chat with my friends. Oh, and watch movies online as well
Well, this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs. I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month
Which includes a connection speed of two megabytes that way you can play games online without any lag
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall. Absolutely free. Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you this month. We aren't charging our normal installation fee
You're saving yourself a hundred bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive awesome
All right, so interesting a lot of these a technical terms
Specifically for internet computers and connection and all that stuff
Yeah, and the nice thing about some of these words is that they can be used in other ways as well
So we're learning about these and expanding our vocabulary
But they're useful in many other
Contexts as well. Okay, so let's get started with these words now in language takeaway
Language takeaway
So this first phrase for example is something that you see advertised all the time and it's well
It's a kind of internet connection. Mm-hmm broadband Internet. Okay, so internet is pretty clear
But broadband you might be asking what the heck can this mean? Okay, so you have broad
So broad means wide wide and a band is basically a kind of like a frequency that at which something works like band with
Band with huh, so you have broadband you have fast or high speed internet. That means the bigger the space is the more
Information can be transferred, so it's it's a fast connection
Exactly before broadband we had dial up
Internet
Yeah
Remember A well yeah
So slow you have to use your modem and call a number and then get connected by my telephone toy was a dial up connection
But it was so slow and every time it broke the connection would break you had to dial up again
Like the whole process is so annoying exactly so
Fortunately now not many people use dial up anymore and we have broadband internet
Now that if you have broadband internet, it's really convenient because you can download any type of application or music videos
etc. Right, so this is another key computer word that actually has a couple of different uses for example
As you said you can download music
We're download photos that means you find a photo on the internet that you like and you could save it on your computer
But you can also have a download so it can be a thing too. Okay
So if maybe you're downloading three different files you have three downloads. Okay, so two download and download
Very good, so now we internet you have different speeds as we talked about right how fast you're downloading something and the guy
mentioned a 512 K BPS. Oh no, not
One of these K BPS, so this man actually this was pretty simple
You can think about kilobytes you've heard about megabytes kilobytes. This is a this is a size
Hmm, that how fast you can receive these packets of information
So 512 kilobytes per second per second. That's I have no idea how much that is it's maybe a lot
It sounds like a lot right well basically it is a lot
But we saw later that he was asking for a connection speed of two megabytes
Ooh, so mega is bigger than K P B s right right all right
So these are different speeds of transferring information right so this is a way for you to see what kind of internet plan you want
Exactly and so you have kilobytes
We have megabytes and basically you want a faster connection speed because you want to avoid lag
lag
All right
This is a word that you can use in a lot of different ways for example
My brother always lags behind
Okay, so it's it's a verb
But in this case we're talking about the noun so lag is
Slowness yeah, it's like a delay. Yeah, it's delay and in something so in this case
I can't even play my video games because there's too much lag
So I mean the internet's too slow too slow exactly so that's what happens when you have a slow connection speed
You have lag and as you can say it refers to something that slow or delayed
So you can use it in other contexts when you want to say something is a little bit slow
Well, and another key thing here as we're talking about internet connections is the router
So router something that helps us to
route an internet connection so it for example is
So it basically distributes the internet connection to different computers or to different users and some of these you plug in and some of them are wireless
That means without a wire so a wireless router is something a little box in your house that allows you to maybe have
Your four computers on one
broadband connection right so it's very popular now
You go to Starbucks and you have Wi-Fi and in order to have Wi-Fi or wireless internet
You need a router a wireless router. Okay, so wireless router and
Finally, what is something that might get in the way of a connection?
You have a firewall very important security measure when navigating the internet
All right, so a personal firewall is a firewall that you have on your computer to keep people from
Spying on you this keeps other people out
So it's exactly that it's a wall between your between your computer and the outside world
So it protects you from any type of maybe malicious intruders right and oftentimes
Governments and
Public offices things like that law offices
They have
Firewalls to protect the information that they store because it's so important that it's secretive. Yeah
So firewalls there are many different types of firewalls, but a personal firewall is just a basic one
Great, so that is our language takeaway for today. Let's check out this dialogue again and slow it down a bit this time
Welcome to Galen it. How can I help you? Hi, I would like to get an internet plan for my house
Of course we have three different plans with different prices you can choose from the first one is the cheapest
But most basic plan which is $30 a month
This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps
I have no idea what kbps means
I just want to be able to get online play games and chat with my friends. Oh, and watch movies online as well
Well this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month which includes a connection speed of two megabytes
That way you can play games online without any lag
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall
Absolutely free do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee
You're saving yourself a hundred bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive
Awesome
All right great so we just heard all these words that we looked at before
But now why don't we take a look at some of these phrases in fluency builder
Fluency builder what's this first one I can't read it. I have no idea what what did you write it down?
I have no idea what you're talking about all right enough game. No, I have no idea
This is if this is it. Well, it's gonna treat this as a phrase that gets said as is we're not gonna take bits and pieces of it
So I have no idea or he has no idea is a way to say listen I don't know I don't know
I really don't know right the guy was talking about KBPS and all these things and and the other guy was like
I have no idea what you're talking about I don't understand and I can
I can definitely am I late. Yeah, well we'll leave that for another one
But after this it got a bucks all right so bucks what is this slang bucks a hundred bucks
200 bucks a lot of money right so bucks is basically another way of saying dollars all right
So this is a way for well this is the way that most Americans talk about money
It's a one buck is one US dollar all right so
Kind of brought ten bucks Marco right. Oh, yeah sure. There you go now bucks you can only use it for American currency right you can't use it for like a year-olds
No, no, you can't say like ten-year-olds would be ten bucks no, no, no, no, usually you say this about American dollars
And you say this just when you're hanging out or how much is this cost oh five bucks
Yeah, but very good so the guy was telling him about the price of the internet and everything and he said
He's gonna throw in a pendrive right he's gonna throw it away. I don't know he's gonna throw in a pendrive for free. Oh
See so throw in means to add or include include so
Listen sir
Here's your large popcorn and I'm gonna throw in a small-deck cook for free. Wow
So you throw in something it's you include it for free, right exactly
So this is usually complimentary item
Great, I think this word is really interesting or this phrase
So why don't we listen to a couple of other examples using throw in example one
If you buy two pizzas, we will throw in another one for free
Example two
Tell you what I'll buy this computer if you throw in a pair of headphones deal
Example three
The salesman threw in a subscription to the local newspaper for buying his product. Isn't that great?
All right great so a good example. I think it's clear now the phrases all these words related to the internet
Absolutely and so useful right so why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more
Welcome to Gallinet. How can I help you?
Hi, I would like to get an internet plan for my house of course
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from the first one is the cheapest
But most basic plan which is $30 a month
This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps
I have no idea what kbps means
I just want to be able to get online play games and chat with my friends. Oh and watch movies online as well
Well this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month
Which includes a connection speed of two megabytes that way you can play games online without any lag
This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall absolutely free
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you this month. We aren't charging our normal installation fee
You're saving yourself a hundred bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive awesome
So the internet is a big deal nowadays and now you can do so much on it not only navigate websites anymore
But watch movies download applications photos Facebook all this type of things now that you can do on the internet
You can even do it from your phone like when you're in the bathroom or on the train
I mean it's scary you're there's we're always connected right so it's it's interesting
You're always connected you're always online with people and it's actually very noticeable when you maybe live somewhere else
Before you used to have to write letters. I don't think many people will receive
Handwritten letters anymore never I'm speaking for myself. I never received and I don't write them either
So yeah, I guess I'm guilty of it so now people just send emails obviously it's more convenient
But maybe it's a little bit less
Significant maybe then actually going to the post office or taking the time to write a letter going to the post office and stuff
Well, I don't know there's something nice about having a physical thing you can hold on to but I wonder if one day
We're gonna forget how to write yeah, you know like write with a pen with a pen and pencil exactly
We're gonna have these little pda's and these little iPhones and they're gonna just
We're gonna talk and they're gonna take everything down and note form for you well now it's kind of happening with the Kindle right now
You can have books on this electronic device that lets you read through them and you can carry a hundred books with you
Exactly, so now you don't even really need physical books and which is good on in on some level because you know
You're saving trees and space and all that stuff, but but there's something
Physical about reading a book you hold it you flip the pages you know how many pages you have left
I don't know we'll see maybe I'll be a Convert one day, but for now
I'm good with paper books all right, so well, what do you guys think about the internet about
Electronic book you can also tell us any problems or confusion you have with the things that we talked about today
Hopefully everything is clear, but if not we are here to answer your questions
Would like to do so so check out our website EnglishPod.com
All right, we'll see you guys there and until next time good bye everyone