Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we're talking about being on the road
yeah we're gonna be on the road but we're gonna encounter a little bit of a car problems
my favorite kind
I think it's happened to everyone you're on the road or maybe you're coming back from work
you get a flat tie or something happens to your car right
and it's always when you're in a rush
and most of the time it's raining
yeah we're just knowing so all of the circumstances definitely well they don't help
let's just say alright so before we listen to this dialogue let's take a look at some of the words in today's vocabulary preview
very cablery preview
alright so we're gonna take a look at two words
they're kind of strange I don't know kind of difficult to understand so that's what we're gonna explain them
the first one is spew to spew
it's a verb okay to spew
well what can spew volcano can spew?
exactly an engine can spew a person can spew
yeah that's not very nice
so basically it's to like expel or to shoot out shoot out from your mouth or something liquid
so in the case of a person right
so if a person spews it means a person throws up but it's usually very forceful
alright it's very messy
volcano can spew lava
exactly so volcano is spewing lava
now for the next word that we have it's a it's a informal way of saying that something is broken
because it's busted
it's busted my DVD player is busted
man my phone is busted
so it's an informal way very popular very common I would say
to describe that something is not working
I don't think many people actually say it's broken or it's damaged
yeah that pretty much makes I think but you will definitely hear busted if you're talking to native English people
or even like for example your arm oh he's got a busted arm
exactly so busted
alright so let's listen to our dialogue for the first time let's see what's going on with this card trouble
and then we'll come back and explain something
howdy nice card what seems to be the problem
I don't know the stupid old car started being white smoke and it just died on me
luckily I managed to start it up and drive it here
what do you think it is not sure yet how about you pop the hood and we can take a look
mmm it doesn't look good
what do you mean my daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month
it's brand new
well missy the white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator
you overheated your engine so now the pistons are busted and so is your transmission
you should have called us and we could have told you over here when you car died
so how long is this going to take an hour
how much freight a bit more than that we need to order the spare parts
take a part of your electrical system fuel pump and engine and then put it back together again
you're going to have to leave it here for at least two weeks
what? how am I supposed to go to school or go shopping?
this is not happening
so if I were the mechanic I would not be very happy to be dealing with someone like this girl
I think it's well maybe it's a little bit stereotypical that we put it as a as a girl
because guys and girls so many people don't know anything about cars or mechanics
and in the states there's a lot of female mechanics too so it's mix
but definitely it's something that happens all the time
and probably the mechanic will overcharge her as well because apparently she doesn't know what she's doing
and that's one of the reasons we want to give you the vocabulary to deal with these situations
so let's look at some of those car words in today's language takeaway
language takeaway
all right so we're going to take a look at very specific words related to cars and the engines and everything
so let's start with the first one
radiator
all right so the radiator of the car
so radiator is something that you normally find in the front of the car near the engine
it usually gets very very hot right?
yeah so one of the biggest issues is radiator is getting too hot because there's no way to cool them down
so if you live in a place that's very hot the radiator keeps your engine cool because it has water in it
so if it overheats or maybe you didn't put enough water in there then it'll start spewing
steam like in this dialogue
and if you have a problem with your radiator you could actually do a lot of damage to your engine
which is why this is important
and exactly and that's what happened in this dialogue
so a radiator
now because the radiator wasn't working well it overheated the engine
and he said they had some busted pistons
so broken pistons pistons are important because they're kind of like valves that go up and down
right so inside your engine you have many explosions and the pistons move up and down and that's what actually moves your car
right and so pistons in general are things in mechanics so like a trumpet has pistons things that go up and down
and that allow for the flow of air or something like that very good
so that's a piston and well another very common mechanic term is the transmission
all right so the transmission what happens if your transmission dies can you still drive
you basically can't move or maybe you only have one gear or two gears
all right so think about transmission is coming from the word to transmit that means to transfer
so this is the part of the car that transfers energy or the power to actually move the car
so the transmission
and we've got the mechanic who says well we've got to order you some spare parts
so first let's look at the word spare what's another word for spare
additional maybe extra
right so spare means extra parts are well pieces
so he's talking about ordering a new transmission new pistons things to replace the broken things
spare parts so this is where you go to the mechanic to get some spare parts and get them installed
you probably don't have many spare parts at home right you got a transmission lying around
oh yeah so spare parts and the last word that we're going to take a look at is a fuel pump
okay so a pump is you could have a bike pump a water pump water pumps so these are
something these are something that we use very very often but a fuel pump is something that
allows gas gasoline to get into your engine so it's basically a device that pushes gasoline
into the engine so you can start and that's the same thing with the water pump it's a device that pushes water
or an air pump is something that pushes air into your tires and your bicycle
exactly so a fuel pump water pump etc
wow I feel like we know a lot about cars apparently we do see alright so now that we've taken
look at all of these great words let's move on to a couple of phrases in low and
see builder
alright these are phrases that you hear sometimes when you're talking about electronics
but in today's lesson we're all talking about specific car phrases you're going to hear these
all the time with mechanics
right and the first one is the car suddenly died on me
alright to die on so we keep these two words together die on
man so while you were driving your car died it stopped moving
so that means that it it doesn't work anymore and it's not only for cars right you can say my
MP3 player died on me today
exactly and what it means is it's not like you left it and you forgot about it and you tried it again
it didn't work it means while you're using it it dies
it doesn't work
so I think this phrase is a good one to give some other example so let's listen
example one
my CD player died on me and I had to listen to the radio
example two
get that medicine over here fast or this guy's going to die on me
example three
I forgot to charge my mobile phone it's going to die on me soon
so this next one is a phrase you hear the first thing you hear maybe
when you tell someone you have a car problem
right you tell them to pop the hood
or let's pop the hood
so this means let's open the front part of the car the hood
to look at the engine transmission all those parts
exactly so you can say open the hood
but the most common one is pop the hood
so the reason is because there is a little spring
and you have to pull inside the car and goes
pop and there's a little there's a little jump
so it's literally popping
right or you can also say the trunk right the back part of the car
hey can you pop the trunk for me I've got to put some stuff inside
exactly so pop the hood pop the trunk
and next we've got this this girl actually who's talking about her car
because she just got this car
so it's another way to say it's a new car
it's brand new
is that more new than new?
it's like newer newer than new
all right so brand you think about brands like Ford or
good cheetahs or brands but brand new means
she maybe got it like today
so it's brand new it's very very new
did you see my brand new watch?
oh it is nice but you get it
all right so brand new
and well the last phrase that we have for you today
is to take apart something
all right so this is very popular with young children
like they like to take things apart
so they can find out how they work
but to take up more means to take all the pieces and to pull them out
yeah I used to do that a lot when I was a kid
I used to take apart any electronic device
to kind of see how it works and then I would try to put it
back together again and that's why you're so smart
well it never really worked
it worked half the time
so the problem is always putting them back together again
exactly so you can take it apart
but then you put it back together
and there's always a screw missing
or a screw that's extra or two or three parts
very not a good sign
all right so we're taking a look at a lot of great words and phrases
so let's listen to this dialogue for the last time
howdy nice card what seems to be the problem
I don't know the stupid old car started being white smoke
and it just died on me
luckily I managed to start it up and drive it here
what do you think it is?
not sure yet
how about you pop the hood and we can take a look
mmmm doesn't look good
what do you mean?
my daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month
it's brand new
well missy
the white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator
you overheated your engine so now the pistons are busted
and so is your transmission
you should have called us and we could have told you over here when you car died
so how long is this going to take an hour?
how much for a bit more than that?
we need to order the spare parts
take a part of your electrical system
fuel pump and engine and then put it back together again
you're going to have to leave it here for at least two weeks
what?
how am I supposed to go to school?
or go shopping?
this is not happening
alright so car travel?
have you ever had any very serious car travel or something weird happened to your car?
actually
the week before I decided to leave Chicago
I had this 1991 Honda Civic
hatchback so only two doors
nice
and I was driving home from work
I was on the highway, I had the radio on
the windows open and then
it died
in the middle of the highway during rush hour
so that's when there's tons of cars
and I didn't know what to do
I'm calling people and then all the sudden I see someone tapping on my window
and there's cars everywhere
and it's this guy
and he's like listen
do you need a hand?
I said yes
so I put the car in neutral
so there's no break
and he pushed it
to his side road and gave me a right home
it was the coolest guy
it was so nice
and he was just there with his truck
he's a gardener
and just gave me right home
it was super, super cool
and so it turns out my engine dot
the engine was new
it was a transmission
it was shot
it was totally broken
but I was very lucky to have such a kind person
yeah that's a good story
because usually people are too afraid
or maybe a little bit reluctant to
to stop and see if you're okay or if you need a ride
or something
because you can't really trust people these days
but it's good
once I saw somebody on the side of the road
and had a flat tire
it was two girls
and they didn't know what to do
so I was passing by
it was actually raining
and I was like hey do you guys need a hand
and then like yeah
we can't
we can't locate my dad
or whatever so I was like
changing the tire
it's not a big deal right
and they wanted to tip me
they wanted to give me some money
and they said like oh please say
it's just so kind of your time
and you're all wet
and I'm like no no
what are you about it?
No it's just a nice thing to do
if you know anything
what cars I mean
yeah yeah
or if you can offer someone
I know it's not terribly safe
to ride with strangers
but this guy totally helped me out
so nice
alright well maybe you guys have some cool
or maybe some interesting stories
of what's happened with your cars
or maybe you've helped somebody out
so come to our website at EnglishPod.com
and let us know
and of course if you have any questions
about the vocabulary of phrases that you heard today
please ask away
Don't hesitate
and well again
we hope to see you on the website
alright we'll see you guys there
bye