Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got a lesson for you that's about an unusual topic.
Something we've never talked about here on EnglishPod.
That's right. As you know in EnglishPod we like to talk about all sorts of topics, especially
topics that are real life topics. So probably a lot of things that you won't find in your normal
English notebooks or English learning books. That's right. So we want to tell you in advance
today's lesson is about drugs. So if you're a younger user or you have if you have kids maybe
they shouldn't listen to today's lesson. But you're going to learn a lot of the names for drugs and
also how to turn down and offer of drugs. So let's check out today's dialogue and we back in a
moment to talk about the things that you've heard.
Hey man you want to buy some weed?
Some what? weed. You know, pot, ganger, Mary Jane some chronic. Oh, and no thanks.
I also have blow if you prefer to do a few lines.
No, I'm okay. Really. Come on man. I've got dope and acid. Try some. Do you really have all of
these drugs? Where do you get them from? I got my connections. Just tell me what you want and I'll
even give you a nouns for free. Hmm sounds good. Let's see. I want. Yeah. I want you to put your hands
behind your head. You're under arrest. Don't.
All right we're back. So as Katherine mentioned obviously everywhere in the world maybe most
likely you've been offered drugs. So we're not only going to talk about drugs but we're also
going to give you some vocab in English how to reject or turn down the offer of drugs.
And now what we're going to take a look at. Let's start in language takeaway with some of the
names of these drugs in English. Language takeaway. Okay so we're in language takeaway here and
I want to warn you some of these words are slang. That means they're not words from like a dictionary.
These are words people use when they're talking to each other in daily life or words that you
hear on the street. That's right you may even hear them a lot in movies as well.
Yes movies and TV. So this first one weed is something there's even a TV show called weeds.
That's right that talks about this topic. So weed is the street name or the most common name for
the drug marijuana. That's right marijuana is the drug name but there are many many many other
names in English that you will hear. So weed is one of them. A weed is a kind of thing that
grows like grass or a flower that you cut because you don't want it. It's bad. It smells bad.
That's right that's exactly right. So the the colloquial name for marijuana is weed and obviously
the the person that's being offered these drugs doesn't understand what that means. So he goes on
and he gives a couple of different other street names for the same drug. So the first one
so the next one is pot. That's right. So he says pot or ganda or Mary Jane or even chronic.
So all of these are synonyms. They mean exactly the same thing. They all mean marijuana. Okay,
but then after that the drug dealer offers other kinds of drugs. He says blow.
So now we may know the verb to blow. Right. That's right to blow air. But in this case it's a noun.
Okay. So he says I have blow. That's right. So he's offering this drug a called blow. And what is
blow? Blow is the street name for cocaine. So there's a very famous movie called blow and it was about
selling cocaine. Now um so after he talks about having blow he also says um if you want to do a few
lines. And so this is what you'll commonly hear people saying how they do this drug. That's right.
So for example, we you may know that many drugs they're consumed in different ways. For example,
weed people smoke it. Right. And this case when we're talking about cocaine or blow then that's
why he refers to do a few lines. All right, because people breathe it in. There knows. That's right.
So that's the colloquial way of saying of how you say that how you consume this drug.
Okay. So moving along there's two more drugs that got mentioned in today's dialogue. They're
dope and acid. Now dope can mean two different things. Sometimes it means marijuana. Like some of
those other words we heard earlier. But sometimes it also means a very, very serious drug called crack
cocaine. Okay. And that's something that people breathe in. And it's very, very addictive.
Yeah, that's right. And also the other word that we have there or the other drug acid. You may know
the word acid is a is a very harmful substance. Like for example batteries they have a certain type of
acid that for example will melt metal or if it gets on your skin it will burn you. That's right.
But acid when it's a drug means LSD. And that is a drug that people take that makes them see things.
So it's called a hallucinogenic. It makes you see crazy things and it was very, very popular in the
1970s. That's right. So that's acid or LSD. Very good. So we've taken a look at a lot of
vocab here specifically all the drugs. Why don't we go back to our dialogue? Let's take another
listen and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Hey, man. You want to buy some weed?
Some what? weed. You know, pot, ganger, Mary Jane, some chronic. Oh, and no, thanks.
I also have blow if you prefer to do a few lines. No, I'm okay. Really. Come on, man. I've
got dope and acid. Try some. Do you really have all of these drugs? Where do you get them from?
I got my connections. Just tell me what you want and I'll even give you a nouns for free.
Sounds good. Let's see. I want. Yeah. I want you to put your hands behind your head. You are under arrest.
Don't.
Okay. So now in fluency builder, we've got a couple of phrases for you about the other side of things.
How to say no to drugs and what you might hear from a police officer like we hear in today's
dialogue. That's right. So let's take a look at these phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So the first one we hear is no thanks. So the guy says, um,
no thanks. He doesn't want the drugs. That's right. So obviously you're being offered something
that you don't like. Let's take into consideration drugs or maybe somebody wants to offer you a drink
or somebody wants to take you on a date. You can say no thanks. No thanks. So hey, Marco,
you want to drink. I'm going to go right now. It's only like two o'clock. But you know, we can go for a drink.
No, thanks. No. Okay. All right. And now we also have another phrase. If a person insist,
the person is continually insisting like, oh, come on, come on, come on, Marco. Let's go for a drink.
I really want a drink. Come with me. Right. And you can say no, I'm okay. Really. So it may
sound confusing. I am okay because that would mean you're in good health. I feel good. I feel good.
But I am in this case when you say to someone, no, I'm okay. You're saying, no, I'm fine. The way I am.
I don't, I don't really need to do anything. I don't need it. So I'm okay, means I don't need it.
All right. And this is a great way to really say, listen, no, I don't want it. Okay. So those are the two
ways that we have in which you can say no. We're going to give you a couple of more towards the end
of the lesson. But let's take a look very quickly at our next phrase when the police officers said,
you are under arrest. All right. So the man did an note. The person didn't know this was a police officer.
And finally, in the end, he says, you are under arrest. That's right. Okay. So this is something you
hear in the movies when they put the hand handcuffs on somebody. The, the preposition is under.
It's strange. But you just have to remember this as a phrase. You are under arrest. I am arresting you.
That means you are going to the police station with me. You broke the law. Right. Or you can say,
oh, a Tim is under arrest. He's at the police station right now. Okay. All right. So we've taken a look at a
couple of phrases and a couple of different things. Why don't we take another short break? Let's
listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit. Hey, man. You want to buy some weed?
Some what? weed. You know, pot, ganger, Mary Jane, some chronic. Oh, no, thanks. I also have
below if you prefer to do a few lines. No, I'm okay. Really. Come on, man. I've got dope and acid
tricem. Do you really have all of these drugs? Where do you get them from? I got my connections.
Just tell me what you want and I'll even give you a nouns for free. Hmm. Sounds good. Let's see.
I want. Yeah. I want you to put your hands behind your head. You are under arrest. Don't.
All right. So obviously a very serious topic, but at the same time, I think very necessary
because it may happen or you may hear it in a movie and it's part of the English language. Now,
obviously we are not advocating or saying that drugs are good or anything. We are saying we are
giving you the tool. So you know how to recognize when somebody is offering you a drug and the way
that you can say no. That's right. So remember that these are things that you might hear when you're
in a country like America or England or Australia, we hope that you don't have to worry about this,
but if you do hear it or you hear it in a movie, you will understand it. But Marker, we had some
other ways to say no to drugs, right, to say no to something, to refuse. So we heard no thanks and I'm okay.
But what are some other ways to say no? Well, for example, if the person also persists or insists,
you can say no, I'm good. Thank you. I'm good. Yeah. So it doesn't really make sense because
you're saying I'm good. What does that exactly mean? So like Marko, you want to cigarette?
No, I'm good. Thanks. Okay. So that's the way of saying no thanks. No thanks. I'm also,
I'm cool. Not saying like I'm really cool. Right. It's like saying no, I'm good. I'm cool. Thanks.
That's right. I'm cool. No thank you. No thank you. Or as well, you can also just say no thank you.
I think the most clear is no I don't smoke or no I don't do drugs.
Yes. Exactly. That's the that's the verb that we use when referring to drugs. You do drugs.
You don't do drugs. So he does drugs or don't do drugs. You often hear this phrase. So you can say,
listen, no, no thank you. I'm cool. I don't do drugs. That's right. So as we said, this is all the
kind of street slang or colloquial, very common ways of referring to drugs in in English.
So you can keep an eye out for that. If you hear that in movies now, you know more or less what
they're referring to. And also, of course, if you have any questions, any comments or any suggestions,
we are always available on our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there and until next time.
Bye.