Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we're talking about a very important day in a couple's life
That's right, we're going to a wedding and but this time it's not going to be so romantic
because actually the groom is having second thoughts about the wedding
Okay, that means he's nervous and he's not positive he wants to get married today
So remember the groom is the man the bride is the woman
Let's jump right into this dialogue. Let's do what's going on
And when we come back we'll be talking about some of the words and phrases you've heard
Man I'm freaking out. You gotta help me. Whoa whoa take it easy relax
Cheese you're sweating like a pig. What's going on?
I can't go through with this. I just can't. I'm not ready for marriage
What was I thinking?
I'm only 35 years old. I've got my entire life ahead of me. Adventure is waiting
I can't settle down yet. What are you talking about?
It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living the life of a
Bachelor and how you envy your friends that have a family. I know I know
Let's think this through. First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar
Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the woman that you love and the woman of your dreams
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this? Second of all, you were just getting cold feet
You know deep down inside that you want to marry her. So cut the crap and do it. You're right. I'm being crazy
Okay, I'm ready. Let's do this. Great. Whew. That was a close one. You hadn't me going there for a minute
I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you
All right. We're back. So almost he almost didn't get married, but luckily you have a good friend to help you out
Exactly. So this friend really saved the day made sure that the groom didn't get too nervous and had some really positive words
So let's take a listen to some of these marriage words in today's language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right. So as you mentioned, we have this word marriage. Now marriage is the noun form right of actually getting married or to be married
Right. Marriage is the noun. The word that describes the relationship between two married people
Okay, and so you have a relationship maybe you're dating, but once you get married the thing between you as a man and woman
That's your marriage. So you could say our marriage is in danger
We need to work on our marriage. Exactly. Or we have a happy marriage. All right. Okay, so that's marriage. Now if you get married and this guy
He mentioned a phrase which was to settle down to settle down. This is a very important phrase to settle down means to get serious mature
And to stop living like a child. It means really to have a house or to start having kids. It's a it's a time and life
So to settle down is to become more stable right as you say to buy a house to have a family to stay in one place and not be so adventurous or stuff like that
Exactly. So it's to calm down and to be more fixed in life. All right. Now the opposite of this would be to be a bachelor
Right. So bachelor is a single man, someone who's not married
And you often hear this term when we talk about apartments. So bachelor pad is an apartment that's specific to a single man
Usually there's lots of video games and the fancy TV and a pool table exactly
All right. So bachelor. We had a lesson about this called bachelor party
Right. Which is a party for a man right before he gets married
Okay, and a bachelor is a special word for a man who's not married
Okay, very good. And now as they were talking about not getting married he said that he can't leave any at the altar
Hmm, so you often hit his in movies. She got left at the altar or you can't leave her at the altar
This word altar is actually religious. Alter is the table in a church where the priest does all of his work
Right. All right. So an altar is a special religious table. So usually two people will stand in front of an altar and get married
Right with the priest who is doing his thing there. Exactly. So that happens at a special place called the altar. Okay, very good
It's also common in the normal mass like on Sundays. Right. Okay. And for the last word or phrase today
It's to get cold feet. You're just getting cold feet. Okay, so this is a very funny phrase in English because it doesn't actually mean that you're your your cold right
So cold feet means you're nervous about something you might change your mind. Okay. Okay, so people often talk about men and women getting cold feet before a wedding
But you can also related to any other situation not only getting married, right?
Yeah, for example, I'm gonna go jump out of an airplane tomorrow. Okay, fast forward tomorrow
Oh, no, I have cold feet. I don't think I want to jump out of an airplane. Okay, so that's the good cold feet
Right. Second thoughts or doubts about actually doing something exactly cold feet. All right, so why don't we listen to our dialogue again
Let's keep a lookout for all of these words and we'll be back in a little bit
Man, I'm freaking out. You gotta help me. Whoa, whoa, take it easy relax. Geez, you're sweating like a pig. What's going on?
I can't go through with this. I just can't. I'm not ready for marriage. What was I thinking? I'm only 35 years old. I've got my entire life ahead of me adventures waiting
I can't settle down yet. What are you talking about? It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living the life of a bachelor
And how you envy your friends that have a family. I know. I know. Let's think this through
First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar. Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the woman that you love and the woman of your dreams
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this? Second of all, you were just getting cold feet
You know deep down inside that you want to marry her. So cut the crap and do it. You're right. I'm being crazy. Okay, I'm ready. Let's do this. Great.
Whew, that was a close one. You had me going there for a minute. I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you.
All right, we're back. So now why don't we take a look at four key phrases that we found in this dialogue on fluency builder?
Fluency builder. This first one is a really great phrase because it's very, well, it's easy to picture this what we're describing.
Sweating like a pig to sweat like a pig. Okay, you're sweating like a pig.
All right, this is a this is a way to say that someone is sweating a lot. Okay, and it's really gross or disgusting. Now do pigs actually sweat.
I don't know if pigs actually sweat, but you imagine someone smells bad and they have, you know, sweat on their face and they're back in their arms.
All right, well, sometimes don't you say you're sweating like a dog.
You could also say that. I guess we like animals in English, but this is just a really great way to say that someone is really sweaty.
All right, and while he was sweating and he was really nervous because he said, I can't go through with this. What does he mean go through with this with what to go through with means to actually do something.
Okay, so maybe I say, I don't want to jump out of an airplane. I can't go through with this. Okay, I can't jump. So it depends on what we're actually talking about.
Okay, if we're talking about a wedding, you say, I can't go through with this. I can't get married.
So if you're planning a robbery, you say, well, in the last minute, I couldn't go through with it. I backed out.
I can't complete what I talked about doing.
Okay, and now the friend, he finally gets kind of angry and he says, cut the crap.
Oh, man, this is a very common phrase.
This is, this is someone says this if they don't want to listen to you complaining anymore. Okay, Marko cut the crap. Okay, I don't want to hear your excuses. I don't want to hear your complaints.
I want to just hear solutions.
Solutions ideas, positive things. So to cut the crap is no more complaints, no more excuses, or no more talking nonsense.
Exactly. This is this is common among teachers and well parents.
All right, so cut the crap. Now it's not very polite, right? So you won't really say to your boss or not, or like a friend.
Cut the crap is kind of rude and it's very spoken language. So I wouldn't write it down.
And I would not use this with someone who is like a teacher. Well, yeah, like a authority.
You don't use it with them. They might use it with you.
Okay, and for our last phrase, he said, who you had me going there for a while, or you had me going there for a minute.
Okay, so this is a really interesting phrase. We use this a lot in English, but it's not clear from listening to it what it might mean.
So you had me going there in this sense means, oh, I was really nervous for a minute.
I really believed what you were saying.
Exactly. So maybe we could give an example, Marco.
All right.
Did you know that yesterday I won a lottery?
I mean, I won like a million dollars and I had the perfect numbers.
Oh my god, really? Can I have a million dollars?
I would love to help you out, man, but yeah, no, I didn't actually win a million dollars.
You had me going there for a minute. You believe me?
You believe me? Okay, maybe not. He's not that.
That gullible. All right, but that's what it means, right?
To believe someone's story, or to think that something's going to happen, even though it doesn't.
You had me going there. That means what you thought was going to happen didn't happen.
So you can use it in the third person.
It's like, yeah, I was telling him this awesome story. And I really had him going for a while.
He really believed me.
And then I told him it wasn't true.
Great phrases. Now let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more about getting cold feet.
Man, I'm freaking out. You gotta help me.
Whoa, whoa, take it easy, relax.
Jeez, you're sweating like a pig. What's going on?
I can't go through with this. I just can't. I'm not ready for marriage.
What was I thinking? I'm only 35 years old. I've got my entire life ahead of me.
Adventures waiting. I can't settle down yet.
What are you talking about?
It wasn't more than a month ago that you were rambling on about how you are tired of living the life of a bachelor and how you envy your friends that have a family.
I know, I know.
Let's think this through.
First of all, you cannot leave Amy at the altar.
Not only will she be humiliated and kill you, but she is the woman that you love and the woman of your dreams.
Why would you want to end that or jeopardize it like this?
Second of all, you were just getting cold feet. You know deep down inside that you want to marry her.
So cut the crap and do it.
You're right. I'm being crazy.
Okay, I'm ready. Let's do this.
Great.
That was a close one. You hadn't me going there for a minute.
I thought I was going to have to slap some sense into you.
All right. So this is a popular scenario.
Somebody at Dom and the wedding day, they get cold feet and they, you know, they back out.
TV, movies, books, everyone loves the situation.
Have you ever actually heard of or experience or maybe known of somebody who actually left the bright at the altar or the groom at the altar?
I don't know anyone who did that luckily.
I think it's really sad. I mean, you know, I don't think it's really that common.
Now, but there was a movie just about this.
So there's a woman Julia Roberts who tries and tries and tries to get married but never can.
So it's called Runaway Bride.
Right.
Because every time she goes to the altar, she gets nervous. She gets cold feet and she runs away.
Right. It's the call her the Runaway Bride.
I can't imagine this actually happening to someone. I mean, you have all your family there, your friends.
You know, be so embarrassing.
It's amazing.
And expensive.
Exactly. Because you've already paid for everything.
So do you get to eat the cake if you're the one who's left behind?
I don't think so. Everything's paid for, right?
Exactly.
You drink all the liquor.
All right.
So that's all the time we have for today.
If you have any questions, any comments, you can come to our website at EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.