Hello everyone and welcome to English and hot my name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we're talking about some very interesting stories
we're going to learn some words for stories or tales but specifically what kind of stories
Marco? They're popular stories that you hear maybe through emails or maybe in your town
there's some particular story about maybe a ghost or many different things that
they're kind of hard to believe but that happened a long time ago and people still talk about today
and they're scary. Yeah, normally. So let's listen to today's dialogue here some interesting
stories and when we come back we'll be talking more about what these words and phrases mean
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world? What do you mean?
I was really about some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their organs removed
then they're sold on the black market. Don't tell me actually believe all that. Don't be so
gullible they are just urban legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even satanic messages
if you played them backwards. Can you believe that? You really think an artist or songwriter is
going to go through the trouble of putting subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right but how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster? Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true. Don't you think?
All right, we're back. So let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So here on language takeaway today we have some words that'll help us understand the dialogue. The first word is
drugged. So I was reading about how some people get drugged in their hotel rooms.
That's right. So if you get drugged it means that someone gave you some drugs in order to
make you sleepy or in order for you to not remember what happened. All right. So he was drugged means
someone gave him a drug something that made him go to sleep. Right. And it's not necessarily
always a bad thing because obviously if you go to the hospital the doctor made drug you in order
to you know not so you don't feel so much pain or something. Exactly. If you're an accident
you're in a lot of pain the doctor drugs you so you don't feel that pain. That's right. So he was
drugged and then what happens? Well his organs were removed. All right. So organ and organ is
a noun. It's thing. Those are actually the things that are inside our body. Right. So your heart
liver, kidneys, kidneys, etc. These are all organs and this is basically the category for
the part of the body. It's anything really inside your body that has a function. Okay. So this is
supposedly this story is that people you know usually tourists they get tricked or drugged and then
they get their organs removed. Now what kind of a story is this markup because it's not just a normal
story. Right. All of these stories that we saw in the dialogue are called urban legends.
Okay. Urban has to do with cities. Right. Legend is a story that may or may not be true. That's right.
It comes from a long time ago. Right. So an urban legend is actually a story that is probably not true
that you hear from other people like your friends. That's right. So usually most of these stories
fall under this category, you know, there are urban legends. You don't really know if they're true
but people say it happened to a friend of theirs from a long time ago or stuff like that. Exactly.
So a friend of a friend of a friend of mine told me that in hotels sometimes they take your organs.
Well, obviously, that's not right. Right. Right. All right. So after that we have two great
adjectives for describing people who like to believe stories like this. What are those two adjectives?
Well, we have the adjective to be gullible and to be naive. All right. So there are a little bit
different to be gullible means to believe everything that people tell you. Right. So if you're gullible
you pretty much believe anything you see or hear or you hear. Yeah. So maybe your friend says
did you know Michael Jordan is coming to the office tomorrow. Right. And you believe it.
Then you're very, very gullible. Very gullible. You believe what people tell you. But naive,
similar, it's similar. But I guess it has a little bit of a different meaning in the sense that
you're not, it's not that you're so gullible but you wholeheartedly trust people. So you're naive.
You're innocent. You're innocent. Maybe you don't have a lot of life experience. So you trust people.
And you can call a person naive. You say, well, he's very naive about these kinds of things.
I guess that's the main key, right? That or the main point is that you don't really have too much
life experience. So that's why you're naive. That's right. And just be careful because gullible and
naive are things that we say about people but they're not nice things. They're not compliments.
Right. Right. So you don't, you shouldn't really say it to someone directly like in the dialogue.
Exactly. Maybe as a joke, but not seriously. Okay. So we have the great adjective
as way to describe people. And lastly, we also have something else that how to describe this situation.
Maybe it's too far fetched. It's too difficult to believe. So far fetched. This is a great word. It
means basically that something is very difficult to believe. Like you say, for example,
the story about Michael Jordan. Michael Jordan is coming tomorrow. You say, oh, that's pretty far
fetched. Right. I don't really think that could happen. Right. So something that is far fetched
is difficult to happen or very, very unlikely to happen. Very unlikely. Okay. So very good. We've had
we saw five keywords there. Let's take a break and listen to the dialogue again.
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world? What do you mean?
I was really about some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their
organs removed. Then they're sold on the black market. Don't tell me you actually believe all that.
Don't be so gullible. They are just urban legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even satanic messages. If you
played them backwards, can you believe that? You really think an artist or songwriter is going to go
through the trouble of putting subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right. But how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chicken
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster? Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true. Don't you think?
All right. Let's take a look now at a couple of phrases on fluency builder. fluency builder.
Now in fluency builder today, we're going to start out with the story about organs. This urban legend.
Now what happens when the organ is taken? The story says that it's sold on the black market.
That's right. So you probably hear this in the news or a lot of places. The black market,
basically it's not really a physical place but it's where things are sold illegally. So guns,
organs, stuff like that. Exactly. So the black market, like you say, is not a place you can go to.
It's an idea and it's basically anything that's illegal that's being sold. Like guns are often
sold in the black market. That's right. Sometimes stolen cars are sold in the black market.
Also organs can be sold in the black market and this is a serious problem because obviously all of this
is illegal. That's right. So the black market is where all this happens. Now moving on to the next
urban legend that we actually didn't really talk about too much is how many people believe that
popular songs have subliminal or satanic messages in them. All right. So let's take a look at the
word subliminal first. We all know what a message is. Right. And something that's told to us.
But a subliminal message is something that is told to us without us knowing. That's right. So it goes into
your mind. But you don't even know it. Right. So it's something that a lot of people believe in because
they think that marketing people or big businesses are trying to control our behavior. That's right.
So I could say very quietly. Marco, by me, did I? And that's a subliminal message.
Hey, you're also going to about getting everyone dinner tonight. And then that's that's basically
a way to control your actions. So whether or not this is possible. That's another discussion.
That's another discussion. But so yeah, that's basically a lot of people say that
to some TV commercials or ads have these subliminal messages that are trying to convince you or
persuade you into maybe consuming that product. Exactly. But they're a little bit different from
satanic messages. That's right. So that's basically dealing with Satan or the devil. That's right.
So the idea that there are satanic messages means that their their messages about the devil
about how maybe God does not exist or like, you know, that you should do evil, not good.
Right. So they're very dark and very kind of angry messages. Yeah, they think they talk about,
for example, I'm not sure which song it is, but like by Ozzy Osbourne that if you play it
backwards supposedly, there's this message that says, you know, worship the devil and stuff like that.
So that's where these urban legends come from. But obviously it's either coincidence or not,
not true, right? That's right. So we've got these messages that are also an urban legend. But
the final one is about KFC. So KFC would be Kentucky Fried Chicken. And what is the legend?
The legend is about their their food. That's right. They say that they don't really have real
chickens that will they take chickens and they they just, you know, super super grow them.
They the chickens are super grown in order for them to get bigger and faster. And that's basically
that they don't really even really have heads. They just, you know, have some hoses that go into
their bodies and feed them in four weeks. You have a chicken. That's disgusting. That's disgusting.
It's the ideas. Yeah, super grown chickens. And so they're basically,
they're not real chickens. Right. That that's what the legend says is that they're not, I mean they
really are, but they're not like naturally grown. You know, usually a chicken takes three
months to grow or something. Yeah. All right. That's disgusting. I don't want that. The idea of super
growing is like using chemicals to do something that's not natural. That's right. That's right.
Chemicals are hormones. This stuff. So that's the use it for example on plants. You can super grow
a plant by adding fertilizer and vitamins and stuff to the soil that makes it grow faster.
Or maybe you have bigger carrots than normal, bigger potatoes because they're super grown. That's right.
So all right. That's a lot of great stuff. Let's take a listen to the dialogue one last time.
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world? What do you mean?
I was reading about how some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their
organs removed. Then they're sold on the black market. Don't tell me actually believe all that.
Don't be so gullible. They are just urban legends. They're just stories people make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even satanic messages
if you played them backwards. Can you believe that? You really think an artist or songwriter is
going to go through the trouble of putting subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right. But how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens,
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster? Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true.
Don't you think?
All right. So all these urban legends they are obviously most of them if not all of them are untrue.
But they're very popular. Why do you think that is? I think people like to believe these stories.
They're gossipy. You know, they're scary. You get to make your friends kind of
nervous about stuff. But I think also we don't trust a lot of these things because we've heard
for years and years and years and years about subliminal messages, marketing strategies,
or about these kind of hidden messages and songs. So there's part of us that wants to believe them.
But the other part is that you hear it enough. You start to believe it. Right. Because
you know, I was reading up on a couple of them and the most recent ones are about how
they make the connection about how Nostradamus predicted the 9-11 incident
or how Coca-Cola is actually the one that invented Santa Claus. And even this KFC one where,
you know, people just believe a lot of different things. I even found one that urban legend about
be careful when you go to the movie theater because there might be a syringe or something on the
seat that if you sit down, they're in Fexy with AIDS or something like this. So there's so many
of them out there that if you think about it, they don't even really make sense. They don't
and I understand that sometimes there'll be one news story like about a needle in a candy box.
And all of the sudden people say, well, don't eat candy because there's needles in candy box.
Right. And obviously, you know, one time event turns into this massive kind of craze.
But it is interesting, especially with this whole topic of subliminal messages, I do remember that
actually there was a marketing campaign that was banned in movie theaters when the previews before
the actual movie came on. Supposedly they had the sound or maybe on the screen,
somebody opening up a Coke can. And the smell of Coke actually coming into the theater and that was
kind of like subliminal marketing making people want to go get a Coke. Definitely. Well, we used to
pump the exhaust from the popcorn maker when I worked in a movie theater throughout the lobby.
There you go. Everyone smells it and it smells so good. You want to buy it. Oh yeah, we would totally
use that. So yeah, that is a way of like I guess it's it is subliminal because you you're not
directly telling them to buy it, but you are just giving them all of the stuff just to get through
audio or visual or oratory cues. Right. And then you have the opportunity to sell them the most
expensive popcorn they'll ever buy. Exactly. 12 dollars for a bag of popcorn. All right, so
it's a very interesting topic. Let us know if you have any comments or questions about it.
You can find us at EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there. Bye.