Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very technical, very advanced lesson for you.
This is all about one of my favorite subjects.
That's right. We're going to talk about music, but specifically we're going to talk about
the piano and learning how to play the piano. So we're going to talk about very specific
vocabularity to this instrument. Right. So piano and playing music, not listening to music.
So we're going to hear a lot of interesting words and phrases here. Some of them actually come from
foreign languages like Italian. So listen up. We'll be back in a moment and when we come back,
we'll be talking about what these words and phrases mean.
Hi Cody. How did practice and go this week? Well, I had several tests in an oral presentation this week.
So I didn't get a chance to memorize the second page, but I think I mastered the tricky section.
Great. Warm up with some scales in our videos first.
Good. Good. This week we're going to keep the rhythm steady when you play the last part
with the 16th notes. Now let's take a look at this tricky section.
Charlie, and before I start I was wondering if it was okay if I put a small crescendo in here
and then a decrescendo back to pianissimo again over here. Hmm, it might work. I'll have to
hear it. Show me what you've done.
Not bad. It was horrible. I played it much better at home.
Oh, it's just nerves. Just play the right hand for now.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 5, 6, 5, T, triple E, T. Good. Good. Don't forget the accidentally.
The key signature says that note should be a G sharp, but now it's a G natural.
Now add the bass clef. You're going to fast. Remember the temple for this piece is undunty.
Is that better? Yes, much better. Watch where you lift your foot off the pedal. What was that?
Sorry, the stretch for that octave is always hard to make. And that's okay. Keep going. You're
moving ahead by leaps and bounds. Watch your dynamics. Keep your elbows lifted. Remember to stroke
the keys. Don't pound. That's better. Remember that as a pianist or any other musician
your technique will be what separates you from the pack. Just as much or as more so as your musicianship.
Alright, we're back. So you probably noticed that there are a lot of ways to describe certain
aspects of playing the piano. They talked about scales and all that stuff. So why don't we take a
deeper look at this vocab in language takeaway part one? Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first part of the lesson is the warm up. That's when we start to get our fingers
moving and really stretch out. This is an important part of any musicians' routine because it's
also a way to practice some very basic, very fundamental things for the first, the first of which is a
scale. Okay, so actually Cody started warming up with some scales. So what exactly are scales?
Well, basically there are different musical notes. Some people know them as Do Re Mi Fa Solato Do.
Some people call them CDEFGAPC. But each of those and many others have scale. So that's eight
notes together. Okay, so basically when you're playing scales you're just playing a sequence of these
eight notes. Right, going up or down. Okay, to warm up. And what about in our pedgio? I think this is
Italian, right? Definitely. Our pedgio is another kind of warm up where you're not playing every
single note. You're playing some notes in a scale. Right, so da da da da da da da da da. That's in our
pedgio. Okay, very good. So as you said, these are usually for warmups, right? Yeah, they're also
very important because they come into play later when you're talking about the key that a song or piece
of music is in. So this helps you memorize the key that some music is in. Okay, very good.
So I think related to this is the rhythm of the piece that you're playing. That's right. So rhythm
is really important. Some people can even say, you know, he's got rhythm or they have rhythm.
It's a way to describe the beat of a kind of music. So sometimes it has to do with how fast
or how slow something is. Other times it has to do with the way that the notes work together.
For example, a steady beat would be 1, 2, 3, 4, 1, 2, 3, 4. This is a complicated beat. It goes
tad, t, trippoli, tad, t, trippoli. So this is a very difficult kind of rhythm. Okay, so the rhythm
is just kind of, it gives you the how fast, how slow it is. And I guess if you can take a look at notes
and you can play it in many different rhythms, but not necessarily they're going to sound correct.
Right. And actually it's interesting. In English, we also have a group of instruments that are
called rhythm instruments. So this would be like the drums. Okay. So it gives the beat. Yes.
Very good. And we're moving on. I think some other Italian words popped up in here when they
talked about crescendo and decresendo. Right. So crescendo is when something becomes louder.
So I can make a crescendo. Okay. But a decrescendo, day in Italian, just like an English means it's
the opposite. So it means it's getting really softer. Okay. And what about Pianissimo?
Pianissimo is basically an indication. It also comes from Italian. It's an indication
that a player, a musician should play something very, very, very quietly. It's almost like a whisper.
Okay. So these three words have to do with the volume of or how loud or not so loud you play the
instrument. That's right. Okay. Very good. And well, moving on now, we talk about
accidental's. Okay. This is important. Remember earlier, we were talking about scales. Well, for
example, the G scale has one sharp. So that's an F sharp. So if I'm playing it on the Piano,
there are seven white keys and one black key. Okay. So actually here they mentioned G sharp.
And then something like G natural. All this, just like for everyone that's out there is
complete Chinese. We have no idea what this is all about. So you have the accidentals in G sharp.
And you're describing something about sharpness with accidentals. That's right. So basically,
if you look at a Piano, you have white keys. Right. Those are those are natural. So they don't have
a sharper flat. The sharp and flats are actually played on the black keys. Usually, it's a half
step from a normal note. So G, it's a half step. Okay. We're talking about different keys.
So if something is in the key of G and all of the music people note, no, this is key of G.
There's one accidental. What's the accidental? It's always F sharp. And so an accidental means a
sharp or a flat in that key. Okay. And when we talk about sharp on the piano, they're basically
the black keys. Yes. Well, sharp and flats can both be black keys. Okay. Very good. And
well, apart from accidentals in G sharp, G natural, the teacher also talked about a base clef.
Okay. This is important for people who play lower instruments like the base, you know, the upright
base that I'm doing. That they won or people who play the piano, obviously. This represents a
way of writing the lower notes. Okay. Okay. So you see the lines, those five lines on paper,
and people write the notes. Well, sometimes they're for higher instruments, you know, the
flute or the trumpet. But sometimes when they're for lower instruments like the left hand of a
piano or for the upright base, you have to write it in a special register, a special part of the
sound kind of continuum. And that's the treble. That's the bass clef. Okay. So basically,
if everyone has ever seen piano notes, it tells you what to play with your left hand and your right
hand. So I imagine the bass clef will be everything that's on your left hand because that sounds
like deeper, graver, right? Yeah. It's lower. No, it's lower on the scale. Instead of like,
a pie up here where it's on the treble clef. All right. So, oh, so the opposite would be the treble clef.
That's right. The treble clef is a pieer. It's most other instruments like the trumpet. The
base clef is for lower instruments. And it just means that the way that you read the music on the
page is a little bit different. Okay. Very good. And well, we also got into things like tempo
and the piece, it was described as Andante. Andante. This is a very Italian word. Okay. So Andante means
that something is played slowly. Okay. So apart from Andante, if so it's a style or a tempo,
I guess tempo is the speed of which is played, right? That's right. But in your right to say that
it's also a style because in many symphonies, for example, there's a movement, a part of the symphony
that's called the Andante. And that's when everything starts to get slow and slow and slow,
it's so pretty. I've heard, I don't know, in piano, I've heard of something called the Cato.
And I think this is also related to tempo, right? Stacato is the way that you play something.
So instead of having these long, pretty notes, you're playing them like this.
Not very very sharp. Right. Like machine gun. Okay. So, but it's not related to the tempo.
It's kind of more just like the way that you press the keys. Exactly. It's a style for playing.
Okay. All right. Well, the teacher also told the student to be careful where they lift the
foot off the pedal. And the students hit, um, just the so sorry, the stretch for that octave is always
hard to make. Okay. So an octave is really, really important in music. Like we were talking
about earlier with the scale, a scale is eight notes. Well, the the root, the the place the word
octave comes from is the number eight, like an octagon. Right. So, octave means eight notes
together or like low C high C. That's an octave. Okay. So, I think about the piano when you're
putting your fingers on the keys covering eight keys means you have to stretch your thumb and your
pinky out really, really far. And so he's saying, ah, sorry, it's hard for me to do this because the
octave, those that that stretch is really hard for my hand. Right. Okay. So this is different from
eighth, right? Well, it depends. Or you're talking about eighth note. I don't know because
I just gave it to like as an octave is eight and eighth note. No, it's there's a different
thing that can. Yeah. Well, you're you're heard in the dialogue 16th note, eighth note. That's actually
talking about the length of a note. How long you hold it? Okay. So basically you're saying it's
the way you measure the music. You can have four count or three count, but you divide that into pieces.
It's like a pie in math where you divide it into pieces. So if it's a 16th note or an eighth note,
that's the length based on the kind of music you're playing. So I imagine 16th note is shorter than
eighth. Yes. Okay. At least at least I got that one. And 30 seconds note is shorter than a 16th note.
Wow, you have all the way up to 30 seconds. 64th note is okay. It gets very complicated. Very
mathy. All right. And towards the end of teacher recommended for Cody to watch his dynamics. What what does
she mean with? Watch your dynamics. I used to get this all the time in music. So you're concentrating
on your music, you're playing, you're getting the notes and Cody is stretching his hands, the
octaves are so far away. And he forgets to play it loud or soft. Because on the page it says like
we heard earlier, Decaresendo. So get much, much softer. So Cody completely forgot. He's not
listening. He's not reading the page and seeing what it says about the volume of the music.
So basically the dynamics are like the instructions of how loud to play it or not or not so loud.
Exactly. So it does it say Pianissimo or the opposite. Does it say forte?
Oh, so it and it will actually say this on the notes in forte. I'll say that.
F-O-R-T-E or sometimes just F. Okay. So P is piano. That means like we said earlier quiet. Pianissimo
is P-P. It's very quiet. F is forte. Low. Okay. So I think if anyone out there plays an instrument,
you can relate and you can maybe know about these things that you may know it in your original
language. I know many people who play musical instruments and don't really know the technical
words in their original language. I mean things like Andante and Pianissimo things like this. I think
are universal. They're used in whatever language. Exactly. Very widely used.
But things like the accidentals or bass clar for scales and stuff like that. I think it's obviously
different languages. For example, you know Italian like scales or accidentals or they do you
different different. They're different. All of the other words. So the instructions on the page
because music is shared all over the world. The instructions on the page are almost always
in Italian. So Piano and Andante or their in German. All really. But everything else scales,
octaves. These are all in your native language. And so they're very, very important to study
if you want to play. And I think very, very useful if you want to study an instrument. Yeah, of course.
I think it's also a very good idea to just have a general knowledge about these things because
you know, sometimes it's nice to know a little bit about it and maybe if a friend is talking
about music, you can maybe understand a little bit more about what it's like or if you see music,
a sheet of music, you can now more or less know what's going on with all those drawings and little
scribbles. Absolutely. And if you have any questions, of course, you're welcome to come to our website
and ask or share your experiences as Marco has just said. So please come to EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there. All right. We'll see you guys next time. Bye. Bye.