Hello English learners. Welcome back to English.
Pod, my name is Marco. And my name is Catherine. And today, Marco and I get to share with you
the thrilling conclusion to the, well, very popular. I'm gonna say series. I'm sorry. I love you.
That's right. Today is the finale, the final episode. Episode 10. This is where it all ends. So,
what do you think is going to happen? If I guess you're just going to get angry at me because I
actually know how it ends, but let's just say I hope that it ends well for protagonists.
There was a lot of controversy around it because, you know, I wanted to know if people wanted
a happy ending, a sad ending, unexpected. I guess everyone wants a happy ending, right? Absolutely. So,
we're gonna, well, keep our fingers crossed for Steven and Veronica and check out this dialogue one time.
What's your name? Steven, good to see you, brother. How are you? How was your trip?
It was fine. I've been better, but it's a great to be home. I've missed you all. How's mom?
She's great. All she ever does is talk about you or little boy that have entenied its states.
You're her pride and joy. You know that. I can't wait to see you. You, what's new with you?
Well, niche, I and I are expecting. You'll have another nephew, our niece soon.
That's great. Wow. Congrats. You two are great together, you know. You have such a beautiful family.
I hope that one day I can have that. Of course, man. Come on. I mean, everything was said here
for you to marry Shalini. You know, she is still planning after you. I don't think she'll ever get over you.
He's talking about. I hardly knew her. How could she be in love with me? I can go through with it,
even though she is a great woman. No, I left my hard night at states.
I just hope Veronica is happy. Get over it. You're home now. Everyone here, thanks. So highly of you.
They'll be girls trying themselves at you. You can marry anyone you want. I don't want to marry anyone.
I want to marry her. Don't you understand? You are incredible.
See you, man. My baby, how war are you? I'm mid-you so much. You are great to see you.
You look so thin. They're in those American speed. Come, come. Let's have some tie.
By the way, there is a girl here waiting for you. Hi, Steven. Veronica, how did you get here? How do you know
where I live? I waited for you at the airport, but you never showed. I also have some little
secrets that I haven't told you about, but we can discuss that later. I realized that I was just
scared. Scared of how much I love you and of the commitment that marriage requires. I'm here now.
Now, there's something I want to ask you. Steven, will you marry me?
I now declare you husband and wife. You may kiss the bride.
All right, so they got married. You got married. I got married. Wow, I should have called my mom.
And not only did you get married, but you got married. Bollywood style with music and everything.
Those weddings are like four days long. I hope you enjoyed the finale of this story.
Absolutely. I was glad to see that it was a happy ending. I have to say if it had been a sad ending,
I would have been a little bit disappointed because, well, Veronica and I, you get along.
We get along. All right, so apart from this happy ending and this happy finale that we had,
we did look at a lot of great words and phrases. So what do we start now with language takeaway?
Language takeaway. So the first couple of phrases I want to talk about here have to do with maybe
catching up and talking about family or gossip because we're talking to family members.
In the end, family, right, and seen for a long time. And the first thing he's he's talking to
his brother about his brother and his wife. So Goulaman Nisha are expecting we find out.
Right, they're expecting. So if Goulaman Nisha are expecting, what does that mean?
Exactly. They're expecting a letter. Expecting a baby maybe? Ah, yeah, so here we go.
I'm expecting is very common English way of saying, I'm going to have a baby. I'm pregnant.
All right, so don't get this confused. As somebody says, oh, well, I'm expecting. You don't have to say
expecting what? Exactly. When it's only expecting when it's not a thing afterwards,
I'm expecting means I'm pregnant or she's expecting. She's going to have a baby.
So they are expecting a baby or they're expecting. Well, and they were talking about, well,
so Steven, he was supposed to get married in India and his brother said a very interesting
where he said, well, these girls are still, this girl is still pining over you. So the Shaliini,
some girl that Steven used to know when he was living in India, she's pining after you.
Well, pine has many different meanings. Right. But in this sense, we're talking about
having a crush on or being in love with. And also, it's a way of saying that you are that you desire
you yearn for this person very, very much, but that you don't have them. Right. You want them.
You want them. So you're pining over this person. Now can you pine over an object?
No. No. Usually, it's maybe related to love or to an a person. Right. Yeah. So she stands by the door
every day waiting the letter that doesn't come. She's pining away for her dear love, Thomas or whatever.
And you know what I read recently is that people can get addicted to pining. Really?
Yeah. After a breakup, maybe you can pine after a person not because you miss them or you want to
put you kind of grow a custom to it and you become addicted to this pain that's kind of pleasurable.
There is a way to describe this is called patroc and love. Well, it's this kind of traditional
idea in poetry where you have a love that's never consumated. It's never filled. You never get
to be with the person that you love that you desire. And so it's a way, yeah. It's a way of
distinguishing the two different kinds of love. One where you're with the person and the other where
you always want them, but you can never have them. Well, but hopefully none of our listeners
are pining over anyone or get to experience that, huh? Exactly. But if you do pine away or if you
pine after someone, you have to hope that one day you'll get over that person. Yeah. You have to get
over it. And that's what his brother says, hey, get over it. I don't think she'll ever get over you.
So what does it mean when you're supposed to get over someone?
Okay. This is a good question because, you know, we're talking here not about actually getting
up on top of a fence or a wall. We're talking about emotions. So getting over someone, so I have
to get over him means that I have to stop feeling so sad about what happened, right? Because usually
you say this when someone's sad or angry. And also it kind of means that you have to forget or let
that person go, you know, like get over it. We're going to move on here too. It's the last word
in today's language takeaway, which is incarageable. Okay. An incarageable person.
All right. In corageable. What could this mean? Well, let's look at the sentence where we find it.
You are incarageable. Mm-hmm. Gulam says this to Stephen. Right. So it's an adjective and basically
means that you have no correction of some sort. Or there's an argument between Stephen and Gulam.
So their brothers and Stephen says, I don't want to get married. I don't want to marry her.
Ah. He's complaining and his brother says, you are incarageable. You just won't stop. Right.
So someone's, someone's feelings, their emotions, their ideas about something. They just can't
be changed or altered, their fixed, you know, this guy. He's like, I'm not going to get married and
his brother says, you're incarageable. I just can't change your mind. It's kind of like being stubborn.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. And we hear this phrase a lot together. So you're incarageable. Right.
So this is often just kind of a, it's a, it's not an insult, but it's a way for us to kind of be
sarcastic or to make fun of someone. You're in a hard or a mark. Oh, you usually say when you're
loud, you know, you're being nice. All right. Mm-hmm. Okay. Cool. So five great words in language
takeaway today. And well, before we move on and listen to the dialogue, again, why don't we take a look
at fluency builder? Fluency builder. All right. This first phrase is something that parents
often use and grandparents as well because obviously, parents and grandparents are very proud
of their children and grandchildren. So they describe something as being their pride and joy.
Hmm, my pride and joy. So it's usually a person that you're pride and joy. It could be a thing too.
It could be a thing. His poor spockster is his pride and joy. He goes out every morning and he
washes it. He changes the oil. He checks the gas. He checks the tires. So it's his pride and joy.
All right. It says most valued possession. So it always goes together, right? My pride and joy.
Pride and joy. Yeah. Just think of it as a phrase. Pride and joy. All right. So I'm my mother's pride and joy.
I think you are. All right. So yeah. All right. So yeah. All right. So somebody's pride and joy.
So now in other phrase that we took a look at and it's a way of making conversation, especially
with a person that you haven't seen in a while. He said, hey, what's new with you? What's new with you?
Uh-huh. What's new with you? All right. So this might sound a little strange because normally we say,
how have you been? It's been a long time. How are you? But this is like, you know, it's a fluency
builder phrase. So it's very colloquial. It's very spoken language. So this you hear often between friends
or family members. Hey, Marco, what's new with you? So how do you, I would answer this by saying,
oh, well, not much or I just bought a new house. So basically, you're asking for news from the
person. I haven't seen you in a long time. You look happy and healthy. So what's new with you? Oh,
I got married. I got a new car. These things that you can say, these are changes in my life. All right.
And usually after somebody asks you, what's new with you? You say something. And then
you usually would follow up and ask that person as well, right? What's new and what's new with you?
Exactly. So, you know, I got a new house, got a new job. What's new with you?
Yeah. Or what about you? What about you? So it's a nice, very relaxed, informal way of asking
someone for news in their life. Perfect. All right. What's new with you? What else? Now,
he was supposed to get married, right? Right. So this is news. He was supposed to get married. He didn't
get married. What's going on? His brother, his mother, they all want to know what's going on. And we
find out that wedding, that girl, he just couldn't go through with it. So I can't, I couldn't go through
with it. Okay. This past tense. So he's saying, before I came to India with this girl,
I couldn't go through with it. So present would be, I can't go through with it. And going through
with what? Here. We've got it. So this kind of magical strange word, it, what it would
could this be? So basically, what he's saying is that he couldn't complete or maybe
finish something that he started, right? So in this case, we're talking about a relationship or marriage.
Yeah, a relationship. So maybe we love each other, but I couldn't go through with it. I couldn't go
to the finish line. Mm-hmm. Right. I couldn't get married. You see that a lot when maybe in
movies, two people are supposed to get married. They're at the altar. And all of a sudden, the bride
says, I can't, or she goes away crying. I can't go through it. Exactly. Right. So because she
loves somebody else, so can't go through with it. Mm, great. So really good phrase. I can't
go through with it. He couldn't go through with it. And we find out that, well, not such a bad thing.
Steve and he's very popular in India. The girls love him. We've got a great phrase for describing
having lots of girls who love you. Right. He says, there will be girls throwing themselves at you.
Literally like, oh, that might be a horror. I can't imagine that. Like, just somebody throwing
them. No. It's not literal. It's basically saying girls are very interesting. You
girls are so interesting. You that they'll be chasing you almost. All right. So many many girls,
they will follow you. They'll want to be in a relationship with you. They like you. So he's saying,
listen, there are other girls. Don't worry. Girls here, they love you. And it doesn't only work
with girls, right? I can say they'll be boys throwing themselves at you. Right. So this is,
this is something we say about both genders. Boys and girls. You can say, oh, God, all the
boys were throwing themselves at her. I'm so jealous. Right. So, but it's only basically in a loving way.
Right. It can't be anything else. Like somebody's chasing you for other reasons.
Now, this is saying that they have crushes. They have feelings. They want to be romantic. It's not
like a, it's not a bad thing. But sometimes it's too much attention. So it can be kind of negative.
Yeah. All right. Well, interesting phrases on Fluency Builder today. I think it's time for us to
listen to this dialogue for one last time. Get up and dance. Yeah. Get up and dance. And we'll be back
in a little bit.
Music
Steven, good to see you, brother. How are you? How was your trip? It was fine. I've been better,
but it's a great to be home. I've missed you all. How's mom? She's great. All she ever does is talk about
you or little boy that have entangled states, you're her pride and joy. You know that.
Can't wait to see you. You, what's new with you? Well, niche, I know I are expecting. You'll have
another nephew, or niece soon. That's great. Wow. Congrats to a great together. You know,
you have such a beautiful family. I hope that one day I can have that. Of course, man. Come on.
I mean, everything was said here for you to marry Shalini. You know, she is still planning
out for you. I don't think she'll ever get over you. What are you talking about? I hardly
knew her. How could she be in love with me? I couldn't go through with it even though she is a great woman.
No, I left my hard night at states. I just hope Veronica is happy. Get over it. You're home now.
Everyone here thinks so highly of you. They'll be girls trying themselves at you. You can marry
anyone you want. I don't want to marry anyone. I want to marry her. Don't you understand?
You are incorrigible.
Steven, my baby, how war are you? I'm Mrs. Soma.
You, um, great to see you. You look so thin. Did I know some Americans feed you? Come, come.
Let's have some time. By the way, there is a girl here waiting for you.
Hi, Steven. Veronica, how did you get here? How do you know where I live?
I waited for you at the airport, but you never showed. I also have some little secrets that I haven't told
you about, but we can discuss that later. I realized that I was just scared, scared of how much I love
you and of the commitment that marriage requires. I'm here now. Now, there's something I want to
ask you. Steven, will you marry me?
I now declare you husband and wife. You may kiss the bro.
All right, so it's over. Sad, sad, sad, but sweet. Sad, but sweet, and on,
we went from them meeting casually by a bike accident. Yeah, we had nice music.
Then it turned out that she was angry. They kind of broke up. They got back together.
He was being strained with all of these secret trips to save people.
It's uh, it was interesting. We went a lot of different ways people. She was pregnant. She wasn't
the doctor was stalking the doctor. He's in the secret service. It was an interesting
ride. Very interesting. Well, now we need to think of a new drama and new soap opera or novel.
We need your input. Maybe we should open it up. What did you like? What didn't you like?
And what kind of genre are you interested in? Because you know, there's tons of different
kinds of stories we could tell. Right, maybe we can do something scary, like a thriller or horror.
I'm a big fan of sci-fi. Or sci-fi, maybe we can do something sci-fi. Maybe we can do a comedy,
something maybe like friends. I don't know. That'd be kind of cute. Yeah, it could be. All right,
so listeners, why don't you give us your input? We need your feedback. Tell us what series you
would like next? What type of series? Maybe like we said drama, sci-fi, action. What would you like?
And please get in touch with us, leave comments and questions on our website, EnglishPod.com.
We'd like to check those and answer you. So yeah, get in touch with us and have a great day.
All right, we'll see you guys there. Bye.