Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson for you all about money.
That's right we are trading money. We're actually negotiating in this very popular topic nowadays
the whole foreign exchange market.
Okay so we're talking about currency which is the money of different countries. For example the currency
of Ecuador is the US dollar. Yeah yeah hard to believe but I'll tell you all about it later.
Okay well the currency of America is also the US dollar so with that in mind let's listen to
today's dialogue.
Hey John I haven't seen you in ages. What's new? What have you been up to?
Pete nice to see you. Well on top of the norm you know life and kids and work. I've actually
gotten into doing some trading trading. You big guy what are you trading currencies currencies as in
euros dollars pounds and rupees it's called forx foreign exchange. The great thing about it is that
I don't have to invest a huge amount. I put in a margin deposit in the night can buy and sell up to
100 times that much. I don't understand you're buying and selling money you got it just last night
I made $150 US dollars last night yeah it's a 24 hour market. I bought some remin beer earlier
at a low-asking price but last night it appreciated drastically so I made a split second decision
and sold all of my RMB at an amazing bid. I've also done some trading with Swiss francs and
Australian dollars in Hong Kong dollars. I've made some good profits but I've also suffered some
losses. Depends on a lot of factors just like any other market. In total I've made about 500 US
dollars in the past few months. You're kidding I'm on where do I sign up?
All right we're back so this guy is trading currencies as we heard and well we're going to talk about
a lot of the specific vocab that it used about this topic so I want to take a look at some of those now
in language takeaway. Language takeaway. Well the first thing I think we should talk about is
one of the first things that he says actually Peter says I haven't seen you in ages. I haven't seen
you in ages right so obviously he hasn't seen him in a long time and that's what in ages means.
That's right so we haven't seen each other in ages. So what other ways can we use in ages or
or the word ages? Well you could actually say it's been ages. So that means it's been a long time.
It's been a long time or we haven't gone out for ages. Okay so then you can use it with four, four
ages. Four ages in ages so the keyword here is ages which means a long time. Long time okay and
well he hasn't seen him in ages and the guy's like well you know what I've actually gone into trading.
So that means he's started doing some trading. Right now trading is a very broad word because
you can trade as in this case currencies which is basically to buy in sell currencies. But you could
also trade stocks right? Mm-hmm you can trade stocks or even people that are involved in
import export they are involved in trading. Trading so basically trading is buying and selling
something. Right so you're trading you are exchanging a product for money or money for a product.
But the difference is you're not actually making any products. Right. Mm-hmm okay so that's
that's called trading you're not really manufacturing anything you're just exchanging goods and
services and money. All right so that's for trading now moving on he was explaining how the foreign
exchange market works and he says I don't have to invest a huge amount. I put in a margin deposit
and then I can buy and sell up to a hundred times that much. So Marco here's the question what is
a margin deposit because a deposit is basically money that you put invest somewhere or that you
you pay in. Right well basically a margin deposit is like a percentage so he basically puts in a
percentage of what he intends to buy. So for example a margin deposit of a thousand dollars might be
one dollar for $10. Okay so maybe if it's $10 you're talking about a 1% margin. Mm-hmm exactly.
So that's what he means by a margin deposit and that's why he explains that you don't have to have
a large amount of money in order to trade in the foreign exchange market you just put in
a margin deposit and then you can work around that. Well it sounds pretty easy but then he explains
some more details about it and it gets to be a little bit more complicated. That's right he explained
about how he makes money and how he bought some Chinese Remin B and then he sold it because
it appreciated drastically. So he bought it when it was cheap and he sold it when it was expensive
so the price changed. Right. So this kind of price change when something goes from cheap to expensive
it's called appreciating. Mm-hmm. Appreciation so the verb is to appreciate. It's very different
from using it in the sense of you appreciate someone right like I really appreciate you.
Yeah no it's very different we could say this about most goods or investments for example
my parents bought a house in 1970 and the value of the house has really appreciated over the last
40 years so now the value is much much greater. Mm-hmm and actually just mentioning it while we're
on the topic to appreciate as you say is something becomes more expensive the opposite when something
becomes cheaper or maybe the value goes down is to depreciate. D depreciate so that D at the
beginning means it's going down. Right. Okay and moving on to our last word for language takeaway
so when he was talking about selling the Chinese currency he said that he sold it at an amazing
bid. Okay let's talk about bid here. BID bid what does this mean? So to bid is to place and offer
for something. Okay so for example at an auction when someone is selling many old objects or some art
I can bid $100. Right and maybe someone doesn't accept my bid. Mm-hmm but if they do accept my bid
then I pay for it. Right. So basically a bid is just another way of saying and offer
of you're offering a certain amount of money for that product or that service and you see it a
lot for example on eBay. Right. That's right so eBay is an auction website basically and
someone who's selling someone can see many many bids and they select the best bid. Exactly so that's
what a bid is. So that's all we have for language takeaway let's move on now to Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. Marko what have you been up to lately I never see you. All right this is actually
a very common sentence what have you been up to but most English learners don't really understand what it means.
Well this is a really interesting point because I say this all the time this is very native
very colloquial what have you been up to. It's almost the same as saying what's up. What's up or
where have you been recently what have you been doing recently? Right. How's your life? Right.
So this part up to what have you been up to? It doesn't really say much if you translate it
literally but basically it's what have you been doing? What have you been spending your time on?
So to be up to means to do something to do. Right and there are many other definitions of up
too but in this case what have you been up to means that? What have you been doing?
So next time you see a friend you haven't seen and a week or two you can say what have you been up to?
Hmm. All right and John answers well you know on top of the norm
five kids and work that phrase right there on top of the norm. Well the norm here means the normal.
That means basically normal life. I've been working I've got my kids my wife on top of the norm.
Just like this normal. Right. So the norm or the wife kids and work on top of that I'm actually
gunning into trading. Right. So the normal situation the normal life is wife kids and work
and he's saying on top of that I've actually been doing this exactly. Okay and now moving on to
when he's explaining again the the market and and the currencies he talked about in asking price.
Okay asking price. This is remember we're talking about bids we could say that someone has an
asking price which is the price they would like to receive for an object or a service that they are selling.
And so for example I'm going to sell my desk my asking price is a hundred bucks.
Hundred dollars. Maybe you don't want to pay that much but my asking price is the way that I'm going to
start that's how much I want for it. Right. So that's your asking price that's how much you ideally want to
sell it for but you can negotiate you are willing to accept maybe a lower offer. Exactly. Okay and
what is our last phrase? A split second decision this is really really important these words go
together very often split second and decision. Okay so that basically means that you made a very
quick decision. That's right split second very fast it's almost like it's less than a second and so
a split second decision means a decision in no time. It's very very quick. So we can actually mix
split second with other things right for example so maybe you can say he reacted in a split second
and avoided the crash. Okay so good for him he reacted quickly enough to avoid the accident.
That's right so split second very fast very quickly a split second decision a decision that was made
very fast. Okay so that's all we have for fluency builder when we go back listen to this dialogue one more
time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more. Hey John I haven't seen you in ages what's new
what have you been up to Pete nice to see you well on top of the norm you know life and kids and work
I've actually gotten into doing some trading trading you big guy what are you trading currencies
currencies as in euros dollars pounds and rupees it's called forx foreign exchange the great thing
about it is that I don't have to invest a huge amount I put in a margin deposit in the night
can buy and sell up to a hundred times that much I don't understand you're buying and selling money
you got it just last night I made one hundred fifty US dollars last night yeah it's a twenty four
hour market I bought some remin beer earlier at a low-asking price but last night it appreciated
drastically so I made a split second decision and sold all of my R&B at an amazing bid. I've also
done some trading with Swiss francs and australian dollars and Hong Kong dollars. I've made some good
profits but I've also suffered some losses depends on a lot of factors just like any other market
in total I've made about five hundred US dollars in the past few months you're kidding I'm on where do I
sign up so Marco you have to explain this to me we're talking about currency today so every nation
has a currency for example in the dialogue we learned that India has rupees pounds are in Britain
has pounds and australia has australian dollars America has American dollars but you just said
earlier that Ecuador has American dollars too that's right actually Ecuador went through a very
difficult economic situation in late 1998 early 1999 where there was hyperinflation so basically
there was an inflation that was very very very large so that means that the old currency lost its
value very fast exactly so for example if the currency before an Ecuador used to be so goodness so
if 10 zookles was one dollar all of a sudden it was 50 zookles was one dollar oh wow so and it got to
the point where goods and services went from $3,000 to $25,000 okay so people have bags full of money and
it's not really worth anything exactly so what happened was the the central bank couldn't absorb
this this currency depreciation they couldn't really regulate prices obviously salaries were about
the same so you have a lot less money comparatively and so the government decided that there were
two options either they would follow Argentina's example what they did a couple of years before and set
a fixed rate so our Argentina it's three pesos to a dollar or we would just get rid of our currency
and just use US dollars so that's what they did right they use US dollars and now if you ever
travel to Ecuador you will you will use US dollars the same exact bills that you use in the US are
the same exact bills in Ecuador so no need to exchange currency no need to exchange currency and that's why
I guess there are many factors that people say are a lot better for example trading has become a lot
less complicated because now you're negotiating a US dollars as in everywhere else in the world
but then other things as you know not having a national currency also affects so there are a lot
of things going on but it's an interesting topic very interesting well so maybe for those of you
who are listening you could tell us about your country and your currency um what are you use what
you spend money on and do people buy and trade currencies where you're from exactly or maybe you can
even enlighten us with the foreign with the exchange rate maybe usually it's a good question to ask
how much is a leader of milk or how much is a haircut right because these are things that
everyone needs so the price doesn't change that much exactly we're really curious to know how
inexpensive or maybe very expensive your country is so come to englishpod.com and we'll see everyone there
bye bye