Hello everyone and welcome to English My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a kind of education that is quite unique
actually a little bit different from the kind of education that most people get.
That's right so we normally go to school to learn but I'm this occasion we're going to talk
about a different way of obtaining your education.
We're talking about home schooling someone.
Let's check this word out in today's vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview.
Alright so the word is home school to home school someone.
It's like it's a verb and what does it mean if you're home school?
Well you think about the word school home means that you study at home but you don't go to school
every day.
Instead you have a parent or maybe a friend of a parent who comes to your house to teach you every
So it's basically like having a tutor for but not to help you with school but it's actually
teach you everything that you learn at school.
That's right and some people are home schooled with their siblings so brothers and sisters.
Other people are home schooled alone.
We'll talk about some of these things in a moment but let's take a listen to our dialogue.
I think we should home school our children but we decided to have kids.
What? Why?
Well our home school's here are not very good and prime schools are just too expensive.
I've been reading up on some home schooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing something like that we would be isolating our children from social interaction.
Well first of all I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school
and more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having one on one class is much better since you can focus more on his or her strengths
or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents or mine would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brooch.
Good luck with that.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some of that language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So as we mentioned in the introduction to today's podcast a home schooling is one of many
different educational options. The most common ones are in the beginning of the dialogue.
Public and private school.
Right so in most places you will have public schools where basically the education is paid for by the
government.
Yeah that's right so public schools are schools that are available to all students.
You don't have to pay to attend them.
These are this is of course in America and Britain the system is a bit different.
But in America you have the public schools which most kids go to.
Of course if your parents don't want you to study in public school there's another option
that's called private school.
That's right so a private school as the name says it's it's not really private
but what happens is that it's not available free for everyone.
You have to actually pay to go to the school.
That's right the school has a tuition kind of like a private college or university.
So you have to pay every semester or every year.
And usually these schools also have applications standards so they interview you,
they interview your parents.
So there's a lot of different things you have to do to attend these schools.
That's right.
So they're a bit more exclusive.
That's right now so these are basically some three options you have home schooling public schools
private schools and well the two parents are kind of discussing the options of why
it would be maybe not a good idea to home school one of the kids and she says that it would be
isolating our children from social interaction.
All right so let's take a look at the word to isolate the sub verb.
And I like to think of island isolate kind of similar in a way.
Basically to isolate from is to keep away from.
So if your student or your child is being homeschooled, he or she might be isolated from other
students.
They're not near or with other students.
That's right so to isolate means to keep away from or to keep separately.
So like you said maybe if you're on an island you are isolated from the rest of the world.
That's right or if I live in the country far away from the city,
I feel isolated from other people.
So she's saying that the kid might be isolated from social interaction.
All right now social interaction this is a two word phrase.
We'll usually take it as a phrase.
This basically means talking to or playing with other people.
Mm-hmm.
Other kids.
Right.
So I guess in this case it's a it's personal or physical social interaction because
nowadays you have social interaction via the internet.
That's right but in the case of a student going to school it would be of course playing on the
playground, attending class.
But social interaction means talking to or being with other people.
That's right.
Well and the other parent argued that there are many advantages and specifically you said
that having a one on one class is better for the kids.
All right so this word one on one refers to one teacher one student.
Right.
One parent one child.
It means when you're talking to someone and there's no one else around.
Mm-hmm.
All right so usually twoters teach you one on one.
Right.
You sit at a table and your tutor helps you study.
But in the case of home schooling the student learns one on one.
So learns directly from the teacher.
Right and that's different from public schools obviously because you have one teacher for maybe
30 students.
That's right so that's not one on one that's one on many.
Right exactly.
But one on one is also a word you can use when you talk about meetings.
So you could say hey Marco can we have a one on one meeting later?
I'd like to talk to you alone.
So that means I'm not going to talk to you with other people.
Right.
Okay it's like a private meeting.
Yeah.
Very good.
So let's take a listen to the dialogue again and then we're going to come back and we're going to take a look
at some key phrases.
I think we should homeschool our children when we decide to have kids.
What?
Why?
Well our public schools here are not very good and prime schools are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing something like that we would be isolating our children from social
interaction.
Well first of all I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school and more
relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having one on one class is much better since you can focus more on his or
her strengths or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents or mind would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
Good luck with that.
Alright we've picked out four key phrases for you today.
Let's take a look at those on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So the first phrase today in fluency builder is the phrase to read up on.
So the sentence was I've been reading up on home schooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Right.
So basically if you say you have been reading up on a subject or a topic or something
it means that you've been reading about it you've kind of been informing yourself.
You're doing research about a topic.
So in this case one parent is researching the home schooling option.
Right.
So it is reading maybe articles in a magazine or books or looking on the internet.
But you don't actually just have to read up on education.
You can read up on anything.
Right.
Exactly.
So you can read up on anything that interests you or you can do research on anything.
So you can read up on dinosaurs for example.
I've been reading up on dinosaurs lately and did you know that the bront of source is not
a real dinosaur anymore?
That's right.
Okay.
So we've been reading up on the advantages of home schooling and he starts by well defending
his position on what the advantages are with the phrase well first of all.
All right.
This is an important little phrase.
This is something you can use like you say marker when you're going to have an argument
or maybe a discussion about something and you want to tell your points.
You're inside of the argument.
And so first of all means I have a list but this is my first point.
Right.
So it's a nice little phrase to open up this list of things that you're going to say.
That's right.
So you should drink orange juice, Marco, because first of all it tastes good but second
of all or but also it's very good for your body.
So first of all it's the first main point.
So you can say second of all.
Can you go like third of all for fourth of all not really right?
Yeah.
You don't really say it.
I guess you could but so you'll go first of all second of all and then maybe just
go and also or lastly and then lastly to end it.
Okay.
Very good.
Now one of the other points that he talked about will apart from the one on one
class was that the reason why a one on one class was better is because he could focus
on his or her strengths and or weaknesses.
All right.
So strengths or weaknesses or strengths and weaknesses.
This is a set phrase and it's important to remember that these two words are opposites.
So strengths.
That's the things you're good at.
Right.
And weaknesses.
Things you're bad at.
And so especially when you're studying in a school or your home schooling, it's
important that the teacher understands the strengths and weaknesses of the student.
Right.
Because something that you're really good at maybe you should encourage and something
you're bad at, you should work harder at improving.
That's right.
So it's usually fixed phrase.
You'll even get it in job interview.
Somebody will say, well, what do you think are your strengths and weaknesses?
That's right.
So remember that phrase strengths and weaknesses.
Okay.
And lastly, he said that well, even though the idea is interesting, it might be difficult
to make the parents or the grandparents agree with him.
So he said he will bring it up over Sunday brunch.
Okay.
I will bring it up.
Hmm, bring it up.
Well, you're not actually holding something.
And this means that you will mention it in conversation.
It mentioned the topic, right?
That's right.
So maybe grandma and grandpa don't think home schooling is a good idea, but you will discuss
it or you will suggest it during Sunday brunch.
Right.
So if you want to discuss a topic, you usually say I will bring it up with the president
for example.
That's right.
You'll talk about it with the president.
You can also say, please don't bring it up.
Right.
So I will go to the secret and you don't want the other person to know.
You say, okay, please Marco, don't bring it up.
Okay, very good.
All right.
Let's listen to her dialogue one last time.
I think we should homeschool our children, but we decided to have kids.
What?
Why?
Well, our public schools here are not very good.
And the primary schools are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what?
I think that by doing something like that, we would be isolating our children from social
interaction.
Well, first of all, I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school
and more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having one of one class is much better since you can focus more on
his or her strengths or weaknesses.
I think neither your parents are mine would agree to such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
Good luck with that.
Okay, so homeschooling is a very interesting option.
I think it's very common more common nowadays in Britain and North America, but how do
people that are homeschool go to college if they didn't go to a high school?
Well, I believe that most people when they finish homeschooling will take some tests to
prove that they've actually learned the material that is required by the state.
Because in America, each state sets the educational standards.
So it's important that you learn certain science and math skills.
And then once you take those tests, you would get your GED, your graduate diploma.
And that means that you've learned everything that a high school student should know.
So it's interesting because it would seem a little bit strange to not want your kid
to go to school.
But at the same time, there are many reasons why parents don't want their kids to go to school
like in this dialogue.
Maybe the schools are not really good or too expensive.
What do you think about homeschooling?
Would you send your kids to homeschool?
I don't think I would do homeschooling because I think it's really important for students
to or for children to learn how to get along with others and to learn to negotiate and to
learn to play and to also learn to respect their teachers because you have a different
relationship with your parents than you do your teachers and.
Right.
I think there's a lot of valuable social lessons you can learn at school.
But I do understand why a lot of people choose this option, especially if the schools in their
area are poor performing schools.
So the students aren't learning enough or if maybe they're not safe because some schools
there's some bullying or there's some violence.
And so for those reasons, I definitely understand the motivation to do homeschooling.
But then again, you can't, I mean, you can get homeschooled from kindergarten all the way
to high school, right?
But I don't, there is no homeschooling for university.
Unless you do like an online degree or something like that.
You can't really be homeschooled for college.
No, there's distance courses so you could use the internet and learn online.
But now you can't homeschool for university.
Yeah.
It's a very debatable topic.
A lot of people defend it saying it's good.
You know, it brings parents closer together to their kids, that kids enjoy learning, that
they learn better, etc.
Other people don't really agree with it.
So what is your opinion do you agree with homeschooling?
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to hear your arguments there.
Okay, we'll see you there.
Bye.