Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a dream home, so building the home of your dreams.
That's right and this lesson today is advanced so it might be a little bit hard and we're
going to be taking a look at not only some vocabulary related to your home or decorations and
stuff but also how to treat your loved one in a nice way or a little what we call a nicknames.
That's right.
So stay tuned we'll be talking about very specific things having to do with building a home
and home remodeling and so we'll hear this with dialogue one time but we'll more back in just a
minute here we'll be talking about what those things mean.
Mr. and Mrs. Robinson, let's get straight to it.
You have saved up your money for years and are now ready to build your dream home. What did you have in mind?
A suburban bungalow straight out of the 60s, a perfect lawn with minimal landscaping,
brick patio in the backyard with an old fashioned grill, clean lawn furniture and a swimming pool,
a two-car car port pastel sighting and a gable roof,
completed with white shutters and a white picket fence.
Uh honey.
In the living room we would have moss green rugs and a fireplace with a stone mantle
and wood paneling on the walls. In the kitchen the cupboards would be a pale yellow
and we would have a turquoise metal oven and vinyl flooring.
Um, sweetie, but I was thinking of more modern style house, an open concept house or glass,
wood, metal and concrete.
But sweetomes, there's always a lot of wasted space in those kinds of homes.
Besides it's just a fad, it doesn't have the homey feeling the old homes do.
Sweetie Pie, it's not a lot of waste to space. It is relaxing and the house would be eco-friendly
with an inflore heating system and designed to retain the heat of the sun in the winter.
And keep the house cool in the summer. We would have solar panels on the roof.
Do you know how much those things cost?
What about your vintage furniture, dearest?
And instead of a lawn which is also a lot of wasted space and would require environmentally
harmful pesticides, we would have a fish pond in the backyard and a garden that would cover
the whole yard so we could grow our own food.
But buttercup, I thought you always said that you love visiting your grandmother's house.
And I thought you, Mr. Scientist, were all up and saving the planet with your technical advancements.
Um, well, I am just going to get some coffee while you two keep discussing.
All right, we're back. So apparently the couple can't seem to agree. He wants something
different than what she does and in the end I think they were a little bit irritated with each other.
Doesn't this always happen though? I mean, my dream home is probably not your dream home.
I don't know, it's weird. But I mean, you would probably have to, I don't know, compensate somehow
or, well, that's the beauty of compromise. You can go back and forth, but with your loved one or
your spouse, you have to make some decisions about what you want, what they want.
All you need to do is give a guy his own room in which he can decorate and do whatever he wants with it.
That's all you need. No, no, no, no, no, just any guy. Just you want to decorate the house in
any way you want to find, but just give us one room, you know, like five meters by five meters where
we can put anything we want. I fear cooler, an EV, a PS3, a sun system, and a couple guitars.
Yeah, probably, yeah, yeah, yeah, that's not. You've described it.
I've been to your house like that. Anyway, we've got a lot of great words here in that language
takeaway, so let's take a peek at some of those.
Language takeaway. All right, so the first word that we have or it's actually a concept,
minimal landscaping. Okay, so minimal is a style minimal list, actually. And minimal,
landscaping is this kind of style of, well, designing your lawn or your garden. Okay.
So minimal means not having a dormant or decorations. Okay, so it's kind of like the less is more
type thing. Exactly. So minimal architecture could be very simple, lots of clean lines,
not much decoration. It's the opposite of something that's broke and highly ornamented.
Yeah, and I don't like that. I'm into minimal. All right, minimalist. Anyways, we have minimal landscaping
and we're talking about his patio, the old fashioned grill, and he said,
Quaint lawn furniture. Quaint is sometimes, well, it's usually kind of a bad thing.
We say something is quaint in the way of saying that it's cute, but we don't really like it because
it's maybe old fashioned or, you know, kind of old style. So always in that quaint is something
that people from the city often say about people in the country, at least in America. So,
because you know, I went to school on the East Coast and I'm from the Midwest. So people on the East
Coast would say, oh, your house is so quaint. You know, small and cute and old fashioned. Right, right.
Because they live in a big fancy New York apartment or whatever. So quaint is usually something that's
not the nicest, but so he's looking for some lawn furniture that's not like plastic or
or new. It's more like old fashioned maybe wood, right? Right. And kind of traditional and
not, not fancy, kind of simple. Now he's also talking about the house and he wants well,
a two-carb carport pastel sighting and a gable roof. So now we know what a roof is, but what is a
gable roof? A gable is a thing, right? And it's almost like an extension of the roof in certain
parts. For example, on a traditional Cape Cod style house, you have windows in the front that
they're not a part of the roof. They're in extension. They kind of like, stopping out like eyes. Exactly.
They're coming out like eyes. And so the roof obviously you need a roof on top of those windows.
So that kind of roof, that little extension that's called a gable. Okay. And so there's a wonderful
book that's famous in American history called The House of Seven Gables. I mean, that on this roof
of the house, there are seven different parts that come out seven gables. It's very unique.
Those houses usually look a little bit scary. They do Victorian and imposing. All right.
So you have a gable roof. Now you have shutters and a white picket fence. This is typical.
Everyone talks about a white picket fence around their house. That's right. There was even a TV
show in America years ago called Picket Fences. And I think a picket fence is kind of this ideal
in American culture about having your own home in the suburbs and having your own space. And so
around your yard, around your garden, you have this white picket fence. And so picket is, I think the
pointed parts. So a picket fence is thin pieces of wood that stand in the ground and are connected
to protect your property from other people coming inside. Okay. So that's a white picket fence. You'll
hear it all the time. Usually in movies or in TV shows, they talk about having their own little
house with their dog and a white picket fence. Exactly. Two kids, two cars. And a white picket fence.
All right. So now the woman argued that she wanted something a little bit more modern. And
well, the guy said, you know what? That's just weights at space. And those types of homes are just
a fad. A fad is something that is passing. It's something that's popular for a short time,
but then it goes away. It's not popular anymore. Right. So for example, I think for a while,
remember those shoes that used to have little red lights in the back in the heel. Oh yeah,
it lights. Those were a fad. It was really popular for like a year. Everyone had them,
everyone wore them. And then they just went away. One of my favorite fads of the 1980s were those shirts
that would change color if the room temperature changed color. So if you go outside and it's hot,
they would become bright pink. But if you're in a cold room, they would go blue and green. It was
really fun, but they're definitely out of fashion. Yeah, something they wear them anymore. So
that's a fad. Something that's temporary. It's popular for a while. So he called her house a fad.
And she says, well, what about your house? All this vintage furniture? What's vintage?
Vintage? Well, some people think that vintage is a fad. A lot of people really enjoy buying
vintage furniture or vintage clothing. Vintage means old. So it's a nice way of saying old. They're like a
nice or cool way of saying old. Yeah, so it's almost like, for example, right now, 1940s and 50s
clothes are very popular. Girls are into this kind of style. So it's called, you know, vintage clothing,
because it's not, it's not from today's style. It's an old style. Or you could even call,
you know, those big, glowing dresses from the 1970s vintage clothing. So vintage furniture would be
furniture that comes from a different time, a different era. But it's popular now. Right, they're
popular now. Or people like to buy them now. That's right. So they're special because they come from
a different time. Okay. So those are the words that we have for today on language takeaway.
What do we move on now to some pet names or some sweet ways that you can call your loved ones
on fluency builder? Fluency builder. So the reason this dialogue is very funny is because we
had these two people who are clearly in disagreement about the kinds of furniture and how
they want. But they're, they're being so nice to each other. They have these cute names for each
other. So it's really, I don't know, it's really funny. It almost seems like they're newlyweds,
but apparently they've been saving up their entire life. So maybe they're just one of those,
really loving couples. Oh, sweet thumbs.
Pity pie, kitty. All right. So that's the first one.
Sweetams. Sweetams. So obviously the main part of this word is sweet, sweetams. Sweetams. And this
is the way to say hey, sweetie. Sweetams. Sweetams. Sweetams. So you can say sweetie or sweetams. Exactly.
And that's a nice way of saying something. Or you can go sweetie pie. Sweetie pie. So pie is a food.
You know, it's like sweet. It's sweet. It's a sweet pie. Because they honey pie. Honey pie,
sweetie pie. So these are all cute. And the nice thing about these kind of pet names, these cute
names, is you can change them if you want. And they're yours. So you could say honey pie, sugar bun.
You know, they're, they're silly, but there's no real rule. But these are the most common.
Right. Sweetams and sweetie pie. Okay. Now moving on to something a little bit maybe more formal,
dearest. Dearest. This makes me think of my grandparents. Oh, really. Dearest. So dearest comes from
dearest. Dearest is the most dearest. So someone who's the most important to you. Okay. And so you could say
money dearest, mother dearest. Oh, really heard that's how we all, yeah. Do people call that their mother's
like mother dearest? Mother dearest. No, it's very 19th century. It's so arrogant. It's an old time
thing. It's not who you do not say this anymore. But you can say, you know, a dearest would you mind
moving the car? I like the accent of the kind of like English. All right. And the last one,
buttercup. This is really popular. It is really popular and you've heard this in a song before.
You want to sing this song? No, you do this. Why do you buy it? Do you buy it?
Yep. But it got baby. Okay. So that was in a lot of movies. The word is buttercup. Buttercup.
Also in the movie, the Princess Bride was the character of Princess Buttercup. And so this is a sweet,
you know, obviously a sweet thing. I think a buttercup is a flower. Oh, really?
Yeah. And so these are all words you can use. The names you could use with men and women,
but buttercup is mostly women. I think the other ones are more general. But do you think like
do guys say to their loved ones like Sweden, Sweden, Pai? Oh yeah. Yeah. Oh yeah.
All right. So I guess guys, if you want to be really sweet and you want to win over the heart
so the ladies you can use these these words as well. Another popular one is babe.
Babe. More of a young person thing to say. Yeah. I think the smaller modernist will be.
Honey or babe. Baby. Baby.
You're virgin on. Not so sweet. Yeah, but like, hey, baby. How are you? It's nice. It's like not like, hey, baby.
All right. Well, we're going to leave you with that thought and go listen to this dialogue one more time.
But we'll be back in a moment.
Mr. and Mrs. Robinson, let's get straight to it. You have saved up your money for years and are
now ready to build your dream home. What did you have in mind? A suburban bungalow straight out of the
60s, a perfect lawn with minimal landscaping, a brick patio in the backyard with an old fashion
grill, clean lawn furniture and a swimming pool, a two-car car port pastel sighting and a
gable roof, completed with white shutters and a white picket fence. Honey. In the living room,
we would have moss green rugs and a fireplace with a stone mantle and wood paneling on the walls.
In the kitchen, the cupboards would be a pale yellow and we would have a turquoise metal oven
and vinyl flooring. Um, sweetie, but I was thinking of more modern style house, an open concept house
or glass wood, metal and concrete. But sweetomes, there's always a lot of wasted space in those
kinds of homes. Besides, it's just a fad, it doesn't have the homey feeling the old homes do.
Sweetie pie, it's not a lot of waste to space. It is relaxing and the house would be eco-friendly
with an inflore heating system and designed to retain the heat of the sun in the winter and keep
a house cool in the summer. We would have solar panels on the roof. Do you know how much those things
cost? What about your vintage furniture, dearest? And instead of a lawn, which is also a lot of
wasted space and would require environmentally harmful pesticides, we would have a fish pond in the
backyard and a garden that would cover the whole yard so we could grow our own food. But buttercup,
I thought you always said that you love visiting your grandmother's house. And I thought you,
Mr. Scientist, were all up and saving the planet with your technological advancements.
Um, well, I am just going to get some coffee while you two keep discussing.
All right, we're back. So, um, apart from this decoration and stuff, are you do you agree with the
vintage home, the more like minimalist thing or do you like the open concept one? The bigger one?
I, I love the look of minimalism, but as a place to live, it's not comfortable, right? And so,
when I think of an aesthetic that I like, you know, a look that I like, I really like
kind of dark wood, velvety, nightroof, kind of, like, like, I think of old Vienna.
You like Castle Dracula. No, not dark. I like things to be open. And I like a lot of natural light,
but I also like oversized kind of heavy furniture and really luscious fabrics and things like that.
So, that's my, I'm actually completely different because I do like this open concept. I like
those houses that I like the way they look inside as well as outside when they're kind of
squared, big windows, clean lines. Inside is like, for example, in the kitchen, you have
polished aluminum or polished steel furniture in the kitchen, um, as well as a lot of white and red
or black, especially, um, I kind of like that kind of open spaces. Primary colors. Yeah,
flat screen TVs on the wall and stuff like that. Like, like, remote control. Ikea lamps. Yeah,
you know, like those remote controls where you can, um, open your curtains, your TV and the lights,
all the same time. I kind of like that stuff. Cool. Well, let us know what you guys like because
everyone has their own opinion on, right? A beautiful house is, and if you have any pictures,
feel free to share them with us on our website, EnglishPod.com. All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.