Hello English learners, welcome back to English pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another part of our sports series and today we're
going to be talking about volleyball. That's right and we're going all the way to New Zealand to
visit the Men's volleyball championships. So we're going to be looking at some great words and phrases
related to volleyball and also how to describe a sporting event. So before we start on the dialogue
let's take a look at two words on vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview. All right we're going
to hear both of these words in the dialogue. Now the first one encounter encounter and exciting
encounter. All right so if we have an exciting encounter it means we have an exciting meeting of two
people or two teams or two groups. If I say I had an incredible encounter last night with my best friend
you met up your best friend with your best friend and something happened. Okay so that's what an
encounter would mean. Yes looking at our second word now powerhouse. Two powerhouse teams. All right so we
have two powerhouse teams, China and Brazil. That's right so a powerhouse team is basically a strong
powerful, really energetic, great team right? Okay so we can use it for teams such as in this case but
we can also describe maybe a company or a person at powerhouse. That guy is a powerhouse. You can
lift 500 pounds. Now I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the first time. We're
going to be listening to this great sporting event as we are taken to New Zealand to see China and
Brazil play.
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the Men's volleyball world championship. My name is Rick
Field and I'm joined by the man of the plant Bob Copeland. Thank you Rick. We've got a very exciting
encounter ahead of us today is two powerhouse teams Brazil and China. These off against each other
and try to qualify for the next round without a doubt. Both teams are in top shape and this will
prove to be a competitive match. The ref signals are started the game and here we go.
Li Beh who serves and China quickly receives the ball. Chun bumps it to the center and
very nice set by Chun. She was spiced. Wow what a great hit. The Brazilian blockers anticipated
the play and tried to block him but he managed to get the ball in great play. It's China service now
what a superb jump serve by Li. Oh oh and we have a let's serve. The ball was coming in fast
and almost made it over the net. Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back after a short
commercial break.
Well sounds like a pretty exciting encounter between these two countries. Very good teams and both of them
as they mentioned our powerhouse teams. Well why don't we take a look at some of the vocabulary
that we came across in this dialogue. We're going to be focusing on volleyball words here in
language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay so in language takeaway today we're going to have six words
and let's start with the first one. Chen bumps it to the center. All right two bumps. All right so
in volleyball when you are going to receive the ball you put your arms together and you hit it
with your four arms. That's right so at the top of your arm. Right and that's how you pass it to
another player. That's called a bump. So it is a noun and a verb. A bump too bump. Exactly. Now
another type of way to move the ball in volleyball we heard in the dialogue is a set. A very nice
set by Chen. So a set or two set. Right the word can be used as a verb and a noun and again you take
the ball and you move it with the tips of your fingers. That is actually done by the center. Right
that is done by the center and he does this. He sets the ball so then the attacker can spike the ball.
That's our next word. Two spike. So two spike the ball or a spike is when you hit the ball
very hard and very fast with the palm of your hand. That's right and that's how you score your
points right? Exactly so you'll see three basic moves the bump set and spike. But what about the
serve? All right so our fourth word in volleyball is service. So it's China's service now.
Right so the service is the opportunity for the team to serve the ball. Yeah pretty simple. Right
and that means basically to start the game by hitting it to the other side. Now one type of serve
is the jump serve. Jump serve. Now this is very popular and you will see some players do this.
They will throw the ball in the air and then jump in the air and hit it. That's right. All right so
that's a jump serve and our last word for today is let's serve. A let's serve. Okay we have a
let's serve today. So a let's serve is when you serve the ball and it sort of brushes over the net.
Right it'll hit the net but it will still pass to the other side. That's right and that's an
illegal move in volleyball isn't it? When you are serving yes. So a let's serve. Right so those are
the six terms related to volleyball that we're going to be looking at today and well with this in mind
let's move on to looking at some phrases now in what is it fluency builder fluency builder
all right so our two announcers Bob and Rick said that we've got an exciting encounter ahead of us.
Right so they use this phrase ahead of us ahead of us. So basically what does that mean?
Something will happen in the very near future. So they are expecting it or they will encounter it maybe.
Yes so why don't we give a few examples of this phrase Marko we've got a long day ahead of us.
We have a very exciting trip ahead of us today. Mm hmm okay so ahead of us. So we know it's an exciting
game and we heard the announcer say without a doubt both teams are in top shape.
Okay so the phrase without a doubt without a doubt. So if I start a phrase using without a doubt
you're basically saying there's no question it's so obvious this definitely is true.
It's very true okay so without a doubt English pod is the best pod cast out there.
Without a doubt this is the strategy we should take. Okay very good so without a doubt why don't we
move on to our third phrase now. This will prove to be a competitive match.
So let's look at the phrase will prove to be something will prove to be. Okay so before we get into
it why don't we listen to some examples. Example one. And I think you'll prove to be the greatest
president we've ever had. Example two. The new HR policy is proving to be a waste of time.
Example three. We were worried that we were going to get laid off but our fears proved to be untrue.
Okay so when something will prove to be it will show itself to be this thing right?
It will demonstrate we will see it we will see for sure how it will be and now for our fourth phrase
a very simple one but very common in sports commentators or when you're watching a game.
You'll say great play. Great play. Great play. A great play. Now we know play is usually a verb right?
But here it's acting as a noun. A play is basically a move in a sport or a game.
So when somebody says a great play it means all the succession of moves and passes and hits to make
the point. Yeah so it was a great play. And that you can use that for any sport. Right.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue now for the second time and then we'll come back and talk
about this very popular sport volleyball.
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the Men's volleyball world championship.
My name is Rick Field and I'm joined by the man of the plant Bob Copeland.
Thank you Rick. We've got a very exciting encounter ahead of us today is two power house teams
Brazil and China. These off against each other and try to qualify for the next round without a doubt.
Both teams are in top shape and this will prove to be a competitive match.
The ref signals are started the game and here we go.
Li Beh who serves and China quickly receives the ball. Chun bumps it to the center and very nice set by Chun.
She was spiced. Wow what a great hit. The Brazilian blockers anticipated the play and tried to block him.
But he managed to get the ball in. Great play. It's China service now.
What a superb jump serve by Li. Oh, oh, and we have a let serve. The ball was coming in fast and almost made it over the net.
Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back after a short commercial break.
So you were volleyball fan Marco? It's a very nice sport. It's very fast and it's very hard.
Yep. But it's very interesting to get together with friends. Maybe at the beach and play some beach volleyball or something like that.
Yeah, I think that's the best place to play volleyball. You know, we even have beach volleyball up in freezing cold Canada.
And do you have sand? Um, occasionally. All right. So volleyball is a great sport. But now we want to know what sport you want to learn about.
We've covered soccer. We've covered basketball. We've covered volleyball. So tell us what other sports you would like to learn
vocabulary and phrases on that's right. You can tell us this and many more things at EnglishPod.com our website. So check it out.
Right. Leave your questions in comments and we'll see you guys there. Thanks for downloading and until next time. Bye.