Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we've got a
monologue. We've got one person talking telling you how to make the perfect sandwich. That's right. She's a chef and she's going to teach us
She's going to talk about all the ingredients and some tips on how to make a sandwich. So be prepared. This is going to be a really good lesson
and I'm already hungry thinking about it. So let's listen to the dialogue we'll be back in a moment.
Welcome to our show. Today I'm going to show you how to make the perfect mouthwatering sandwich. Are you ready?
Let's get started. Let's start with the basics. Bread. Bread is an important ingredient here. You need to
remember one thing. Choose the bread according to the following criteria. Freshness, crumb, and color.
If you want to close sandwich, I recommend you first toast your bread in a toaster or oven or
grill it slightly until it gets a light brown color. Now that our bread is ready, let's talk about the ingredients.
Of course, each person's palette is different but I'm going to give you a few tips that you'll be able to use
when turning any sandwich into the perfect sandwich. I would strongly recommend you put fresh
vegetables in your sandwich. Do not undervalue them as they play a big role in forming the taste and
we'll make the sandwich more refreshing and light. The best choices here are evident.
Cucumbers, tomatoes, onions, sweet pepper, chili, lettuce and of course herbs. You can't go wrong with them.
As for our aubergines, mushrooms and asparagus, I would recommend you first grill them slightly with a
little touch of olive oil. Last but not least, we have a wide variety of condiments that we can add to our
perfect sandwich. We can be subtle and add just a touch of salt and pepper or we can combine mustard
sauce, mayonnaise, ketchup or even caviar to achieve a stronger flavor. It's always a good idea to
cut your sandwich in triangles or manageable pieces to avoid all your ingredients falling out and
standing your shirt. That's all the time we have for today but join us next time where we'll be going
over how to make the perfect lasagna. Until next time.
Alright we're back so obviously I think she knows what she's talking about. This is going to be a great
sandwich. Alright so as she mentioned a lot of ingredients, a couple of different words that we might
not understand. So let's take a look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay at the beginning of this monologue as I said, the chef is talking about
things that you need to look for in a bread because bread is the base of a sandwich and she
mentioned the word crumb. Okay yeah she said freshness crumb and color so what does she mean by crumb
of the bread? Okay so crumb a crumb is a very very very very very very small piece of bread like
when you put bread in a toaster maybe it's what falls down actually. We call them bread crumbs sometimes
you can cook with them but they're they're basically little pieces of bread that fall off
little grains. Okay yeah so yeah usually it happens all the time you're having cookies or you're having
some bread you bite into it and little pieces of bread or cookie fall down those are called crumbs. That's
right and a bear this is a very and I want to remind everyone that the word crumb has a be on the end
see are you mb but we don't pronounce the be we just say crumb. Yeah you don't say crumb. No okay
so just crumb. Yeah be careful with that one. All right so we have to keep it look out for the crumb
of the bread I guess how fresh and how sometimes when you squeeze bread it makes a nice little sound.
Crunch crunch. Exactly so but she's also recommending a couple of different ingredients and she said
well it depends on each person's palate. So after we've chosen our bread she talks about a close
sandwich and maybe toasting it. Okay so there are two options for sandwiches you might see these
on menus as well as when you're cooking yourself a close sandwich means you have two pieces of bread
one on the bottom and one on top it's closed. Okay but the opposite is an open sandwich that means
you only have one piece of bread and then maybe you have some meat on top. Oh okay actually I always
thought that for it to be a sandwich you had to have two pieces of bread. Well now when you I would
challenge you to look on Google for an open-faced sandwich or open sandwich you'll find some very
interesting. Yeah I've had them actually you can put some meat in some cheese just on top of a piece
of bread and you're done. I'm a huge fan of those yeah so that's a close sandwich though when you have
two pieces of bread and the meat in the middle and after that she talks a little bit about people's
taste and what people want but she used a very special word. That's right she said each person's
palate is different. Okay a palate in the context of food and taste means the way that food
flavors affect a person individually. That's right so sometimes you say that some people have
very good palate so they can maybe tell the difference between a wine from 1978 and a wine from
1980 or something like that. That's right so you can have a palate a good palate for wine but also in
in this case where I'm out food I could say I have a very sensitive palate so I don't like to use
very very strong flavors. Okay so the palate is basically your taste it's actually a physical part
of your mouth it's the top of your mouth or your tongue can touch the top of your mouth. They
move with your mouth exactly it's not just your ability to taste sweet it's sweet and salty and sour
and all these different flavors. Okay so a person's palate now herbs right now moving on to the
main ingredient she mentioned a lot of easy ones like tomatoes onions lettuce but then we got into
a little bit more specific things like for example this word that's always mispronounced herbs.
Actually you can say herbs it's a very British thing to do though American to Canadian say herbs
it has an H in the front that's why it's confusing. Okay so we can accept basically if somebody says
herbs but I guess in American English it's more commonly the it's more commonly pronounced as
an a silent H. That's right herbs herbs. And what are herbs you might be asking well herbs can
come in many different shapes and sizes they're usually green they're usually grown they're
ways of making giving food different flavors and so basil for example is an herb it's a big
green leaf something that we use in pesto for example. Okay I'm you can also have rosemary or mint
these are all kinds of herbs. Okay some people even have an herb garden that's right they grow their
own herbs. Okay so now moving on to these weird looking vegetables for example abrogines. Okay
abrogines are the same as eggplant so you might hear this word sometimes it's basically a big
purple vegetable. Okay so for those of you who haven't seen an abrogine or an eggplant yeah it's a
big purple vegetable they kind of looks like a cucumber but a little bit fatter. Very fat and um they
they're if you hold them they're not very hard they're kind of soft. Yeah and a lot of people
like to grill these or to cook with them in for example Chinese with there's a lot of eggplant or
abrogines. All right so we've had those we have mushrooms and what about asparagus?
Asparagus is actually one of my favorite foods but it's very strange looking. It's kind of green and
it kind of has this little head right? That's right it's long it's it's green it's kind of like a
pencil but at the very top it's it's kind of like a plant almost. Yeah they have a very strong taste
and many people don't like asparagus. That's right and the Germans I think actually Germans and the
Dutch have special asparagus that's white. Oh really it's called shbargle. Oh wow. But if any of you
know what that is it's basically a white asparagus but asparagus is very popular in a lot of parts of the
world. Okay so now we have our vegetables we have our bread but now we need to add a little
bit of extra flavor to the sandwich so this is where we add some condiments. Okay so condiments are
category. You can have many different kinds of condiments the most common are salt and pepper. Okay
so a condiment is a category of the things that you would add flavor to as you said salt, pepper
but here they mention for example mayonnaise or ketchup. Ooh and mustard as well these are all condiments.
So in different parts of the world they had different kinds of condiments. I've seen for example
a lot of vinegar in in Asia. You can also have pepper flakes like in Europe. Uh-huh yeah
the condiments that you add to your sandwich are very that I've seen people put all types of condiments
in their sandwich and for example one that maybe a little bit strange or maybe a little bit more
expensive condiment is caviar. Okay so caviar is not always considered a condiment it can be
but it can also be eaten alone but it's basically just fish eggs. It's their little fish eggs.
Very small. It always usually in people's mind it's kind of like a fancy food very luxurious,
very expensive. Well it can be very expensive if you get like buluga caviar. A lot of caviar comes
from the Caucasus and Russia and Ukraine these places and it's very salty in flavor. That's right
so that is also considered a condiment in our case because we're using it for a sandwich right
okay so a lot of words there are a lot of interesting things that going on in our sandwich.
Why don't we move on now to fluency builder where we're going to take a look at some phrases.
Fluency builder. All right so let's go back to the very beginning of the dialogue.
When she said all right let's start with the basics. Okay the basics is a set phrase in this
context and we can say this about many different things but the basics basically are first to the
most simple ingredients or the most simple elements. In this case bread bread or meat but you can also
talk about the basics and other contexts like cloth shopping like you know when school started when
I was a kid my mom always used to buy me the basics so t-shirts and socks. Exactly so I guess the
basics are the absolute necessary things. Yes. Right that that are and also very simple. So for
example if you talk about dancing the basics would be maybe a certain sequence of steps that
important essential right. That's right and would caviar be a part of the basics for example. No no no no no
no that's an extra. Okay so this is what we refer to when we say the basics. Now our chef
when she continued talking about her sandwich she said I would strongly recommend you use fresh
vegetables in your sandwich. Okay so you can say I would recommend this but to strongly recommend
is to have a very very strong feeling about something. That's right you're saying to the person
basically do it. You must. Yeah so if maybe your friend is sick you can say something like
I would strongly recommend you go to the doctor today. That means you really really should go to
the doctor. I would be upset if you didn't. It's kind of formal though I don't it it seems like you
would maybe use it with a boss with your boss or maybe with a person you don't really know that
well but with your friend you would say I really think you should go to the doctor. Yeah but you
can you can say it in both contexts but yeah definitely more of a formal thing. Okay so we strongly
recommend that you. All right so now for our lesson. All right now moving on to our next phrase
she when she started talking about the condom and she said last but not least we have a wide variety
of condomants. Okay this is a very very common phrase it's a set phrase you will hear these words
together very often last but not least. What could this possibly mean so obviously last means
the last step here. The last point. But why not least? Well it's not least important just because
it's last it doesn't mean that it's not important. Okay so maybe there are many people who have to
give presentations in school and I'm the very very last person to go the teacher will say last but
not least Katherine. That's right. Makes me feel better because you're saying you're last but it
doesn't mean you're not important. Exactly so when you want to make sure that the last point
of your presentation or what you're talking about is not ignored or you just you want to make sure
that everyone knows that it's also very important you say last but not least. Great. All right and
now last but not least the end of fluency builder we're going to close off with this little phrase
when she was talking about salt and pepper she said a touch of salt and pepper. Okay a touch of
salt and pepper is basically a measure. It's not a lot it's very little amount of salt and pepper
so we can say a touch. So it's not really a specific quantity though right we're not saying like a
a spoon of salt and pepper. Not at all it basically means a little bit a little bit so it's so you're
just saying maybe you'll hear this and maybe a cooking show or you'll read in books when they'll say
a pinch of salt or a touch of salt or a dash of salt. That's right you could even say it
about other things for example if my friend just wrote this article and he wanted me to read
I say it's a really good article but it could use a touch of humor. Okay maybe if you made it
a little bit funny it would be better. Or maybe if you're painting your house you can say oh I think
a touch of red paint would look really nice on this wall. That's right a little bit of red paint
would be good. Okay so a touch of a really really good phrase it makes you sound very natural.
Okay so that's all the time we have for today but before we go let's listen to the dialogue again.
Welcome to our show. Today I'm going to show you how to make the perfect mouth watering sandwich.
Are you ready? Let's get started. Let's start with the basics. Bread. Bread is an important ingredient here.
You need to remember one thing. Choose the bread according to the following criteria. Freshness,
crumb, and color. If you want to close sandwich I recommend you first toast your bread in a
toaster or oven or grill it slightly until it gets a light brown color. Now that our bread is ready
let's talk about the ingredients. Of course each person's palette is different but I'm going to
give you a few tips that you'll be able to use when turning any sandwich into the perfect sandwich.
I would strongly recommend you put fresh vegetables in your sandwich. Do not
undervalue them as they play a big role in forming the taste and we'll make the sandwich more refreshing
and light. The best choices here are evident. Cucumbers, tomatoes, onions, sweet pepper,
chili, lettuce and of course herbs. You can't go wrong with them. As for
Aubrogines, mushrooms and asparagus I would recommend you first grill them slightly with a little touch
of olive oil. Last but not least we have a wide variety of condiments that we can add to our
perfect sandwich. We can be subtle and add just a touch of salt and pepper or we can combine mustard
sauce, mayonnaise, ketchup or even caviar to achieve a stronger flavor. It's always a good idea to cut
your sandwich in triangles or manageable pieces to avoid all your ingredients falling out and
staining your shirt. That's all the time we have for today but join us next time
where we'll be going over how to make the perfect lasagna. Until next time.
All right so talking about sandwich this really reminds me of making sandwiches at home grilled
cheese sandwich. We didn't really talk about it here but I think it's my favorite sandwich.
The grilled cheese sandwich. Very easy to make just two pieces of bread and cheese inside.
Do you use butter though? Yes. Yeah so you have to butter the bread and so when you grill it it
gets really nice and brown. Yeah actually I'm not a very big sandwich fan. When I'm having for
example a meal like lunch I don't really I don't know I think I need something more solid than
just a sandwich at times. Interesting I had a sandwich for dinner last night. Yeah we speak about it yeah.
I had an egg salad sandwich. Egg so you had egg salad inside a two pieces of bread. That's right
but the bread I had was French bread so that long thin bread was very crunchy very delicious but
actually I like sandwiches for dinner. There a little bit lighter yeah when you're having a big
meal it just seems like although maybe sometimes places give you very big heavy sandwiches that have
you know like ham and salami and just a lot of things in there so they're very very filling.
It's very true like a meatball sub for example is a very heavy sandwich. That's right.
But sandwiches come in all shapes and sizes you can make basically any sandwich that your
brain can think of and so we hope that you've learned some words for talking about sandwiches today.
Of course if you have any questions or comments or you want to share with us your very favorite
sandwich you should do so on English.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.