Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about weddings.
That's right, we are having a wedding but we're actually planning all the things out for the wedding.
That's right, so there are lots of things to think about when you're planning a wedding and I don't think that the woman in today's dialogue has forgotten anything.
Let's take a listen to the dialogue first and we'll be back in a moment.
I'm going to be back in a moment.
Trina, will you marry me?
Yes, yes, yes!
Jared of course I'm married you.
Oh babe, I can't wait to spend the rest of my life with you.
I can't wait for all the adventures we're going to have for all the fights and the laughter.
Can't wait to grow old and wrinkly with you.
Oh Jared, I can't wait for our wedding. I hope you don't mind but I've already chosen a date.
Six months from now in the summer.
Melissa saw you buying the ring last month so I had plenty of time to start planning.
She what?
Oh, don't worry, sweetie. I didn't know when you were going to propose.
It was still a nice surprise. As I was saying, I got it all planned out.
There's almost nothing left to do. I wrote up our guest list and we will have roughly 400 guests attending.
400? No need to sweat it. My parents agreed to pay for most of the wedding, which is going to be a low budget anyway.
So roughly 400 people, which means that the whole at Northwood Heights will be our reception venue.
I thought it would be nice if we had the wedding at your parents' church and my uncle of course would be
officiating. We'll meet with him soon for some pre-wetting counseling.
The music for the wedding ceremony was a no-brainer. My step sister and her string quartet will take care of that.
My cousin will be the official photographer. I thought it would also be nice if his daughter could sing a solo.
Did you know that she's going to be a professional opera singer?
And then of course the ladies at the church would love to be our caterers for the banquet
and we'll get the youth group to serve us. But it's thinking that your friends' band could be our
entertainment for the night. Though they might have to turn it down a bit. Or we could hire a DJ.
Your sister's husband could get us a discount with that company that does the day court weddings.
Once they're named again, I was thinking that we could have an island paradise theme wedding and our
theme colour would be a soothing blue-like acqua marine and there will be a huge seashell in the
wall behind the podium where we'll make our toast. What do you think of small packages of
drink mixes for our wedding favors? Who else am I missing? Oh, your uncle could be our florist and
his wife could make our wedding gate. Oh wow. See, it's going to be wonderful. Oh this wedding
is going to be everything I ever dreamed of. If I survived the next six months.
All right, we're back. So she talked a lot. So there are a lot of words and phrases here that we're
going to take a look at. So let's start with a couple of them on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right. So on language takeaway, when we start off with the first word
and the basic one before you start to plan a wedding, the guy needs to propose.
For the woman, let's be a 21st century here, normally it's the man, but to propose in this
instance means to propose marriage. So basically this is the part where someone gets down on his knee
and he says, you know, sweetie pie, I want to be with you forever. Will you marry me? Right. To propose.
So to propose is to ask someone to marry you. That's right. But it can also mean something else
right to suggest. That's right. So I could propose an idea or I could propose a plan.
But in this case, to propose has another meaning and it's basically to ask someone to marry you.
Okay. Very good. So now we've proposed to someone. So we need to start planning our wedding and I think
one of the first steps is you need to know how many people are going to be there and who you're
going to invite. That's right. So when you're planning a wedding, you have to think about the people
that are going to attend the wedding. So you prepare a guest list. Okay. So a guest list. Now it's
pretty simple. Right. You have a list where you put everyone's name there and you know how many
people are coming. Exactly. Okay. A guest list. Now you have your guest list and now you need to pick a
place where your wedding will be. That's right. So we often talk about two parts to a wedding. The
first part is the ceremony, the wedding ceremony. Maybe if your religious that happens in a church.
Okay. But there's a party afterwards. And that's that's what we're talking about here. We're talking
about a reception. Okay. Our reception is basically the party part of the wedding where you drink
and eat and listen to music and dance. So obviously for that you need a space. I'm placed to have
the party and we call it the reception venue. Okay. A venue. So as you said, the reception is the
party and the venue is the place where you have it. Now a venue is not a specific word. Right. You
can use venue for many different places. That's right. So for example, someone's having a concert
I can ask him, hey, what's the venue? Okay. That means what is the theater or where's this place
you're going to have the concert? Okay. So for example, a stadium can be a venue or a restaurant can
be a venue. Exactly. So a venue is a place where an event can be held. Okay. Very good. So now
we have our reception venue. We have our guest list and the girl was talking about her
uncle officiating. What does she mean by to officiate? Okay. So like you said, the verb here is
two officiate. Her uncle will be officiating. I mean, he will be the person who marries them.
So maybe you've seen movies before where there's a priest who says, you know, do you take this woman
to be your lawfully wedded wife and tell them death to you part? Right. That person who says that,
the person who asks the questions, he or she officiates. Okay. officiates. So that's basically the
action of marrying someone or leading the ceremony. That's right. And in America, this isn't just
anybody. Someone has to have like a license or license or has to be a priest and has to have the
authority to officiate. Okay. Very good. So that's a very interesting word there too. officiate. Now
moving on when we talk about the food for the reception venue will we need somebody to cook it
and prepare it and that's when we hire caters. That's right. So a caterer is kind of like a cook.
But a caterer basically arranges a meal for many people. And usually the person will bring the food
to you. So for example, if we're going to have a party mark, oh, we're going to throw it at a
venue 10 miles away, the caterer will bring the food to us. Okay. Okay. So that's a caterer. You
get someone to cater your wedding. That's right. We're a caterer party. So I've had parties before
that I've called caterers to make the food for. Okay. So basically they work with me and I tell
them the kind of food I would like and they prepare it. Okay. Very good. And now for our last part
for the wedding planning, you have the food, you have the venue, you have everything but you also
need to decorate a little bit and this is when you call a florist. Florist. So this sounds a lot like
flower, right? Florist flower and then that's that's basically what this person does. A florist
is a person who prepares flowers or who cuts flowers and uses them to decorate. Okay. So you go to
the florist to buy flowers, roses and different types of things. Okay. A florist. Very good. So
six key words there that are related to planning a wedding. Why don't we move on now to a couple of
phrases on fluency builder? Fluency builder. All right. So this first phrase is is a really good one.
It's a little bit gross. We're talking about sweat. The woman in this dialogue says, hey,
no need to sweat it. So what does this mean? All right. So if you say to sweat means when you
are running, you're doing exercise. It's hot. Water starts to come out of your skin. Mm. Yummy.
Right. But if the person says, hey, don't sweat it or no need to sweat it. It's a collogial way
of saying don't worry. Okay. So we're not actually talking about sweat here. So maybe Marco
you and I are working on a project together and I say listen, Marco, I'm so sorry. I have a family
emergency. I can't finish the project with you. Would you be able to help me out? I'm so sorry.
Sure. Sure. Don't sweat it. It's not a problem. Okay. So don't worry. Don't worry. Right. So if
you tell someone to not sweat it, don't sweat it or no need to sweat it. Because you're basically
telling them it's okay. It's not a problem. Everything is going to be fine. Great. So the next phrase
here is also kind of relaxed. It's kind of laid back. So the woman is still describing some of the
things she's prepared for the wedding and she says, hey, listen, don't worry. The music was a no
brainer. Mm-hmm. Okay. No brainer. Okay. This is really easy. Well, your brain is inside your head,
right? So if you say no brainer, it's basically saying you don't have to think about it too much
or it's very easy, very simple. Okay. So I was deciding on where to go on vacation and the
options were Thailand or Antarctica. That's a no brainer. Right. Obviously, I want to go
where it's sunny and warm. So a no brainer means I didn't even have to think about it. It was
that easy. Right. The decision making was a no brainer. All right. So for our next phrase, the girl was
also talking about the music and she was talking about a band, maybe like a rock band. And
she said, well, maybe they could play, but they would need to tone it down. Okay. So this is a
favorite phrase of parents. I think all over the English-speaking world, tone it down. In this case,
we're talking about music. So maybe like you said, the the friends band is a rock and roll band
and it's really loud and angry and you know, in your face, but for a wedding, that's not appropriate.
So to tone it down means to make it more appropriate for the occasion. So maybe it lasts loud
or no offensive language or no swear words. Right. That's basically what tone it down means. Right.
If someone says you need to tone it down, it's a little bit more direct. Like you said, if your
parents tell you this, it's maybe because you're being a little bit too loud or you're yelling or
you're being irrespectful. Yeah. So that's why your parents would tell you, hey, you need to tone it
down a bit. That's right. Or sometimes we have this in the office where someone doesn't
understand how to communicate in a positive way. And so they say, oh, that paper you did was really
bad. It was stupid. I don't ever want to see it again. Say, well, maybe you need to tone it down a
little bit. Think about the words you're using and make them a little bit less harsh. So kind of to
relax to reduce your level of being aggressive, being loud. That's to tone it down. Exactly.
Okay. A lot of great phrases there. Why don't we now go back, listen to our great dialogue one last
time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Trina, will you marry me? Yes, yes, yes. DARREN OF COOLS ON MARE YOU. Oh, babe. I can't wait to spend
the rest of my life with you. I can't wait for all the adventures we're going to have for all the
fights and the laughter. Can we to grow all dinner wrinkly with you? Oh, Jared, I can't wait for
our wedding. I hope you don't mind, but I've already chosen a date. Six months from now in the summer.
Melissa saw you buying the ring last month so I had plenty of time to start planning.
She what? Oh, don't worry, sweetie. I didn't know when you were going to propose. It was still a
nice surprise. As I was saying, I got it all planned out. There's almost nothing left to do. I wrote
up our guest list and we will have roughly 400 guests attending. For 100? No need to sweat it. My
parents agreed to pay for most of the wedding, which is going to be a low budget anyway. So roughly
400 people, which means that the whole at Northwood Heights will be our reception venue. I thought
it would be nice if we had the wedding at your parents' church and my uncle of course would be
officiating. We'll meet with him soon for some pre-wedding counseling. The music for the wedding
ceremony was a no-brainer. My step sister and her string quartet will take care of that. My cousin
will be the official photographer. I thought it would also be nice if his daughter could sing a solo.
Did you know that she's going to be a professional opera singer? And then of course the ladies at
the church would love to be our caterers for the banquet and we'll get the youth group to serve us.
But I was thinking that your friends' band could be our entertainment for the night,
though they might have to turn it down a bit. Or we could hire a DJ. Your sister's husband could
get us a discount with that company that does the day-core at weddings. Once they're name again,
I was thinking that we could have an island paradise theme wedding and our theme colour would be
a soothing blue-like aqua marine and there would be a huge seashell on the wall behind the
podium where we'll make our toast. What do you think of small packages of drink mixes for our
wedding favors? Who asked my missing? Oh, your uncle could be our florist and his wife could make
our wedding cake. Oh wow. See, it's going to be wonderful. Oh this wedding is going to be
everything I ever dreamed of. It's five to five the next six months.
All right, so about weddings and planning out a wedding. Do you think 400 guests
is a small wedding? No. I think this woman is out of control. In fact, in English, we have a word
for a bride or like a woman who's getting married that describes someone who's completely nuts
about the wedding. We call her a bridezilla. Rightzilla. That's right, like Godzilla. Exactly.
The movie Godzilla. He's a monster. And he's out of control. He's out of control. And a bride who's
so obsessed with her wedding that nothing else is important, she is a bridezilla. Now, it's a very
big thing for a woman, right, for her wedding to be nice and perfect and everything. Do you think
guys are more relaxed in this sense? I don't know. I think it depends on the guy. As always,
there are some people who want to be very involved and some people who don't care. But in general,
I think a man or less worried about the details. Mm-hmm. They just as long as there's a wedding
is fine. Exactly. Although a lot of men when the wedding actually happens start to get very nervous.
Oh, but kind of like having doubts maybe cold feet. Yes, cold feet. Like should I get married?
I think it's very interesting because you see this and movies a lot. And I've always wondered
how often or how common is it for a guy or a girl to say no or to leave a wedding when it
has already started? Because you know, you have invited all these people, all these friends and family
maybe people came from different countries and food is paid for venue. You spend so much money
on a wedding and for you to say no. I don't know how common it is. It's very common in movies,
but I really don't know anyone who's experienced this. I don't either actually know that you're
bringing it up. So maybe we could talk about this. Is this common in your country? First of all,
do people spend a lot of money on weddings? And second of all, have you ever heard of someone
actually leaving the wedding before they finished? Yeah, during this ceremony, not before during
this ceremony. So our website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there until next time. Bye.