Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Margo.
My name is Katherine and we're here talking about some special foods today.
That's right today. We're going to talk about sea food. So everything that comes from the sea that we eat.
That's right. So we're in a restaurant and we're going to hear about the different options this restaurant offers.
Let's take a listen to the dialogue.
This is such a nice restaurant. I feel so classy.
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey but they serve the best seafood in town.
May I take your order?
Yes, I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and I'll also have the lobster.
Excellent, choisere and for you, madam?
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood platter.
Very good, madam.
Let's see if the platter sounds good. Excuse me, what does the platter have?
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, muscles, calamari and filet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great. Can't sit a lobster and give me one of the same please.
Very well, sir. Anything to drink?
Can we get a bottle of your house white wine please?
Superb choice. I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right, we're back. So today we're going to take a look at a lot of vocabes.
So we're going to have two parts of language takeaway and let's start with the first one.
Language takeaway.
Now in language takeaway part one. Today we have a number of really important and useful
adjectives. The first one is classy. That's right. So we're going to a nice restaurant and so
you feel like you're in a classy place. Now a classy place is a nice place.
You might be expected to dress nicely. It might be a little bit fancy.
Exactly. So classy is kind of a synonym of fancy or luxurious.
Right. So if you're going on a date with someone, it might be a good idea to go to a classy restaurant.
That's right. But usually if a restaurant is classy, it also means that it's a little bit
pricey. Okay. So something that is pricey is expensive and seafood is famous in America for being
very pricey. That's right. So something that is pricey means that it's a little bit expensive.
Now going to the food that we're going to get today, we had a couple of different ways of describing
how the food was prepared. So for example, the first one is marinated grilled shrimp.
All right. Now something that is marinated is covered in a sauce or a liquid before it's cooked.
All right. So you can have maybe a regular steak, but you can also have a marinated steak,
which would be marinated in some kind of flavor like garlic or yogurt. That's right. So usually
you leave it in maybe some sauce like garlic sauce for a couple of hours or a couple of minutes
before you cook it. Now when we cook it, there are different ways of cooking things. In this
case, we're having grilled shrimp. All right. Now grilled is different from fried fried. We do in a
pan with some oil, but a grill. Usually there's no pan, no oil. There's just a grill. So grilled grilled
grill is the tool that we use. Grilled food tends to be quite healthy. There's very little oil.
It's a bit more dry. And oftentimes we do grilling outside because there's lots of smoke.
That's right. Because usually you have like maybe a barbecue and you have some charcoal in there
or some wood. That's what you used to cook the food with. Yeah. And grilled food is very easy to notice
because there are usually black lines on top and bottom. That's from the grill. That's right.
So we ordered marinated grilled shrimp for starters. So what is a starter? Well, think about the
word starter. Start. Now a starter is something you eat at the start of your meal at the beginning.
You eat it before you eat the main course. All right. So it's also known as an appetizer.
That's right. Starters and appetizers are the same thing. And these are small. Things you eat
before you start to eat your main meal. So they're not very filling. Mm-hmm. Okay. So yeah,
it'll be something small like a soup or maybe like in this case some marinated grilled shrimp.
All right. So great vocab there. When we review that part and we'll be back in a bit.
This is such a nice restaurant. I feel so classy. Yeah. It's a little bit pricey, but they serve the
best seafood in town. May I take your order? Um, yes. I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for
starters and I'll also have the lobster. Excellent, choisere and for you, madam.
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood platter. Very good, madam.
Let's see if the platter sounds good. Excuse me. What does the platter have?
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, muscles, calamari and filet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of butter sauce and french fries. That sounds great. Can't
be one of the same please. Very well, sir. Anything to drink? Can we get a bottle of your house
white wine, please? Superb choice. I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right. So now let's take a look at all the exquisite types of seafood that we have here on
language takeaway part two. All right. Now the first thing we have in language takeaway part two
is a very distinctive animal from the ocean. It's bright red and it has two claws.
Right. We're talking about a lobster. Now lobsters, you don't find everywhere. In fact,
there are some parts of America where they're very famous for their lobster like Maine.
Now these are animals that are hard on the outside and soft and white on the inside and they're
quite difficult to eat. That's right. So they look kind of like crabs because they also have the
claws and everything but they're a lot longer, right? That's right. A crab is round and a lobster
is long and lobsters are also famous for one part for their tails. Right. The tails are full of meat.
They're very delicate, very delicious. Okay. So we're having some lobster and we also ordered
some baked oysters. Now oysters are another kind of thing that comes from the ocean. They come
in a shell. All right. And you might hear about oysters because some people some restaurants
like to have an oyster bar where they serve raw oysters over ice. That's right. So they look like
big rocks basically and when you open them inside you have meat and actually I think you get pearls
from oysters, right? That's right. So these two are special. They have a nice relationship. The
pearl forms inside a grows inside of the oyster. Very good. So now we've taken a look at some
oysters and talking about these things that have shells. We also have clams. Now while oysters are
big and sometimes quite shiny, clams are smaller. Usually white or gray and they have lines on them
and their shells that you open up and you eat the meat from inside. Right. So I guess if you've ever
been on the beach and you're collecting little sea shells, usually those are kind of like clams.
That's right. They're quite small. They can be about the size of an American quarter, 25 cents.
Okay. So now in this seafood platter that we're ordering, we have clams. We have scallops.
Ooh scallops are one of my favorite kinds of seafood. They're quite soft and chewy and they're
usually white. Okay. And then we have some mussels also. Now mussels are much different looking.
They're also in shells but they're long and the shells are black. That's right. So clams are kind of
small and round. The oysters are pretty big and look like rocks. Mussels on the other hand are
long and black and when you open them inside they're shiny also. They're orange on the inside or
yellow and so they're quite they're quite interesting looking but they're also very famous for the
French or Belgian rather the Belgian dish moul-fried, which is a nice specialty. All right and lastly
we are also having some calamari in this seafood platter. Oh this is one another one of my favorites.
Now calamari is a kind of food but the animal is the squid. Okay. So why is it called calamari?
Well calamari I believe comes from the Italian word calamaro. calamari means that it's
squid that's been cooked so that people can eat it. Okay so basically calamari and squid are the
same thing. They are the same animal but calamari means that it's prepared to eat. Yes and usually it's
fried so when squid is fried it becomes hard chewy and that's what calamari tastes like. It's quite chewy.
All right great stuff so why don't we review everything one last time with this exquisite lesson.
This is such a nice restaurant I feel so classy. Yeah it's a little bit pricey but they serve the best
seafood in town. May I take your order? Yes I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and
I'll also have the lobster. Excellent choice sir and for you madam? I would like the baked oysters and
seafood platter. Very good madam. Let's see food platter sounds good. Excuse me what does the platter have?
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, mussels, calamari and filet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of butter sauce and french fries. That sounds great. Can't
for the lobster and give me one of the same please. Very well sir anything to drink? Can we get a
bottle of your house wipe wine please? Superb choice I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right so seafood we said usually has the connotation of being a little bit pricey. Why do you
think that is? I think it's pricey because the best seafood doesn't come from seafood farms. It comes
from people who go and boats and they collect the seafood in nets and also there are fewer and fewer
places now in America where you can find this kind of food because some places have experienced
overfishing too many people are trying to fish and also some places just don't have the right
climate for certain animals. Right so for example in the United States you do have a well the whole
country is covered in the west coast by the Pacific Ocean the east coast you have the Atlantic.
So obviously you do have some coast but if you're in the middle of the United States it's
partly hard to get seafoods where I imagine it's very expensive. It can be very very expensive so
oftentimes we get lake food it's different kind of fish but we don't have lobsters but you'll
find that in the the west you get very good salmon because Alaska and in the northwest is very
famous for salmon from the Pacific and in the east it's very famous for lobster and crab which are delicious.
Now even though you have it's famous for lobster and crab it's still relatively expensive compared to
other dishes like for example I think a lobster how much would a lobster dinner cost?
A lobster dinner could cost you $150 right and you're getting almost almost the same amount of meat
as maybe having a steak that would be $20. Yeah less meat but we have more cows than we have
lobster and also lobsters are famous for being pretty pretty expensive it's a very fancy meal
to have lobster. So it's very interesting and actually some countries for
so it's very interesting but some countries seafood is very very inexpensive some communities or some
countries or communities that fish or have for example shrimp farms it's very inexpensive so it's
such a treat to be able to go there and have seafood all you want and not have to spend $300 on a meal.
It is indeed and it's it's really nice to be able to get these big prawns these big shrimp or lobster
eat them without worrying about the price but I'm curious in your country do you have seafood and
if so what kind is it cheap as it expensive is it pricey? Let us know our website is english.com
all right we'll see you guys there