Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very weather focus lesson. It's all about all the
horrible things that can happen to you with the weather.
Exactly. So as you know there are many different types of weather and not only rain or sunshine
but many other phenomena. So we're going to take a look at some of those but before we go into it
let's take a look at one word on vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. Okay so we're talking about extreme weather today. That's not rain or
drizzle or sunshine. We're talking about really interesting unique and sometimes devastating
things that can happen. So today's vocabulary word is Armageddon. All right so Armageddon.
Now you've probably seen the movie Armageddon. So what does this word mean?
Okay so this word is a reference to the end of the world. It means the time when the
world will end because of a great catastrophe or a great disaster. Okay so everyone talks about
Armageddon. It's mentioned in the Bible and as you say it's when the world stops existing.
Exactly. So think about that one as we listen to today's dialogue. We will be back in a minute to talk
about what's going on.
Those are the headlines for today and now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you Bob. This past week has been the beginning of Armageddon for many.
As a series of unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world, in Switzerland
a major avalanche was reported in the Alps. Fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme cold
this winter, a Blizzard has struck the US Midwest causing classes in schools and universities to be
temporarily cancelled. Moving on to Latin America, Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that has not
only affected farming but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant that provides
electricity for the entire country. In Chile, a major earthquake that registered 7.5 on the Richter scale
struck the southern region losses are reported to be in the billions. Authorities have not yet
released an official statement. Not a great week for the world. Any good news?
I'm afraid not Bob. One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted, causing major floods and landslides
in the region. Meanwhile Mexico's coast has been hit by Hurricane Nileana and officials say that
all the seismic activity leads them to believe that he tsunami made hit Central America,
affecting Honduras, Guatemala and Panama. That's all the news we have for today but stay tuned for
updates on the six o'clock news back to you, Bob.
All right we're back and well this weather report is not really far from the truth. I mean this
kind of stuff happens every day all over the world, right? That's correct and unfortunately it's been
happening very frequently in the past couple months we've heard of a lot of earthquakes,
volcanoes and things like that. So this is very valuable stuff when you're trying to talk
about current events as well. Okay so why don't we start now and losing a couple of different
words and phrases on language takeaway? Language takeaway. Well the first vocabulary item we have here
is meteorological event. It's a real mouthful to belong where meteorological. So for example
meteorological means having to do with the weather something that's related to the weather.
So a meteorological event could be rain snow. Okay so it has to do with meteorology.
Meteorology is the study of the weather and someone who does this is a meteorologist.
So usually the weathermen that you see on TV they're meteorologists. So let's go now to
Marco are resident meteorologists. Right okay so meteorological events. Now moving on
one of the first events that we're going to look at is an avalanche. Avalanche and avalanche has to do
a snow. This means that when a mountain that has a lot of snow on it maybe part of that so breaks
off and starts to roll down you have a wall of snow that comes down. That's an avalanche.
That's an avalanche. So you could say avalanche when the snow comes down and it's actually very
dangerous because people can get buried under the snow. Yeah exactly. All right so another event that
has to do with snow is a blizzard. Okay a blizzard is different from an avalanche because an avalanche
maybe it's not snowing. The snow just falls. But in a blizzard you're talking about a storm of snow.
But it's like a lot of snow coming down from this guy. So much snow that you probably can't see
anything. There's just white everywhere. Okay. All right so that's a blizzard. A lot of
lot of snow coming down from this guy. Now moving on the opposite of snow and things being wet is
we have a drought. Yeah this is the opposite of wet actually so there's no rain in a drought.
A drought means that things are very dry. The land is very dry. Okay so it's a period of time that
there's no snow, there's no water, there's no rain, there's nothing. It's very, very dry. We're going
through a drought. Correct and the problem with a drought is very dangerous is because people cannot
grow food in a drought and so lots of people starve when this happens. Okay so we've got to
watch out for a drought. Now in this case it not only affected farming but also we have a hydro
electric power plant that can't work obviously because there's no water. So hydro means water.
Hydroelectric means electricity that is generated by flowing water. And so for example a mill
something that turns water on our river is a way to get power from water but a hydro electric
project that can give you electricity is maybe like a dam or an electric mill. Right so usually you
have these and rivers and they just take advantage of the flowing of water to turn some huge
turbines and generate power. So that's all we have for now. Why don't we listen to the dialogue again?
And we'll be back shortly to take a look at some more words.
Those are the headlines for today and now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you Bob. This past week has been the beginning of our Megan for many as a series of
unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world. In Switzerland a major
avalanche was reported in the Alps, fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme cold
this winter a blizzard has struck the US Midwest causing classes in schools and universities to
be temporarily cancelled. Moving on to Latin America Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that
has not only affected farming but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant
that provides electricity for the entire country. In Chile a major earthquake that registered
7.5 on the Richter scale struck the southern region losses are reported to be in the billions.
Authorities have not yet released an official statement. Not a great week for the world.
Any good news? I'm afraid not Bob. One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted,
causing major floods and landslides in the region. Meanwhile Mexico's coast has been hit by
Hurricane Nileana and officials say that all the seismic activity leads them to believe that
he tsunami made hit Central America affecting Honduras, Guatemala and Panama. That's all the news
we have for today but stay tuned for updates on the six o'clock news back to you Bob.
Well a word that many people are unfortunately familiar with is Richter or Richter scale.
And now this is something that a lot of people are talking about right now because of the earthquake
in Sichuan China last year and the earthquake in Haiti very recently and so the Richter scale
that's a big are because it's a proper name is a way for us to determine how severe how big the earthquake was.
Right so people talk about a 6.0 7.1 so that's on the Richter scale. The lowest is 0 and the highest is
10 correct. Right but 10 is like impossible apparently. Apparently and a lot of them are actually
underwater but the very serious ones are maybe 8.0 7.0. All right so Richter scale.
Now we talked about earthquakes we talked about snowing. Now let's talk about volcano.
A volcano in Mexico has erupted. Okay so we've got two words here volcano.
A volcano is a mountain that has an opening in the center where lava from the middle of the earth
the center of the earth can come out. So it's very dangerous obviously because it's very hot.
Right but a volcano doesn't open it erupts. So the verb here that we use without volcano is too
erupt. Okay so it doesn't explode if volcano erupts. That means to open violently very quickly.
Okay so when this happens obviously you have a lot of lava you have maybe snow that melts and you
have floods and landslides. Okay land slides a landslide is one word but it's made up of two words
that you probably already know. So land obviously it's the ground and it's like that the earth.
But a slide is to move down across the ground and so a landslide happens when you've got something
like lava or water that's pushing all of the earth all of the ground down and it's destroying houses
and trees and land and it's very very destructive. Right so usually see this that happens
on the side of mountains or on the side of hills where all that land starts to slide down or to go
down and it's very similar to an avalanche but instead of snow falling down it's a mud and land.
All right so we have a landslide and because of all the eruptions and the earthquakes they said
that they have a lot of seismic activity. This word seismic is something that I've heard a lot recently
in movies like 2012. So seismic means having to do with the movement of the plates under the earth's
crust. So you know the earth is not everything that we see it's also activity things happening
underneath the ground and so underneath the ground we have these big plates and seismic activity
is what happens when these kind of things start to move. Activity is movement and so seismic activity
refers to earthquakes and volcanoes things that are changing under the ground that will affect us.
Okay so that seismic activity is pronounced seismic right?
seismic seismic. Okay and because of all this activity people say that they may have a tsunami.
Well this doesn't sound very English doesn't. I know tsunami and actually if you see the
spelling it's with a TTS. Right I think it's a Japanese word but I'm not positive. I think so too.
tsunami is the name that we give to a giant tidal wave so that's a wave of water in the ocean.
That's very very dangerous because it can get to a hundred two hundred feet tall and this means
that when it comes down it can destroy houses cities, cars, things like that. Right. And there was a
very very famous tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004. Remember that? Yeah in Indonesia right?
That's right in Indonesia and Thailand. Yeah it was it was intense it was big and it was also because
of a earthquake right? I think so all these earthquakes they move the earth around and then all
sudden the reaction is that there's water that moves in the water. Yeah it turned into a wave.
Yeah just imagine what happens with you if you have a bucket of water and then you start moving
the bucket just a little bit and you see how it just water starts to splat all over the place.
That's right. All right so tsunami was our last word for today when we listened to our dialogue
again and we'll be back shortly.
Those are the headlines for today and now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you Bob. This past week has been the beginning of our Megan for many.
As a series of unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world, in Switzerland
a major avalanche was reported in the Alps fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme cold
this winter a Blizzard has struck the US Midwest causing classes in schools and universities to be
temporarily cancelled. Moving on to Latin America Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that has not
only affected farming but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant that provides
electricity for the entire country. In Chile a major earthquake that registered 7.5 on the Richter scale
struck the southern region losses are reported to be in the billions. Authorities have not yet
released an official statement. Not a great week for the world. Any good news? I'm afraid not Bob.
One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted causing major floods and landslides in the region.
Meanwhile Mexico's coast has been hit by Hurricane Nileana and officials say that all the
seismic activity leads them to believe that he's tsunami made hit Central America affecting Honduras,
Guatemala and Panama. That's all the news we have for today but stay tuned for updates on the six
o'clock news back to you Bob.
So Marco these are all pretty terrifying. Have you ever experienced a meteorological event like
one of the ones that we talked about today? I've actually lived it through like three years
quakes like pretty big ones because you used to live in Los Angeles. So we get a
model of time in L.A. Apart from that I actually have seen a volcano erupt a couple of times because
you know Ecuador is part of the volcano alley right? It's all the Andy's mountains and it's part
of the circle of fire what they call. So we have a couple of different active volcanoes and from
time and time they will start to smoke or to spew some lava but nothing major like there hasn't
been a major catastrophe with the volcanoes hopefully won't either. Well and these days they have
a lot of equipment seismic equipment and meteorological equipment that can help meteorologists
to determine when things will happen like when a volcano will erupt or if there will be an earthquake
because they can study the tremors in the ground. Right. Yeah and I think probably the most
famous volcano is I think it was an Italy right Mount Mesuvius. That's right so you've got
Mount Mesuvius in Naples which famously destroyed a number of cities in this ancient civilization
in ancient. What is a major eruption? It was and what's amazing is that they still have a lot of the
buildings under the ash because when all the ash settled it preserved the bodies like a mummy.
And so you can see the bodies and the things that they're jewelry and their money and it's fascinating
because it's this horrible, horrible natural disaster actually helped us in the future learn about
this old civilization. It's crazy actually in a in a gore you can see a huge hole that has like a
lake in the middle and you're like oh wow that's beautiful but that's actually caused because the
entire mountain just kind of blew the top off like the cone because of this major eruption so you can
just imagine how powerful these eruptions are. I can just imagine what it would have been like Mount
Mesuvius. But anyway on a brighter note if you have any questions any comments or any stories of your
own maybe you've us you've lived through a typhoon hurricane or tornado. You can come to our website
englishpod.com. I hope to see you there. Alright bye guys bye.