Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a sad lesson for you. This is an intermedia level lesson
about what happens when a friend or family member dies.
Exactly. So we have a lot of words that are related to all the preparations for when somebody dies
and also some phrases that you can say to someone that maybe had a family member who recently passed
away. So before we get into all of this we have a key word that we want to take a look at now
in vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview. All right so in vocabulary preview you have that one
word and it's the title of our lesson also funeral. Funeral. So funeral is an event that something
that we have. So basically a funeral is the time when we mourn someone who has died. It's a
celebration of their life. Right so it's kind of like a ceremony where you respect that person
that passed away. Right. Some people will talk about the person that passed away or maybe,
you know it's time to maybe honor that person too. As you say mourn and remember that person.
Right so it's very common for people in different religions to have different traditions.
In some religions like I think in Christianity you have a priest who will say some things
that are very traditional and then say some things about the person who died.
And other religions have different ceremonies. Right. So today we're going to take a look at what
happens in preparing a funeral.
Hi Daniel. How are you holding up? I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you. I'm doing much better.
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I
imagine. There are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time and date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket?
No. When he's being cremated. She was talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
I already chose a cremation, earn, and we planned to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see. That sounds like something she would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be
tasteful. You're doing a great job. Thanks. It hasn't been easy, but luckily we have life
insurance and windy left behind a detailed will that will sort out any other legal matters.
All right we're back so a pretty interesting dialogue and I'm sure you have a lot of
questions regarding some of those words and phrases that you heard. So why don't we take a look at
five key words on language takeaway? Language takeaway. So basically we have two friends in this
dialogue who are discussing arrangements for a funeral and one friend is asking the other about
his preparations and asks if he's bought a burial plot. Okay burial plot. Now what is a burial
plot and why would you buy one? Well a plot PLOT plot is a piece of land. So you can think about
this logically a burial plot burial to bury is a place space in the ground where we bury a person.
Usually you buy one of these at a cemetery, right? That's right so cemeteries have some usually a
lot of land and you can pay for a piece of land. A small portion. A small portion yeah and that's a
burial plot. Okay good and well our next word is related to what you put into this burial plot,
right? Somebody dies and what goes into this piece of land is a casket. That's right and I don't know
if any of you are fans of the TV show six feet under but you'll know from this TV show that there
are many different kinds of caskets. So a casket is a box. You can have fancy caskets or you can have
wooden caskets that are very simple like pine and basically this is the box that the person's
body will go into when they're buried. Right very good so that is called a casket. Well moving on
a new trend I would say in many countries and many people around the world don't want to be buried.
So what happens you get cremated. cremated so this is the option for people who are not buried
in some countries. China for example I don't think you can be buried. You have to be cremated
because there's an issue of space. Right. And this is an option for most people where
basically your friend or your loved one their body is burned and you can collect the remains
afterwards they're very small. They're ashes. Right. So it's like a burning process. Okay interesting
so the word is to be cremated to get cremated. Yeah his body was cremated. It was cremated.
And well as you said you take the ashes and you can put them in a cremation urn or just an urn.
Okay urn this might sound like a strange word to you but an urn is a special kind of pot
okay or a vessel to hold things in. So for example in this case we have a cremation urn that is
a special pot usually very beautiful. Sometimes there's a name on it with the deceased person's
ashes or her remains. Okay very good so as you said it's kind of like a vase or a pot
something very nice and small where you have the person's ashes. All right so now we know what
happened during the funeral we know what happens how you maybe cremate the person or you put them
in a casket and well what happens afterwards? Well afterwards you have a memorial service.
Okay so many people want to know what's the difference between a funeral and a memorial service. Right.
And in my mind a funeral is very quiet and sad and you have some respectful words and you
usually put the casket into the ground or have some kind of ceremony but a memorial service is an
opportunity to talk to friends and family to eat some food to have some drinks to talk about the
person who died. It's almost like the party if that makes sense. Yeah exactly it's a get together of
people who obviously are trying to give support to their friends or the family members who
lost that person but also to talk about that person in a good way and all the great memories they
had I guess that's why it's called a memorial service because you remember and you give out your
memories about that person. Exactly okay great so a lot of interesting words there
are very specific to this topic but obviously really important so why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue again.
Hi Daniel how are you holding up I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you I'm doing much better.
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I imagine
there are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time in date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket? No
Wendy is being cremated. She was talked about how she didn't want to be buried. I already
chose a cremation earn and we planned to spread the ashes in the ocean. I see that sounds like
something she would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful. You're doing
a great job. Thanks it hasn't been easy but luckily we have life insurance and Wendy left behind
a detailed will that will sort out any other legal matters.
All right we're back so we have a couple of phrases for to be exact that we want to take a look at
now in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase is a very useful one if you're trying
to ask someone about maybe the how they're feeling or someone who's had some problems recently
you can ask them how things are going. One person says to the other,
hi Daniel how are you holding up? Right how are you holding up? Now you know that to hold up
something means to have it in your hands but in this case you're talking about how are things going?
Right but I wouldn't say hey how are you holding up? Right you wouldn't say that to somebody.
Right if normal circumstance. Not if Marco looks really happy I want to ask him but if someone
has passed through a very difficult period for example if someone dies and their family or
perhaps if they've been very sick or you know there's some negative or difficult things that
happen that you can say how are you holding up? So basically means how are you dealing with this
difficult situation or how are you dealing with your illness? Okay how are you holding up?
Or how are you holding up with your in-laws? Right exactly how are you dealing with a difficult
situation and then the person complimented this by saying and this is a very good phrase. This whole
sentence is very useful if you want to say something nice to a person that has recently
lost someone you say I am greatly sorry for your loss. Okay so you might have heard the word loss before
lose loss losses and now to think we normally see this about people who have died because you don't
want to say I'm really sorry for your dead brother. Right you know that's it's sad to do it.
Really to the right so in English we say I'm greatly sorry for your loss for this part of your life
that has been you know that has gone away. Right you can also say I'm very sorry for your loss.
This is standard phrase for this is a standard phrase for funerals and memorial service. Exactly
so if somebody's brother died you go up to that person and you can say I am greatly sorry for your
loss. I am very sorry for your loss that's that's what you say and it's very respectful and it's very
nice to say. Yes it's very nice. All right so now moving on we've said that the person is sorry and everything
but then they were talking about the girl Wendy and that she had life insurance and that she also
left behind a detailed will. Does that mean she forgot it? She forgot it but then you can mean that right?
Right no yeah this is a phrase that has a couple different meanings and so it's important to
look at this one we're talking about someone who has died who left behind something.
It means that they have completed it in this case or it survives them. Okay so they left that for you
because as you said it has a couple of different meanings like to leave behind can be to lose or to
forget but in this case specifically it's to leave for you. Yeah you for example you could say he
died and he left behind three children. Okay so that means that he had three children when he
died and there's still there's still a lot. Right okay very interesting phrase to leave
something behind and so she left behind a detailed will and that's going to sort out any other
legal matters. To sort out this is a great verb this is a well as a verbal phrase that we hear a lot
with documents and wills and things like this. Basically to sort out means to solve problems or
to fix or to amend. For example have you sort it out that problem you had with your plane tickets?
Mm-hmm okay yeah to sort out so have you fixed those problems or have you solved those problems
that you had with your plane tickets to sort out to fix to make arrangements for very very useful
phrase. Very useful phrase okay so for key phrases there really good ones why don't we go back
listen to the dialogue and boy back to talk a little bit more.
Hi Daniel how are you holding up I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you I'm doing much better
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I imagine
there are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time in date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket?
No when he's being cremated she was talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
I already chose a cremation urn and we planned to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see that sounds like something she would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be
tasteful you're doing a great job. Thanks it hasn't been easy but luckily we have life insurance
and when the left behind a detailed will that will sort out any other legal matters.
All right we're back so now talking about funerals there's an interesting word. What is it called
when a person speaks at a funeral? Well normally at a funeral a loved one or a friend will give a
ulogy ulogy. Okay that's you right? It looks like a funny word but it's very important and it's
something that you hear a lot who will give the ulogy or his son will give the ulogy. So this is maybe
the keynote address in a funeral. This is the important speech where someone will discuss the
person who has died and his or her contributions and life. Right okay so that's called a ulogy.
That's really really interesting because I don't know it. It's kind of a word that you don't
really use much and you wouldn't really know it. I have for example I didn't really really know about it
until I saw it in a movie when he made a mistake. He said Googleogy or something like that.
Yeah yeah it was in a comedy. So but very interesting words it's a sad topic but it happened
sometimes you have to deal with these things and so if you have to do it in English well what
better way than to learn all of these things which could come in handy sometimes. That's right and
you never know you're watching a movie or something and this comes up. There are a lot of
comedies like you said we call them black comedies. It's a very dark and talk about this. And they
are like four weddings and a funeral is a very famous English movie about this kind of thing. And so
this is useful vocabulary and some useful phrases for those situations as well. Exactly even if you
maybe meet somebody who I remember I knew somebody who met a casket salesman. Really?
Old casket. An interesting job. Yeah so you never know. You never know. Well hope you've
enjoyed this lesson not too dark for you but please do remember to ask us any questions or
practice some of your new words and phrases on our website EnglishPod.com. All right we'll see you
guys there bye.