Hello English learners, welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be bringing you a very useful lesson about being sick
Yeah, we're going to learn how to tell your boss that you can't go to work because you're sick
Exactly, this is really important because we all get sick and sometimes you just can't go to work
Yes, or maybe sometimes you just don't want to go to work
Exactly, maybe you're lying, but we're going to be teaching you how to do it anyways
So before we start with our dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
In this vocabulary preview, we have two words for you
The first one is quite ill
quite ill quite ill
So quite ill
Very sick very sick quite is a synonym of very
Exactly, okay, yeah, ill
Sick sick yep, so they both mean the same thing no difference no difference at all
I just think ill is more common in British English
Exactly, all right, let's take a look at our second word flu the flu the flu
So the flu is a virus. Yeah, it's a sickness
Okay, and it's very similar to a cold
Yes, but just a lot worse a lot worse so it's stronger. Yeah, yeah
It's also called influenza influenza
Exactly, so the flu
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue. What's gonna happen here today? Well, we're going to listen as Julie calls her boss to tell him she's sick
All right, but if she really sick, I don't know what's find out
Help you
Hi Daniel Julie here
Well, hi Julie how are you?
Actually, I'm feeling quite ill today. Oh, I'm sorry to hear that what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache
So throat
Running nose and I'm feeling slightly feverish see so you're calling in sick
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off
To recover okay then try and get some rest
All right, so Julie didn't really seem to be sick, huh? Yeah, I don't know that that cough was just a little too
My it seemed like she was acting. Yeah, all right, so let's take a look at some of this vocabulary in language take away
Language take away
We have five words for you here and these are all great words to describe a sickness, right?
All right the first one headache headache headache headache headache
So when you have a headache you have a sore head, right? Right your head hurts
So it's pretty simple. Yep. You have a headache. It's the way you feel after
Being at the bar too late. Yeah, when you drink too much you get a headache. Yeah, all right
Let's take a look at our next word sore throat sore throat
sore throat sore throat
So basically we have two words here. Let's look at the first one's sore
hurting it hurts right and your throat is well, it's you know it's the part right here with a bat
You can't see me
Well, it's the part um at the back of your mouth that goes down to your stomach. All right. That's your throat. Yeah
So you use your throat to swallow
Okay now we can use the word sore with different body parts, right? Yeah like a sore back a sore back right or maybe you were playing tennis all week
And so you have a sore arm a huh or even a sore neck right
So the word sore let's take a look at our third word
Roney nose
This is a very strange word. I know
But it doesn't mean that your nose is running, right? No, but okay, um
No, but when you have a runny nose
There's lots of water coming out of your nose, right? Right? So it's interesting though because when you run
You go fast, right? So a lot of water is coming fast out of your nose
You're nose runny nose. Yeah, okay our fourth word today slightly feverish
slightly feverish slightly feverish slightly feverish
So again slightly is a little bit a little bit right a little bit and feverish well let's break this word down
We know fever right?
So when you're when your body is very very hot because you're sick
So feverish is the feeling of your body being very very hot
Okay, so you have a high temperature. It's not that you have a high temperature
But you feel like you have a high temperature. Okay, so slightly feverish and our last word
To recover recover recover recover recover
So this means to get better, right?
Can you only use it when you're sick? So when you recover you get better and you rest
So maybe you can say I was so busy this week. I need to recover this weekend. Okay, so yeah, if you feel tired
You feel sick you can recover
Okay, let's listen to our dialogue again and we can listen to these words that we've just talked about
Hello Daniel speaking how my help you?
Hi Daniel Julie here
Hi Julie how are you?
Actually I'm feeling quite ill today. Oh, I'm sorry to hear that what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache
So throat a running nose and I'm feeling slightly feverish. I see so you're calling in sick
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off to recover okay then try and get some rest
In this dialogue we listen to some really interesting phrases of how you can tell your boss that you are feeling sick, right?
Yeah, some great phrases. So let's look at these and fluency builder
Fluency builder. Okay, let's take a look at our first phrase on fluency builder
I'm coming down with I'm coming down with I'm coming down with I'm coming down with I'm coming down with
All right, so let's listen to some examples and then we'll come back and explain this interesting phrase
Example one
My throat really hurts. I think I'm coming down with a cold
Example two
You have a runny nose are you coming down with the flu?
Example three
I don't feel well. I think I'm coming down with something
Okay, so basically coming down with means starting to get sick I'm beginning to feel sick. Yes, okay
So you can use it with I'm coming down with the flu. I'm coming down with a cold
Coming down with a cough yeah, or I'm coming down with something with something you don't know what it is exactly
Okay, let's take a look at our second phrase calling in sick calling in sick
Okay calling in sick
So this phrase is great. You know when you say I'm calling in sick you're saying hey
I'm not going to come to work today because I am sick. Okay, so literally it means that you call your office
You say you're not going to work. Yes, but it's great because it's three words that show such a long idea
Right because otherwise you would have to say I'm calling because I don't feel well
So I'm not gonna go to work. Yes, but if you say I'm calling in sick everyone knows everyone understands that you're not gonna go to work
Okay, now let's take a look at our last phrase take the day off take the day off
Take the day off take the day off. Now. This is a great phrase
To take the day off is to not go to work on that day. Yes now you can say take the week off
Take the month off take the month off or take the year off if you are so lucky
All right, so take the day off means to not go to work on that day
All right, let's listen to our dialogue again now and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more
Hello Daniel speaking how my help you? Hi Daniel Julie here
Hi Julie how are you?
Actually I'm feeling quite ill today. Oh, I'm sorry to hear that what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache
So throat
Ronnie knows and I'm feeling slightly feverish see so you're calling in sick
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off to recover okay then trying get some rest
Well Marco have you ever done what Julie did? Did you ever call your boss to say you're sick
When you're not really yeah of course. I mean sometimes you just don't feel very well
But you're not really sick you just don't feel like going to work. Yes, or sometimes you have something to do
Right, yep, you know what we call those in Canada
We call them personal days personal days. Yeah, so you say oh I'm gonna take a personal day
I'm gonna call in sick but then go shopping
We used to do that a lot because for example soccer games are such a big deal. Oh, yeah, and you know sometimes
You would have a soccer match between I don't know Brazil and it would be maybe a 10 a.m. or 11 a.m
So everyone would call and sick on that day. Yes, so the boss at least could plan that he would have an empty office
Yeah, or sometimes you would take half the day off
So you would just go you say well, I'm not gonna make it in the morning, but I'll come in the afternoon
So you would recover very quickly. Yeah
I'm feeling a little bit sick, but I'm going to be better in the afternoon
All right, so well if you have any questions or comments
Please come to our website and if you have any calling in six stories, please let us know
Yes, you can visit us at EnglishPod.com and Marko and I are always there to answer your questions
All right folks, so we'll see you next time. Thanks for listening. Goodbye