Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got part three of an exciting series you've got for you at the elementary level.
That's right. As you may remember, this is a series that we're studying all about a job interview.
So in the first part we just talked about the introduction. The second part was talking about your personal background.
And now we're going to talk about your educational background.
Okay. So the key topic here today is education. Let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a minute.
Now if I look here, I see that you completed a BA in English.
Yes, that's right. After graduating from high school in New York, I attended York University in the UK.
My major was English and my minor was business. I completed my BA in 2004.
Yes, I'm pleased to see that you also got a distinction. Yes, that's right. I've always enjoyed studying.
My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm, but my father always pushed us to succeed at school.
Well, it looks like his encouragement paid off for Becca. So how about extra curricular activities at
Well, I've always been keen on writing, so I became the editor for the university student newspaper,
which I really loved. Also, I volunteered for a group called Shelter to help the homeless in the
York. What did that involve? Providing warm meals and Shelter, especially in the winter months.
I found it really fulfilling to be part of that group. I'm sure. Okay, now let's move on to your work experience.
Shall we? Yeah, okay. Okay.
All right, we're back. So the girl was talking about her education, about her university,
and she talked about some very interesting words. So why don't we take a look at those in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. So at the very beginning, Mr. Parsons, who's the interviewer here,
asks Rebecca about her background and says, I see that you completed your BA in English. Okay,
so we have an acronym there. Hey, BA. This stands for Bachelor's, or usually a four-year degree
at the beginning of your university studies. That's right. So it's a type of degree, right?
A BA is, as you say, your Bachelor's degree, and it usually takes four years. That's right. You have
the Bachelor of the Arts BA, but you also have a Bachelor of Science, which is a BS. So as you can tell,
one is for the arts, like art history, music, and things like that. The other is for sciences,
like physics, or chemistry. Very good. All right. So she has a BA in English. So she obviously studied
the English language in university. Then she moved on to talk about her major and minor. That's right.
So as you know, a degree is not just a degree, a degree in the arts in general, but it usually
has a focus or an area of focus. So her area of focus, her major, was English. This is the most
important part of her studies. So many of her courses, most of her courses, at university, were in
English. That's right, but she also has a minor in business studies. Okay, that means she also studied
business and business studies. That's not as important as her English studies, but it was very
much a part of her degree. So let's say that when she was studying in university,
70% of what she studied was related to her major English, and maybe 30% was her minor,
was business studies. That's right. And she goes on to talk about herself and her friends who describe
her as a bookworm. This is a really nice adjective and very common in English. That's right. So
if you are a bookworm or you describe yourself as a bookworm, it means that you like to study
like, you like to read a lot of books. So birthworm is just like what you said is someone who really
likes to read someone who's always reading, maybe someone who lives in the library. So that's why
you call them a bookworm. They live in the library or they read a lot of books. All right, so that's
the noun bookworm. Now moving on to other parts of university when you're studying, you're not
only studying English or sciences and things like that. Sometimes you also do other activities or
other things. That's right. So you have your schoolwork, which is during school, it's English
and business studies for this woman, Rebecca, but you also have what you do outside of school. This is
called extra curricular activities. So that's a long word, extra curricular. That's right. So
extra curricular means it's not in the curriculum, right? That's right. It's outside of school.
So it's not really like a specific subject or something that's related to your studies. If you
don't do extra curricular activities, it's okay, right? That's right. A lot of people don't do
any extra curricular activities, but many people do, for example, writing for the school newspaper
or playing soccer. Exactly. So those are extra curricular activities. Anything that you want to do
in university apart from studying, playing soccer, writing, etc. And it's not just university,
you can do these in high school as well. Okay. Very good. So those are the words that we have
picked out for you today. I think they're very specific to education. And I think we should go back,
listen to the dialogue again and we're back in a bit with fluency builder.
Now, if I look here, I see that you completed a BA in English. Yes, that's right. After graduating
from high school in New York, I attended York University in the UK. My major was English and my
minor was business. I completed my BA in 2004. Yes, I'm pleased to see that you also got a distinction.
Yes, that's right. I've always enjoyed studying. My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm,
but my father always pushed us to succeed at school. Well, it looks like his encouragement paid off
for Becca. So how about extra curricular activities at university? Well, I've always been keen on
writing, so I became the editor for the university student newspaper, which I really loved.
Also, I volunteered for a group called Shelter to help the homeless in New York. What did that
involve? Providing warm meals and Shelter, especially in the winter months, I found it really
fulfilling to be part of that group. I'm sure. Okay, now let's move on to your work experience, shall we?
Yeah, okay. Okay.
Alright, we're back. So now let's start off with our first phrase on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So Rebecca is talking about her father and her friends, and she says,
she's a bookworm, but her father always pushed us. That means her and her family members,
her siblings, to succeed. And this verb, to push us, to push someone is very important, because it's
not the same as like to push a door. Right. So it's not physically that you're pushing somebody.
It's actually to motivate somebody or to inspire someone to become better at something. That's right.
So to push someone is to encourage them to do something bad. It's not always a good thing. So
right. She was always pushing me to do what she wanted to do. Not what I wanted to do. That means
someone's always trying to influence you or to get you to do something. Exactly. So as you say,
to push someone is to influence them, to motivate them, to encourage them, to do something good or bad.
Well, and Mr. Parsons agreed with her dad's encouragement, and he said, well, it really paid off.
Okay. This is a great verbal phrase to pay off. This means to have benefits. Okay. So all of
your hard work really paid off. So you can see the results. You can see the positive results of
your hard work. It paid off. You can even ask someone, all that hard work. Did it pay off?
Right. So that your basically asking, was it worth it? Yeah. Okay. To pay off.
And well, when she was talking about extra curricular activities, she said she was always keen
on writing. Now, I think this is more common among British people to say you're keen on something,
but it basically means to like. So remember the phrase, keen on. This is the preposition here.
keen on. I'm keen on writing. So can you say that you are keen on someone? Yes, you can. That means
you like someone, maybe romantically. Okay. So it's kind of as Catherine said, a more of a British
thing, but it's correct. And you can use it in replacement of to like. I can think it also
sounds a little bit more formal. Instead of saying, well, I've always liked writing. If she says,
well, I've always been keen on writing. I think it sounds nice. Well, smarter. Yeah. All right.
And our last word, it's actually an interesting word. It might be a little bit complicated to
understand. But when she said that, but when she said that volunteering was very fulfilling and to be
part of a group. Okay. For filling, sounds a lot like the word filling, but you shouldn't confuse
these two because the meaning is very different, right? So something that is fulfilling makes you feel
really good. You maybe maybe you don't make money from it or you don't get a lot of praise from it,
but it still makes you feel happy about life for yourself or something. So you get satisfaction.
Now, notice the pronunciation. You don't say full filling. No, you say fulfilling. For filling. So
the L there is kind of silence. Kind of optional. But maybe you could ask someone,
what do you find fulfilling in your life? Or you can ask, do you think your job is fulfilling?
Yeah. Okay. So a lot of great words there, a lot of interesting things related to education and not so
much. Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time?
You can go back and listen to the dialogue one last time.
Now, if I look here, I see that you completed a BA in English.
Yes, that's right. After graduating from high school in New York, I attended York University
in the UK. My major was English and my minor was business. I completed my BA in 2004.
Yes, I'm pleased to see that you also got a distinction.
Yes, that's right. I've always enjoyed studying. My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm,
but my father always pushed us to succeed at school. Well, it looks like his encouragement paid
off for back. So how about extra curricular activities at university? Well, I've always been keen
on writing, so I became the editor for the University student newspaper, which I really loved.
Also, I volunteered for a group called Shelter to help the homeless in New York. What did that
provide in warm meals and shelter, especially in the winter months? I found it really
fulfilling to be part of that group. I'm sure. Okay, now let's move on to your work experience, shall we?
Yeah, okay. Okay.
All right, so talking about going to university, I think they used a really specific
verb there that's worth mentioning. She said I attended York University in the UK. So to attend.
That's right. So you can say I studied at York University, but the more formal way of saying that
I was a student at York University is to say I attended that school. So to attend means to
to be a student at that place. Okay, and what about you, Katherine? Did you participate in
any extra curricular activities back in college? I did. I participated in a lot of extra
curricular activities. I was in the orchestra at my university and I played in a lot of musical groups.
I also was in a discussion group for politics and the India Pakistan dialogue group.
I was in a number of different film clubs, so we were talking about film and I even helped out
at the TV station for my university. Wow, the university had a TV station. Yeah, so all of it was
student directed, so basically the students controlled the TV station. That's really interesting. I think
these types of extra curricular activities are as many as these are maybe not as common in
in other places or maybe there are a little bit different. I know for example in the US you have all
these political ones and a lot of sports and things like that, but you also have very
strange far ones like, I don't know, like there's a cooking club and there's even like a
gardening club, a astronomy club, astronomy club, there's all types of extra curricular activities.
What's really nice about a lot of American universities is that there are many, many resources
that students can use. And so maybe the reason there's a cooking club is because there are massive
kitchens, the students can use to cook food and experiment and even teachers and professors
sometimes come to help. So it's a really nice environment because everyone's teaching each other.
Right. No, it's very, very interesting. And what are actually curious to know how university
is working your country? Are you able to have a minor in a subject? Because many universities
don't offer this option. Right. They just have one major and that's all. Right. Or maybe do you
are you able to participate in extra curricular activities? Like sports or radio or writing? Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com. All right. So we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.