Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
Hi, my name is Mira.
Alright, Mira is here today and she is going to tell us about the wonderful lesson she has
prepared this time.
Well, thank you, Marco.
Well, today we have a very interesting lesson prepared for you. It's about someone cutting
in line.
Cutting in line, okay.
It happens all the time and we all get very upset about it, but you know, it happens.
Right, right.
Well, I imagine that everyone is wondering what cutting in line is. Why don't we just listen
to the dialogue one time?
And then when we come back, Mira and I will gladly explain all the vocabulary in this
dialogue.
Let's listen.
I can't believe it took us two hours to get here. The traffic in New York is unbelievable.
Yeah, but just relax honey. We're here. We're going on vacation. In a few hours will be
in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course.
Oh, no. Look at that line. It must be a mile long. There's no way I'm waiting for
another two hours.
Honey, don't.
Hey, man, the end of the line is over there. Yeah. No, seriously, I was here first and you
can't cut in line like this.
Says who I do. So sue me. All right, that's it.
Whoa, I think there's punching. Yeah, I guess this guy was just a crazy, I don't know,
impatient man, huh?
Yes, yes, but we don't want to talk about this now. But for now, we will treat some
of the vocabulary and very useful phrases in the dialogue. Great.
Mark, are you going to start? Yes, let's take a look at our first word. It would be
unbelievable. Unbelievable. Unbelievable. Exactly. And just how you say it, it's something
incredible, something amazing. Yeah, but I would like to point out that unbelievable was
used here to describe the man's frustration. He's not happy about the traffic in New York.
Exactly, perfect. Okay, in the next part, the woman she's trying to calm and relax her
husband. And she says that they, they'll be in Hawaii in a few hours. And you'll be on
the golf course. Right. So we'll be in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course. Yes,
so this is a great way of talking about your physical location in the future. Right. So for example,
Amirat tomorrow where will you be? Don't worry, Marko. I'll be in the office tomorrow. Perfect. Right.
That's where I need you to be. Yes. Okay. All right. Well, I have another interesting phrase here for you.
Must be a mile long. A mile long. A mile long. Now that's basically not a mile. It's not a kilometer long.
But it's another way of saying that this line is really, really long. Right. It's just an exaggeration.
Now let's look. Take a look at there's no way.
But it's a really long. Right. It's just an exaggeration. Now let's look. Take a look at there's no way.
There's no way. There's no way. There's no way. There's no way. Perfect. Let's listen to some other examples on how we use.
There's no way in a different situation. And then we can come back and talk about it a little bit more.
There's no way I can have those reports finished today.
The stadium is so crowded that there's no way we'll find a seat.
Do you think Michael's going to buy that house? There's no way he has enough money to buy it.
All right. Everyone. So there's no way. Is another way of saying it is impossible. Exactly. There's no way you should miss this podcast. Right. Yes.
Well, I have another phrase for you as well. Cut in line. Cut in line. Cut in line. Cut in line.
So again, we have some really good examples on how you could use this phrase in different situations. Let's listen to the examples and then we can come back and talk about it some more.
Excuse me. I'm really late. Can I cut in line, please?
I hate it when people cut in line at the bank. It's so rude. I think it's okay when a pregnant woman cuts in line.
All right. Everyone cut in line. Right. So from the examples we can understand that it means when you are standing in line somewhere and somebody gets in front of you.
I have another phrase for you here. Sumi. Sumi. Sumi.
Okay. Now, Sumi is not a nice phrase. If you hear that, you know you're in trouble.
Yeah, it's kind of rude, I guess, to say Sumi. Right. Well, it actually means like taking someone to court and asking for money because someone has harmed you in a way.
I think that we should listen to the dialogue one more time and try to figure out why he used that phrase and if he's really going to take him to court.
I can't believe it took us two hours to get here. The traffic in New York is unbelievable.
Yeah, but just relax honey. We're here. We're going on vacation. In a few hours will be in Hawaii and he'll be on the golf course.
Oh, no. Look at that line. It must be a mile long. There's no way. I'm waiting for another two hours.
Honey, don't.
Hey, man, the end of the line is over there. Yeah. No, seriously. I was your first and you can't cut in line like this.
Says who I do. So Sumi. All right. That's it.
All right. We're back. Now this guy, when he says Sumi, he's just being rude. I mean, he's just being kind of impolite,
and telling him I don't care. Right exactly. Like you can't do anything about it. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Today in the studio, we have a guest. Her name is Sarah and she's from England.
Hi, that. Hello.
All right. So we're going to be asking her a couple of questions and she'll be a frequent guests on our show. So you can expect to hear from her a lot.
Well, she didn't know that. Yes. Yes. It's a surprise. She knows now. Well, Sarah, our topic today is about jumping the cue.
Okay. I mean, I'll wait. What is this jump the cue? It's the same as cut in line, but in British English. Oh, okay. Yes. Curing is very important in England. We're very proud of our cues.
That's true. So what would be the reaction of people if they like, you know, cut in line? I think we do take it very seriously. I'm laughing now, but it's quite serious.
So you don't don't the cue. If people jump in front of you, it's you get a little touch and so you shouldn't be doing that. And we make it very obvious. And in the show you don't loud.
We would, you know, perhaps say something and we have systems, you know, in London on the Metro, on the underground. You have to stand on the escalators on the right and cue and you can't jump in front. You have to walk on the left and cue on the right. There's all very serious. There's rules and regulation.
Is there like a cue handbook that you have to read in high school and kind of take a test on?
That should be. That should be. Yeah. What about New York, Marco? Well, no, definitely. I guess this dialogue is similar to a reality of New York. If somebody gets in front of you or cuts the line, somebody's going to say something and probably end up in a fight.
Oh, the guy is rude. Oh my god. Well, Sarah, why don't you tell us is there a line or a cue for almost everything in England?
It seems like we do just like to form a cue. Yeah. So, you know, can you think of like some other examples of where you would normally you wouldn't cue, but you do.
Oh, gosh. Things like in the supermarket when you're trying to find some vegetables or something, I'd never push. I'd never reach round or anything. I'd just wait until that person had finished picking up their stuff and then and then go in.
So, just just try and.
So, if like five people want to buy oranges at the supermarket, then you have a little mini cue of five people waiting. There's no there's no sort of just shoving through to the front. You just don't do that.
So, you don't stick your hand out and grab like a tomato or like again, you would make sure that that person knows oh, I'm sorry. I'm just in a hurry or whatever, but yeah, it's just letting someone go before you is a courtesy. I think.
Okay. Okay.
All right. Great. Well, thank you so much Sarah. The pleasure. Yeah, we'll have you back very soon. So, all right. We're at a time, but we'll be back tomorrow with another lesson and be sure to visit our website.
Don't forget that English.com has many, many resources and also a community of users and teachers that can help you answer questions and interact with you.
Yes, and you should definitely leave your suggestions. But for now, I wish you all well and bye.