Hello everyone and welcome to the English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a very important topic. This is about time.
That's right. So sometimes we are a little bit lazy or maybe we sleep too much and we're late to work or a meeting.
Alright so learn many different ways to talk about being late today. Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Okay everyone shall we begin? Sorry Maggie but we're missing a few people. Can we hang on a sec?
Well I did say 11 o'clock shop and it's now 5 past so...
Hi everyone. I'm so sorry I'm late. It's raining cats and dogs outside and I had to wait ages for a taxi.
Okay James, take a seat quickly please.
The subject of the meeting is the importance.
Hi guys please excuse me. I was held up in traffic.
Right. As I was saying the subject of the meeting is...
Time Maggie I'm terribly sorry. The traffic is murder out there.
Sit down bro no.
Okay now. As you're aware, the topic for the meeting is the importance of being punctual.
Who would like to start?
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some of this vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So first up we have a word that we heard. The phrase was I did say 11 o'clock sharp.
Okay so if you say the time like 11 o'clock and then you add sharp at the end. What does that mean?
That means exactly. So 11 o'clock exactly 11 o'clock.
11 0 0. Not 11 o' one. Not 11 o' two but 11 o'clock.
So if I say I'll be there at three o'clock sharp.
That means you won't be there at 258.
You will not be there at 304. You'll be there at three o'clock.
That's right. Okay so three o'clock sharp. So if you say the time and then you add sharp it means at that exact time.
Now James was late he said he was late because he had to wait ages for a taxi.
Okay so this might be confusing for some people Marco because I can say what's your age?
How old are you?
But here ages has a different meaning. So I have to wait ages means I waited a very long time.
That's right. So the word ages means for a very long time. It's always related to time and indiscents.
Exactly. So I could say Marco it's so good to see you. I haven't seen you in ages.
I haven't seen you in such a long time.
Okay very good. And now the next person Sally came in and she said she was held up in traffic.
Okay to be held up in traffic means to be stuck in traffic. That means you were made late because there were so many cars on the road.
Okay so somebody or something else made you late.
That's right. So to be held up means to be made late. I could ask you Marco why are you so late? What held you up?
Exactly. What held you up? That means what made me late.
That's right. It could be many different things.
Okay yeah. Okay yeah so it could be traffic or maybe I could be held up by the doctor.
Maybe he took longer than what I expected.
There's no elevator and I'm waiting for the elevator and I got held up by the elevator.
Okay very good. And now the importance of being punctual. That's the topic of the meeting.
And so what is this word punctual?
Okay so punctual is an adjective and it describes something is being on time.
Okay so the opposite of this word would be what?
So the opposite would be late.
Okay so she's a very punctual student. She always comes to class on time.
She's never late.
punctual. So you describe a person as being punctual or not.
That's right.
Okay very good. Let's review all this vocabulary. Let's go back and listen to the dialogue again.
Okay everyone. Shall we begin?
Sorry Maggie but we're missing a few people. Can we hang on a sec?
Well I did say 11 o'clock sharp and it's now 5 past. So...
Hi everyone. I'm so sorry I'm late. It's raining cats and dogs outside and I had to wait ages for a taxi.
Okay James. Take a seat quickly please.
Right the subject of the meeting is the importance.
Hi guys please excuse me. I was held up in traffic.
Right as I was saying the subject of the meeting is...
Time Maggie I'm terribly sorry. The traffic is murder out there.
Sit down bro no.
Okay now as you're aware the topic of the meeting is the importance of being punctual.
Who would like to start?
Alright now let's take a look at some phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
We have a lot of really great phrases today that describe...
Well that are excuses for not being on time or for not being punctual.
The first one we heard was actually different though.
One of the students said can we hang on a sec?
Hang on a sec okay. So if you ask someone to hang on that means to wait.
Hang on wait. Yeah exactly so hang on just means to wait. It's very casual.
Okay now if we add a sec hang on a sec or hang on a minute that means wait for a little while.
A little while a sec SEC stands for second and it's very common in this phrase.
We hear hang on a sec or wait a sec.
Wait a sec.
Okay very good. So it's very casual. It's very spoken English though.
The word sec doesn't really exist. It's just a short way of saying a second.
Exactly. And later on we heard James come in.
He was one of those people that we had to wait for.
And he said it's raining cats and dogs outside.
That's right. Okay it's raining cats and dogs.
So our cats and dogs falling from the sky.
They are not. So this might sound very weird to you.
This does not mean there are cats and dogs falling down from the clouds.
But it does mean that it's raining a lot.
It's raining really hard outside.
Okay very good. So it's a phrase used to say it's raining a lot.
It's raining very very hard.
Raining cats and dogs.
So Maggie is trying to continue with the meeting as many people keep coming in
and disrupting her. So she says right as I was saying the subject of the meeting.
As I was saying now this is a really important phrase because you're going to hear
that's a lot in in meetings or in conversations where someone is distracted.
So okay we're having a wait. I'm sorry I have to talk to this person over here.
When you want to come back to what you were talking about, you want to return to the topic.
You say as I was saying that's right.
As I was saying so maybe you were interrupted, maybe you got distracted.
And you want to continue talking about the same topic.
As I was saying and then you continue talking.
So you return to the original point you are making.
Okay very good.
And well Bruno was the last guy to come in and he said that traffic is murder out there.
Okay so murder to murder means to kill someone.
But we're not talking about killing people here.
We're talking about analogy or saying it says bad as murder.
So in this case traffic is murder means traffic is really awful.
It's really terrible outside.
So in what other situation or with what other noun instead of traffic.
Can we use this something is murder?
The wait is murder.
Okay so that means you have to wait a very very long time.
Uh-huh okay.
All right very good.
So now why don't we go back to the dialogue.
Let's have one last review and we'll be right back.
Okay everyone shall we begin?
Sorry Maggie but we're missing a few people. Can we hang on a sec?
Well I did say 11 o'clock shop.
And it's now 5 past.
So...
Hi everyone.
I'm so sorry I'm late.
It's raining cats and dogs outside and I had to wait ages for a taxi.
Okay James.
Take a seat quickly please.
Right the subject of the meeting is the importance.
Hi guys please excuse me.
I was held up in traffic.
Right as I was saying the subject of the meeting is.
Time Maggie I'm terribly sorry.
The traffic is murder out there.
Sit down Bruno.
Okay now as you're aware the topic for the meeting is the importance of being
punctual.
Who would like to start?
So Marco are you a punctual person or are you usually late?
Uh-for social gatherings I'm usually pretty punctual.
For work I'm usually very late.
I've noticed you're the last people to come in in the morning.
Usually for work I arrive late but not like too late.
You know some people may even be an hour or two or something.
A couple minutes 15 minutes is alright but I do hate to wait if we agree to meet up
at 2 o'clock and you come in at 2 o'clock and you come in at 2 o'clock and I don't know let's say to the movies.
Then I think that's really irritating.
I agree that's I'm a very punctual person and I get very annoyed when people are
late to meetings or when people come late to appointments or parties.
Yeah and I think it's different in different countries because you know in many different places they have what they call the local time.
So if you say okay the meetings at 9 then everyone assumes that the meeting is supposed to start at 9 but then everyone comes in at 9 but
grabs a cup of coffee, talks at the cooler, gets their seat, checks their email and then the meeting will start at 930 instead of 9.
Right or for example the transportation you will find in different countries can be punctual or not punctual.
In Germany their transportation is very famous for being punctual.
But in India you will find that the trains are not very punctual you might wait 1 or 2 or 6 hours.
Yeah yeah exactly.
So it's different in different countries I imagine that in a place like Germany it would be very.
It would be considered a very bad thing to arrive late to a meeting for example.
Yeah I'm curious about that so let us know is it acceptable in your country to be a little bit late to a meeting or to an appointment?
Is punctuality important?
Let us know our website is english.com.
All right we'll see you guys there.
Bye.
Thank you.