Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking a little bit about going to sleep or not being able to sleep.
That's right, we are having some sleeping problems and we're actually going to check out a couple of words related to this topic right now on vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview.
Okay, so the first word is actually the technical word that describes being unable to sleep.
It's called insomnia.
Right, so if you have insomnia, it means that you can't fall asleep. You can't sleep.
Okay, so this is a pretty serious condition. For example, if you have insomnia and you don't sleep with three or four nights,
you're not going to do very well at work, right?
Right, or if you're studying your tired at school, you can concentrate, so it's a very big problem.
What's that other word though? We haven't sammed the up, but we also have another interesting disorder.
Right, if somebody is able to sleep, but walks while they're sleeping, that person is called a sleep walker.
That's right, and you don't actually just have to walk to be a sleepwalker. You can do any number of strange things like
basically acting like you're awake when you're not. Exactly, so some people get up and walk
actually go outside, some people get dressed, some people have a go downstairs and cook.
Yeah, that's right, and the worst is the people who eat because they gain weight and they don't know why.
Exactly, so sleepwalking is what you do, and if you do this, you're called a sleepwalker.
Okay, sleepwalk is the verb sleepwalker is the noun or the person.
All right, so we've taken a look at two words that we're going to find in our dialogue today.
Why don't we go now and listen to the dialogue for the first time?
Alex, what's up with you? You look dreadful. Hey, Jill. I don't know.
I've been having trouble sleeping these past few weeks. I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get to sleep.
I've tried stretching in different breathing techniques before going to bed. I've tried eating
and nodding different foods. I've even tried counting sheep. And then when I finally get to sleep,
I have these really disturbing nightmares, so I usually wake up in a panic and more tired than before I went to sleep.
Wow, maybe you should get that checked out. Maybe you're stressed?
Just take some sedatives, works for me. Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when I have
trouble sleeping. It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders. It's the stuff pilots use to regular
their sleeping patterns. I heard of that, but does that apply to Alex's situation? Yeah, sure. Why not?
Sounds like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing, so taking melatonin should
do the trick. But shouldn't he be looking into why it's been happening? Well, aren't you the little
psychologist? Our buddy's having trouble sleeping. It's easy and curable. It's not something
freakish, like if he was a sleepwalker. Well, there's that too.
All right, we're back. So obviously this person not only has insomnia, but also has nightmares,
sleepwalks, a mess. That's right. And you can tell when someone hasn't been sleeping well. They have
that look like there's bags under their eyes or they just look really tired. And so the friend here
says Alex, you look dreadful. That's right, dreadful. So this is an adjective and it's a
weight of describe someone that looks terrible. You look horrible. You look tired. You look sleepy.
That's right. So this is not a compliment. This is something that you say when you're worried
about someone. So for example, so for example, if someone's really really tired, you say you look dreadful.
Or if someone is wearing very dirty clothes, they don't look like they went home yesterday.
What's wrong? You look dreadful. Right. I think you can also use it to describe objects or maybe
food, right? This lasagna is dreadful. It's very bad. And you don't want to say that to the person
who looked at it first. Exactly. All right. So the person obviously because it's suffering from
insomnia looks dreadful. And he was explaining what he does to try to fall asleep. For example,
counting sheep, stretching, and he also said that he tried different breathing techniques.
Okay. So basically a technique is an approach to something, a kind of method. But in this
case, we're talking about breathing techniques. So for some people, one breathing technique is
breathing in through your nose and breathing out through your mouth. Like that. That's one kind of
technique. So a technique, as you say, is a way of doing something. So breathing techniques are
different ways of breathing. So maybe you will relax. So maybe you'll fall asleep. Things like this.
Exactly. It's one of those things that you might learn about in a yoga class, for example,
there's different breathing techniques. Right. And you can combine techniques with other words,
as well, adding the ing for example, you have walking techniques, maybe to put less stress on your
knees or running techniques, swimming techniques. I think there's a technique for almost everything.
Just about anything you can do. There's a technique for it. Right. Yeah. Yeah. For sure. All right. And
well, moving on, he was talking about his nightmares. And he described his nightmares as disturbing.
He has disturbing nightmares. Okay. Well, I think this is an important word to cover here,
Marco, because we've heard the verb to disturb before. Like, I'm sorry to disturb you.
I mean, I'm sorry to bother you. But disturbing is an adjective. It describes something that
makes me very uncomfortable. Right. Right. So for example, a lot of times in the news, we see
very disturbing images, car accidents or fires or bombs. And what's disturbing is when you see
human beings who have been hurt. So images that make you really uncomfortable or sad, these are
disturbing. Exactly. So disturbing nightmares are nightmares that are not very pleasant. They
they make him scared, maybe, or uncomfortable. Right. Like a dream, for example, where your parents die.
It's pretty disturbing. Exactly. All right. And well, one of his friends recommended,
you know what? Stop with all of this. Just take some sedatives. Okay. So sedatives are kind of
medicine that help a person relax or that help make a person tired. Right. So I think it comes
from the verb to sedate. Yes. And basically that is to calm down to tranquilize. That's right. So
in this case, we're talking about a person, but you can also give an animal sedatives. For example,
if you want to take your dog on an airplane, the dog needs to relax. You give it some sedatives.
Exactly. And I think when he mentioned a specific name of a sedative, it's melatonin.
That's right. So melatonin, melatonin, is a chemical that our bodies naturally produce that
help calm us down. And so a lot of pharmaceutical companies or drug companies sell melatonin
in a pill form. It's basically it's a chemical that helps you relax. Exactly. So obviously,
if you take melatonin, you're going to feel sleepy or you're going to be very relaxed and you're
going to fall asleep a lot easier. Well, hopefully. Hopefully. That's right. So and well,
the whole thing that we've been talking about in some neonsleep walking, these are called sleeping
disorders. Right. Or you might also hear the term sleep disorders. They mean problems with sleeping.
So people who either cannot fall asleep or people who have bad dreams or people who sleep walk.
Exactly. So a disorder is something of an illness or a condition that is not normal. So
for example, as you said, a sleeping disorder or a sleep disorder, it means that you're not
able to sleep properly or normally. But there are other kinds of disorders, right? Right. I guess many
people have heard of eating disorders. Okay. So that's basically people who do not eat like everyone else.
Exactly. So that's what happens with a disorder. All right. So we've taken a look at a lot of
vocab. Now it's time for us to take a look at fluency builder. But before that, why don't we listen to
the dialogue again? Alex, what's up with you? You look dreadful. Hey, Jill. I don't know.
I've been having trouble sleeping these past few weeks. I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get
to sleep. I've tried stretching and different breathing techniques before going to bed. I've tried
eating and not eating different foods. I've even tried counting sheep. And then when I finally get to
sleep, I have these really disturbing nightmares. So I usually wake up in a panic and more tired
than before I went to sleep. Wow. Maybe you should get that checked out. Maybe you're stressed.
Just take some sedatives, works for me. Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when I have
trouble sleeping. It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders. It's the stuff pilots use to regular
their sleeping patterns. I heard of that. But does that apply to Alex's situation? Yeah, sure.
Why not? So Alex like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing. So taking
melatonin should do the trick. But shouldn't he be looking into why it's been happening?
Well, aren't you the little psychologist? Our buddies having trouble sleeping. It's easy and curable.
It's not something freakish like if he was a sleepwalker. Well, there's that too.
All right, we're back. So now we have three main phrases for fluency balder. Why don't we
start with the first one? Okay, so you heard in today's dialogue, an interesting phrase. I don't know
if it exists in other languages. But in English, we say when you're trying to fall asleep,
there's a good technique to help you do. So you count sheep. Yeah, I think you see it in cartoons
all the time. A person is sleeping and over that cartoon's head is a little cloud and you see sheep
jumping over a fence. So yeah, basically there's a fence and you say one, two, three, and the
process of counting helps relax a person. And then you fall asleep. Right. So counting sheep, I guess
you're not literally out in a field counting sheep. You're just imagining sheep in your head and
you're trying to fall asleep. That's right, counting sheep. All right. And well, one of his friends
recommended that maybe he should go to a doctor and Jill said that by saying maybe you should get
that checked out. Okay. So to get something checked out, to get it checked out, this means to have
a professional give you a suggestion or to have a professional look at something. Exactly. So maybe
you should get examined. Maybe you should go to the doctor. This isn't just about disorders,
right? I mean, what if I have a sore tooth? I could say this. Right. So if you have a tooth ache,
I would recommend, maybe you should get that checked out by my dentist. Right. Or maybe if you have
a bad rash, you know, your skin is very red. I say, Marco, I think you should get that checked out by a doctor.
Exactly. So to get something checked to get something examined by a doctor or a professional.
All right. And the last phrase that we have for you. So last phrase we have today comes from
a suggestion at the end. The friends suggest taking melatonin and he says, listen, taking melatonin
should do the trick. Right. So if you end a phrase by saying that should do the trick. Basically,
you're saying that should solve your problem. That should help you. Exactly. So the trick you
don't have to think about what the trick is. It's just a way of saying it should fix your problem.
So for example, when someone is fixing my car and they have one more thing to do and it's finished,
he says the calmer canic might say, that should do the trick. Right. That means problem solves.
Or maybe you're having you want to hang a picture on your wall. So somebody puts a nail in the wall
and that should do the trick and maybe that'll hold up the painting. Done. Done. Okay. So that's a
way of saying that should solve the problem. This should be the solution that should be all.
Okay. Okay. So why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time?
Alex, what's up with you? You look dreadful. Hey, Jill. I don't know. I've been having trouble
sleeping these past few weeks. I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get to sleep. I've tried
stretching in different breathing techniques before going to bed. I've tried eating and not eating
different foods. I've even tried counting sheep. And then when I finally get to sleep,
I have these really disturbing nightmares. So I usually wake up in a panic and more tired than
before I went to sleep. Wow. Maybe you should get that checked out. Maybe you're stressed.
Just take some sedatives, works for me. Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when
I have trouble sleeping. It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders. It's the stuff pilots use to
regular their sleeping patterns. I heard of that, but does that apply to Alex's situation? Yeah.
Sure. Why not? Sounds like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing. So taking
melatonin should do the trick. But shouldn't he be looking into why it's been happening?
Well, aren't you the little psychologist? Our buddy's having trouble sleeping. It's easy and
curable. It's not something freakish like if he was a sleepwalker. Well, there's that too.
Alright, we're back. So talking about dreaming nightmares and ssamnia all of this,
what do you do if you can't fall asleep? I don't really have this problem personally because
I could fall asleep anywhere any time. I've heard some people take like warm milk before going to sleep.
Yes, some people take milk. Although I also heard that dairy products before bed time
can make you have nightmares. I really do. Cheese before bed. I've heard that as well. I've heard
that if you have seafood before bed, you'll have nightmares as well. But actually, have you ever had a
dream when you are doing something and you wake up in the middle of that? Yes. I remember once I was
dreaming, I was drinking a soda. And all of a sudden I woke up and I had my hand in the air.
Like doing the action of me actually drinking the soda. Actually, sometimes this happens to me when
I'm falling asleep. I imagine I'm on a bike or something and I start to feel myself moving my leg.
And I wake up and I'm like, wait, wait, what am I doing? So the brain is very strange. I think,
especially in those times when you're kind of asleep and you're kind of awake. Also when you wake
up suddenly, I don't know if other people have experienced this, but you feel like you're falling or
something. Obviously, you just wake up and like with a shake. Yeah, your body moves. Yeah, it's really
scary. Your heart starts to beat. I don't know why that happens. It's unusual. Well, we're curious
to know what your sleep habits are. Do you have a hard time sleeping or are you like me? It's
very easy for you to fall asleep. Let us know on our website EnglishPod.com. All right, we'll see you
guys there. Bye.