Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson at English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and in the spirit of Halloween we have a Halloween lesson for you.
Happy Halloween.
It's Halloween.
This is an elementary level lesson so we're talking about some basic but important things today.
Exactly so we're not going to preview anything because the dialogue is pretty simple.
So why don't we listen to it for the first time and we'll be right back.
Trick or treat Tom, on your little two old-speed trick or treating.
What are you talking about?
Where's your Halloween spirit?
Didn't you ever dress up in a costume and go around the neighborhood trick or treating with your friends?
Of course I did but when I was 10 trick or treating is for kids.
It's plus I'm sure people will think you're a kidnap or something running around with kids at night.
Whatever.
I'm going next door.
I heard Mrs. Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
Alright we're back so trick or treating.
Ding dong.
Trick or treat.
Alright so we're going to explain what trick or treating is.
Just in a little bit but before we get into it why don't we take a look at four important words in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Well the first one that Marco is very important because it's the name of this special holiday that isn't celebrated everywhere.
It's only celebrated in some places and Americans I think love it above all.
Right yeah Halloween.
Now it just actually comes from all halos Eve right?
That's right so it's the night of the spirits of the dead.
Alright exactly so the day of the dead and as Catherine mentions it celebrated in different ways in different countries but I think probably the United States is one of the few that where people dress up and go trick or treating.
That's right.
And Halloween is the last day of October so October 31st and it's a really fun holiday where mostly children dress up in cost of being in the same place.
And costumes and they ask for candy.
Alright so to dress up means to get in the costume.
Alright well you could say dress up to mean a couple of different things but in this case you dress up in a costume.
So that means you you change your clothes so that you're wearing a costume which is maybe a witch's costume or vampire or something scary.
So you would say he dressed up as a vampire.
He dressed up as a vampire or they got dressed up for the for the wedding.
Okay very good. So dress up and then we have the word kidnapper.
So the friend is afraid that his friend will look like a kidnapper if he goes out trick or treating with the kids.
Right and so a kidnapper comes from the word to take or to grab.
So a kidnapper and that means that you're going to take children from the streets and steal them.
Right but you can kidnap an adult right so it's not only for kids.
That's right it's for any kind of person who you take without them wanting you to.
So against their will.
Okay kidnap her.
And finally we have Eminem's.
What are Eminem's?
Nothing in the right.
No Eminem is spelled differently the singer.
So delicious chocolate treat it's a candy and it comes in big brown bags and if you want them with peanuts they come in a yellow bag.
And you know your Eminem.
Oh man I could tell you all the colors but Eminem's are really delicious and it's actually a brand.
It's a brand right so many people probably know it but just in case they're called Eminem's very good candy.
All right so these words were relatively easy and simple so why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
Let's slow it down just a little bit and we'll be right back to take a look at fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right we're back so on fluency builder we promised that we were going to look at this word trick or treating so let's look at it now trick or treat.
It's a verb right to trick or treat.
And it comes from the words that we say when we're children to the person who's door we knock on so for example I say.
And then I open the door.
I say trick or treat.
Okay so what are you supposed to do in this when somebody says trick or treat?
Well I'm a child I'm holding my bag and you're supposed to say happy Halloween and give me some candy.
Okay.
All right so trick or treat means you could either trick someone.
You could play a trick on them like scare them or put some toilet paper on their house or you can give them a treat.
Uh-huh.
Or accept a treat and so the idea is if you don't give me a treat I will do something bad to you.
I see but this isn't really happened right like when kids go to people's houses they say trick or treat and then they get candy automatically.
Almost automatically yeah sometimes people avoid the holiday and they they close their doors and lock them and they don't answer the door.
Yeah and that's when someone maybe throws an egg at the house or put a toilet paper on their treat.
Yeah.
Yeah so trick or treat is what we say but it's also something we can do so we can go trick or treating.
Go trick or treating.
Right.
Okay.
Very good trick or treat and now we have another phrase here that's a little bit complicated but when the friend answered the door he said,
Aren't you a little too old to be trick or treating?
All right.
I like this phrase because it's sarcastic.
The person is not asking a real question he's saying listen you are too old to be trick or treating and so in this case aren't you?
Mm-hmm.
Is a way to introduce something that we know is true that we think is true.
It's kind of rude and sarcastic.
So if I say aren't you supposed to be at work?
Oh right.
So it's in that form.
Not really asking the question you're more demanding an explanation.
Right.
It's a suggestion.
It's like you're probably supposed to be at work right now.
Right.
So Marco aren't you supposed to be at school right now?
So do we always but we always use it in that sense right aren't you and then?
Yeah aren't you?
Aren't you a little old for that kind of an outfit?
Right.
So aren't you?
Very good.
So those are the two phrases for fluency builder today.
Let's listen quickly to our dialogue one more time and we'll be right back.
Trick or treat Tom, on your little two old to be trick or treating.
What are you talking about?
Where's your Halloween spirit?
Didn't you ever dress up in a costume and go around the neighborhood trick or treating with your friends?
Of course I did.
When I was 10, trick or treating is for kids.
Plus I'm sure people would think you're a kidnap or something running around with kids at night.
Whatever.
I'm going next door.
I heard Mrs. Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
I had so Marco have you ever trick or treat it?
I did.
I used to go trick or treating when I was little and it was actually really fun.
We used to have competitions about who had the most candy.
I've heard about this.
Right because you don't necessarily bring a bag.
You bring a pillowcase.
Right.
And you fill your pillowcase with candy.
Now the interesting thing is that sometimes you wouldn't necessarily only get candy from people.
Right.
Sometimes you got weird things like pennies or toothbrushes or apples.
Yeah.
So you would go to someone's house and they would give you an apple you'd be like, okay.
But there was always an old lady who lived near well she lived in the neighborhood and every neighborhood had had one.
You know, all my friends had a lady they would go to and she gave the full size candy bars.
Wow.
Right.
Because normally stores sell small candy bars for the Halloween holiday because they're smaller.
They're cheaper.
It's easier to give them to many people.
But there's always one person who has the big full size candy bars and everyone goes to her.
Right.
Exactly.
And actually it's amazing how Halloween is such an important event in the states because everyone dresses up.
Everyone puts out decorations or pumpkins outside of their homes.
They have pumpkin carving contest which are really cool how they carve out pumpkins.
They make faces in the pumpkins and then we can put a candle inside and light it up.
That's really fun.
So that's called a jackal lantern, right?
That's right.
Why is it called a jackal lantern?
You know?
It's like a jack like a person looks like a person's name.
Maybe a jack.
Because a lantern is a light.
You know, it's like a light with a candle in it.
It's actually very fun holiday.
It's really interesting.
It's kind of strange when people really oppose it because they say that it's, you know,
it has to do with the devil or it has to do.
It's a pagan ritual and things like this.
It's just good fun.
It's silly.
Everyone likes to dress up in a costume.
So it was the weirdest costume that you've dressed up as as an adult or a child.
Because I know you've dressed up as an adult as well.
I dress up every year.
I was happy.
Well, as a child, one year, I dressed up as an injured soldier.
Because like my dad was in the military.
So we always had fatigues around the house.
So I used his fatigues and I put blood on my face and I had crutches.
And people thought that I really had a broken leg.
So they used to give me double.
They gave me that year.
They gave me double the candy because I thought, oh, here's a poor grown crutches.
And a trick or treat.
And my costume was an injured soldier.
So they didn't understand it.
It's really funny.
Nice.
Well, we want to hear about you guys.
If you go trick or treating or if you dress up for Halloween,
I know that many places around the world have parties or festivities for Halloween.
And people dress up.
So come to our website EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there.
And we'll see you guys next time.
Happy Halloween.