Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we have
a very fun lesson for you today. That's right. We're going to talk about toys. So we're going
to actually take a look at a lot of different types of toys and we're going to be listening
to a couple of commercials. That's right. So we've got two children who are watching TV and
they're listening to a number of different commercials. So we're going to learn about some
of these very popular products in a moment. Let's first listen to our dialogue.
Switch Bob Square fans will be right back after these brief messages. Once that on the horizon,
the pirate ship, rape villages and fight very treasure with these new pirates'
Lego set. Build the ship and decide who rules to see.
Ah, cool.
The new Play Doe sparkling brights precious gem press. Make large colorful gems for you and your
friends with five special molds. Comes with a new sparkling brights play Doe
compound in four new colors. Treasure chest salt separately. Wow, mommy. Can I get them
for my birthday?
I'm Jean Gray. And Professor X. Collect all four of these special edition collectable
X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world. No way. I want
Professor X. The new collector's edition nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls. Little Bob
Abe comes with their own shape and staff. Her clothes are made with the finest fabrics
in real Italian lace. And her face has been hand painted by our finest artists. Only $199.
Oh, she's pretty. I've never had a porcelain doll before. I don't mom and dad will get you
that for your birthday. She costs a pretty penny. Plus, you'd most likely break her.
That's ingenious. Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now you can take sponge Bob Square pants wherever you go with a new sponge Bob Square
in the dark and you'll go back to our show.
All right, we're back. So a lot of great toys. And actually it's very popular that
maybe you're watching cartoons. You get a lot of these commercials that are selling you
all types of toys. Absolutely, because normally children watch cartoons and children like toys.
Exactly. So why don't we take a look at six keywords that we have for you on language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay, Marco. So what's the first word we're looking at here today?
All right, we have actually a brand, a very famous type of toy. They're called Legos.
Legos. So Legos. Legos. Legos are basically little pieces that you put together to build
things. Yeah, they're like little blocks. Okay. So when you see them, they don't look like anything.
But as a child, you get to create anything you want. Mm-hmm. So Legos have become very
famous. They have like special types that you can recreate maybe a spaceship from Star Wars,
a pirate ship, a lot of different types now. Okay. So the one in today's commercial is Pirate
Legos. So they're building a pirate ship. Exactly. Legos. All right. And the next toy that we have
is also a proper noun. It's a brand and it's called Play Do. Play Do. Okay. So Play, like playing with
something playing basketball. But Play Do is it's like Play, right? It's like Play. But it's made out of
flower, I think, and you can shape it into anything you want. So when I was little, I used to make
Play Do animals. You know, you could you could make a ball and you make another ball and then
all of a sudden you have a cow. Right. So it's a very soft texture type of a material that
you can mold. You can give it different shapes. And that's what we call Play Do. And obviously,
as you say, it's safe for children. I think it's made out of a head of some flower, salt and flower.
And I think a lot of children sometimes eat this. So it's pretty safe for kids. Right. So yeah,
that's Play Do. It's a proper noun. And I guess everyone just calls it Play Do. So this is the toy
that we're talking about. Now moving on, we are talking about the X-Men Wolverine Gen Grey,
Rogue, Professor X, and all of these come in little statues that we call action figures.
All right. So what you're talking about here are obviously the X-Men Markov. And X-Men, there are
many different kinds of X-Men you have, like you said Wolverine, who's maybe one of the most
famous and Rogue. But when you collect these little statues, these little dolls, they're called
action figures. So figure is like a kind of doll. Right. So at the X-Men is just an example. You have
action figures of all sorts of cartoons or movies. Star Wars action figures are very popular.
Right. Or GI Joe action figures are very popular as well. That's right. So they're little
toys that choose it. Children play with. All right. Moving on now we have an adjective
a way to describe the X-Men. That's right. So the X-Men, as you know, are not normal people.
They have special powers. Some X-Men can fly. Wolverine has animal abilities. He can use his
long claws. So these are newtints. That means that they were humans, but something changed in them.
And it makes them have these special powers. Okay. So a mutant is maybe a person that has special powers,
like, like, as you say Wolverine and all these types of X-Men. But I guess to,
taken maybe a look at the verb mutate, that means to change, to change, right? Okay. So to mutate
is to change. So we could say, I found a frog that had three legs. Okay. So it clearly mutated.
Because normally frogs have, like, four legs. Exactly. You see that sometimes with chickens that
maybe have two heads or something like this. These are mutants. Okay. They have mutated. Okay.
Very good. And now moving on to our dolls, they were talking about these beautiful,
porcelain dolls. Okay. So let's talk about porcelain because I think everyone knows what a doll is,
but porcelain is a special kind of doll, right? Right. It's a material. And usually you can find
this material very commonly in your plates. All right. So it's not clear. It's not glass. No.
It's colored. It's normally whitish. Mm-hmm. And very, very fine. Very pretty. Mm-hmm.
So you call it porcelain. I guess it's a type of ceramic, right? That's right. Okay. So yeah,
you have porcelain dolls. Many people also have very fine china that you call it, like dinner plates.
Or tikka or tikka and those are usually made of porcelain. Mm-hmm. All right. And finally,
they were talking about a game that has three games in one and one of the kids said, wow,
that's ingenious. In genius. This is a great word. Makes you sound really fluent. So ingenious
basically means clever. Right. It's a really good idea. It's very clever, a good idea. Yeah.
Mm-hmm. So if something is ingenious, it's just, wow. It's very creative. For example,
I have a pair of gloves, but on the fingers, sometimes I can pull a cover over them and they turn
into mittens. All right. I think it's ingenious. Yeah, because I have gloves and mittens all the time.
All right. So a lot of interesting words there, a lot of specific toys and particularly brands
that you may or may not know. But why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again and we'll
be back with fluency builder. Splendid Bob Squarepants will be right back after these brief messages.
What's that on the horizon? A pirate ship, raid villages and find buried treasure with these new
pirates' Lego set. Build the ship and decide who rules to see. Ah, cool. The new Play Doh
sparkling brights precious gem press. Make large colorful gems for you and your friends with five
special molds. Comes with the new sparkling brights Play Doh compound in four new colors.
Treasure chest sold separately. Wow, mommy. Can I get that for my birthday? Wolverine,
Jean Grey, Rogue and Professor X. Collect all four of these special edition collectible
X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world. No way. I want Professor X.
The new collector's edition nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls. Little Bob Peep comes with their own
sheep and staff. Her clothes are made with the finest fabrics and real Italian lace and her
face has been hand painted by our finest artists. Only $199 dollars. Oh, she's pretty. I've never
had a porcelain doll before. I don't mom and dad will get you that for your birthday. She costs
a pretty penny. Plus, you'd most likely break her. What is better than a board? What is better
than one board game? Three board games in one. Enjoy playing chess and checkers on this side of the
board. But if you're looking for some more fun, flip it and play the classic game of Sari.
Fetch ingenious. Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now you can take SpongeBob Squarepants wherever you go with the new SpongeBob Squarepants
Glowing the Dark Yoyo. And now, back to our show.
Okay, so the first phrase here in Fluency Builders is a really important one for anyone who's
buying anything because you often see this phrase on packages or you hear it in commercials.
Right. As you saw in the Play Do commercial, the guy said, treasure chest sold separately.
Okay, sold separately. That means the treasure chest is not included. You have to buy it extra.
As you say, usually see it in packaging as well, maybe you buy a toy car. And at the bottom,
it will say, battery sold separately. That means there are no batteries in the box. You have to buy
batteries extra. Exactly. So that's what the phrase sold separately means. It indicates that
you it's not included in the product that you are buying. Mm-hmm. All right. Now moving on
again to the action figures and the dolls. We saw this very interesting way of describing them.
For example, the action figures said special edition collectible X-Men action figures.
Okay, special edition. This is really important. And it's very common, I think, with
with special toys or action figures or even baseball cards. Special edition means that they're
produced specially on one occasion at one time. They're not always produced. Right. So for example,
if you have, like you say baseball cards or maybe action figures, they're produced normally,
but then limited amounts, a special type of the same action figure will be produced. So that's a
special edition or also commonly known as a collector's edition. All right. So some people collect
stamps, you know, stamps for letters that you send. And I know many countries like America
offer special edition or collectors edition stamps. These are produced once and usually they mark
a special occasion. Like the Olympics in 1996, we had special edition stamps. Right. So these
special edition objects are usually not used. They're for collectors. Like the namesets,
right, collectors edition. Right. So you plan to sell them later on or you collect them for yourself.
They're not normal. Right. They usually go up in value because they're very limited. That's right.
Okay. So collectors edition, special edition. And now when they were talking about the
porcelain dolls as well, it's pretty expensive, right, almost $200. That's a really expensive doll.
And so one of the kids said, you know what? I think a mom and dad won't buy you that because
it costs a pretty penny. A pretty penny. This does not mean that the penny is beautiful.
Right. A penny is a one cent coin in the United States. That means it's very, very low in value.
The coin. But a pretty penny is actually the opposite. It means it's very expensive.
So what would, how would you use this in another, in another example? I've always wanted to buy a
Ferrari, but man, Ferrari's cost a pretty penny. Okay. So you have to add the word cost before you say
pretty penny, right? That's right. You can't say it is a pretty penny. You have to say it costs a pretty
penny or it's worth a pretty penny. Exactly. It's worth a pretty penny. Okay. Very good. And for our last phrase.
I think this one is a very good phrase because it describes a lot of different toys that glow in the
dark. Glowing the dark toys. Okay. So something that glows in the dark, the verb here is too glow.
Means that it can be seen even when it's dark. Right. So for example, when I turn the lights off
and I can see this yoyo in my room, that means it's glow in the dark. It has light even in the
dark. Right. So there are a lot of different toys and things like this usually glow in the dark
toys. They have a green glow. Right. They look green in the dark. I used to have stars. So they were
stickers, stars, stickers, and I put them on my ceiling so that when I was in bed, I could look at them
and they were glow in the dark. So when the lights were off, I still had stars. You can see them, right?
So yeah, glow in the dark. It's a way of describing an item, an object that you are able to see in the
dark. All right. So that's all we have for you on language. All right. So that's all we have for you on
Fluency Builder. When we go back, listen to the dialogue one last time. Have a look back to talk some more.
A pirate ship, rape villages, and fight very treasure with these new pirates Lego set.
Build the ship and decide who rules to see.
Ah. Cool. The new Play Do, sparkling brights, precious gem breath, make large colorful gems for
you and your friends with five special molds. Comes with the new sparkling brights, play
do, compound in four new colors. Treasure chest salt separately. Wow, mommy, take it down for
my birthday. Hey, gee, great. And Professor X. Collect all four of these special edition
collectable X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world.
No way. I want Professor X. The new collector's edition nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls.
Little Bobbabe comes with their own shape and staff. Her clothes are made with the finest fabrics
and real Italian lace. And her face has been hand painted by our finest artists. Only $199.
Oh, she's pretty. I've never had a porcelain doll before. I doubt mom and dad will get you that
for your birthday. She costs a pretty penny. Plus, you'd most likely break her.
One is better than a board. One is better than one board game. Three board games in one.
Enjoy playing Justin Chekker's on this side of the board. What if you looking for some more fun
to put it in place in classic game of sorry? That's ingenious. Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now you can take a sponge Bobb square pants wherever you go with a new sponge Bobb square pants
below into Narnillo. And now, back to our show.
All right, so talking about toys, these are really interesting toys. Are there any specific toys
that you had when you were growing up or that you really, really liked? I had an amazing
bro train set. This is when I was young and a train set is basically like, like,
it was with trains. So you build a track and you push the train around the track. And so I used to
have a track that was as big as the living room. And my my challenge, my goal was to use
every single piece. She's very hard because some pieces don't fit with other pieces. And so
that was my favorite toy because I got to be very creative. And then you would turn on the train
I would go away. It wasn't electric. I wasn't. I had to push it myself. What was your favorite toy?
Actually, when I was growing up I used to collect little toy cars. I had a lot of
I used to have a lot of little toy cars and I even had a little special, I don't know, like, a box
for them when you can, so I could see them. And then as time went on, I got to collect the scale
cars, you know, the ones that are one to ten, one to four. Did you build them or did you buy them
made? No, usually I bought them made. I actually tried the whole building model cars,
model airplanes, but it's so hard. Very hard. Even adults have a hard time. It's not very difficult.
So I don't know what type of kid actually does that when they're growing up. But yeah, so many toys
out there, so many people collect them, play with them. You have childhood toys that you're very fond of.
So that's what we want to know. What type of toy did you grow up with? What did you like to play with
when you were a kid? Or if you have kids, what toys do your kids like? Because we're not too familiar
with toys these days. We'd be curious to hear about those. That's right. So we want to hear from you
come to EnglishPod.com and we'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.