Hello English learners. Welcome back to another sports lesson with us here at English
Pod. My name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we're going to be talking about a very
interesting and very difficult game to play and it's golf. So we've got some golf vocabulary
for you in this lesson. And I think we better actually look at a few vocabulary words in vocabulary
preview before we start with the dialogue. Very vocabulary preview.
On vocabulary preview today we have three words and the first one is a
ficionado.
Aficionado.
A golf, aficionado.
Alright so this basically is a very fancy word of. There's a very fancy way of saying
a fan.
Yes, someone who likes something a lot.
Okay so you are an efficient, I like golf.
Yeah you can also be in a wine efficientado.
Okay so it's kind of like a hobby.
Yeah you know a lot about it and you like it.
And now our second word is not anywhere in the dialogue.
No but we're going to use it when we explain some of these words so you need to know
it.
Okay the word is club.
Club.
A golf club.
Okay so a golf club is the tool you use to hit the golf ball.
Right so it's a long tube basically that looks like a j kind of.
Yeah so and you hit the ball with it.
So that's a golf club.
And now our third word is golf course.
Golf course.
A golf course.
A course.
So this is the area where you play golf.
Yeah it's the like the golf field.
Exactly.
So it's a very big green area where you play golf.
So those are the three words we have for vocabulary preview.
So now we could listen to our dialogue for the first time as we listen to our sports
announcers Rick Fields and Bob Copeland and see what happens on this occasion.
Good morning golf official not owes my name is Rick Fields and you guessed it.
I'm here with my main man Bob Copeland.
Thank you Rick as you can see ladies and gentlemen.
We are here in beautiful pebble beach with a top golf within the world of wine to win the
grand prize of one million dollars.
Whoa that's a lot of cash.
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
All right we're here at the eight hall.
It's a par fourth and has some very difficult hazards which many golfers find difficult
to avoid.
Although I did see Jack Nicolae's hit a hole on this very same hole.
Tiger Woods is about to off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger is asking his caddy for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Oh no not a good swing at all.
It's definitely not his day today.
On the seventh hole he got a bogey and before that he barely made part.
He will definitely not get a birdie on this short.
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep into the trees.
He's having a hard time finding it and even his caddy is claimed to treat to try and
spot it.
Oh no.
I bet.
Run, tell you, run.
Somebody go out of control.
So a pretty exciting ending to that dialogue there.
A bear on the golf course.
Yeah I wonder if Tiger is okay.
I sure hope so because it would be a huge loss to the world of golf.
Right so we did learn a lot about golf because they used some very specific and technical
words for golf.
So let's look at these now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright so the announcers were talking about the game and they were talking about the
course and they were here on the eighth hole and they said that last time Jack Nickelowski
hit a hole in one.
Hole in one.
A hole in one.
Okay a hole in one.
So this is when you hit the ball once and the ball goes in the hole.
Exactly.
So it's something very difficult to do.
Yes.
Right a hole in one.
I've certainly never made one.
Okay so sometimes it's also called an ace.
So it can be a hole in one or called an ace.
Ah okay.
Now for our second word, now once we get to the hole to the ninth hole or the tenth
hole, we have to tee off.
T off.
So when you tee off, you begin playing.
Right so it's the very first instance where you put the little ball on the tee.
And you hit the ball for the first time.
Exactly.
So to tee off.
Now another golf vocabulary, they were talking about a caddy.
Right a caddy.
A caddy.
Now a caddy is a person.
Yes it's the person who carries your golf clubs.
Exactly.
So he carries your bag, your golf clubs and basically helps you while you're playing golf.
Yeah he tells you which way you should hit the ball and maybe you know it gives you
an ice-cold drink and it looks after you.
Very good.
So that's a caddy.
And now the caddy since he has to carry all the golf clubs, Tiger Woods asked him
for his driver.
A driver.
Now a driver is a type of golf club.
Right it's not a person.
No no.
It's a type of golf club and it's a very big and heavy golf club that is used to tee off.
So it's used to hit the ball a very long way.
Yes.
That is called the driver.
Okay so in the next thing they were talking about were some different types of scores
that you could get on a hole.
And the first one they mentioned was PAR.
Okay so you can make PAR.
Okay or the PAR of the course can be for.
Okay very good.
So basically the PAR is the maximum number of swings or strokes you can make before putting
the ball into the hole.
Right so it's like it's like the right.
So when the when the when a hole is PAR for you should only hit the ball four times.
Four times or less.
Yeah.
Very good.
If you don't make PAR there are some options.
You can make a bogey.
All right a bogey.
A bogey.
Now sometimes the golf course is very difficult.
Yeah.
So instead of putting the ball in the hole let's say in four turns.
You do it in five.
Okay so it's one over PAR.
One over PAR.
So that's bad.
Yeah that's bad because you get a point.
So it's kind of strange because in golf the more points you have.
The worse you are.
So that is a bogey.
Now they also talked about a birdie.
Birdie is the opposite if you hit one under PAR.
So that's good.
Yeah that's good because you have minus one one less than PAR.
All right so this is actually a lot of weird crazy strange language birdie bogey,
catty driver.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue one more time to help us understand.
Good morning golf official notos.
My name is Rick Fields and you guessed it.
I'm here with my main man Bob Copeland.
Thank you Rick.
As you can see ladies and gentlemen we are here in beautiful pebble beach where the top golf
is in the world of vying to win the grand prize of one million dollars.
Whoa that's a lot of cash.
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
All right we're here at the eight hole.
It's a par four and has some very difficult houses which many golfers find difficult to
avoid.
Although I did see Jack Nicholoss hit a hole in one on this very same hole.
Tiger Woods is about to tear off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger is asking his catty for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Oh no not a good swing at all.
It is definitely not his day today.
On the seventh hole he got a bogey and before that he barely made par.
He'll definitely not get a birdie on this shot.
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep in the trees.
He is having a hard time finding it and even his catty has climbed the tree to try and
spot it.
Oh no!
A bear!
Run Tiger!
Run!
Oh I don't look at Ro!
All right great so I think it's clear now what type of rules they have in golf and
how it works.
So why don't we take a look now at some of the phrases that we heard in the dialogue
in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Okay well one of the phrases I want to talk about is something that Bob Copeland said.
He said as you can see ladies and gentlemen we're here at beautiful Pable Beach.
Okay as you can see.
As you can see so this usually goes in the beginning of a sentence.
Yeah it's a way to say I know you can see this.
I'm telling you something you know.
Okay so maybe I'm showing you my house and I can say as you can see our living room is
very spacious.
Yes so this is actually a really helpful phrase.
It can help you sound really native like so why don't we hear some examples of how
it's used.
As you can see we recently remodeled our entire kitchen.
Example two.
As you can see here the damage to the building is very serious.
Example three.
As you can see the hair stylist made him steak when cutting my hair.
All right great so as you can see now for our second phrase we'll take a look at the
wood wasn't doing very well and the announcer said it's not his day.
It's not his day.
It's not his day today.
All right so when it's not your day you're having a bad time or a bad day.
Right maybe you're having difficulties or you're having bad luck that day.
Yeah so for example today I had a headache and I ripped my pants and I spilled coffee
on myself so it really wasn't my day.
Okay it's not your day today.
No great phrase and also very common and it makes you sound very native.
That's right.
Now the last phrase similar to it's not your day we also heard that tiger was having
a hard time.
Okay to have a hard time.
To have a hard time.
Now if you have a hard time with something you have difficulty with it.
Okay now it's not only related to golf right of course you can talk about anything
like this so I'm having a hard time understanding what this word means.
Okay or when I was in school I had a hard time with math.
All right me too.
So to have a hard time means that you have difficulties with something.
So great phrases great words and let's listen to this dialogue for the last time and then
we'll come back and talk a little bit more about golf.
Good morning golf official not owes my name is Rick Fields and you guessed it I'm here
with my main man Bob Copeland.
Thank you Rick as you can see ladies and gentlemen we are here in beautiful pebble beach
where the top golf is in the world of wine to win the grand prize of one million dollars.
Whoa that's a lot of cash.
Let's go to the course and see how Tiger Woods is doing.
All right we're here at the eight hall it's a path for and has some very difficult hazards
which many golfers find difficult to avoid although I did see Jack and Clouse hit a
hole of one on this very same hole.
Tiger Woods is about to see off and let's see if he has the same luck as Jack.
Tiger is asking his caddy for his driver and he seems to be very nervous.
Oh no not a good swing at all it's definitely not his day today on the seventh
hole he got a bogey and before that he barely made part he will definitely not get a
birdy on this shot.
It seems that his ball has flown somewhere deep into the trees he's having a hard time
finding it and even his caddy is climbing to treat to try and spot it.
Oh no okay run Tiger run somebody call out him control.
All right so Marco I know that in the western business world golf is actually super important
for your career isn't it?
Well many times you know when you see in movies or the stereo type is that business is
done on a golf course.
Yeah and yeah it is true many times you know people will invite you
out to a golf course and you'll be playing a game and you know talking business and relaxing
at the same time.
So maybe you negotiate a deep ideal out on the golf course.
Exactly and of course if you lose it's a good thing because then the deal will pull through.
Uh-huh okay well actually I know that is so important for people who are wanting to do
well in business and many people who don't speak English as their first language take golf
English lessons.
Right so not only golf lessons like how to play golf but also in English.
Like how to talk about golf how to you know talk to other people and make deals while you're
on the golf course.
Yeah because like in many other sports golf has also it's slaying and it's terms and stuff.
So yeah it's very interesting and it's one of those cultural things.
That's right so if you have any questions or comments about today's lesson why don't you
visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
Right we're always there to answer any questions or doubts you might have and until next time
we'll see you there.
Bye.