Hello English learners! Welcome back to EnglishPod! My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're bringing you another lesson on our sport series.
We're talking about baseball today.
Baseball the American National Pastime.
Is it?
Yes it is.
Okay.
So we're going to be looking at this interesting sport that is played mainly in the Caribbean
and well it's actually very popular in the United States and Japan.
That's right.
Korea.
Yep.
So we're not only going to learn a bunch of baseball language, but we're also going to see
how baseball has a big influence on English in general.
That's right.
So we're going to learn a lot of great things today.
So why don't we start and listen to our dialogue.
Hello baseball fans and welcome back to today's game.
My name is Rick Fields and of course I am here once again with a man that seals the
deal Bob Copeland.
It's a beautiful day to see two world-class teams face each other and fight for their
right to be called champions.
Well the National Anthem has just been sung and the Empire has started the game.
It's time to play ball.
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
Picture winds up and strike one very nice curve ball by the pitcher.
The catcher gives him the sign.
He winds up and Vargas gets a line drive.
The players are scrambling to get the ball.
Vargas gets to first base and he's still doing it.
The outfielder throws it to second.
Vargas slides.
He's safe.
Great play.
We have a runner on third and.
But that is Brian O'Cummy.
There's the pitch.
He hits it.
It's going.
That ball is gone.
Home run by O'Cummy.
That puts this team ahead by two as we are at the bottom of the fifties.
Here at Richie Stadium.
Alright well a pretty exciting game there at Richie Stadium.
Exactly.
We have some interesting players.
Roger Vargas and Brian O'Cummy.
Alright so we saw some great words.
Well it's time for us to take a look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay we're going to look at some common sports and baseball words here.
The first phrase we'll hear this almost at any sort of international sports event.
Exactly.
And it's the national anthem.
National anthem.
So this is a song right?
Exactly.
It's the song that you sing about your country and many people confuse it right?
Yeah a lot of people might say national hymn.
Okay hymn because in some languages it might be like a hymn.
Like literally translating.
Yeah but in English it's called the national anthem.
The national anthem.
Alright so what about our next word?
How we were talking about the picture.
Picture.
P-I-T-C-H-E-R.
The picture.
Picture.
Okay and now this is one of the players on the baseball team and his job is to throw the ball
to throw the ball really fast so that the guy can hit it with the bat.
Okay so that's the picture.
Now the interesting thing is that the baseball commentator said the picture winds up.
To wind up.
Okay well let me paint you a picture.
Okay.
So imagine a clock.
Uh-huh.
And you're turning, turning and turning the clock to wind up to get it ready to go.
To make it work.
Exactly.
So imagine the picture doing the same sort of thing.
Bringing his arm back behind him getting ready to throw the ball.
Okay so that is to wind up.
Hmm.
Very good.
So you can use this word not only in baseball but for other things that require you
to do this section.
Right to turn something and get it ready to have lots of power.
Like some toy or maybe like a music box.
Okay.
Wind up.
What about our next phrase?
Well Roger Vargas hit a line drive.
Line drive.
Okay so what is a line drive?
What's a term from baseball and when you hit a line drive you hit the ball sort of
low on towards the ground and it travels along the outside of the field.
Right so the ball basically travels along the foul line.
That white line.
The white line.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Very good.
So that's a line drive.
And so the players on the field were scrambling to get the ball scrambling.
Scrambleing.
Now we know scrambled eggs from one of our lessons.
Yes.
But the verb two scramble means two move quickly in a disorder going to be a
organized way to do something.
Okay so the players are moving very fast trying to get the ball but they're not doing
it very well.
Right.
And you can use this in other ways, right?
Not just in baseball.
Right.
For example we can say the people are scrambling to buy their tickets for the concert.
Yeah.
Or I'm going on vacation tomorrow and I'm scrambling to get everything ready.
Exactly.
It's a very good term that you can use also in your daily life.
Alright.
And what about our last word for today on language takeaway?
Well they were in the fifth inning of the game.
Okay.
So inning inning.
Alright.
This is another baseball term and it just means the period of play.
Okay.
So we learn for example that in soccer you have two halves or in hockey you have three
periods.
Alright.
And in baseball you have nine innings.
Okay.
Great.
So some interesting sports and baseball vocabulary.
Now I think it will help us to hear this again slower.
So let's listen to the dialogue.
Hello baseball fans and welcome back to today's game.
My name is Rick Fields and of course I am here once again with the man that seals the
deal Bob Copeland.
It's a beautiful day to see two world class teams face each other and fight for their
right to be called champions.
Well the national anthem has just been sung and the Empire has started the game.
It's time to play ball.
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
The pitcher winds up and strike one.
A very nice curve ball by the pitcher.
The catcher gives him the sign.
He winds up.
And Vargas gets a line drive.
The players are scrambling to get the ball.
Vargas gets to first base and he's still going.
The outfielder throws it to second.
Vargas slides.
He's safe.
Great play.
We have a runner on third and up at bat is Brian O'Kami.
There's the pitch.
He hits it.
It's going.
Going.
That ball is gone.
Home run by O'Kami.
That puts this team ahead by two.
As we are at the bottom of the fifth inning here at Richie Stadium.
Alright so as we said there are a lot of English terms that come from baseball but we
use them in business context during your daily life right?
Yeah why don't we look at those now and fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
Alright so the first phrase that we have is up to bat.
Up to bat.
So literally in this dialogue it means the guy is standing on home plate ready to hit
the ball right?
He has the bat and he's ready to hit it.
But what about in other contexts?
So for example you can be at a meeting and maybe it's your turn to talk.
So you're up to bat.
So the exactly your boss will say okay Erica you're up to bat.
Okay so it means sort of like it's your turn.
It's your turn.
Yeah very good.
Alright so that's another term that is using baseball.
Very commonly used in other circumstances.
So we also saw in the dialogue that Roger Vegas he hit the ball but he missed and that
was strike one.
Right strike one.
So in baseball you have three strikes.
Three tries.
Three tries before you're out.
Yes and so now the same thing happens in daily life.
So if someone says that was strike one.
It means you made the first mistake.
Yes and if you make two more you will be fired for example.
Yeah or maybe your parents will say okay that wasn't nice strike one.
And then two more times and you'll have a timeout.
Oh you'll be grounded.
Yes.
Okay so that's also called a strike and the picture through a curve ball.
A curve ball.
So okay pretty clear a curve ball is when you throw the ball and it sort of goes in
a curve it doesn't go straight right?
Right exactly.
But how can this be used outside of baseball?
So you can say oh my boss threw me a curve ball today.
So he gave you an unexpected problem or something that was difficult to handle.
Okay this one is pretty interesting.
I'd like to hear a few more examples.
Example one.
My boss threw me a curve ball today so I have to stay and work late.
Example two.
It was a huge curve ball when she asked me how many kids I wanted to have.
Oh my I suppose to know.
Alright so that's basically a curve ball you can say an unexpected problem in the situation.
That's right and our last phrase and we'll probably one that's you already know home
run.
A home run.
From baseball we know that that's when you hit the ball really far and you hit it
outside of the of the playing area outside the park.
Yes and now if you use it in a business context or in your daily life.
It means something similar why don't we take a listen to the examples and see if we can
figure it out.
Example one.
Great job on that sales presentation.
You really hit a home run.
Example two.
Our sales team hit a home run this month by doubling our revenue.
Okay so basically a home run is a success.
A victory.
Yeah something a big accomplishment.
That's right so we've seen a lot of these great phrases and as you can see a lot of them
from baseball are using your daily life and there are many many more.
Okay well why don't we hear them again in the baseball context and we'll listen to the dialogue
one more time.
Hello baseball fans and welcome back to today's game.
My name is Rick Fields and of course I am here once again with a man that seals the
deal Bob Copeland.
It's a beautiful day to see two world-class teams face each other and fight for their
right to be called champions.
Well the national anthem has just been sung and the Empire has started the game.
It's time to play ball.
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
Roger winds up and strike one very nice curve ball by the pitcher.
The catcher gives him the sign.
He winds up and Vargas gets a line drive.
The players are scrambling to get them all.
Vargas gets to first base and he's still doing the outfielder throws it to second.
Vargas slides.
He's safe.
Great play.
We have a runner on third and a bit bat is Brian O'Comie.
There's the pitch.
He hits it.
It's going.
Going.
That ball is gone.
Home run by O'Comie.
That puts this team ahead by two as we are at the bottom of the fiddling here at the
Richie Stadium.
Alright so an interesting dialogue, a very interesting sport.
And well personally I never played this as a child.
I mean either really.
I don't really like it too much but it is kind of fun to go to a game and especially
in the United States have those hot dogs and all that.
Okay.
Yep.
A cultural event.
A really important piece of American culture.
Exactly.
So we encourage you to come to our website EnglishPod.com.
Tell us what you think and also of course if you have questions or doubts be sure to
tell us.
If you have any other sort of baseball related phrases, let us know about them on the
website.
Okay so we'll see you guys there.
Thanks for downloading and until next time.
Bye.