Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you all about computers.
That's right. So we are going to take a look at some of the basic parts of a computer
and also about bad programs that could affect your computer and make it not work.
That's right. So before we get going we have a verb for you that we're going to look at in vocabulary
preview. Very cabbiery preview. All right. So today on vocabulary preview we have a verb as you said
and it's to crash to crash. Okay. This has a couple of different meanings but in today's
dialogue this means for your computer to shut down or to freeze or to stop working. Right. Because
maybe you heard of a car crash right when two cars bam hit each other. In this case your computer
is just not working anymore. It's stopped working. It freezes. That's right. So you can't use it. So my computer
crashed is a way to say my computer stopped working. Okay. So that's a word that we're going to
listen in our dialogue today. Why don't we jump right into it and we'll be back shortly.
Hello. Thanks for calling 1 2 3 tech help. I'm Todd. How can I help you?
Hello. Can you help me? I'm my computer. Oh man. It's okay sir. Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my laptop at a broke. I mean the monitor went black. Okay sir. It sounds like you might
have a virus. I don't feel sick. I'll be check. Nope. No fever. I'm fine. No. Your computer might
have a virus. I mean it has a bad program on it. Maybe that's why it crashed. I recommend that you
run an anti virus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware or trojans. Wait a minute.
Crash. spyware. Trojans. What? Where? When?
All right. So lots of great technology words today. Let's take a look at a few of them in
language takeaway. Language takeaway. All right. So let's start off with our first word. You've
probably heard it before but let's go over it just in case. A laptop. A laptop is a kind of computer.
Mm hmm. We have desktop laptop. Right. So your lap is the top part of your legs.
So a laptop computer is a small portable computer that you can take with you anywhere. That's
right. A lot of students have laptops and businessmen as well. So you mentioned the opposite
would be a desktop. Right. So it sits on top of a desk. Okay. So both a desktop and the laptop
have monitors. A computer monitor. So a monitor is like a TV for your computer. It's where you can
see what you're doing. Okay. So it's called a monitor or a screen maybe. You can also use the word
screen but monitor is the the technical word for the usually a box like a TV that goes with the
desktop computer. Okay. Very good. So Todd the computer guy said, hey, I think your computer
might have a virus. Ooh. That doesn't sound good. Yeah. A virus. So I guess you know what a
virus is when you get sick, right? You get the flu or the cold. That's right. You can say I have a virus.
But how can a computer have a virus? This means it's a program that is designed to hurt your computer.
All right. So it's like your computer is sick and it doesn't work. So a virus might make your computer
crash. Exactly. So in order to avoid this, what we need is an anti-virus program. Okay. So a virus
is a bad thing. Anti-virus is a good thing. An anti-virus program is a program that protects
your computer from viruses. So you would say anti-virus. You might have heard of a very famous
program called Norton anti-virus or McAfee anti-virus. These are brands. Okay. Very good. So those are some
of the main technical terms that we have on language takeaway. Why don't we listen to our dialogue
quickly one signal? Why don't we listen to our dialogue quickly again and we'll be back with fluency
builder. Hello. Thanks for calling 1, 2, 3 tech help. I'm Todd. How can I help you?
Hello. Can you help me? My computer. Oh man. It's okay, sir. Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my laptop and it broke. I mean the monitor went black. Okay, sir. It sounds like you might
have a virus. I don't feel sick. I'll be check. Nope. No fever. I'm fired. No. Your computer might
have a virus. I mean it has a bad program on it. Maybe that's why it crashed. I recommend that you
run an anti-virus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware or trojans. Phew. Wait a minute.
Crash. spyware. Trojans. What? Where? When?
All right. We're back. So now let's start off with three key phrases on fluency builder.
This first phrase is one that I know you use a lot. I use it too. If you say, oh man. Oh man.
So now depending on the tone, it can mean different things, right? So in this case, what does it mean?
So the man who's having problems with his computer says, my computer. Oh man.
Right. He seems a little bit anguish. This is a point. Yeah. Oh man. So it's an interjection.
That's right. So you can say, oh man. My computer crashed. Right. Oh man. You're always late.
Now you can also say it for maybe surprise. Like oh man. So when you're excited about something.
Oh man. This computer game is awesome. Mm-hmm. Okay. So it's just a way of expressing maybe disappointment or in some cases excitement.
That's right. So think about the way that you say it. Oh man. Oh man. Okay. So now the guy Todd. He tells him, hey, sir.
It's okay. Calm down. Right. Okay. So this might be funny sounding because we say,
calm. So be calm. Calm down. This is a phrase. It's almost like you're so upset and you're standing up.
Calm down. Calm down. Cool it. Okay. So you tell someone to calm down. That's right. So you might hear a
parent say about their child. The child won't calm down. What do I do? Mm-hmm. Okay. So it's a phrase.
Let's use it together. Calm down. Calm down. To calm down. All right. And now for our third phrase.
I mean, I mean, okay. So this is also in an interjection and it's very, very, very common. Okay.
So you'll probably hear people when they're talking. They're like, oh, I went over there. I mean,
we went to this place. It's an interjection. That's right. And usually we say this when we want to
correct what we just said. For example, your computer might have a virus. I mean,
it has a bad program on it. Okay. So the computer support man Todd, he understands maybe this person
doesn't know what a virus is. So I mean, he's he's changing what he just said. Mm-hmm. It could say,
oh, Saturday I'm going to the movie. I mean, Sunday I'm going to the movies. Mm-hmm.
Okay. What are you doing on Sunday? All right. So you use it to correct yourself or maybe
further explain something because maybe you are talking about a topic and maybe the person is not
understanding you. So you want to make it more clear. Mm-hmm. That's right. I mean,
right. Like she was very angry at me. I mean, of course she was because I did something wrong.
Right. So it's a way to offer an explanation. Mm-hmm. All right. So try and use that one in your
speech this week. It's really really great common English phrase. All right. So why don't we
listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Hello. Thanks for calling 1-2-3 TechHelp. I'm Todd. How can I help you?
Hello. Can you help me? I'm my computer. Oh, man. It's okay, sir. Calm down. What happened?
I turned on my laptop at a broke. I mean, the monitor went black. Okay, sir. It sounds like you might
have a virus. I don't feel sick. I'll be check. Nope. Don't fever up-vide. No, your computer
might have a virus. I mean, it has a bad program on it. Maybe that's why it crashed. I recommend
that you run an anti-virus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware or trojans.
Wait a minute. Crash. spyware. Trojan. Watch. Where? When?
All right. So Marco, in today's dialogue, we heard a couple of strange words about computer viruses.
One of them, you might be familiar with from Greek stories and fables.
Trojan. All right. A trojan. So it's a kind of bad software that will hurt your computer.
Yeah. It's a type of virus that comes in. It's supposed to be a good program or not harm your
computer, but it's really just a lie. It's disguised as something else. And then it starts to
really ruin your computer. They're very, very dangerous. Yeah. So why do you think it's called a trojan?
I don't know. Probably because of a trojan, something because it's very difficult like a trojan.
Well, think about the story of the Trojan horse, right? You know, that story. So
so back in ancient Greece, there was a war happening and Troye wanted to defeat its enemy
and they didn't know how to do it. So they thought and thought and thought and they came up with an idea.
They would build a horse and they would give it as a gift. But inside the horse, would be warriors,
fighters. Right. So when the city opened its doors to this wonderful gift, they would
receive a horrible gift and attack. And so Trojan is like that. It's like software that you
think is safe, but then it attacks your computer by surprise. They're very dangerous. And now things
have come up like Trojans and worms and a lot of different names for them, but it's crazy now.
Although I hear Mac users don't have these problems. We do not. That's if you use a Mac and
Tosh computer, you probably have very few problems with viruses and things like that. Wow.
That's one point in favor for Mac users. Absolutely. So let us know. Have you had problems with
a virus on your computer? Have you ever called TechSupport? Our website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see
you there. All right. Bye everyone. Bye.