Hello English learners and welcome back to another episode of English Pod My Name is Marco
And I'm Erica
And today with Erica we are getting married
Well, we're not getting married
We're not, but our actors in the podcast are
That's right, so we've got a lesson today about weddings
And you know what? A lot of the language in this lesson is about weddings and marriages
And maybe you don't need to use this language every day
But learning this vocabulary will definitely help you understand or learn a lot more about
Anglow culture
Okay, great point Marco
I think now we can look at our vocabulary preview
The vocabulary preview
So two simple words in this vocabulary preview
The first one is
Grume
So who is the groom?
Is the man the man that's getting married
Okay, and our second word is bride
bride bride
And obviously the bride is the woman getting married
Perfect
Now we have our bride and our groom so it's time to listen to our dialogue the first time
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married
Yeah, well it's about time
You've been living with his parents for 40 years
Don't be mean
Look, here come the bride's mates, oh, their dresses look beautiful
Who are those kids walking in the aisle?
That's the flower girl and the ring bear
I'm pretty sure that they're the groom's niece and nephew
Oh, they look so cute
He just told the priest makes it quick
I hope the food is good at the reception
That's all you ever think about
Food
Oh, I think the bride's coming now
She looks gorgeous
Wait, what's she doing?
Where's she going?
So great
Does this mean the reception is cancelled?
Oh, Markle that's so sad
Yeah, I know the reception is cancelled
Markle, we're not getting married
Oh, well, I mean the best part is when you go in eat and drink at the reception
Okay
Well there's some great language in this dialogue
And now let's look at our language takeaway
Language takeaway
Great, our first word on the language takeaway today is
It's about time
So now we are going to listen to some examples on how we use this great phrase
Example one
Dinner's ready
It's about time, I'm starving
Example two
Guess what?
I finally got a job
It's about time you've been unemployed for two years
Example three
We're almost there, just a couple more minutes
It's about time, we've been driving for 12 hours
So this phrase means finally
Finally
Finally, at last
We've been waiting a long time for this
Exactly
Okay, so it's about time
Great, let's take a look at our second word now
Iol
A-I-S-L-E
Iol, it's a tricky word, it sounds like the contraction of I-Wil
Yeah, but it's spelled so strangely
Right
We don't pronounce the S, the S is silent
That's true
Iol
So what is an Iol
In a big room
Where you have a lot of chairs
That space in the middle that allows people to walk through
That's the Iol
So the Iol is the part where you walk
Yes, in a big room
In a big room
With many chairs
Okay
So in the church
The bride and groom
Walked on the Iol
Exactly
Let's move to a third word
Bridesmaid
So who are the bridesmaids?
Or maybe you should ask me that
Yeah, because we don't get bridesmaids
Okay, so the bridesmaids are
The women who are friends of the bride
Who stand next to her when she's getting married
Usually they're her best friends
Right, okay
Okay, so we have our bridesmaids
Now we have our flower girl
Flower girl
Again, I'll explain the one
Please please
The flower girl is that cute little girl
Who walks down the Iol
And who throws flowers
That's the flower girl
And with the flower girl
We have our ring bearer
Ring bearer
So the ring bearer
Is the cute little boy
Who walks down the Iol
Carrying the rings
Yep, okay, so a lot of useful vocabulary for a wedding ceremony
That's true
Now let's look at our last word
Gorgeous
Gorgeous means beautiful
Very beautiful
Yeah, you know beautiful
You can only use with a woman
Can you use gorgeous with a woman or with a man?
Yes, gorgeous is unisex
So both men and women are gorgeous
Right, you can say that girl is gorgeous
That guy is gorgeous
Right, or you can say even this house is gorgeous
Okay, so men women objects
Yes, yes
All right, well
We've learned some really interesting vocabulary
That will help us to understand an Anglo wedding
So why don't we listen to the dialogue slow down?
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married
Yeah, well, it's about time
He's been living with his parents for 40 years
Don't be mean
Look, here come the bridesmaids
Their dresses look beautiful
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
That's the flower girl
And the ring bear
I'm pretty sure they're the groom's niece and nephew
Oh, they look so cute
I just hope the priest makes it quick
I'm starving
I hope the food's good at the reception
That's all you ever think about
Food
Oh, I think the brides coming now
She looks gorgeous
Wait, what's she doing?
Where's she going?
Oh, great
Does this mean that the reception is cancelled?
Now in this dialogue, we have a word
That many students often make mistakes on
So this is a word that causes a lot of problems
Yes, the word Mary Mary, right?
So we are going to listen now
To some common mistakes on how English learners use this word
Right, so these are wrong examples
Example one
Honey, let's marry
Example two
We married four years ago
Example three
When I'm married, I want a huge wedding
These are great examples of mistakes students make with the word
Mary, they're missing a word
Let's listen to these right examples to see what word is missing
Example one
Honey, let's get married
Example two
We got married four years ago
Example three
When I get married, I want a huge wedding
Great, so we can see that when we use the word Mary, we say to get married
Exactly right, get married
To get married, right?
Okay, don't forget that
Yes, get married, I will get married
We got married
Right, so now you know exactly how to use this word
We are ready to listen to our dialogue again for a third time
And this time it's going to be at a normal speed
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married
Yeah, well it's about time
You've been living with his parents for 40 years
Don't be mean
Look, here come the bride's mates, oh, their dresses look beautiful
Who are those kids walking in the aisle?
That's the flower girl and the ring bear
I'm pretty sure that they're the groom's niece and nephew
Oh, they look so cute
He just told the priest makes it quite kind of starving
I hope the food's good at the reception
That's all you ever think about
Food
Oh, I think the bride's coming now
She looks gorgeous
Wait, what's she doing?
Where's she going?
So great, does this mean the reception is canceled?
Okay, well, I'm going to be honest with you
I don't know too much about marriages
Because first of all, I'm not married
And I've never really been to many marriages
So, Erica, some questions for you
Okay, what are these bride's mates doing?
What do they, what do they about?
What are the bride's mates doing?
Yeah, what are they, what are they doing there?
Well, like I said earlier, the bride's mates are the friends of the bride
But the most important people
Besides the bride and groom are the best man
And the maid of honor
Okay, and what do they do there in the ceremony?
Well, what they do is they sign the marriage license
Okay, so they're like witnesses
Exactly
Okay, so, but wait a minute, they sign the marriage license
They're in the church
Yeah, of course, right inside the church, you sign the marriage license
Oh, that's strange
Because from what I know, in other countries, usually you will sign the marriage license before the ceremony
So you get married twice
Yeah, you have like the civil marriage
And then you have like the church wedding or whatever
That's so complicated
Well, yeah, I mean the church wedding is just the ceremony
It's not really anything official
Oh, in Canada, it's the official part as well
I guess maybe you're just more efficient
Maybe
Well, this is a really fascinating, a really interesting subject isn't it?
Yeah, because there's so many countries that have different marriage ceremonies
I know that marriage is in India last around seven days
Yeah, yeah, I want to know more about how our users get married in their country
Yeah, so please go to our website at EnglishPod.com
And tell us how you get married in your countries
Yeah, I can't wait to hear your stories
Yeah, it should be interesting, right?
Okay, well everyone, thanks for listening
And until next time
Goodbye