Hello English learners, welcome back to another lesson with us at English Pod, my name is Marko
and I'm Erica. And today we don't feel very good. That's right. Actually in this lesson
we're talking about a hangover. Hangover, wow. That's an interesting word. What does that mean?
Well, when you when you drink beer or wine or vodka, you drink too much a bit. The next morning
you have a hangover. Okay, so a lot of our listeners have probably experienced the hangover before.
It's very likely. But the problem is when you have to go to work the next day. Yes,
and you might need to actually miss work, but you need some good words and phrases to describe
how bad you feel. Okay, so let's listen to this dialogue for the first time. We have a guy
describing his hangover and why he missed the work that day.
Are you okay, man? You don't look very well. Well, you feel terrible. I went out last night with
Trevor and things got a little out of hand. Nice. So where did you guys go? We hit up a couple
of local bars and met up with some friends. Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned
out that it was his birthday yesterday. Oh no, Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
And then tell me about it. We drink everything in the bar. Is that why you missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous. I threw up like five times.
Ew. I was so dehydrated that I drank a gallon of water and my head has been pounding all day.
I swear I am never going to drink again. Too bad, man. Tonight is Tracy's going away party.
She asked if you were going to go. Oh, yeah, I'm there.
All right, so he's never drinking again, but then at the next chance for a party, he's already ready to go.
I think that's the typical lie of every person that drinks. They out never drink again, but a
week later or a month later, they are again. Or a day later. All right, so we saw some great
vocab here. So let's look at it now in language takeaway. Language takeaway.
Going to look at five words here. Now the first one, and they talked about how Mike's birthday is a
drink fast. A drink fast. It's a drink fast. All right, so we have this word drink fast.
Now what is this fast part? Well, maybe you recognize the word October fast. Okay, or festival.
Mm-hmm, so fast is like a party. There's lots of food. There's lots of drink. A drink fast.
There's an event where there's a lot of drinks. Okay, so can I have different types of fasts?
Yeah, this is a really informal sort of slang way of saying there's lots of something. So I could say,
oh my god, it's a puppy fast. So there are a lot of puppies. Uh-huh. All right, can say like a fast food fast.
Okay, so we're eating a lot of fast food. There's a lot of fast food. All right, so fast, interesting.
Now when he was describing his hangover, he said that he felt really nauseous.
Nautious. Now I always have a hard time spelling this word. So NA you ask E O U S. Nautious.
Nautious. It kind of seems like you should say Nautious. Right, but you say nauseous. Yeah. Okay, so when you're
feeling nauseous, what do you feel like? So you feel dizzy. You don't feel very well. Like your stomach hurts.
Yeah, and your head is kind of spinning. Okay, and you feel like you might throw up. Right, exactly.
Now this word that you just mentioned, throw up is actually our next word. And well, we're not
going to describe it. Why don't we just listen to a person throwing up?
Oh, Marco, that was horrible. Well, that's the only way we could actually explain, throw up. I mean,
it's kind of hard word to explain, but I'm sure everyone understands now what it means, right?
The word is two throw up. Two throw up. Two throw up. Our next word. Now our guy who's hung over,
he said, I was so dehydrated. dehydrated. To be dehydrated. So this is an adjective and it means that
I have no water in my body. Exactly. Okay, so I am dehydrated. I need water. Yeah,
common feeling after drinking too much beer, huh? Exactly. Now our final word, he said he had a headache.
And he said, my head's been pounding all day. Okay, so his head has been pounding all day.
Now this verb pounding. It sounds like this.
All right, so a clear example of what your head feels like when you have this very bad headache.
You can also say I have a pounding headache. I have a pounding headache, exactly.
Where my head is pounding. All right, so five great words that we just looked at right now.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue a second time? Let's slow it down just a little bit.
And then we'll come back and take a look at some phrases.
Are you okay, man? You don't look very well. No, you feel terrible.
I went out last night with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
Nice. So where did you guys go? We hit up a couple of local bars and met up with some friends.
Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned out that it was his birthday yesterday.
Oh no, Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure. And it's telling me about it.
We drink everything in the bar. Is that why you missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous.
I threw up like five times. I was so dehydrated that I drink a gallon of water.
And my head has been pounding all day. I swear I am never going to drink again.
Too bad, man. Tonight is Tracy going away part and she asks if you're going to go.
Oh yeah, I'm there.
All right, well that was a little easier to understand this time. Now you mentioned that we've got
some great phrases. So let's go to them now and fluency builder. Fluency builder.
All right, so as we heard in the dialogue, the party was, I think it was a great party, right?
What sounds like it was fantastic? Well, apparently it was a great party. And he said that
he went out with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
Things got a little out of hand. Right, so things got a little out of hand.
Now to get out of hand, what's that mean? Well, we have some examples. So let's listen to a
couple of them before we explain it. Example one. Honey, the kids are getting a little out of hand.
Can you do something? Example two. Guys, this argument is getting out of hand.
All come down. Example three. The party last night got out of hand. The neighbors called the police.
Okay, so when things get out of hand, you lose control. Exactly. They get out of control.
Just a little bit, maybe. Yeah, go a little crazy. All right, so things got a little out of hand.
Now the opposite of this was everything was cool. Everything was cool. So everything was cool.
So basically everything was okay, everything was relaxed, everything was going fine. Exactly. And then
Mike came along and then things got a little out of hand. Well, that Mike. And now for our last phrase,
he was describing that Mike's birthday party was a drink fest, right? And then his friend agreed.
He said, tell me about it. Tell me about it. Tell me about it. Now what does this mean?
Exactly when he says, tell me about it. Basically, it means I completely understand.
I completely agree with you. Yeah. Okay. So I could say, oh my god, Marco, it's so hot outside today.
Right. And I was like, oh, I know, tell me about it. Mm-hmm. Right. So I'm saying, yeah, I agree with you. You are right.
Yeah. Very good. So these phrases. Okay. So three great phrases that we just looked at.
Let's listen to our dialogue for the last time. And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
Are you okay, man? You don't look very well.
No, you feel terrible. I went out last night with Trevor and things got a little out of hand.
Nice. So where did you guys go? We hit up a couple of local bars and met up with some friends.
Everything was cool until Mike came along and it turned out that it was his birthday yesterday.
Oh no. Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure. And tell me about it. We drink everything in the bar.
Is that why you missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning feeling really nauseous. I threw up like five times.
Ew. I was so dehydrated that I drank a gallon of water and my head has been pounding all day.
I swear I am never going to drink again. Too bad, man. Tonight is Tracy's going away part
and she asks if you're going to go. Oh yeah, I'm there.
So it sounds like these guys sure like to go out and have a few drinks. Don't they?
Yeah, exactly. And I think this is a very common thing among young people, usually in the United
States, after a day at the office or something they'll go or even Europe, they'll go to the pub, right?
Yeah, but the thing is that in America and Canada, we're very careful about alcohol and young people, right?
Yeah, exactly. The legal drinking age in the most part of the United States is 21 years of age.
And really many parents or families will never let their children drink alcohol until they're
21. Right. And also the laws that control alcohol like for example on television. If you notice a TV commercial
with beer or a wine, you will never see the person actually drinking it. It's illegal. Yeah, that's true.
While another country is okay, you'll see people drinking it and having fun. And these
commercials, they can only maybe put them close to their lips but not drink it. Interesting.
I mean, another weird thing is that sometimes you might want to sit in your back garden or out on your
your porch and have a beer after work, right? But in places it's totally illegal to do that.
You can't be outside with alcohol. Right. You can't be seen drinking or you can't be on the
sidewalk or on a bus drinking. While in other places you can, right? You can just have a beer on a
subway. So it's a little bit different policies on alcohol control. What do you guys think about
it? Do you think it's correct or think maybe it's a little bit too exaggerated?
Come to our website EnglishPod.com and tell us about it. All right, we'll see you guys there
and until next time. Thanks for downloading and goodbye.