Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right. We are going to talk about winter, but specifically about the clothes you wear during winter
when it's very very cold outside.
That's right and I hear you're not too familiar with some of these practices because where you come from,
you don't really have winter. We don't have winter. We have dry season and rainy season
but same temperature. Well Chicago definitely has a snowy season so I'm very familiar with these things.
So let's jump right into today's dialogue. We'll be hearing it one time and in a minute we'll be back to talk about it.
Bye mom. Wait Jimmy it's cold outside. Put a hat on.
Okay bye. No wait you'll be too cold without mittens.
All right see ya. Hold on with that wind you're going to catch a cold. Where this scarf?
Okay see ya after school and earmuffs put these on. Here we go.
What? Yes honey. I can't breathe.
Hey.
All right we're back so there were a couple of different items of clothing that we saw in this dialogue.
So let's look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay well first of all we have mom and Jimmy. Jimmy is a boy's name. He's a little boy and
mom is saying goodbye to him but first she wants him to put on clothes. So the first item the first thing
she asks him to put on is a hat. Now you probably've seen like a baseball cap or many different
types of hats but and sometimes in other languages they have specific names for a hat for winter right
but in English it's a hat. Anything that covers your head is a hat that's kind of like the category.
So maybe this one is a warm wool hat but it's in the end it's a hat. The hat.
Okay so he's put on the hat now what else is he going to put on? Well we need to keep our fingers warm.
Okay so there are two kinds of ways to keep your fingers warm and the way in this dialogue that
the boy keeps his fingers warm is with mittens. All right so mittens you put on your hands. Now what's
the difference between mittens and gloves? Okay gloves have special places for each finger one two
three four five on each hand. Right and mittens there's two spaces one for your thumb and one for all
your other fingers. Okay so that means you can't really hold things. So you kind of look like a
pink way or something like yeah you look like a yeah exactly like a pink when it and it's mostly
for children adults don't wear mittens because adults need to hold things like keys and phones and
cars steering wheels. So in this case mittens is usually for children. Okay so mittens
and while the mother is still a little bit worried so she tells him to wear a scarf. Okay a scarf
is all long usually made of wool a long piece of fabric that you put around your neck to keep
your neck warm. Okay so a scarf. A scarf. Okay and he's put on the mittens the scarf that had
and he's missing some ear muffs. Okay this is a little funny because usually if you're wearing a hat
you don't need ear muffs but ear muffs are like headphones but they keep your ears warm. Right and
we wear these they don't cover your head they just cover your ears and usually they're just two
rounds circles over your ears. So as you say exactly they look like big earphones and they keep your
ears warm now. As you say usually don't wear this if you're wearing a hat because well you would
put your ears inside your hat. So it looks pretty silly if he's wearing all of this together.
All right and so those four key items those four key pieces of clothing are for our language
takeaway today. When we listen to this dialogue again and we'll come back soon to talk about fluency
and see you both there. Bye mom. Wait Jimmy it's cold outside but I have it on.
Okay bye. No wait you'll be too cold without mittens. All right see ya. Hold on with that wind
you're gonna catch a cold where this scarf. Okay see you after school. Oh and ear muffs put these on
here we go. Whoa. Yes honey. All right we're back so now let's take a look at four key phrases on fluency
builder fluency builder. Okay this first phrase as I said before has to do with the mom and the boy
saying goodbye to each other. So he says all right see ya see ya. Yeah okay so see as into look to
write you see something and what about y a yeah see ya. So this is a very spoken language way of saying
you. So we could say see you later but if you want to make it shorter you can say see ya. See ya. Bye.
Bye. Goodbye. All right so see ya and then what's our next way of saying goodbye. Hold on.
Wait that's. We're not there yet no um hold on is our next phrase and this is a way to say wait.
Wait hold on so you just say hold on it means wait it's not really rude right it's just a little
bit more casual. Exactly it's very casual so you cannot say hold that doesn't make sense you have to
use these two words together hold on so like I said before with Marco who wants to go fast I can
say hold on wait a second. All right okay so hold on see ya and now you gotta be careful because
you're going to catch a cold to catch a cold okay so a cold is when you you know when you cough you
have a sore throat it's starting to get cold outside and you don't feel well okay so you're have
a running nose it's it's a illness and most people get this every year it's very common but you
don't get a cold you catch a cold okay okay so catch is the same where we use for when we
we talk about sports like throwing and catching okay it's almost like it just hits you it's so fast you
just catch a cold so that's really important what you just said because you don't use the verb
get you don't get a cold you catch a cold or if you say that you were sick last week because you
had a cold you would say oh I caught a cold or I had a cold exactly so remember present tense I
catch a cold past tense I caught a cold last week okay and our last phrase for fluency builder is
here we go here we go okay so when do we hear this phrase the mother says to the boy put these on
here we go so she's doing something with him she's helping him put his earmuffs on and here we go
is a way to say okay I've finished okay I'm done okay your earmuffs are on you so you're ready here you
there you go right so we say here we go like everything is ready your earmuffs are on
exactly so maybe I'm a computer and I have a problem and I'm waiting waiting waiting waiting
and you know when the bar is loading and finally thing it's ready here we go here we go
now I can start it's ready or sometimes a waitress will come and serve you food and say here we go
here's your order exactly so this is a way to say what you've been waiting for it's ready now okay
great so I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue one last time before we come back here we go
by mom wait Jimmy it's cold outside put a hat on okay bye no wait you'll be too cold without
mittens all right see yeah hold on with that wind you're gonna catch a cold where this scoff
okay see after scoff and earmuffs put these on here we go
well yes honey I can't breathe
all right we're back so as you mentioned in Chicago it's very very cold so I imagine you had all of these
winter clothes right that's right and it's funny because I remember being a small child and my
mother doing this to me putting on snow pants and boots and earmuffs and hats and gloves and
scarves and all of the sudden it's so hot inside because you're wearing everything and so you can't even
walk like you're saying a pink you look like a penguin walking out the door and you get to school
and you're sweating right and so in school we had to take we had a special room and we had to take
everything off because there's snow everywhere and snow can be very dangerous because it melts and it
turns into water okay so I have very strong memories of all of this putting them on taking them off
and it's being warm all the time they will yeah when it's cold or you live in a place with cold
weather you have to have these items of clothing because otherwise you might catch a cold exactly so
I hope that no one out there catches a cold but if you want some suggestions where scarf
cover your neck that's the most important you're head and you're scarf but that was important
all right and if you guys have any other questions or comments you can visit our website
englishpod.com and we'll see you every one there bye everyone bye