Hello English learners. Welcome to another great lesson with EnglishPod. My name is Margot.
And I'm Erica.
So, Erica, how are you today?
I'm doing pretty well. And I think we've got a good lesson today. A really helpful lesson.
What are we talking about today?
We have an elementary lesson about making an appointment.
All right, making an appointment.
Yeah, that's really helpful. I guess you have to make appointments for the doctor or...
At work, maybe.
Or with your friends?
Yeah, so this is language that you can use every day to make appointments.
Great. Well, so why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview?
Very vocabulary preview.
We only have one word today, which you need to know to understand this dialogue.
And it is financial advisor.
Financial advisor.
So, what is a financial advisor?
A financial advisor is a person who gives suggestions or recommendations about investing money.
Someone who wants you to put money in the stock markets.
Okay. Great.
I guess we're ready now to listen to our dialogue for the first time.
And as always, it's going to be at a normal speed, but you don't have to worry about it because...
We'll come back and teach you all the important words.
Hello.
Fairbrook Consulting. How may I help you?
Yes, this is Julian Horton. I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. Meely.
Certainly, what day were you thinking of?
How was Thursday? Did she have any time available then?
Let me double check.
Unfortunately, she's booked solid on Thursday. How does next Monday work for you?
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday. Can she do a Tuesday?
Sure. Tuesday's perfect.
May I ask where you're calling from?
Sure. That's a financial advisor.
Oh. Actually, Tuesday's no good. Sorry about that.
Well, I guess Ms. Meely does not want to speak to any financial advisors.
Yes. I guess she doesn't really want to invest in the stock market.
Or maybe she just gets too many phone calls from them.
Yeah. If you have money, I guess you'll get phone calls from people like that.
I guess we don't have that problem. No, we don't.
Okay, let's start with our language takeaway for today.
Language takeaway.
So, forward's today. The first one is available.
Available. Available.
Meaning that you are not busy.
That you're free. You're free. You're not busy.
Exactly. Let's move to our next word.
Double check.
Double check. I think we've got some examples of this phrase.
Example one.
Do you have the tickets?
I think so. But let me just double check.
Example two.
I thought I sent that email already, but let's go.
Okay, so double check basically means to check something twice.
Exactly. To check it again.
Oh, okay. Our third word for language takeaway today is scheduled.
Scheduled.
Scheduled. Scheduled.
SCHEDULEed. Scheduled.
Scheduled.
So when you have something schedule it means that you have something planned plan right yeah or booked at that time
booked at that time. Yeah, we've got a
Lunch schedule this afternoon. Don't wait. Yes, we do all right lunch looking forward to it and our last word for today is
Bookt solid booked solid booked solid
Be okay, ED booked solid
So we have some great examples on how you can use this great phrase booked solid and you can understand what it means
Example one
I can't get a hotel room their book solid until after the new year
Example two
I'm sorry. There are no seats available in this flight. We booked solid over the Christmas holidays
Example three
Sorry, I can't meet with you today. I'm booked solid
Okay, great. So book solid basically is you have no free time no available time right so you've got appointments scheduled all day
All day great. So with this in mind now we can listen to our dialogue a second time this time
It's gonna be slow so we can understand a little bit better
Hello, fair brick consulting how may I help you?
Yes, this is Julian Horton and I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely
Certainly what date were you thinking of how's Thursday?
Does she have any time available then?
Let me double check
No, unfortunately she's booked solid on Thursday. How does next Monday work for you?
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday
Can she do choose day?
Sure, Tuesday's perfect. May I ask where you're calling from?
Sure, Matt and financial advisors. Oh
Actually, Tuesday's no good. Sorry about that
Okay, so now it's a little bit more clear and with this we can start with putting it together
Put your hands together
There's some great examples in this dialogue of phrases you can use when you need to schedule an appointment
And we're gonna look at those today in the dialogue we heard Julian ask about making an appointment and she said this
I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. McNeely
So this is a great way to schedule an appointment to ask for some time from somebody else
Yeah, and we have some more examples of this phrase
Example one
Please book an appointment for next week
Example two
Please schedule an appointment for next week
Great, so after that when you're scheduling an appointment you need to
Suggest a day when maybe that person has time. Yes, let's listen to what they said in the dialogue
How's this day? Does she have any time available then?
You say well how's Thursday or how's Tuesday? And maybe that person doesn't have time that day
So they'll say something like this
Can't you do Tuesday
Okay, because so if I want to have a meeting with you, I would say how's Monday sound or how's Monday?
Monday's no good. I busy all day. How's Tuesday?
Sorry Tuesday's no good either. What about Wednesday? Okay Wednesday works. All right great. Wednesday's perfect. Okay, it's great
So we have a meeting on Wednesday. Okay. Yeah, those are some great phrases. Hey for scheduling an appointment. Yeah, they're really good
Okay, so now we can listen to our dialogue a third time and we're ready to understand everything that we've just talked about
Hello, they're bro consulting. How may I help you?
Yes, this is Julian Horton and I'm calling to arrange an appointment with Ms. Melee
Certainly what day were you thinking of? How's Thursday? Does she have any time available then?
Um, let me double check
Unfortunately, she's booked solid on Thursday. How does next Monday work for you?
Actually, I've got something scheduled on Monday. Can't you do a Tuesday?
Sure, Tuesday's perfect. May I ask where you're calling from? Sure, that's in financial advices
Oh, actually Tuesday's no good. Sorry about that
The language in this dialogue is really useful isn't it Marco? Yeah, it's from an every day situation.
You always have to make appointments at some point. Yes, and like we said earlier, it's
Language you can use when you need to talk about work with your boss, maybe? Right or
When you need to do daily things like go to the doctor or even when you're planning something with your friends
Right, yeah, you can use this in all those in all situations. Uh-huh
Great well, we're at a time now, but I hope you enjoyed our lesson and found it useful
And if you have any questions or comments, please go to our website at EnglishPod.com
Where we'll be there to answer everything. Yes, we will so thanks for listening guys and until next time bye