Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson with us here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going out to eat. Yes, good thing too because I'm hungry.
It's almost lunchtime. Yeah. So today we're going to be talking about eating at a restaurant
and giving some great recommendations and suggestions. Yes, we have language for describing food
for describing restaurants and for making suggestions. Great. So let's start with our vocabulary
for this lesson. Very cablory preview. We have two words today from our dialogue which you'll
need to know to understand the dialogue. Great. The first one that we have today is food poisoning.
Food poisoning. Food poisoning. Food poisoning. So food poisoning is not a good thing. Not a good
thing. It is when you eat some bad food and that food makes you sick. So you get
food poisoning. Okay, so food poisoning. Yeah, not a good thing. Okay, the next words.
allergic allergic allergic allergic allergic allergic. So when you're allergic to something,
it makes you sick. That one thing makes you sick. Right. For example, I'm allergic to seafood.
Right. If I eat seafood, I cannot breathe. Okay, so you definitely want to stay away from fish.
Yes, yes. Some people are allergic to nuts like peanuts or maybe milk, milk. Yeah. Cool.
So when one type of food makes you sick, you are allergic to that food. Okay, great. So with this in
mind, now we can listen to our dialogue for the first time at its normal speed, but don't worry if
you don't get everything now because we'll come back and teach you the important language.
Do you have any plans for the evening? We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the
neighborhood. Do you have any suggestions? I know there's really nice Italian place. The food
is fantastic and the date core is beautiful. I'd recommend giving it to try. Actually, I'm not
all that crazy about Italian food. I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter. In that case,
I know a great little bistro and they can really taste your seafood platter. The fish is outstanding.
It sounds fantastic, but I'm allergic to seafood, so... Okay, well, let me think.
Oh, I know this great little place is just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing
sandwiches. You can give them a try. Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning.
Remember?
Well, I'm getting hungry just thinking about all of those great restaurants. Yes, I'm really
good recommendations. Exactly. For food poisoning, right? No. That's okay. Let's start with our
language takeaway for this lesson. Language takeaway. Our first word on language takeaway is
check out. Check out. Check out. Check out. Check out. So we have some great examples on how we can
use check out in different situations and then you can understand the meaning. Example one.
Have you been to New Café next door? Yeah, I checked it out yesterday. The food was great.
Example two. Hey, check out my new car.
Example three. I'm going to check out the new shopping mall these weekends.
So I can understand that it just means look at. Yeah, look at. Or yeah, or go see. So let's go check out
that new bar in town. Yeah, okay. Cool. Next word is bistro bistro bistro bistro.
So what's a bistro? It's kind of complicated but it's like a small restaurant that's not really
cheap though. Not so cheap, but not so expensive. And it's usually French. Yes. So it's small
informal restaurant. Yeah bistro. Okay, so our third phrase for today is not all that crazy about.
Not all that crazy about. I'm not all that crazy about. Okay, again, kind of a funny phrase,
but we've got some examples that will help you understand the meaning. Example one.
Do you want to go shopping with me tomorrow? I'm not all that crazy about shopping. I don't like spending money.
Example two.
I'm not crazy about jazz music. I changed the song.
So this is just a really polite way of saying you don't like something. Exactly. But now the
opposite of this would be tasty. That's our fourth word, tasty. tasty. So when something is
tasty, it's good. It's good. Like delicious delicious. Yeah, you know what? In English we almost
never say the food is delicious, but we always say it's really tasty. Yes. This is really tasty.
Yes. Okay. tasty. And our last phrase for language takeaway in the mood for. In the mood for.
In the mood for. Let's listen to some examples of this phrase and we'll understand the meaning a
little bit better. Example one. We always eat hamburger it's for dinner. I'm in the mood for something different.
Example two. Let's watch movie. How about Texas, Chainsaw, Massica? I am not in the mood for a horror movie.
So if I'm in the mood for something, I feel like doing or eating or watching. Yeah. It means you
want to do that now. Yeah. I'm in the mood for. Okay. Some great language we just looked at.
And I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time.
We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the neighborhood. Do you have any suggestions?
I know this really nice Italian place. The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful. I'd recommend
giving it a try. Actually, I'm not all that crazy about Italian food. I'm in the mood for something
a bit lighter. In that case, I know a great little bistro. They make a really tasty seafood
platter. The fish is outstanding. It sounds fantastic but I'm allergic to seafood so
okay well let me think. Oh I know this great little place. It's just a hole in the wall
but they do the most amazing sandwiches. You've got to give them a try.
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning. Remember?
Okay, some really great and useful phrases there and I know you want to talk about specifically
some of these phrases. Yes, today's lesson is all about making recommendations, right?
Right. So let's look at some useful phrases in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So in the dialogue, we heard a great way of asking for a suggestion. That's right. Let's listen.
Do you have any suggestions? Do you have any suggestions?
So that's how you would ask for a suggestion or you can say something else like
do you have any ideas? Yeah or you might say do you have any thoughts?
Okay so that's great ways. Asking for a suggestion. Yep. In response to this you can say something like this.
I'd recommend giving it a try. I'd recommend giving it a try.
We also heard another phrase that we use for giving suggestions.
You can give them a try. You've got to give them a try.
So these two phrases are great. I'd recommend or you got to give them a try.
Yeah. Great ways of suggesting. Yes. Now what's really important here is the pronunciation of these words, right?
Yeah, you'll notice that we don't say I would recommend. Right. We use the contraction
I'd. I'd. I'd. I'd recommend. I'd recommend. Similarly, in the phrase you have got to
We shorten that to say you got to you got to you got to give them a try. You got to you know what guys
if you can shorten your phrases like this if you can push the sounds together you'll sound a lot
more natural. And also you'll be able to understand because in movies or in shows they will never
say you have got to give them a try. Yeah. So if you know how to use this form you'll understand
exactly. Okay, great. Well, why don't we listen to the dialogue a third time and you'll hear some of these
contractions in the dialogue.
Do you two have any plans for the evening? We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the
neighborhood. Do you have any suggestions? I know there's really nice Italian place. The food is
fantastic and the date call is beautiful. I'd recommend giving it a try. Actually, I'm not all that
crazy about Italian food. I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter. In that case, I know
a great little bistro and make a really tasty seafood platter. The fish is outstanding. It sounds
fantastic but I'm allergic to seafood so. Okay, well let me think. Oh, I know this great
little place is just a hole in the wall but they do the most amazing sandwiches. You can give
them a try. Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning. Remember?
Okay, great dialogue and Erica, I know that you have some food poisoning stories for us.
I don't know about stories but I've definitely had food poisoning before. Yeah. One of the worst
times that I ever had food poisoning was when I was traveling in Morocco. Okay, I had some really
amazing orange juice, really fresh squeeze that day in the morning and then I got on a bus.
Okay, I think you can see where this is going. Yeah, so I was on the bus and then I started to feel
really sick and I was just hoping and hoping and hoping that the bus ride would be over soon
but unfortunately it wasn't. Oh, no. All I can say is that I was sick and I would
all I can say is that I was pretty sick and really, really unhappy. Yeah, I bet. Well, that's very
strange that you got sick from orange juice, huh? Well, yeah, maybe it was with some dirty water or
something like that. I don't know. It was just a terrible situation. Yeah, it's always complicated
when you're traveling to other countries, it could be the water, it could be the way they prepare
things. Yeah, yeah, food poisoning. Guys, I hope that you don't get food poisoning. And if you
have any food poisoning stories, it would be great for you to share them. Yes, at our website
EnglishPod.com and we'll see you there to answer all your questions and comments but now we have to go.
Okay, guys, thanks for listening. We'll see you there. Bye bye.