Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're at a wedding ceremony.
All right, nice.
Another nice wedding.
Yeah. But of course it wouldn't be EnglishPod unless we have something unexpected happening
at this wedding.
Okay, so we're going to be talking about hands.
Oh, but Marco, what is there to say about a hand?
Well, as you may or may not know, each finger has a name on your hand.
Okay. So we're going to learn how, so we're going to learn what those names are in English.
Perfect. And also, we're going to learn about some common phrases that you might hear in an English wedding.
Exactly. Because I think exactly because usually it's old English.
Maybe English that's not used anymore.
All right. Well, I'm excited to find out what this unexpected event is.
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
The ring, please.
May this ring be blessed.
So he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in peace and continue in love until lives end.
With this ring, I be wet.
Where it is a symbol of our love and commitment.
Honey, that's my pinky.
The ring goes on the ring finger.
So what?
That's my index finger.
No, right. This one, right.
That's the thumb, Nick.
Okay, I got it. This is the ring finger.
That's my middle finger, Nick. This is my ring finger.
All right. Embarrassing moments for the groom.
Yes. Confusing the fingers in front of all his friends and family.
Not good.
So I mentioned before that we're going to learn the names of each finger in your hand.
So let's get started. Let's take a look at these in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right. Well, why don't we start with the smallest finger on your hand.
The smallest finger on your hand.
That's called the pinky pinky pinky.
Sometimes people call it the little finger.
Yes.
Right. Yep.
So the pinky and the next finger is the one the groom couldn't find.
Okay. The ring finger.
The ring finger.
So this is, of course, like the name says, where the wedding ring is usually placed.
Exactly.
Yep.
Now the next one is a controversial finger.
That must be the middle finger.
Okay. Easy middle finger.
So why is it controversial?
Well, you know, if you put your middle finger up and you put your right hand.
Sorry, Mark, go do it this way.
And all other fingers down.
You are making a very rude gesture.
It's a rude sign.
So what would you call that?
I would call that giving the middle finger.
Giving the middle finger or I've also heard the phrase flip someone off.
Yes, or also flip the bird.
Flip the bird exactly or give him the bird.
Yes.
So all phrases that you can use when you are showing only your middle finger somebody.
It's not very polite.
No, don't do it.
Unless somebody deserves it, I guess.
We won't talk about that.
The next finger.
The index finger.
Index finger.
So this is the finger you use to point.
Right.
Yep.
The index finger.
Any idea why they call it the index finger?
Because when you're looking through the index of a book, you always use this finger.
Right.
I think you also use this finger to pass pages on a book, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Don't believe anything I just told you.
Well, we're not sure.
Maybe you guys know the real answer to this.
And our last finger, the most important one.
The thumb.
Thumb.
THU-MB.
The thumb.
Okay.
So that's the short but fat finger.
The very movable one.
The move.
And then you use to play playstation.
Video games.
Okay.
So the pronunciation here.
Do you say the B at the end of this word?
No.
I actually only pronounce the M.
Yes.
The thumb.
Yeah.
You wouldn't say the thumb.
No.
Okay.
So now that we're clear on all five fingers, let's listen to our dialogue again.
And then we'll come back and talk about these difficult phrases that the priest used.
The rings, please.
May this ring be blessed.
So he who gives it.
And she who wears it may abide in peace.
And continue in love.
Until lives end.
With this ring, I V-Wed.
Where it is a symbol of our love and commitment.
Honey, that's my pinky.
The ring goes on the ring finger.
Is one?
That's my index finger.
No right.
This one right.
Let's the thumb, Nick.
Okay.
I got it.
This is the ring finger.
That's my middle finger, Nick.
This is my ring finger.
Oh.
Well, this is really common wedding speak, isn't it?
Yeah, it's really common.
That's what usually the priest or the person who is marrying somebody would say.
Well, why don't we look at some of these phrases now because it's really interesting to talk about their meaning.
So the first one.
May this ring be blessed.
So what does it mean when you bless something or someone?
Well, usually the religious leader does this right?
And he's giving good wishes to that thing.
Could be for an object or to a person, right?
Yes.
You can be blessed, of course.
And so these good wishes usually come from God.
Okay.
Great.
So what about our next phrase?
A bite in peace.
Wow. So this verb a bite.
It means to live, to live, to be, to be in peace.
Yeah.
But it's very fancy.
I don't know if you use it anymore.
No.
I think you would never use this word in conversation or even very rarely in writing.
It's quite old.
Yes.
Definitely.
I would agree.
So a bite in peace.
Okay.
What about our next phrase?
I like this and it's the common phrase you're hearing all movies and in all marriages.
Yeah.
With this ring, I, the wed.
Okay. We've got two words in here that are also older English words.
So the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the.
So this is an, this is a middle English term for you.
You.
Right.
So I would, can I say, I love the?
You could.
That would be very romantic.
Prettysilence.
But also inappropriate for the offers.
But it's very olding.
I guess you would, if your reading Shakespeare, you would definitely come upon this, right?
Yes.
And what about wed.
This is also an old word for an old verb for the action of marrying someone.
So I can say, we will be wed next year.
Hmm, but don't say that now, because you'll sound quite silly.
Yeah.
It's too old fashioned.
Yeah, it's so.
Especially if you guys are reading something a little bit more classical or you plan to get married to an English person
All right, and our last phrase
Where it as a symbol of our love and commitment where it as a symbol of our love and commitment
So now he's referring to the rings right where the ring yeah has a symbol a sign a representation yes
Of love and commitment so why would you wear a ring as a as a symbol of something well obviously you know
Love you can't see it you can't touch it right so you need something to show you that it's there
So you need a sign of that love something that you can see so that's what the ring represents
Yeah, but how about this word
Commitment the commitment is a strong promise so you promise to love that person to take care of them
Yes, okay great
So now we are a little bit more familiar with some of the language you hear in a wedding ceremony and we also know all of the names of the fingers
Exactly, so why don't we listen to the dialogue one more time to hear these all in context
The ring please
May this ring be blessed so he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in peace and
Continuying love until lives and with this ring I be wed
Where it is a symbol of our love and commitment
Honey, that's my pinky the ring goes on the ring finger
So that's why index finger no right this one right
Let's let's make
Okay, I got it this is the ring finger that's my middle finger neck this is my ring finger
All right, so now it's perfectly clear and a romantic dialogue in the end. Yeah, very romantic
Although a little bit embarrassing. Yeah, so what about wedding rings now?
We have different types of rings right we have the wedding ring the one that that we just heard yeah, but we also have an engagement ring
Yes, yeah in most English speaking countries the woman is very very lucky because she gets to ring right
So when the man asks her to marry him
He gives her a diamond a diamond ring. That is usually that's the engagement ring
And it's it's really really important that he does this and it's also really important that he spends a lot of money on the
And the diamond I know about this diamonds are forever
Yes, and and the tradition is you must spend at least one month salary. Wow. Yeah, I said it
Yeah, so the girl gets and a diamond engagement ring and then on wedding day
She gets the the wedding ring. Yes, and usually will she wear both of them? Yeah
She'll always wear both of them so the engagement ring goes goes closest to you and then the wedding ring on top and the engagement ring
It represents the commitment to marry her so wait the commitment from the man to marry her
Okay, so that it's a symbol that they will get married. Yes. It's a symbol of the promise
Now what happens if they break up and and they don't get married does he get the ring back?
I don't know
Okay, here's the rule
If he was a jerk
No, but but if it was sort of like a happy breakup then okay, okay, I get to get to a big brisk right?
All right, so that's all for today guys
Let us know if you guys have any interesting wedding stories
I know that sometimes weddings can be embarrassing people
I don't know objecting maybe I've seen the groom faint or even falling a pool falling a pool
So if you have any stories, please share them with us come to EnglishPod.com and also if you have any questions or doubts
Eric and I are always there to answer them. Well, thanks for listening to this lesson everyone and until next time. Bye