Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we have another great elementary lesson for you all
that's right we've got a lesson for all you sports fans out there
alright we're doing a podcast on sports today
we're starting off with basketball
so we've got lots of language about basketball and sports in this lesson today
great so let's take a look at our vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
two words for you today the first one is foul
foul
a foul
basically it's an action in a game that is not allowed
right so if you're playing basketball and you kick the other player
that's a foul that's a pretty big foul
yeah if you're playing soccer and you pick up the ball
that's also a foul
our second word is
rf rf
also known as a referee
right
so a referee is
basically like the judge of a game
the judge of the game so he's the one that will say that was a foul
that was a foul
yeah
rf also known as referee
okay so two great words we're going to hear them in our dialogue
and we're going to be listening to two guys who are watching a basketball game on TV
and
hey is the game started yet
yeah about five minutes ago
who's running
bulls of course
what that wasn't a foul
come on raf
sorry
shack always screws up free throws
you were right he didn't make a shot
yeah that was a great shot
three pointer yeah
did you see that he traveled to the raf didn't even call us
raf needs glasses
hey raf open your eyes
can't believe you can see that
okay
I did the first quarter
alright I'm going to make a beer run
alright a really common situation
whenever you're watching games with friends right
you need to get a beer
we'll talk about that in a little while
let's take a look at language takeaway
language takeaway
okay let's take a look at our first word on language takeaway
free throw free throw free throw
this one's a bit hard to say isn't it it's a little bit hard to explain
but if you're playing basketball
and if someone fouls you you get a free throw
so that's when all the players line up around you
and you can throw the ball
to the basket without anyone blocking you
right a little bit complicated but I'm sure the basketball fans
understand what a free throw is
alright our next word is
make the shot
let's listen to some examples and we'll understand the meaning of
example one
I can't believe it
you made the shot from the other side of the court
example two
there's no way he's going to make that shot
he's way too far away from the net
example three
if gritsky makes a shot they're going to win the Stanley Cup
so it's clear now to make the shot is to successfully
that the ball in the basket you can use this expression in other
sports as well right yeah you could use it in hockey to make the shot
could also use it in golf in a lot of different sports that use the term to
shoot yes shoot the ball so at any time you shoot the ball you can make the shot
exactly
okay our next word today three pointer three pointer three pointer
three pointer
it's a shot in basketball when you get three points
yes usually this shot is taken from further out
yeah father distance yeah so it's a little bit more difficult to make
shot you know sometimes people might say a three point shot or something like that
but our English pot learners they know
it's a three point yeah you'll sound really knowledgeable really cool
three pointer and our last word today
travel travel to travel travel
when you walk with the basketball well technically you're allowed to
take two steps in basketball okay so when you take more than two steps
right so yeah traveling means to take more than two steps with the ball
let's listen to the dialogue a second time this time it'll be a bit slower
so that we can understand some of these great phrases we just talked about
hey has the game started yet
yeah about five minutes ago oh who's winning the bulls of course
what that wasn't a foul come on raf don't worry
check always screws up free throws yeah you were right they didn't make this shot
yeah that was a great shot three pointer yeah oh did you see that he
traveled the raf didn't even call it this ref needs glasses hey ref open your eyes
I can't believe you didn't see that okay then to the first quarter hey I'm going to
be a run sweet all right sports fans so now let's take a look at
fluency builder fluency builder okay today on fluency builder we have two really
common words that you would listen to while you're watching a game yeah these are sort of
slang words hey yeah they're kind of a common like informal informal the first one that we have is
screw up screw up screw up screw up screw up yeah so this is a good way of saying
to make a mistake let's listen to some examples of how this word is used
example one
jail you really screwed up this time you'll fight
example two
this game is important if you screw it up we're out of the finals
example three
I'm sorry I know I screwed up we forgive me
okay so screw up is mess up yeah make a mistake make a mistake huh great in our last word
on fluency builder today a beer run a beer run beer run so what is this beer run
you run to get beer you go to the store and get beer get more beer so it's just an
expression to meaning to go and get more beer yeah usually you're watching a game
or you're at home with your friends you run out of beer so somebody has to make a
get some beer go get some beer make a beer run yeah
good good block out of silence open's got to use the game started yet yeah about five minutes ago
who's running goals of course what that wasn't a foul come on raf so
sorry shack always screws up free throws you were right he didn't make a shot
yeah that was a great shot three pointer yeah did you see that he traveled
the raf didn't even call his ref needs glasses hey raf open your eyes can't believe it
see that okay I did the first quarter alright I'm gonna make a beer run
okay guys I hope you enjoyed our lesson today we'll be bringing you more sports lessons
future yes so if you have a particular sport that you want to learn about you can
tell us and we have our website EnglishPod.com yeah and leave us your comments or
your suggestions or any doubts that you have and we're always there to answer it so
we'll see you there yes until next time bye