Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we have a special lesson for Arlar's sci-fi or science fiction
fans.
Yes and actually one special user was the inspiration for this lesson.
Wolfgang, this one is for you.
Well sci-fi is very popular star-tracks, star wars.
And well there are some really interesting words that maybe you wouldn't use in real life
or in normal circumstances but you do want to understand these movies or why they say
these words, right?
So we're going to look at some sci-fi language in this lesson.
But before we start, let's look at vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
And in vocabulary preview today we have one phrase only.
That's right.
And identified spacecraft.
Unidentified spacecraft.
Okay so unidentified.
You don't know which one it is.
You don't know the name, you don't know the identity.
Yes.
Okay and a spacecraft.
A spacecraft is a vehicle that travels in space.
Okay also known as a spaceship.
That's right.
Actually this is interesting because you know the word UFO.
Yes.
That comes from.
Unidentified flying objects.
Exactly.
So unidentified spacecraft.
An unknown vehicle flying in space.
Right.
A UFO.
Have you ever seen a UFO?
No.
Yes.
Have you?
Of course.
Hasn't any of it?
Well I think the people in our dialogue may or may not have seen a UFO.
So why don't we take a look at that?
They all breaking through.
Such a blast, just a full power.
Excellent job.
Search the ship.
She's got to be in here somewhere.
Bring her to me.
Oh.
More handkerchief.
We have a survivor here.
Where is she?
Don't make me destroy you.
Tell me where she is.
Not so fast.
She will no longer be your prisoner.
It's time you and I settled this once and for all.
You are unwise, I think you can defeat me.
You know nothing of the power of your obscure side.
We win a stop.
More handkerchief.
We have an unwise identified spacecraft taking off from the rare dock.
They somehow managed to escape out of the trucker bay.
After that.
They are accelerating towards the speed of light.
We lost them, sir.
Okay, so a really cool Lord Hater.
You know the music and everything.
Well, you may have noticed that it's similar to a certain movie out there.
I don't know.
I mean, seems quite original to me.
But everything for educational purposes.
That's right.
Okay, so we saw some words that were maybe a little bit difficult.
So let's take a look at these now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, I guess in the dialogue, the bad guys were breaking through.
Breaking through.
In the simple present, it would be to break through.
Okay, break through.
And what does that mean?
Well, let's listen to some examples to help us find out.
Example one.
After 15 minutes, the worker is broke through the wall and rescued everyone from the fire.
Example two.
He is such a good player.
He broke through the entire defense.
Example three.
They are breaking through our impenetrable wall.
Run.
All right, so it's kind of like to enter by four somewhere.
Yeah, to maybe break some glass and come into a room or something like that.
Break through.
Yeah.
All right, so Lord Hater had a fight with his enemy.
And he said he wants to settle this.
To settle this.
So what do you do when you settle something?
Well, when you settle something is you end a fight or a dispute or an argument or an argument or a problem.
Yeah, when you settle an argument, does everyone always agree?
No, not always, right?
Sometimes you are forced to agree.
Okay, not everyone agrees, but you have no other choice.
So it's a little bit different from reaching an agreement because those usually a winner and a loser.
Right, exactly.
Well, now another very popular word and within sci-fi is this word tractor beam.
Tractor beam.
A tractor beam.
Now I'm not sure of this really exists in real life.
Well, I've never heard of it.
But a tractor beam in sci-fi movies is like this invisible force that grabs an object and doesn't let it escape and brings it towards another spaceship.
So it's like almost like a rope that you can't see.
Right, and it brings it in.
So the spaceship managed to escape their tractor beam.
Okay, I think that is definitely not true.
Well, maybe, I don't know, but in sci-fi you will always hear this tractor beam.
Okay.
Now let's move on to our final word.
This spaceship was accelerating towards the speed of light accelerating.
Accelerating.
To a celery.
That's right.
So that means to increase speed.
Yeah, just to go faster.
To go faster.
So if you are in your car, you want to accelerate so you can pass another car.
Okay.
Or even when you stop at a red light and it turns green, you got to accelerate.
To accelerate.
This listens to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and take a look at some of the phrases that came up in this dialogue.
The breaking through such a blaster's to full power.
Excellent job.
Search the ship.
She's got to be in here somewhere.
Bring her to me.
Lord, hey, we have a survivor here.
Where is she?
Don't make me destroy you.
Tell me where she is.
Not so fast.
She will no longer be a prisoner.
It's time you and I settled this once and for all.
You are unwise to think you can defeat me.
You know nothing of the power of the obscure side.
We will stop you.
Lord, heard of.
We have an unidentified spacecraft taking off from the rear dock.
They somehow managed to escape our tractor beam.
After them, they are accelerating towards the speed of light.
We lost them, sir.
We will see the future.
We'll see the future.
Great.
I think that's a little bit more clear this time.
But Marko said, I want to look at now some phrases that you might hear in a sci-fi context.
Fluency Builder.
So, Lillancy Builder.
The first phrase that we can take a look at,
and maybe it looks a little bit strange.
He said, she will no longer be your prisoner.
No longer be.
So, what is he mean by no longer?
Anymore.
Anymore, right?
Yeah, so you will not be my prisoner anymore.
Okay.
So, how would I use it in this form no longer be?
You've always got to use it in the future tense.
Okay.
She'll no longer be your prisoner.
I will no longer be your employee.
Okay.
Or I can say, I will no longer be your boyfriend.
So, it's always will no longer be.
It's always in the future.
Okay.
One more thing, Marco.
Is this quite commonly used or maybe a little bit formal?
I think it's a little bit formal.
And it's very, I don't know, to a certain point, poetic.
Yeah.
Which I think is why we hear a little bit more often in sci-fi movies.
All right.
So, no longer be.
What about our next phrase?
You know nothing of the power of the obscure side.
Okay.
You know nothing of.
So, again, it's very poetic.
Yeah.
I think.
Basically, meaning you don't know about.
You don't know about.
Yeah.
So, again, let's take a look at how you would use it.
You know nothing of and then science fiction.
You know nothing of science fiction.
Yeah.
So, you would use a noun afterwards.
Exactly.
Okay.
So, interesting phrases.
Again, the formal and probably quite often used in science fiction movies.
But now you can understand when they use some of these words that maybe are a little
bit difficult and very common in these types of movies.
Now let's go to our last phrase.
Then this one actually can be used in many different circumstances.
Let's settle this once and for all.
Okay.
So, we saw the word settle already.
Now let's settle this once and for all.
What's in for all?
So, what does that mean?
Finally.
That's right.
Forever.
Okay.
So, once and for all forever.
So, why don't we listen to some other examples of how we can use this phrase once
and for all in different contexts?
Example one.
I'm fed up with arguing about this.
That's just settle the argument once and for all.
Example two.
He claims his photographs prove once and for all that UFOs do exist.
Example three.
I told him once and for all that I don't want to be used.
He's gone for anything more.
Okay.
So, now I think it's clear we've seen a lot of words.
We've seen a lot of phrases.
Let's listen to our dialogue one more time.
There are breaking through.
Show Blastos the full power.
Excellent job.
Search the ship.
She's got to be in here somewhere.
Bring her to me.
Lord Hanger, we have a survivor here.
Where is she?
Don't make me destroy you.
Tell me where she is.
Not so fast.
She will no longer be a prisoner.
It's time you and I settled this once and for all.
You are unwise and think you can defeat me.
You know nothing of the power of your obscure side.
We will stop you.
More Hanger, we have an unwise and defyed spacecraft taking off from the rare dock.
They somehow managed to escape out of the tractor bay.
After that.
There are accelerating boards of speed of light.
We lost them sir.
Okay, so are you a big sci-fi fan?
I think as you can tell, no.
Actually, I've seen some of the Star Wars movies, but everyone that I've watched, I've
fallen asleep in the middle of the night.
Really?
Yeah.
Even in the movie theater, I fell asleep in the movie theater, watching Star Wars.
Wow, was it too boring?
It was too boring.
You're not really into the fantasy.
No, I just have the whole time I'm sitting there going, this cannot happen.
Well, that's why it's called science fiction, right?
Yes.
But it is interesting to some people and well, behind Star Wars, there is a huge culture.
Even some people know some of the languages or symbols that are used in it, or the names of some of the robots and models of spacecraft.
Well, maybe we'll have to come up with Star Wars pies.
Exactly.
Well, that's all for today, guys.
I hope you enjoyed our lesson and of course, if you have questions or comments,
you can leave them in a comment section on our website EnglishPod.com.
Well, thanks for listening you guys and until next time, goodbye.