Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we've got a great lesson for you about traveling and getting
directions. That's right so sometimes we are looking for an address, we are looking for our
friend's house and we can't find it so what do you have to do? You have to stop and ask someone for
directions. It's actually a joke in many countries that men hate to ask for directions and so this
the women's approach asking and getting directions and finally finding your way so it's a good thing.
That's a very good thing so we're going to jump right into the dialogue. Let's see what happens here
and if they can find the place you're looking for.
We've been going around in circles for the past hour. Will you just please stop and ask for
we are not lost. I'm just taking the scenic route. Yeah whatever I told you we should buy that GPS
that was on sale but would you listen to me? No this is so typical. Fine I'll ask this guy for
directions if it will shut your trap. Excuse me sir can you tell me how to get to Saint Mary's Church?
Sure go down park road turn left go up as far as the set of traffic lights and turn left.
The place you're looking for is the second building on the right. Thanks.
See was that hard? If you would only listen to me more often you would be better off.
All right we're back so well the woman was obviously a little bit angry that the guy refused to admit
that he was lost. That's right she's very frustrated and this has been in movies and in books and
all sorts of things this kind of story of the man not wanting to ask for directions and so
he keeps saying listen I've got these excuses. I'm taking the scenic route for example.
That's right and that's our first word for today on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So as you say the scenic route what does he mean by that? Okay route is like a
path or a trail or kind of like the way that you go somewhere so the routes to my house but in this
case the scenic route or the scenic route you can say in both ways is the most beautiful way to go.
It's a little bit longer than longer one yeah so you can say oh it's just the scenic route.
It's not really true it's just the longer route. Right exactly so that's the excuse that he's
giving her is like no I'm not lost we're taking longer because well we're taking the beautiful route.
All right with all the trees and the animal of the lakes no I don't I don't buy it I don't believe this that's
right and she said yeah whatever you know what we need a GPS okay GPS global positioning system
so many people have these in their cars these days this is like an electronic map that will
use your location to show you where to go. It's very useful and especially in places like the
United States that have streets that are clearly marked and it's just a little bit easier to get
around you know you can just getting your car type in the address you want to go to and the thing
talks to you it says turn left to go straight turn right creepy so this is a very useful
device it's like a computer that you use in your computer at GPS. All right so she's talking about the GPS
and then at the end of that line she says this is so typical. So what getting lost all right
getting lost is so typical. So something that is typical is common is this is so normal this is so
typical this is so something you normally do. So what other examples could we give with the word
typical something that is typical? Okay well you can have a behavior like this what he did with
typical. We can also say in my typical Saturday I wake up late and drink a coffee and take an
app. Okay cool so it's common it's regular it's frequent maybe. That's right or you know you go
at the dinner and your friend is late you say oh this is so typical of him. Right he's always late.
Okay very good. All right and we have one last set of words here and when the guy was giving
him instructions he said you know what go a laugh go write whatever and then he said until you
reach the set of traffic lights. So what is a traffic light? Well you know what a light is you know
a traffic is traffic is cars driving on the road trucks things like that. So traffic light is a
special light with three colors red yellow and green and it tells you if you can stop or go.
So they're also called stop lights right? That's right. Okay so stop lights and traffic lights
is the same thing usually they hang from above the street. Okay very good words and phrases there
why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in just a little bit.
We've been going around in circles for the past hour will you just please stop and ask for
directions. We are not lost I'm just taking the scenic route. Yeah whatever I told you we should
buy that GPS that was on sale but would you listen to me? No this is so typical. Fine I'll ask
this guy for directions if it will shut your trap. Excuse me sir can you tell me how to get to
Saint Mary's Church? Sure go down park road turn left go up as far as the set of traffic lights
and turn left the place you're looking for is the second building on the right. Thanks.
See was that hard if you would only listen to me more often you would be better off.
Alright so you've got some great phrases coming up in fluency builder fluency builder.
So the first phrase that we're going to look at is what the wife said at the very beginning she said
we have been going around in circles for the past hour. Going around in circles. So we could
say we've been driving in circles. In circles means you've been making the same route over and
over and over again you keep seeing the same house the same tree the same house the same tree.
So this means we're not going anywhere. You could also say Marco I wish you had brought the map.
We've been walking in circles for two hours. Okay okay so you can use it if you're driving or if
you're walking in any situation like that. Exactly. Okay good. All right so going around in
circles. Now moving on the guy was a little bit irritated with her and he said something that's a
little bit in place. You said you know what I'm going to ask for directions if it will shut your trap.
In polite this is rude. This is rude. Yeah this is very rude so be careful when you use this.
You can say pay shut your trap. Okay so shut means to close but trap this is your mouth.
Okay your mouth is a trap. It's kind of like a trap. In this case shut your trap is a set phrase and it
means shut up. Be quiet. Stop talking. So how can we say this in a nicer way? For example I've heard
people say you're yapp. Shut your yapp. Yeah shut your yapper. I would say can you please stop talking
or can we have some quiet time now? Can we have some quiet time? Yeah that's a polite way.
The the rude way is shut up. Shut up. Shut your mouth. That's very direct though right? Very rude.
Yeah that's right. Okay so shut your trap. Shut your trap. And then the wife said well see there you go.
We got directions. We're going to get there now and was that hard? If you would only listen to me
more often you would be better off so the guy would be better off that doesn't really make much sense.
To be better off okay so you have to think of this as a phrase not about the individual words.
To be better off means to be happier or in some way better. So for example if I earned more money
I think I'd be better off. Okay so I have a nicer life. To be happier maybe more successful.
Right. Right. Or if you only listen to me you would be better off.
Means you would make better decisions. You would have a better situation.
So I could say if she got a divorce she would be better off. That's why her life would
improve her life wouldn't improve. To be better off this is a great great very useful phrase.
Very useful. All right so why don't we listen to the dialogue for the very last time and what we
back to talk a little bit more with you.
We've been going around in circles for the past hour will you just please stop and ask for directions.
We are not lost. I'm just taking the scenic route. Yeah whatever I told you we should buy that GPS
that was on sale. But would you listen to me? No this is so typical.
Fine. I'll ask this guy for directions if it will shut your trap. Excuse me sir.
Can you tell me how to get to Saint Mary's Church?
Sure. Go down park road turn left go up as far as the set of traffic lights and turn left.
The place you're looking for is the second building on the right.
Thanks. See was that hard? If you would only listen to me more often you would be better off.
All right so the whole thing about men asking for directions. Why do you think a man don't like
to ask for directions? Well it depends on the person but I think a lot of people don't like to admit
that they don't know. Okay because if you ask for directions it means I don't know where I'm going
I need help. So this is one problem. The other problem is sometimes directions are bad.
I think so too. Sometimes when you receive an invitation or instructions and how to get to someone's
house they're very ambiguous. They're like you know you passed the dog that's sitting at the corner
and you're like there's no dog. What? How? Yeah I know I know someone who lives in Costa Rica and
her address is go down the main street to take the second left after the post office and after that
take the right after the general store and 400 pieces is the house. So there's no address. There's no
address. You know so it happened. These instructions can be very confusing and very vague like you said.
So I think there's a couple of different problems potentially. I also heard a joke the other day about
kid asked his mom. He said hey why was Moses leading everyone through the desert for 40 years?
And she's like because he refused to ask for directions. Funny. I like that. I was going to say why
because he's going in circles. All right so if you have any questions about today's lessons or comments
maybe you can tell us do you like to ask for directions or do you like to figure things out alone?
Let us know on our website EnglishPod.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye bye.