Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right today we're going to take a look at our mobile phones but not the physical phone.
Now we're going to talk about services that you can get for your mobile phone.
All right so in America and many other places you don't buy that little card with money on it.
You actually have to pay every month for a service.
So we're going to learn about this today. Let's check out our dialogue.
Hello.
Tell Como, how can I help you?
Yes, I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
Certainly sir. We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
colliding and also three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great. Are there any other fees?
Not at all. No hidden fees are surcharges. It is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect. I also wanted to note there's any call forwarding service.
I am usually out of town and would like my calls to be forwarded to a local number.
Yes of course. We can activate all these services in about an hour.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some of these services on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Some are going to go the first word that I want to talk about today is this verb to activate.
That's right we have a verb here to activate. In this means to make something start to work
to make something begin. That's right so to turn on but you don't say hey can you activate the light
right right you wouldn't say that you say can you turn on the light but to activate means to
start a service. That's right. So this is what we want today. We want to activate some services
and the first one that we asked for is voicemail service. Voicemail service. Now let's think about
the words that make up this one word. Voicemail. Voicemail so it's like a mailbox for your phone.
That's right where you leave messages obviously not text messages but you leave voice messages.
That's right so you know I'm sorry I cannot answer the phone right now. Please leave a message
after the beep. That's my voice mail message. That's right so it's actually a very useful thing.
We'll talk about that a little bit later but let's take a look at our next service. We also want to get
call waiting. All right so this is a very interesting service. I don't know if they have this
and other parts of the world but in America if I'm talking on the phone to you Marco,
nor having a nice conversation but then my mom calls. When I'm talking I hear beep, beep, beep. I hear
some sounds and that means someone else is trying to call you. That's right. All right so you can't
hear this but I can hear this and that means if I want to talk to my mom I'll say hey Marco
listen someone else's calling can I call you tomorrow. That's right so actually the call waiting is a
very useful service because the person that's calling you will never get a busy signal. You'll
always seem available but the good thing is that you can switch between calls. So I could say hey
Marco listen I think that's my mom can you hold can you wait I will be right back and then I push
a button and then I can talk to my mom and then my mom says okay I'll talk to you later I push a
button and then Marco you're there. That's right that's right. Very useful service as well. Now let's
take a look at our next service that we are also getting as part of this package we are getting
three way calling. So from the name of this we can think of three people talking all right so
maybe Marco you want to talk to my mom too. That's right so we can talk and then we add another
person so you can call a third phone number one two three me you and someone else and the three of us
can talk at the same time. That's right so it's kind of a way of having a small conference between
three people. That's right and so this is what you can do with three way calling you can call two
people simultaneously and talk to them at the same time. So a lot of great services here I think we've
learned a couple of different things why don't we review it and listen to the dialogue again.
Tell Como, how can I help you? Yes I'd like to activate my voicemail service please. Certainly sir.
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
call waiting and also three way calling. Sure that sounds great. Are there any other fees?
Not at all? No hidden fees or surcharges it is a flat monthly rate. Perfect. I also wanted to know if there's
any call forwarding service. I am usually out of town and would like my call to be forwarded to a
local number. Yes of course we can activate all these services in about an hour.
All right we're back so now let's keep on going here towards the last half of our dialogue.
Let's take a look at some more words on language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway. So this first phrase in language takeaway part two is hidden fees.
Hidden fees. What are the? The operator guarantees that there are no hidden fees. So this is usually
what we call the fine print. The small fees that we don't really know about so they say oh it costs
$3 a month but you have small little hidden fees like if you're late on a payment they'll charge
you an extra dollar or if you use the service too much they'll charge you another extra dollar.
Right so a fee is something that you pay. All right and something that is hidden means you cannot see it.
And so like you're saying with this example there are many many conditions, many many different
things rules that we have to follow and if we don't follow those rules exactly then maybe this
company that provides the phone service will ask us for more and more money. That's right and actually
has to do a lot with our next word where she said that there are also no surcharges.
Okay so a surcharge is an extra amount of money that you have to pay. So we say that this service
has no hidden fees or surcharge. So that means that we don't have to pay anything additional to
what we are already paying. For example some companies will say okay pay us $10 and you get your new
cell phone phone plan. But to activate your service is another $5. So the total price is $15 and
that's a surcharge that's an extra fee that you have to pay. That's right. Okay and continuing on
the topic of money she says it is a flat monthly rate, a flat monthly rate. Well monthly is an
adverb that tells us how often we pay. We pay one time every month but this term flat rate is
very, very important and it happened we use this term a lot when we're talking about
paying fees. So a flat rate means it does not change when you for example talk more on the phone.
That's right. So you pay the same amount every month. That's right. A clear example is
probably your internet service provider. You pay $20 a month and that's a flat rate. If you use the
internet 24 hours a day and nothing happens you don't pay more. If you use it less you still pay the
same amount of money. So what if I pay $10 normally? But this month I use the internet a lot.
And now I have to pay $15. Is that a flat rate? No, no that's not a flat rate. Okay that's a chain
that that changes with my use. That's right. Okay and now let's take a look at one last service that
this man was also interested in getting and he says that he wants to get a call forwarding service.
He wants to forward his calls to a local number. Okay so to forward something means to
pass it along. So call forwarding means that if I'm not available for example, I'm not at home and
someone calls my home. There's no one there to talk to the person that's calling. Then maybe I
could have a call forwarding service that will make the call go to my cellular phone.
All right. So the call forwarding means that the call will travel to another phone. That's right.
So as you said this is what call forwarding is and the word to forward as you said to pass along.
Maybe many of you have done it in your emails when you get maybe a nice message. You forward it
to more of your friends and this is the exact same definition. Exactly. So you have one message and
you pass it on to someone else. And so call forwarding. You normally have this service if you're
often on business trips or traveling you're out of town. That's right. It's very, very helpful
for people who are not in one place all the time. That's right. So why don't we listen to the dialogue
one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
Tell Como, how can I help you? Yes. I'd like to activate my voicemail service please. Certainly,
sir. We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
call waiting and also three-way calling. Sure. That sounds great. Are there any other fees?
Not at all? No hidden fees or surcharges. It is a flat monthly rate. Perfect. I also wanted to know
if there's any call forwarding service. I am usually out of town and would like my call to be
forwarded to a local number. Yes, of course. We can activate all these services in about an hour.
So talking about all these services. It's very interesting because many of these services
are not really available everywhere in the world. Like for example voicemail. That's right. So in China,
no one really has voicemail. It's very strange for an American because you think, well, if I'm not
home, I want to know why this person called. But oftentimes you just have to call back and find out.
That's right. And actually, I really think that voicemail service is a very good thing, especially
if you need to leave a message for someone, hey, we're at the restaurant coming back when you have a
chance. But also a call waiting. I really really hate to call someone and have the busy, you know,
the busy tone. Yeah. And then you know that they're on the telephone, but you don't know when they
will stop talking on this really annoys me too, especially when I call for delivery food from
a restaurant. It's like, please answer your phone. But maybe someone's ordering a lot of food.
That's right. So actually, these services are very common in the United States. And I'm sure
even more services now, I know that you can have a telephone number, for example, in another
country, but it'll ring in the United States. Yeah, that's right. Or you can connect your computer
and your messaging service and all these things to your phone. So it's pretty, pretty technologically
advanced. But I'm very curious to know about, you guys are listeners, what kind of services for your
cell phone or for your landline do you have? Do you have call forwarding or voicemail? Let us know
our website is englishpad.com. All right, we'll see everyone there. Bye.