Hello everyone and welcome to another lesson here at English Pod. My name is Marco
and I'm Katherine and today we have an elementary level lesson all about life with a roommate
That's right so sometimes during college you have to live with a roommate because you know
living alone is too expensive. Also after college I know that a lot of people who are just
starting their jobs often live with a roommate to save some money. That's right or maybe
your girlfriend could be considered kind of like your romantic roommate. I hope not. In the sense
of today's lesson we're talking about problems with a roommate so let's listen to this dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment. Charlie do you have a second? Yeah what's up? Well I went and
the bills today and you still haven't given me your half. Yeah I wanted to talk to about that.
I agreed we would go halves on all the bills but frankly I think it's unfair.
Unfair? Why? Well you have long hair and use the hair dryer every morning I don't. You'll
leave your computer on all night downloading torrents I don't. You see what I'm getting at here?
You leave the air conditioner on day and night you also take 30 minutes showers which means you're
using way more gas and water than me. Well while we're on the subject stop bringing your friends
over for drinks every weekend. You always leave a mess and keep me up all night. Maybe you should just
move out and find another place. Maybe you should move out.
All right we're back so we have a couple of different words that we're going to take a look at
now in language takeaway. Language takeaway. So the first word is a dreaded word that means that most
people don't like it they fear it. This is bills. That's right you have to pay your bills.
So a bill is the paper that tells you how much you have to pay. That's right so you can have a gas bill.
And electricity bill. A cable bill. Or even at the restaurant you ask for the bill.
All right so this is the amount of money you need to pay. That's right. And usually at the end of the
month you receive many many bills in the mail and you have to pay the companies like the gas company
and the electricity company. That's right so those are bills. A singular would be a bill.
Okay. And so this is how the argument starts. The two roommates decide that they have to pay the bills
but they don't want to split the bills in half. Go have. They have to pay their own. And so one
person says listen this isn't fair. You leave your computer on all night downloading torrents.
Okay so we understand what it is to download something or you download this podcast but a torrent.
What is that? That's kind of technical. That is so a torrent is a kind of file that you can download
from the internet. So basically when you want to download a movie or some music from the internet
you go to a website that will connect you to someone who owns this movie or book or music and they
will have a special file that's called a torrent file and that's what you download. That's right.
So it's a new way of downloading files off the internet from many people kind of like a peer sharing.
That's right. So when one person disappears or goes offline it shares you with another person.
That's right. So those are torrents and now well they kept arguing about you have to pay this.
I have to pay that. So you said you know what you should just move out.
Ooh. So to move out this is a phrase that has two words to move out it means to leave this house forever.
This apartment. So that means to find a new place to live. Right. So I can say, oh I'm moving out
this weekend. That means I'm changing apartments. Right. Or my boyfriend just moved out.
Okay. So that's really sad. He left your house. Okay. So that is to move out.
And now we have a word that is more colloquial of how to say a house or an apartment.
This is place. Okay. Just say a place. So place normally is a location.
Okay. Where is this place? But we could say, hey, we're going to have dinner at my place.
Would you like to come? So that means we're going to have dinner at my house.
Right. My place. My his place. His place. His place. Or you have a really nice place.
Thanks. Okay. So that means you would have a really nice house. Exactly. Okay. So four key words today
when we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit.
Charlie, do you have a second? Yeah. What's up? Well I went and paid the bills today
and you still haven't given me your half. Yeah. I wanted to talk to you about that.
I agreed we would go have on all the bills but frankly I think it's unfair.
Unfair? Why? Well you have long hair and use the hairdryer every morning. I don't.
You leave your computer on all night downloading torrents. I don't. You see what I'm getting at here?
You leave the air conditioner on day and night. You also take 30 minutes showers
which means you're using way more gas and water than me. Well while we're on the subject,
stop bringing your friends over for drinks every weekend. You always leave a mess and keep me up all night.
Maybe you should just move out and find another place. Maybe you should move out.
Alright we are back and we've got some great phrases today coming up in fluency builders. Let's
take a look at some of those fluency builder. Alright so the first phrase that we have
very common, very very common but also very difficult for English learners to answer this question.
Alright what's up? What's up? So if somebody says what's up what does that mean?
That means what's going on? What's new? How are you? How is it going? Okay. Hi. So how
should you answer this? Okay so think of what's up is being a question about what's new? What's happening?
You can say what's up? Oh not much. Not much. Okay what's up means what's new? Oh not much is new.
Not much. Everything is the same. Or what's up? You could say, hey, hi how are you? It's another way to say
hi. Okay but you can't say this guy. Right or sometimes English learners will say fine thank you
because they think that what's up means how are you? No that's different. So you cannot say fine thank
you fine well these are words about how that answer how are you questions but this isn't
how are you question this is a what's new question? What's new or hi? Okay so somebody says what's
up you can say not much or you can say hey what's up you can say what's up back? What's up what's
up with you? Yeah what's up with you? Okay so that's our first phrase. Now when the guy was talking
about the hair dryer and the computer he finished off that paragraph by saying you see what I'm
getting at here. Okay you're doing this use the hair dryer leave the computer on do you see what I'm
getting at here this phrase do you see what I'm getting at? It means do you understand what I'm
talking about do you see my point? That means I haven't said exactly what I mean but you should
understand what I'm saying so he's saying you're wasting electricity. You use all of these
services more than I do. Right and we could say maybe Marko didn't get a good grant his English
test last week I say listen maybe it has to do with your study habits or how much you love video
or how little time you spend at school do you see what I'm getting at? Okay so you're not
saying directly that I don't study you're telling me the reasons maybe why as to I'm not studying.
Right like a hint. Okay so that's what you say when you don't tell somebody directly what the problem
is you say you see what I'm getting at here? Do you see what I'm getting at? Okay. Getting at means
hinting. Mm-hmm okay and our last phrase when they kept talking about the bills
one of the person said you are using way more gas and water than me. So what about this way more?
Way more. Way means much or a lot so we could say you are using a lot more water than I am or
you're using way more water. Okay. This is very spoken language this is not written language
so don't write this down on your tests but a way more means a lot more much more. Okay you can
say Bob is way more attractive than Bill. That's right or this is way more interesting than that show.
Okay so you can say way more instead of much more or a lot more but it's usually spoken English.
Exactly. All right let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a bit to talk a
little bit more. Charlie do you have a second? Yeah what's up? Well I went and paid the bills today
and you still haven't given me your half. Yeah I wanted to talk to about that. I agreed we would go
have on all the bills but frankly I think it's unfair. Unfair? Why? Well you have long hair and
use the hairdryer every morning I don't. You leave your computer on all night downloading
torrents I don't. You see what I'm getting at here? You leave the air conditioner on day and night
you also take 30 minutes showers which means you're using way more gas and water than me.
Well while we're on the subject stop bringing your friends over for drinks every weekend.
You always leave a mess and keep me up all night. Maybe you should just move out and find another place.
Maybe you should move out.
So Marco have you ever had any of these problems with a roommate? I've actually stayed away from
roommates because of issues like this. You have not had many roommates because you're afraid of
this situation. Yeah I've always actually tried to live on my own by myself like in a small
apartment or studio or if I have to have a roommate maybe just like one not like a house full of
roommates because I think the more people there are they're a little bit more complicated it gets and if
it's just too you know it's a little bit simpler. This is true although sometimes I think it depends
on the people that you're sharing a house with. I've had one awkward experience where people
did not want to pay ever and they were always late with their payments and one situation where
people were very good about it. So always remembered and we're very helpful so it really depends.
Yeah yeah I think it's hard to live with someone always of course even you know if
if you start living with your girlfriend or boyfriend or you get married it's kind of different to
live with someone you know so and especially money wise I think it always complicates things with people.
Definitely so I think you're right though if there's two people it's very easy to share the bills
but if there's five people or six people it's very hard to find out who spent more money or what the rules
are. Yeah so it can get a little bit complicated but I'm sure a lot of our listeners have probably
had roommates before maybe in college maybe even now so let's hear those experiences and maybe
those good and bad stories about living with other people. So please get in touch with us. Our
website is englishpod.com there's lots of places for you to ask questions and to post your own
experiences with roommates. We hope to see you there and until next time. Bye everyone.