Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica
and we're bringing you another great elementary lesson today
one that takes place at the office
yes today we're going to teach you some great phrases so that you can ask people to help you
right and I think this dialogue is with a new person at the office
so when you're new you always need to ask people for favor
exactly
okay
so we're going to be asking for a favor
so Marco what exactly is a favor?
something that a person does for you
like a small helpful thing
yeah a small helpful thing so you know like
can you pass me that pencil maybe that's even a favor
yeah or maybe can you pick me up on your way to work
yeah that's a favor or even lending money to your friend
that's a favor
so that's what we're going to be talking about favors and how to ask for one
because you always have to do this at work
at work with your friends with your family
so let's listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and explain all the vocabulary
um sorry to bother you um my name is Rachel
I'm new here
can I ask you for a favor?
hi Rachel welcome on board
I'm afraid it can help you right now
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting
excuse me but can I bother you for a second?
you know what I'd love to help you but I'm about to meet an important client
don't ask Sean instead
please it's right over there
sorry to interrupt you Sean
could you do me a quick favor?
and actually I'm working in a document that's doing a couple of minutes
I really can't talk right now aside about that
geez
I just want to know where the bathroom is
what's wrong with you people
so a pretty busy office
pretty unhelpful colleagues
I know everyone's so busy they didn't help this poor girl
yeah I hope she found the bathroom
now let's take a look at the language from the dialogue
so let's start with language takeaway
language takeaway
there's some great language in the dialogue wasn't there
yeah a lot of interesting phrases and words
the first one that I saw that was really interesting is unboard
unboard
welcome unboard
well we've got some examples of how this phrase is used
so let's listen to them to help us understand the meaning
example one
welcome on board Sarah
if you have any questions please feel free to ask me
example two
we need to get our new office assistant on board as soon as possible
example three
we decided to bring Melissa on board to join the marketing team
so basically it means
welcome to the company
or the team
yeah
welcome on board
so unboard is the same as to the company
I guess also when you get on a ship they'll tell you welcome on board
yes that's where it comes from
or an airplane
yeah yeah
welcome on board
okay let's take a look at our next word
about two
I'm about two
so this is a great phrase to explain that you're about to do something
I'm going to do this thing really soon
okay so for example you can say
I'm about to go out for lunch
or I could say hey Marco let's go record a show
I'm about to go into a meeting
right
yeah
about to
going to do something really soon
okay
the next word we have is instead
instead
it means
in the place
yeah
so for example if we're at dinner I could say
I'll have the chicken instead of the fish
right
or I can say I wanted to buy a red sweater
but they didn't have one
so I bought a blue one
instead
okay so in the place of
yeah
and our last word for language takeaway
interrupt
so when somebody interrupts you they come in
they talk to you while you're doing something
or maybe while you're speaking
or maybe you're busy
people come in
and bother you
bother you yeah
okay
so interrupt
interrupt
okay some great words here in our dialogue
and now we can listen to it again
this time it's going to be a little bit slower
and you'll be able to understand the language a little bit better
um
sorry to bother you
my name is Rachel
I'm new here
can I ask you for a favor
Hi Rachel
welcome on board
I'm afraid I can't help you right now
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting
excuse me
but can I bother you for a second
you know what?
I'd love to help you
about to meet an important client
do you want to try shawn instead
he sits right over there
sorry to interrupt you shawn
could you do me a quick favor
actually and working on a document that is due in a couple of minutes
I really can't talk to you right now
sorry about that
geez
I just want to know where the bathroom is
what's wrong with you people
okay so there are some great ways that you can ask someone for a favor
right?
yeah we want to show you some really useful phrases for asking for help
so let's start with putting it together
put it together
let's listen to some different ways of how you can ask someone for a favor
example one
may I get you to do me a favor
can you call this package and you'll suit me
example two
can I ask you a favor?
can you just finish this report for me?
example three
can you give me a favor and pass me that file?
okay so those were great examples of asking for a favor
inner dialogue we heard can I ask you a favor?
but we could also say can I get you to do me a favor?
can I get you to do me a favor?
also I could say will you do me a favor?
will you do me a favor?
so those are different ways of asking for a favor
let's say you want to ask someone for a favor
but they're busy
right?
so you'll need some phrases to help you do this
exactly you need some phrases to interrupt somebody
right?
so let's listen to some examples of what phrases you can use to begin to talk to someone
yeah to interrupt them
okay
I hate to bother you but
I'm sorry to bother you but
I don't mean to bother you but
okay so those are really nice and polite ways of beginning to talk to someone
exactly they're really useful at the office
so maybe you want to talk to your boss
you knock on his door kind of open it a little bit and say
I'm sorry to bother you but
I was wondering if you have time for a meeting today
or you could say
I hate to bother you but
do you have time for a meeting today?
exactly
so those are great ways of starting up a conversation
yeah and maybe setting it up to ask for a favor
right?
so we can combine them
I could say
I hate to bother you but
can you do me a favor?
Perfect
right?
yeah really useful
so then you can ask someone for a favor
yeah
okay great stuff
so I guess we can listen to our dialogue again
yeah let's listen to our dialogue for the third time
and this time I'm sure you'll understand it a lot better
um sorry to bother you
um my name is Rachel
I'm new here
can I ask you for a favor?
I'm Rachel
welcome on board
I'm afraid I can't help you right now
I'm getting ready for a very important meeting
excuse me
but can I bother you for a second?
you know what?
I do love to help you
but I'm about to meet an important client
do I ask Sean instead?
please it's right over there
sorry to interrupt you Sean
could you do me a quick favor?
actually I'm working in a document
that's doing a couple of minutes
I really can't talk right now
sorry about that
geez
I just want to know where the bathroom is
what's wrong with you people
I'm just going to ask you
alright so now you have all the vocabulary
necessary the next time you need to ask someone
for a favor
yes
at the office with your friends with your family
anyone
well everyone we are out of time for today
but remember to visit our website
at EnglishPod.com
exactly at our website you'll find
the script of the dialogue
and also you'll find intermediate lessons
upper-intermediate
and even advanced
yeah exactly
our website is a great resource for learning
a Marco and I are always there to answer your questions
and we also have lots of helpful users
who answer your questions
exactly so don't miss out
come to our website at EnglishPod.com
and we'll see you there
until next time
bye
you