Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we're going to have some fun today, Marco, right?
That's right. Today we are taking a small kid and we're going to the park and we're going to play.
Okay, so there are fun things you can do at the park. We're going to learn all about them.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Hey honey, where were you?
I decided to take any of the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were there a lot of kids?
It wasn't too crowded but we had a great time.
We got on the sea saw together.
Then we went on a couple of different slides and then I tried to go with him in the jungle gym but I didn't fit.
Sounds like fun. When we go he always just likes to play in the sandbox.
Yeah, but today he was really hyper. He even got under the monkey bars.
And then he went on to go on the swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted.
You should go to the park more often since you don't go to the gym anymore.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of this great playground equipment on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So as you said, Marco, today we're focusing in language takeaway on some of these things you can do at the park.
Now the first one is one of my personal favorites from childhood called the seesaw.
The seesaw. That's right. And so basically it's that long piece of or sometimes metal or wood
and two people sit at each opposite end. Yes. And so when one person goes down the other person goes up
and when that person goes down the other person goes up. So it's a seesaw. That's right.
So yes, it's actually a very common toy that you can play with at the playground.
But also another very common one. I'm sure everyone knows and has been on is a slide.
A slide. Now this is a bit hard to describe actually slides are usually quite colorful.
They're like tubes that are open and the child can go down. So you're on top maybe two meters high
and then you go down the slide and you come down to the ground. That's right. And actually it's the
noun a slide. But what you do is the verb is you actually slide down the slide.
Yes. And sometimes you go very fast and it's scary. That's right. And well, if you want to have
something a little bit less scary, you can go into the jungle gym. All right. Jungle. Now the jungle
is actually a place. You know in South America for example, you have jungles with lots of trees and
monkeys and I think. But a jungle gym is like many, many different metal bars or would
together to make this open structure that boys and girls can climb on. So basically you start
on the ground and you climb all the way up it. Okay. So I think this is why it's called a kind of
like a jungle gym, right? Because you can climb up and down and grab all these bars. You can hang
like a monkey from the bars. Exactly. Yeah. So basically it's just a cage that boys and girls
can climb on and play with. Right. And I guess you call it a jungle gym because when you're doing
all this, you're doing exercise. That's right. All right. So now maybe for the smaller kids, we just want
to play with some toys. They can just hang out at the sand box. All right. This is one word, but it's
actually quite literal. You'd have sand in a box. That's right. And the sand box is very safe and
very fun because boys and girls can make castles or dig. But there's nothing to it really.
It's just a box. It's just a box with sand. Literally. Yes. That's right. So that's also fun
for the smaller kids to be at the sand box. Now going back to something very similar to the
jungle gym, we have the monkey bars. Okay. Now monkey bars are a very important part of the park.
These are horizontal bars so they're across and you hang on them with your arms so your body hangs
down and when you hang your feet are off the ground, it's very tall. Right. And you have to move.
You have to change from one bar to the other. So it's like a ladder that you're pulling yourself
across. Yes, exactly. So you've probably seen it exactly how you describe it's a ladder and you just
got to hang on to the different bars with your arms. It's actually quite difficult to do.
I always used to get upset because I couldn't go all the way across because you know you go from
one end to the other end. But my arms would get so tired that I had to drop down onto the ground.
Really. All right. Well, something that's a little bit less exhausting but also very fun
when you go on the swings. All right. Swings are great. Now swings are kind of like chairs, but they don't
have a back. So you sit down on a piece that's maybe plastic and I'm someone behind you will
because you're on these hanging chairs and you'll push you and you go forward and backward
and you can go very, very high and then you come back down. Exactly. So these are swings. All of
all of this equipment you've most likely seen at any of the of the parks that are nearby, but
we're going to post some pictures as well so you can see more clearly what they're all about.
Now let's go and review the dialogue again before we move on to Fluency Builder.
Hey honey, where were you? I decided to take any of the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were there a lot of kids? It wasn't too crowded but we had a great time.
We got on the sea saw together, then we're not on a couple of different slides and then I tried
to go with them in the jungle gym but I didn't fit. Sounds like fun. When we go, he always just likes
to play in the sandbox. Yeah, but today was really hyper. He even got under the monkey bars
and then he went on to go on the swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted. You should go to the
park more often since you don't go to the gym anymore.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at three phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. So our first phrase today is actually something that the parent is talking about.
She wants to take Kenny to the park and get some fresh air. Now what does it mean to go get fresh
well basically it means to go out and maybe walk or just be outside and get air from
the outside because sometimes you're in your house all the time and that's not fresh air.
That's right so basically this means exactly what you're saying. It means going outside.
So kids often need to go get some fresh air but also adults do too. Right. Sometimes I feel like
when I'm working in the office for a long time I really need to get some fresh air.
So that means I go outside for a walk. Exactly so you and you can tell your friends oh excuse me
for a minute I'm going to go get some fresh air. Or you know what you're looking a little bit pale.
Maybe you should go get some fresh air. Exactly and talking about all this great equipment and how
much fun you can have. The wife said wow that sounds like fun. Okay so sounds like fun.
It's not actually a sound. This phrase is really important because we say it a lot but it
actually just means that it sounds like it will be a fun time. Right. Or I think it will be fun.
Yeah so from what you're telling me I think it's fun. That's right so we can say this about a lot of
things. I could say hey Marco we're going to go play some football after work. Do you want to come?
Sure that sounds like fun. All right so he thinks it sounds like a good idea.
You're probably coming right. Exactly so if something sounds like fun all right and moving on to our
last phrase that we said that it was a great idea that we're going to the park and getting fresh air because
we don't go to the gym anymore. Okay now this is a really important phrase to keep as a phrase.
First of all we have a gym. What do you do at a gym Marco? Well you work out. Yeah you exercise
maybe you run on the treadmill or you lift weights but it's important to remember that the
verb here is to go to the gym. So I could say I go to the gym three times a week how often do you
go to the gym. Okay so that's the phrase you go to the gym. I stop going to the gym and I gain a little
weight. Okay so that's the way you use it. You don't use any other verb when you're talking about the
gym you say you go to the gym. I go to the gym he goes to the gym regularly. All right very good so
that's all the fluency builder for today let's review our dialogue one last time.
Hey honey where were you? I decided to take any of the park and get some fresh air.
How was it? Were there a lot of kids? It wasn't too crowded but we had a great time. We got on
the sea saw together then when I'm a couple of different slides and then I tried to go with them in
the jungle gym but I didn't fit. Sounds like fun when we go he always just likes to play in the
Yeah but today was really hyper he even got under the monkey bars and then he went on to go on the
swings for half an hour. I'm exhausted. You should go to the park more often since you don't go to the
gym anymore. All right so growing up there are many many different games at parks so you can
probably find especially now you have such great playground equipment but I think these are the
most basic ones that everyone knows about. That's right these are pretty standard things that you'll
see at a playground. I remember that a park doesn't have to have these things. Parkes are just
public places maybe with benches and trees but a playground is the part of the park where you'll see
these kinds of things like a slide or swings and so it's important to remember that they're not the
same. Right right and now did you ever have a bad accident or did you fall off the swing or
the seesaw or it maybe you fell off the slide. Oh I felt all the time. Never a serious accident but
swings I liked to swing and when I was forward you know up in the air I used to let go and jump.
Aha you would jump off the swing. I would jump off the swing so when you're very high in the air
it feels like you're flying for a minute. My mother hated it because she thought I was going to
break my arms but I loved it. It's great fun and actually we would really like to know maybe you
have some pictures that you can share with us of some specific playground equipment that we may have missed.
There are a lot of things out there and maybe locally there even some more fun things that we don't have.
So let us know what do playgrounds look like in your country. We hope to see you at EnglishPod.com.
Alright we'll see you guys there. Bye.