Hello English-letters, welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica. We're bringing you a great elementary podcast today.
That's right. And we're going to be teaching you how to order pizza.
Yeah, you know, pizza is one of my favorite foods and the favorite food of many people.
Exactly, it's one of those common foods that you're at home and you want to order something to eat.
And the typical thing is pizza. Yeah, but you know, there's some very special language
that you've got to use. You've got to know the slang, Go Edge, when you want to order a pizza.
Exactly. So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time as a man is ordering pizza.
Good evening, pizza host. This is Marty's beginning. May I take your order?
Um, yes, I'd like a medium pizza with pepperoni olives and extra cheese.
We have a two-for-one special on large pizzas. Would you like a large pizza instead?
Sure, that sounds good. Great. Would you like your second pizza to be the same size as the first?
No, make the second one with ham, pineapple and green peppers. Oh, and make it thin crust.
Okay, thin crust. Your total is 21-50 and your order will arrive in 30 minutes or it's free.
Perfect. Thank you, bye.
Sure, wait, I need your address.
Okay, so I guess he's not getting his pizza. No, he forgot to give his address.
That's a bit of a problem. Mm-hmm. Okay, let's take a look at some of the vocabulary in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, we've got some great pizza words for you today.
And the first one we have is a medium pizza. Medium pizza. Medium pizza.
So that's the size, right? Yeah. Medium. You can say medium or 12 inch. 12 inch.
Usually a medium pizza is 12 inches. Yeah, so you could say I'd like a 12 inch pizza.
Okay, for those of us who use centimeters, this would be more or less 30 centimeters. Okay.
All right, let's take a look at the next size, a large pizza.
A large pizza. A large pizza. So it might also be called an 18 inch.
18 inch pizza. Or isn't it sometimes called a family size?
Maybe. Family size. I guess it depends where you're ordering. Yeah. Okay, so large and medium pizzas.
Now let's take a look at some of the ingredients. Yes. Okay, we have pepperoni. Pepperoni. Pepperoni.
This is the common ingredient in all pizza. It's my favorite. A pizza is not a pizza unless it has
Okay, so pepperoni is a sausage, right? Yeah, it's a little bit spicy. A little bit spicy and they look like a
Like circles red circles. Yep. Okay. All of all of all of all of all of us are little black or green balls.
Yes, little green or black balls. You can also find them in a martini. Yeah, exactly. Yep. It's very
common for them to have it's very common to have an it's very common to have an olive in a martini.
Okay, and he also ordered extra cheese. Extra cheese. So that means more cheese.
Mm-hmm. Extra. All right, another ingredient. Ham. Ham. The meat of a pig. Yeah, ham. Yeah. Okay,
and he also ordered another strange ingredient for a pizza pineapple. Pineapple. Pineapple.
Now this is a fruit. I know. So weird to put pineapple on a piece. Many people like pineapple on their pizza.
It's a tropical fruit. Yeah, comes from Hawaii. Usually and it kind of looks like a little palm tree at the time.
Yeah, like yeah, the top of a pineapple looks like a tree. Mm-hmm. So pineapple. Yep. All right.
Now the last description of a pizza he ordered it with thin crust. thin crust.
thin crust. Now we know thin is skinny skinny, but crust. What is crust? It's the bread part of the pizza.
The outside part. Yep. Okay, so that's the crust. That's my favorite part of the
really. Yeah. Mm-hmm. Then crust or thick crust. Uh, then crust. Yeah, thin crust. And I just I really love
that bread part. It's important. So a good pizza. Okay, well, you know, they also have um, they also have
the crust filled with cheese. Oh, it's so wrong. That's good, too. No. All right. Let's listen to our
dialogue again. And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more. Good evening. Pizza house. This is
Marty speaking. May I take your order? Um, yes, I'd like a medium pizza with pepperoni olives and
extra cheese. We have a two for one special on large pizzas. Would you like a large pizza instead?
Sure. That sounds good. Great. Would you like your second pizza to be the same as the first?
No. Make the second one with ham, pineapple, and green peppers. Oh, and make it thin crust. Okay,
thin crust. Your total is 2150 and your order will arrive in 30 minutes or it's free.
Perfect. Thank you. Bye. Sir, wait. I need your address. Okay, now we have some really polite language
that you could use possibly with customers or with clients. Yep. Okay. So let's take a look at them
in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay. My, all right, the first phrase we have. Um, I think is my
favorite. This is the way that Marty answered the phone, right? He said, this is Marty speaking.
This is Marty speaking. This is Marty speaking. Now, why is it so important? Because a lot of
people when they answer the phone say, I'm Erica, like hello, I'm Erica, which is not what English
people say. We always say, Erica speaking. This is Erica speaking. Exactly. So guys, remember this,
you'll sound really, really great when you use this on the phone. This is Marty speaking.
Exactly. This is Marty. Well, don't use Marty. Use your name. All right. Then you also mentioned
a two for one special two for one special two for one special. So that means you're getting two
pizzas, right? For the price of one. Mm-hmm. And a special is just a special promotion.
A special price special price. Yes. Two for one special. All right. All right. Now a very easy phrase.
Would you like? Would you like? Would you like? Would you like? Would you like? Now this is a great
way to offer something. It's a more polite way of asking. Do you want? Do you want? Do you want
is okay? Yeah, it's fine. But it's less polite than would you like? Exactly. So whenever you offer
something, would you like a cup of coffee? Would you like to sit down? Okay. Yep. So would you like?
Let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk about pizza
from a pizza expert.
Good evening. Pizza host. This is Marty speaking. May I take your order?
Yes. I'd like a medium pizza with pepperoni olives and extra cheese. We have a two for one special
on large pizzas. Would you like a large pizza instead? Sure. That sounds good. Great. Would you like
your second pizza to be the same size as the first? No. Make the second one with ham, pineapple,
and green peppers. Oh and make it thin crust. Okay. Then crust. Your total is 21-50 and your order will
arrive in 30 minutes or it's free. Perfect. Thank you, bye. Sir, wait. I need your address.
All right. We're back and we are here with our pizza expert who else but Marco from Italian
Pod. Hi, everyone. Marco too, right? Marco won. I am Marco Zero. He is Marco won. Yes. We've come to
an agreement. So zero. What's the deal about this? Well, we're talking about pizza today and we
wanted to know what's your opinion since pizza comes from Italy, right? Well, thanks for the
question first. Marco Zero. Is my mic working? Yeah. It should be. Okay. So the problem with pizza is
yes. It comes from Italy. Reginated the story goes with the right. Regina Margarita.
We're in Margarita. All right. But the problem is that now this confusion worldwide
pizza and pizza hat American pizza Italian pizza that is not the same thing. It's not the same.
It's not the same. Okay. So pizza hat is in Italian pizza. No. No. Oh my god.
So the, okay, here it goes. Italians a little bit. Italians make food but they're not good at
branding it. Okay. Americans are good at branding food. So they have Starbucks and pizza hat and
blah blah blah. The problem is that since they have to branding, they don't change the name.
So they do this pizza hat. It's totally different from Italian pizza. What how is it different?
Have you ever seen the two of them? Have you ever compared them? Yeah. Yeah. They are very different.
That's true. So okay. Can you put pineapple and ham on a pizza? Technically you could.
Like it's possible. As long as you call it Hawaiian, you can put pineapple in everything I guess.
But the problem, what I'm trying to say is that Italian pizza is, you know, you have the
flour, the past, pasta, the pizza. The crust, the crust, the tomato sauce and then the
pepperoni, the cheese and that's the basic and then you can do it on top of it with some variations.
Make a pizza is basically take everything that you have on the table and put it on it.
That's the main difference. But I'm not saying I'm against American pizza. I'm saying that you just
should change the name to another thing. What are you suggest? We should call it Zipa Zipa.
It's closing off. Close enough. Yeah. But you need like an A like Azipa. Azipa. Azipa.
It's okay that it's American. A for America. Maybe. A dot Zipa.
A dot Zipa dot com. Can I have A Azipa? So Margot, Azipa Pao, the dot com. So Margot, I know that
you are very much against having pizza, pizza. I like it as an exotic
experience because I like the fact that it's so much stuff in it that you cannot even tell
the difference between the ingredients. You know, they have the super mega super super super
super super super super. With cheese and the crust. I don't even know what's inside. It's great.
It's great. It's like there's a party in my mouth and everybody's invited.
That's for me the feeling. Well, the another interesting thing when we were eating with pizza with
Marco is that you notice the way that people from different countries eat pizza. That's right. It's
how many people fold their pizza? We do fold it and another thing is that we have a whole pizza.
Like if I order one pizza, it's not like I share everybody as a one slice of it. We order one
pizza, you order your pizza, you order her pizza and so on. Pizza is personal. Pizza is a person.
Don't mess with my pizza, Marco Zipa. All right. Well, this whole pizza discussion. Let's see what
our listeners have to say about it. I know that we have listeners from all over the world and
what do they do with their pizzas? Yes, or their Zipas or their Zipas? What do you like on your pizza?
Exactly. For example, how high do you want the crust to be? Then how high? I know that for
exactly new one you're crust to be. Another for example, in some countries they put ketchup on their pizza.
I know once I was eating pizza, I had a Japanese friend who ordered a pizza from Pizza Hut
and the pizza had the pineapple and other stuff on it and then she took out like ketchup and
mayonnaise. Oh, no. Like wild. Although I must tell you I like to bask go on my pizza and I know that's wrong.
I know. Sorry. But I like it. What do you have to do, Erica? Then you know, history will judge you.
All right. We better go. We're out of time and before Marco has a heart attack or an aneurysm or something.
We're making a mingri here. And if you have any questions for us and also for Marco because I'm sure
he's going to be commenting on this aspect. Sure. So go to our comments section at EnglishPod.com
and Marco and I are Marco Zero and I are always there to answer your questions. All right everyone.
We'll see you there. Bye. Bye.