Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco
and my name is Katherine so Marco today we're talking about rent and housing
right we're actually going to be moving we're going to be going to a new apartment or a new house
and so we're going to look at all the words related to this because sometimes it can be a real
hassle right it can be really difficult. Absolutely but you love moving right you are
timing how much you love moving your stuff and negotiating a new league. Well like the negotiation
of the least but not the moving aspect. Now I don't think anyone likes actually I do like it
at times because then you can just throw away so many things that you have no need for and you
wouldn't throw away unless you move. So let's go check out today's dialogue to find out what happens
to the characters. Okay that's fine bye. What happened? That's it I leases up I have to move.
What? Why? Can't you renew it? The owner apparently is selling this place to make way for the construction
of a parking lot. Well I can help you pack we should start looking for a new place for you ASAP.
I think I might move in with my parents for a couple of months until I can find something.
You know how hard it is to find a decent place around here. I'm going to have to put most of my
stuff in storage for a while. Well let me know if there's anything I can do to help out.
Actually would you mind looking after my pet tarantula and snake for a couple of weeks?
Sure.
All right we're back so well it's not much of a big deal I guess if you have your parents
nearby you can just move back in with your parents. Easier said than that. True true we'll get
to that in a little bit but let's take a look at the words that are used today in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right so this first one is an important one because generally when you're
looking for a house or an apartment there are two things you can do you can buy a house or you can
lease a house or apartment. So lease here Marco. It's basically to rent right it's a contract where you
agree to pay a monthly or a quarterly fee for using that house or apartment. So do you own your
apartment or do you lease it? No I'll mine I lease. Yeah I'm not a home owner yet. Right so owning a
home is a lot more expensive at one kind of period where you have to just pay in and then you can
maybe a mortgage but leasing is just a monthly fee like you said. So in this case they had to leave
because their lease was expired. Exactly so you can at the end of a lease do one of two things you can
stop and you can find a new apartment or you can renew your lease. All right and that's our next word
to renew your lease basically means to to continue to continue. And this is actually a good word
because it can be used with a con any contract because really a lease is a kind of contract. And so
I can say I renewed my job contract or maybe a magazine subscription. Yeah you renewed your magazine
subscription. It's a way of saying that you've committed to paying for the next six months or one year.
Okay well and after that as we said the person decided to move in with the parents. So move in.
Moving what we can say he moved his car he put it in a different place but to move in is actually
to change houses or the change apartments and you're literally moving your things and you're moving
your clothes and you're moving into a new home. So you're living in a new place. So in this case this
person is going to live with the parents move in. All right and our next word is when you have to move
you have to pack. Okay so you can pack a lot of things in this case you're packing a box with all
of your bowlongings your books and your pillows and all that but you can also pack a suitcase or you
can pack luggage. So packing is putting things into something so that you can move them.
So you can carry them or take them somewhere. Exactly. So in this case you have to pack your things
put them in boxes to take them to your new home. And our last word is an acronym when you said A-SAP.
All right snap snap come on A-SAP Marko. A-SAP. Describe this for us quickly. All right so A-SAP is an
acronym for as soon as possible. Okay see you often see this in the office on envelopes or emails.
Right. So please respond A-SAP ASAP. This means please respond right away. As soon as you can as soon
as possible. All right so five great word is that we've just taken a look at let's listen to our
dialogue again and we'll be right back.
Okay that's fine bye. What happened? That's it. I leases up. I have to move.
What? Why? Can't you renew it? The owner apparently is selling this place to make way for the
construction of a parking lot. Well I can help you pack. We should start looking for a new place for
you ASAP. I think I might move in with my parents for a couple of months until I can find something.
You know how hard it is to find a decent place around here. I'm going to have to put most of my
stuff in storage for a while. Well let me know if there's anything I can do to help out.
Actually would you mind looking after my pet tarantulas and snake for a couple of weeks?
Uh sure.
All right we're back and we have a couple of different phrases for you so let's look at those now
in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Our first one's a little bit unusual. We heard the phrase
my lease is up. So Marka let's talk about this phrase to be up. All right so if something is up
as in this case the lease it means it's expired. It's finished. Mm-hmm. So it's over.
It's um you can also say our time is up. Right. If we have a meeting so that's all the time I have
time to go away. Time is up. Very good. So it's always related to time or maybe a contract is in this
case. And my or your lease is up. Mm-hmm. So it means over or finished. Mm-hmm. All right so moving on
to our second phrase. To make way for. All right so this is a great one. This often makes me think of
kings and queens in the old days as they make way for the king so you have to get out of the way.
Yeah get out of the way or to clear some space for them to move because there's too much
stuff in the way. And so in this case the owner of the apartment with the guy was living in
uh is trying to make some space or make way for a parking lot. Right so he's basically going to
sell the building or house and build a parking lot instead. So they are making way for the new parking lot.
They're clearing space and this is actually really sad because my childhood home um they destroyed
to make way for a larger ugly building house. Yeah. Mm-hmm. It happens all the time. Now they're
making way for malls and the big buildings and all the little houses are destroyed. And uh well
moving on to our last phrase the person asked the friend if he would mind looking after the
pet snake entrentula. I would mind. You know next night's a dream for us. I don't mind
having long live with them. So would you mind how this is a nice way to start a a sentence if you
want to ask for a favor right? Exactly. So here's an alternative. Hey Marco. Can you do this for me?
I could maybe. Uh I could say Marco would you mind doing this for me? It sounds it's more polite.
It is more polite and it's a little bit gentler. Mm-hmm. Yeah. So it's nice. It's a nice way of
asking someone for a favor. Exactly and that's why this is funny because the favor is not like
would you mind watching my kitty? The favor is would you mind watching my poison as pets?
Right. All right. So would you mind it? But in the end the person agreed so it's if it works.
Right. It does work. So would you mind uh so listeners would you mind listening to today's
dialogue one more time at its normal speed before we come back to you and talk more about renting an apartment.
Okay that's fine bye. What happened? That's it. I leases up. I have to move.
What? Why? Can't you renew it? The owner apparently is selling this place to make way for the
construction of a parking lot. Well I can help you pack. We should start looking for a new place for you
ASAP. I think I might move in with my parents for a couple of months until I can find something.
You know how hard it is to find a decent place around here. I'm gonna have to put most of my
stuff in storage for a while. Well let me know if there's anything I can do to help out.
Actually would you mind looking after my pet tarantulas and snake for a couple of weeks?
Sure.
All right so moving in now you have different stages in your life right when you move out. For
example you move out of your parents home and you live on your own and then maybe I can this
case you would move back in with your parents. How do you see that happening? I see it very often.
My brother just moved back in with my parents. Really? Yeah I think that it depends on the person.
Honestly I mean especially because the economy has really been suffering for the last year a lot of
people are doing this because you know in a lot of cities in America you can spend $1,000 to $2,000
a month for an apartment to rent and that's a small apartment or a shared apartment.
I understand this is a really well it's a better option now than it was before because everyone
wants independence but sometimes you just can't afford it. It's actually and it's a cultural
thing because some people move out of their parents home maybe for college it's very common in the
US for the city and in another city or another state right and but then maybe coming back home
and moving in with your parents or in other cultures maybe they don't move out at all maybe they
only move out once they're married. Exactly so a lot of people in China I think in Shanghai
specifically don't move out until don't move out of their parents home until they're going to
get married. Right but it does make sense and in many big metropolis because as you say rent is
expensive living on your own is expensive and well you don't have anyone to share those costs with like
gas water electricity even food right it's actually more people and not to mention a little bit
scary living on your own for the first time. It is a little bit scary. What about having somebody
move in with you maybe a roommate or girlfriend boyfriend? Ooh that's always the big stop
the big commitment. The big commitment and your in a relationship and you ask your partner to
move in with you. So yeah the step before marriage I guess. There's nothing before that nothing
before marriage. No that's pretty much it. You tell me I know. All right that's all the time we have
for today but be sure to come to our website englishpod.com if you have any questions or any
comments about this topic we would be glad to have your input on it and we'll see you guys there.
And if you have any suggestions for the step before the step before marriage please let us know
because we're in the dark on this one. So until next time. Bye. Bye.