Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have a lesson for you all about school.
That's right. Today we're going to take a look at a child's report card.
So we're going to talk a little bit about what this means, what is a report card and also
everything that's inside this report.
That's right. So we're going to learn how to describe a child's schoolwork.
Is it good? Is it bad?
Let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a minute to discuss the meaning of
some of these words and phrases.
Look, Jimmie's report card came today.
Let's have a look. What is this?
We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam.
You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school he receives a mark from one to three.
A one means his achievement or work is excellence.
Here in science, for example, he got a two which means it's satisfactory.
What about here in physical education?
He got a three here which means it's unsatisfactory.
We should work on that with him.
So confusing. In my day we got an A or a B if we were doing well and if we failed an exam, we would get an F.
All right, we're back. So now let's start with some language. Take away.
Language takeaway.
All right, the first phrase here we have in language takeaways actually it's thing.
It's the report card and this is the topic of today's dialogue.
That's right. Now you may remember, I'm sure pretty much it's standard everywhere in the world.
You get a report, a small little report that tells your parents how well or how poorly you are doing in school.
That's right. So after maybe two or three months, your teacher will write down how she or he thinks that you're
performing at school.
That's right. And usually parents have to sign this. They have to say, okay, I see that my child is doing well
or that he's doing poorly and then the teacher will know as well.
And I think well, you get report cards in elementary school in high school and also in university, right?
You do get a report card of some sort.
That's right. Well, in university in America, we call them grades. We don't really call them a report card.
In high school, middle school and elementary school. So before college, we actually have a piece of paper.
Right. And that's why it's called a card.
Yeah, that's right. I think now for universities, especially you just go online and you see your grades.
That's right. It's on the internet. But the important thing about the report card is it tells a parent and a student
what his or her grades are.
That's right. So the grades, this is a noun is basically your score.
That's right. So maybe you took a test and you did a very well on your test and you had some homework
and you did very well on your homework. So you have a good grade.
That's right. But if you don't do your homework and you don't do well on your test, you have a bad grade.
That's right. So for example, like in the United States, it's over 100 points.
So maybe a good grade would be 95 points out of 100. So we call that an A.
That's in called an A. That's right. Or if you have a bad grade, maybe that's an F, which is 20
percent or 30 percent. Right. Mm-hmm. Okay. So now this is where we need to make a difference between
the grades that his father was looking for. And then the mom says he's in the third grade. So it's
very different between having good grades or bad grades and fifth grade or third grade. All right.
Two different grades. And we know this is confusing. So we want to explain a little bit.
Third grade is actually the third year of elementary school. That's right. So in the American
Education system, we start in kindergarten and we have first grade, second grade, third grade,
all the way up until the end, which is 12th grade. That's right. So that's everything between
when you're five years old and when you're 18 years old. And each year at school is a grade
level. Mm-hmm. That's right. So as you said, it's a grade in different parts of the country.
I'm not really sure if they call them a grade or they have these the same system. But basically that's
what it means in English. You have first grade, third grade, 12th grade, finally when you graduate.
That's right. So you can say my son is in eighth grade. That's right. I mean, he's in his eighth year
of school. Right. Very good. So that is the difference. And now we're going to take a look at something
that has to do with grades as well is the marks that you get in your test or in your report card.
That's right. So this might actually help. Remember when we set on your report card, your teacher
might write down your grade. Mm-hmm. That means do you have an A or B or a C? Well, another
way to call this is a mark. So he has good marks. He has good grades. So they're basically the same
thing grades and marks. That's right. They are. And I know that in Britain, I think people more
commonly say marks. She got terrible marks at school and her father was angry with her.
Mm-hmm. Okay. But in America, we often say, you know, if you get good grades, I'll buy you sweets.
That's right. Okay. So you get a prize if you get good grades usually.
What depends on your parents? That's right. Now, as we said, you can have a grade that's usually
a number or a letter like ABCD F. But you can also get marks that are just very much
black or white. It's satisfactory or unsatisfactory like in this case. That's right. So satisfactory.
This is an adjective. It describes something. Is a good thing. Okay. So how did he do? Well, his
performance was satisfactory. It's okay. Mm-hmm. But if it's bad or if it's not good, we call it
unsatisfactory. That's right. So this doesn't really have a number as you can tell. It's just basically
pass or fail. That's about it. You know. Good or bad. Good or bad. That's an exact grade.
And we'll explain this in a minute. There are some classes where you can't have a grade like an A or
B. And that's why we have this satisfactory unsatisfactory. That's right. All right. So we've taken a
look at a lot of language there. Why don't we listen to the dialogue again?
Look, Jim means report card came today. Let's have a look. What is this? We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam. You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school,
he receives a mark from one to three. A one means his achievement or work is excellence.
Here in science, for example, he got a two which means it's satisfactory. What about here in physical
education? He got a three here which means it's unsatisfactory. We should work on that with him.
So confusing. In my day, we got an A or a B if we were doing well. And if we failed an exam,
we would get an F.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. You could have said, let's have a look, Marco. That's one of the key phrases
in today's dialogue. That's right. The dad got the report card. You see it. All right. Let's have a look.
This is a very common way to say, let's see or let me look at that. So let's have a look. Maybe
it's just one person. Me, right. We still say this let let us. So it's plural. It's very weird. But
it just means let me look. Right. And exactly as you said, even though it's in plural and you may be
by yourself or only you are going to look at something, people still say, let's have a look.
Let's have a look here. I mean, I want to look at this. So if I say, hey, I just bought this new CD.
Okay. I can say, hey, let's have a look. All right. And I could give it to Marco and he can look at
the case and see who the musician is. That's right. All right. Now talking about one of the
subjects in school. That means some of the classes that you have. We had science. We have history.
And there's another one called physical education. All right. So this is a class that has many
different names. It's physical. So you know that it has to do with your body. So basically it's
sports class. And you play sports like football, basketball, things like that. It's also called PE.
PE for short. Yeah. Because remember, physical and English starts with a PE, PE, physical.
But this is what I was saying earlier, Marco, you can't give a person an A or a B in physical
education. Well, you don't really. So normally students get satisfactory or unsatisfactory.
Right. Because usually it doesn't mean that you have to be very good at sports. Sometimes it just
the effort counts. You may not be very good at soccer or football or basketball. But if you try
really hard, you're running around and you're actually doing what you're supposed to be doing.
Then you get a satisfactory note. It means, yeah, I mean, you're not the best player in the
world, but you're doing what you're supposed to. Exactly. All right. So now when the father was
talking is like, oh, you know, I don't understand this report card. In my day, we got an A or a B.
All right. So this is a common phrase that people say when they want to talk about
when they were children or when they were growing up. So older people often say, oh, in my day,
things were different. So this is a way to make a comparison between now and the past.
Yeah, right. You're basically saying when I was a child or many years ago,
this was what happened or this is how it used to be. In my day, school was much more difficult.
Today, it's very, very easy. That's right. So this is how you start this comparison between
the time when you were a child to now. Yes, in my day. All right. And to finish off, we're going
to talk about failing in exam because obviously, sometimes you do fail. Yeah. And if you fail in exam,
you get a very bad grade in F and F. So F for fail. It's easy to remember. That's right. So you say,
you can say I didn't pass the exam, but you can also say I failed the exam. Yes, and normally
fail means you received less than 60%. That's right. Or 50%. So it's 50%.
So basically, you missed if there are 10 questions on the exam, you missed five or six or seven,
or all day to 10 of them. So you missed more than half of the questions. That's right. And it's not only
for school, for example, your drivers exam, when you're going to get your drivers license,
you can also pass or fail that exam. And if you fail the exam, you have to take it again.
That's right. So that's all the fluency builder words we have for you today. Let's take a look at
them again and we'll be right back.
Look, Jimmy's report card came today. Let's have a look. What is this? We're all the grades.
He's in the third grade, Sam. You see, under each subject that he's being taught in school,
he receives a mark from 1 to 3. A one means his achievement or work is excellence. Here in science,
for example, he got a two which means it's satisfactory. What about here in physical education?
He got a three here which means it's unsatisfactory. We should work on that with him.
So confusing. In my day, we got an A or a B if we were doing well. And if we failed an exam,
we would get an F.
All right. So big question, Marco, when you were a student, did you get good grades?
I got good grades, but not great grades. I was always a type of student that paid attention in class,
did my homework, but never studied. So you did not study for the tests. No, but that's why I never
got an A for example, an A plus, but I always got a B. So I was that type of just more chill type of
student. You like to be in the middle. Yeah. Well, this was the thing. I like to pay attention in class.
So that was different because I would pay attention. I would take some notes, but then I would just
remember everything. So I did all right for the exam. Didn't really have to study. So
but sometimes in other subjects, I did. I really liked them. So it wasn't studying. It was more
fun for me. So then I would get great grades. All right. What about you? Well, I always studied for tests.
Oh, generally my grades were pretty good. Now something that we didn't talk about here is a
GPA. This is something that is very popular in the United States. Basically, even if you want to apply
for schools, your GPA is what counts. What is a GPA? Well, we don't really have a GPA until
high school and then it's in high school and college. And GPA stands for G grade P point A average.
That means we take all of our marks or all of our grades together. So science grade, English grade,
history grade, and we make an average. So if I get most mostly A's, my GPA is 4. Oh,
if I get mostly B's, my GPA is 3.0 and then it goes lower and lower. And if you have a really bad GPA,
like a 1, you probably won't finish high school. Now, this is the GPA is very important for many
reasons. First of all, because it's also kind of a summary of your application to universities.
They take a look at your GPA. Absolutely. So this is a way to say, okay, how is this student
overall? How is the student in all of her classes? Not just one class. Right. And then they see if you have
3.5 a tail. Well, it's pretty good. Yeah, 3.5 is good. 4 is the best. And again,
3 is good. It's okay. But a two or one's not very good. That's right. So it's very interesting because
all around the world, they have different grading systems. I think I would say that the United
States is the only place where I've seen that they use the ABCD F system. In Latin American countries,
for example, they don't do it over 100. They do it over 10. So you would get a grade over 10 or
in some countries over 20. So I've seen that as well in Italy. Yeah, it's over 20. So you would get a
14. I think would be a passing grade over 20. Well, let us know. Listen, there's a few have a
different grading system in your country. Also, you can let us know how were your grades when you're
studying in school. You don't have to tell us, but we'd like to talk to you about grades.
Our website is Englishpad.com. All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.