Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we've got a very sad dialogue today actually Marco.
That's right today. We have a very sad but interesting dialogue of something that happens all the time.
Maybe you have a girlfriend, maybe you had a boyfriend and you break up.
That means you are no longer boyfriend and girlfriend.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Hello.
Hey, do you want to go out tonight?
No, I think I'll pass.
Mark broke up with me. I feel awful.
What? What happened?
Just last week you were talking about going on vacation together.
I don't know what I did wrong.
He said he needed some space to figure things out.
He said I didn't do anything wrong that I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche. Mark's not worth your time Lydia. You deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch but I had hoped we could work it out next weekend when we both had some time off.
I think he found someone else. I had been getting suspicious because he had been spending a lot of time with a coworker.
Whatever, he's a jerk. Forget about him. There are many more fish in the sea.
Talk about being cliche, Maggie. But you're right. There's no use for me to soak around.
Let's go out tonight.
All right, we're back. So obviously this girl Lydia is very torn. She's very sad because her boyfriend broke up with her.
That's right. She's crying the whole time. That's what's going on. That's right. So but she did mention
her and her friend mentioned some interesting things. Why don't we take a look at some of the words they used on language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
So first of all, her friend says, hey, do you want to go out tonight and what is Lydia say?
She says, no, I think I'll pass. All right. I think I'll pass. I will pass. So what is this
verb mean to pass? So that means she is politely rejecting the offer or the invitation. So no thanks.
No thanks. That's basically what it means. I won't go. So hey, Mark, you want to go see a movie in a couple
hours? I think I'll pass. I got homework to do. All right. So Mark will not come. That means
to decline an invitation. That's right. So that's what it means to pass. Now, as they continue to talk,
they mentioned some of the problems with her boyfriend, but Maggie said, that's so cliche.
So the boyfriend said something and Maggie thinks that what he said was very, very cliche.
So what is something that is cliche? cliche means something that is said or done very often.
It's almost like we would expect it. So like for example, what's a cliche phrase or a cliche
well in the dialogue they were talking about ways of breaking up with people. So for example,
it's not you. It's me. Let's break up. So that's a cliche because it's a sentence. It's a phrase.
Everyone always says it's not very, maybe not very honest. Or like a movie cliche would be
a couple. They're getting married, but their parents, the parents of the bride, they're
didn't force the hate each other. But then at the wedding, they get back together. They're
they're going to get married again. That's a cliche story. That's right. Because you've heard it before.
Right. All the time. It's very common. So something's very common. Something that you would expect
to that's almost that's a cliche. And a cliche calling something a cliche is not a good thing.
It's usually a bad thing. That's right. Okay. So Maggie goes on to say that, you know, this guy
Mark her ex-boyfriend. He's not really worth it. She says you deserve so much better.
Okay. So to deserve is a verb. And it means that you should receive something or you should
expect something. So almost like, you know, in this case, you deserve better. You have earned
something better. You're a good person. You should receive a, you know, you should have a good
boyfriend. That's right. So when when she says you deserve so much better, she's talking about
deserving a better guy, a better man. Or for example, so Mark, you work so hard at school.
You're always in your homework. You really deserve good grades. Mm-hmm.
Okay. You should receive good grades. Very good. Now when Lydia said, yeah, you know what,
I just thought we were having some problems. And we had hit a rough patch. So she's talking about a
rough patch. What is that? A rough patch is actually something we talk about a lot in spoken English.
It's a way to describe a period of time. So maybe a week or a month. When things are difficult,
you know, when maybe you argue with your boyfriend or girlfriend or when you're sad a lot or when
you're confused. And so a period of time when you're angry or sad with your boyfriend or girlfriend,
that's a rough patch. So maybe we can apply a rough patch to another situation like at work. Maybe
you're going through a rough patch at work. That means I'm always busy. I'm always tired. I don't
feel happy with my job. I'm going through a rough patch. So it's usually a temporary period of time where
things are going bad. It could be a week. It could be a month. It could be a year. But it's a fixed amount
of time. It's not forever. It's just a period. Mm-hmm. Okay. Very good. And Lydia went on to say that,
you know, she thought that maybe he was going out with someone else. And she was suspicious because
he was spending a lot of time with some other girl. Okay. So to be suspicious is to think that
something is happening. But you don't know. So for example, Marco, I think you've been taking the
milk from the kitchen. Mm-hmm. You are always drinking coffee and you always take milk in your
coffee and there's no more milk. So I think it was you. Mm-hmm. I'm being suspicious. I'm thinking
that maybe you did something bad or wrong. That I'm guilty. So maybe you're suspicious that someone
is stealing the milk or maybe you suspect or you're suspicious that your next door neighbor is
maybe a car thief. Right. So you're very suspicious. That means you're always thinking that this
person or someone else is doing something bad. That's right. Okay. So a lot of words they're talking
about relationships, talking about cliches. Why don't we go back? Let's listen to the dialogue again
and we're back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
Hello. Hey. Do you want to go out tonight? No. I think I'll pass. Mark broke up with me.
I feel awful. What? What happened? Just last week you were talking about going on vacation together.
I don't know what I did wrong. He said he needed some space to figure things out. He said
I didn't do anything wrong that I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche. Mark's not worth your time Lydia. You deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch but I had hoped we could work it out next weekend when we both had
some time off. I think he found someone else. I had been getting suspicious because he had been
spending a lot of time with a coworker. Whatever. He's a jerk. Forget about him. There are
many more fish in the sea. Talk about being cliche Maggie. But you're right. There's no use
for me to soak around. Let's go out tonight.
Alright we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. Alright so Marko these are cliche phrases that we hear in English.
When people are breaking up, okay so there's some breaking up phrases but there's also phrases
that you might hear from your friend after you have a breakup. Okay. The first phrase we're going
to look at I think is to need space. So he said he needed some space. Right and that's a cliche phrase
as we said but it means that maybe her ex-boyfriend or Mark needs more space. Need more time to be
on his own or needs more time to do his own things. That's right. So when you're in a relationship,
you have a boyfriend or a girlfriend. You're always together. I need some space. I mean, I want to be alone.
I don't want to be with my boyfriend or girlfriend. Sometimes this is just a small period. Sometimes
it's forever. It depends. That's right. So when somebody says that they need space, it means they need
a little bit of more time to be on their own or to be alone as you said. And also he had also given
her another cliche phrase. Mark said that she is not the one for him. Okay so the emphasis here is
the one. The one. She's not the one for him. So in English we often talk about the one and this
means the person that you will marry. The love of your life. Your your significant other. Your
your other half. That's right. And so you hope that you will marry the one. But her boyfriend
realized he said, listen, I like you but you're not the one. You're not the person that I will marry.
So this is a phrase you often hear and break up. So if you're single, maybe you don't have a boyfriend
or you're not married, you might say that you haven't found the one. Or yeah, you have a lot of
different boyfriends, but you still haven't found the one. That means the one you will marry.
That's right. Okay very good. And now towards the end of the dialogue, Maggie also gives her
some advice and said, you know what? Forget about him. There are many more fish in the sea.
Okay so this is a phrase that we often say when we're trying to make somebody feel better.
So the person is sad and we want to make them happy. And so there are many more fish in the sea.
Means that there are other men in the world. Okay you're sad. You broke up. I understand.
But there are so many other men you could date. So she's trying to say, hey listen,
look at this world. There's so many different options. That's right. So it's the similarity of
how in the sea you have so many fish in the world you have so many men. So don't worry about it.
And you can say this about women too. So for example, if I'm talking to my male friend or my brother
and my brother just broke up with his girlfriend, I can say, hey listen, there are many more fish in
the sea. Many other women. So don't worry about it. Don't worry about it. You'll be okay.
And Lydia says, you know what? I think you're right. And there's really no use for me to
soak around. So what does she mean to soak around? To soak. Now this is something that is
very visual for me. I see somebody soaking their head is low. They're sad. Someone who is
soaking often wears their sweatpants or their pajamas. They don't they don't make themselves look
good. To soak around means to be in your house, to be sad, to watch TV and eat ice cream.
So stop soaking. Don't look sad. Be happy. So to soak is to act sad and to be very down.
So it's kind of like you're very it's kind of a combination of being lazy but and also sad at the same
time because something bad happened to you. Exactly. And so we often say that in English teenagers
like to soak, you know, oh, I'm so angry at my parents and your parents will say, hey, stop
soaking. Go study. That's right. Very good. Okay, so a lot of great phrases here. I think we can go back.
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
Hello. Hey, do you want to go out tonight? No. I think I'll pass.
Mark broke up with me. I feel awful. What? What happened? Just last week you were talking about
going on vacation together. I don't know what I did wrong. He said he needed some space to figure
things out. He said I didn't do anything wrong that I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche. Mark's not worth your time, Lydia. You deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch, but I had hoped we could work it out next week and when we both
had some time off, I think he found someone else. I had been getting suspicious because he had been
spending a lot of time with a coworker. Whatever, he's a jerk. Forget about him. There are many more
fish in the sea. Talk about being cliche, Maggie. But you're right. There's no use for me to
soak around. Let's go out tonight.
All right, so talking about breakups, these cliche lines and and we'll Maggie's obviously upset.
What other cliche lines or breakup phrases have you heard apart from? It's not you, it's me.
You're just not the one. I need some space. I think if you have more like a friend,
because there's a boyfriend or girlfriend, but then there's a friend and so listen, I like you,
but I think if you have more like a friend. Yeah, I think that's a typical one. Especially if you're
asking someone out on a date, they might say that, you know, I really like you, but I see you more as a
friend than anything else. So there's another one that's very popular. Sometimes you hear people say,
I'm just not ready for a relationship. And that's also a cliche line. Or I'm not ready to commit.
I'm not ready to commit. Yeah, and it's interesting because I think breaking up is one of the
hardest things that people can do. And I think maybe this is why you just use one of these phrases that
are so popular in common because I guess it's kind of a a good way to explain and very soft
terms what you want to say and to break up with someone. That's right. And I think that sometimes
people are afraid to make the other person sad. And so they say these things that are very, you know,
general, like it's not you, it's me. Right. But sometimes this makes the other person even more sad
because they don't understand why that they're breaking up. So what about breaking up over the
telephone or breaking up with the letter? Generally, at least in America, we say that breaking up
over email or letter or phone is not a good way to end a relationship. It's very cold.
It's very cold. So the other person would be very angry if if if that happened. That's right.
You just want to see the person and say listen, let's have a conversation. Let's talk about this face to face.
Okay. So this is actually very interesting because as we say maybe in other countries or in other
cultures, it's not really a negative thing to break up over the phone or maybe send an email
saying you know what, I don't want to see you anymore. Right. So I'd be very curious to hear about
you guys and your cultures and what happens when people break up where you live. So let us know our
website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. And of course, we hope that you haven't had
any very bad big up experiences. But if you're comfortable sharing, we'd like to hear about
your culture and your background. All right. So we'll see you guys there. Bye.