Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you the third part of this series that we've created
called I'm Sorry I Love You. That's right, the third part in our story about our EnglishPod couple
yeah it's a romantic series but today we're bringing you an argument that's right
I can every relationship you have fights you have discussions so we're going to teach you how to do that in English
that's right in today's lesson you'll learn some great language that people use when they get into
an argument with their boyfriend or girlfriends right so when do we take a look at vocabulary preview
very vocabulary preview we have one phrase today get a hold get a hold get a hold to get a hold
to get a hold of someone means to try and communicate with that person exactly so to try and
for example I can say I've been calling his phone all day but I can't to get a hold of him
or I could say finally Marco I got a hold of you where have you been all day exactly hmm
now we're going to listen to our dialogue and as always it's going to be at a normal pace but you don't
have to worry about it. Welcome back and teach you all of the important words
Stephen where have you been I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours I
there was an emergency at work so I was looking for you in the restaurant for three hours
and you didn't even have the decency to call me do you have any idea how embarrassed I was
honey I promise this won't happen again it's just that I
right I've heard it all before I'm not going to take any more of your empty promises this is the
fit time you stood me up in two weeks you need to get your priority straight I'm tired of you putting
your job first all the time come on Veronica that's not fair I do care about you a lot you know that
I try to what maybe we should just take a break I need some time to think about where this
relationship is heading but Veronica would you listen to me there was a fire alarm at my office building today and that was
okay so a little bit of trouble in the relationship yeah that's too bad yeah well I think um
she's overreacting you do what's up about that later on oh we saw some great words and phrases here
so it's time for language takeaway language takeaway today on language takeaway we're bringing you three words
the first word is stood me up stood me up stood me up the phrase stand someone up when do we use this
if for example you have a date and you don't go okay so let's say you and I were supposed to have dinner together
and you just didn't come right and didn't call right so I stood you up yeah okay stand someone up
our next word priorities priorities priorities priorities so priorities are something that's really
important in your life that's right like family or maybe work or making a lot of money
whatever it is what what are your priorities in life right yeah okay and our last word for language
takeaway heading heading heading heading this is a bit of a funny verb so let's listen to a
couple of examples of how it's used so we can understand it's meaning example one
I don't know where our relationship is heading example two
where is this bus heading?
example three where is this project heading?
so basically heading means going exactly a heading is where you're going yep okay easy word
interesting okay so now it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time it's going to be
slower so now we can understand the words that we just talked about
Stephen where have you been? I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours
I there was an emergency at work so I was waiting for you in the restaurant for three hours
and you didn't even have the decency to call me do you have any idea how embarrassed I was?
honey I promise this won't happen again it's just that I yeah right I've heard it all before
I'm not going to take any more of your empty promises this is the fifth time you've stood me up
in two weeks you need to get your priority straight I'm tired of you putting your job first all the time
come on Veronica that's not fair I do care about you a lot you know that I tried you know what
maybe we should just take a break I need some time to think about where this relationship is heading
but Veronica would you just listen to me there was a fire alarm at my office building today and I was stuck
okay now we saw some interesting phrases in dialogue yeah we saw some great phrases that people use
when they're getting in a fight right why don't we take a look at some of them in fluency builder
fluency builder the first phrase that I want to take a look at today is do you have any idea
do you have any idea do you have any idea this is a great way to set up an argument so let's listen to
some examples of how you would set up an argument using this phrase example one
you forgot my birthday do you have any idea how angry I am
example two Julie kiss my boyfriend does she have any idea how mean that was
example three I just broke up with my boyfriend don't you have any idea how sad I am
so it's a great phrase to make that person understand that you were really worried or
really angry yeah yeah okay another second phrase that we can take a look at is I've heard it all before
I heard it all before I've heard it all before I've heard it all before so this is a great phrase of just
saying you don't have to give me an excuse I know what you're gonna say exactly and our last phrase
today take a break take a break take a break so when a couple takes a break they sort of
stop their relationship right they're breaking up yeah but it's it really like forever like a
break up that lasts forever not well maybe it could be forever but they're saying let's just
take some time away from each other for a couple of days or weeks yeah yeah and see what happens yes
take a break take a break okay so our happy couple is going to take a break well I guess they're not that
happy that yeah okay so let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and talk some more
you
Steven where have you been I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours I uh there was an emergency at
works so I was waiting for you in the restaurant for three hours and you didn't even have the
decency to call me do you have any idea how embarrassed I was honey I promise this won't happen again
it's just that I I've heard it all before I'm not going to take any more of your empty promises
this is the fit time you stood me up in two weeks you need to get your priority straight I'm tired
of you putting your job first all the time come on Veronica that's not fair I do care about you a lot you
know that I try something maybe we should just take a break I need some time to think about where
relationship is heading but Veronica would you listen to me there was a fire alarm at my office building
today and I was so Marco this phrase to take a break really reminds me of a friends episode yeah
that really famous friends episode when Ross and Rachel were on a break and and Ross like
went with another girl yeah and then they definitely broke up after that yeah so that's one of the
key issues right if you're taking a break can you start to date someone else I've got to agree with
Rachel really yeah no you can't you can't so what's the point of taking a break just you need some
time away you need some time to think but you're not really broken up exactly hmm that's convenient
I don't know they were on a break I agree with Ross well you would wouldn't you all right guys we're
out of time today I hope you enjoyed our lesson and be sure to listen next time because we will definitely
have a part four to this yes coming out soon yep and also come to our website at englishpod.com
and leave all your questions and comments yeah Marco and I are always happy to hear from you and we love
answering your questions right and maybe you can tell us what you think happens in the fourth part yeah
okay well until then it's goodbye