Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we have a great lesson for you about traveling.
That's right, you know, we have taken a look at previous lessons where you can buy a ticket,
how to book a flight, what to do at the airport, but now we are going to see what we can do if our
flight gets canceled. Okay, this is not a fun situation, but hopefully with our help you'll be able to
understand what these messages are about flights that are canceled or delayed. So let's take
a listen to today's dialogue.
Good afternoon sir. May I please see your passport and reservation? Here you go.
Oh, I'm sorry sir. This flight has been canceled due to some mechanical problems.
Can't hold, what am I supposed to do now? We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this evening,
but it's on a first come first serve basis. So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
What are my other options? Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for
today and you can take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning. That's fine. I'll do that then.
Thank you for your understanding sir. I'll book your flight now.
All right, we're back. So now it's time for us to go into language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, in language takeaway today, we have about four words or phrases. The first one is the
reason for this cancellation. The reason is mechanical problems. That's right. She said that the
airplane has some mechanical problems and that's why the flight is canceled. So the key here is
mechanical. Mechanical meaning like related to machines. All right. So something that's a mechanical
problem has to do with the actual structure of the plane. That's right. So for example, maybe something
is wrong with the wings or maybe something is wrong with the engines. Some type of problem that
has to do with the mechanics of the machine. Right. And obviously, if you have a problem with the wings
or the wheels or the engine, you don't want to fly that plane. That's right. So this caused the
canceled flight. Now after that, we heard this word. We apologize for any incanveniences. What's an
incanvenience, Marco? That's right. Well, obviously, I planned it to take this flight. Let's say two
days at eight a.m. And if the flight is canceled, that means I have to wait an hour or three hours or
maybe for the next day. So it's an inconvenience. It means it's not convenient for me. It causes me
some trouble. All right. So something that is inconvenient causes problems or causes trouble.
That's right. For example, you have this late flight or canceled flight. That's an inconvenience.
But also small things can be inconvenient as well. Like I want to go home at five.
Unfortunately, I have to write this report. It's very inconvenient. That's right. So maybe you
have a doctor's appointment tomorrow at 12, but you also have a meeting at your work. So it's in
convenient these two dates. All right. They cause problems for each other. So after that, the service
person says if your flight is urgent, I can put you on a waiting list. Right.
Waiting list. So this is another important phrase to understand when we're talking about
canceled flights. That's right. We usually get put on a waiting list. And it's basically a list with
everyone's names where you are waiting for the next available flight or you're waiting for
to be able to have the service provided. All right. So you can have a waiting list at an
airport like here, but you can also have a waiting list at a restaurant. Right. That's right.
Some restaurants are super popular. And you gotta get an waiting list. So can I put my name on the
waiting list? That means can you call me when there's a free table? Right. Exactly. So even though
we are on this waiting list, it doesn't mean that we are guaranteed to be able to take this flight
this evening. So there is no guarantee. All right. This guarantee. This is an important thing
to talk about because a guarantee is something that means that we will definitely get a later flight.
Yeah. We promise. We promise. So you often see the word guarantee in advertisements. For
example, this TV has a six month guarantee. So we guarantee it won't break. If it does, we will fix it.
That's right. But no guarantee means that we can't promise. We don't promise. That's right.
So it's possible that you won't get a flight. So for example, if you buy a new car, the
manufacturer will guarantee that it's in good condition and it won't break down. But if you buy a
used car, it's not, it's unlikely that they will give you that same guarantee. No, that's right. They
cannot promise it because they don't know. Exactly. All right. So a lot of words and phrases there
when we go back and listen to our dialogue again.
Good afternoon sir. May I please see your passport and reservation? Here you go.
Oh, I'm sorry sir. This flight has been canceled. Do you just have mechanical problems?
Can't hold. What am I supposed to do now? We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this evening. But
it's on a first come first serve basis. So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
What are my other options? Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for
today and you can take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning. That's fine. I'll do that then.
Thank you for your understanding sir. I'll book your flight now.
All right. So now let's take a look at three key phrases that we have prepared for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. So the first phrase we have here is a very important one. This tells us
about the cause of the problem. The service person said, I'm sorry sir. This flight has been canceled.
Do to some mechanical problems. Right. So this phrase do to basically saying because of
right. That's right. So this flight has been canceled because of mechanical problems. I remember
this do is DE. That's right DE. So I think it's kind of a nicer or more formal way of saying
because of or the reason is. Exactly. For example, the picnic has been canceled due to bad weather.
So it sounds a lot more professional, a lot more formal than if you say because of bad weather.
All right. So just remember here due to indicates the cause or the reason it's like saying because
all right. Now when we were talking about the flights, we said that we are in the waiting list,
but in order to catch this flight, they are going to take people on a first come first served basis.
All right. First come first serve. This is a this is again a very common phrase. It's related to
that waiting list thing we were talking about. If you have a waiting list, usually the waiting
list is first come first serve. So I could say, you know, am I guaranteed a spot and you could say,
well, it's first come for serve. Maybe maybe not. Right. If I'm number one on list, I will probably
get a seat, but if I'm number 30, probably probably not. So what we mean by it is that we don't
give priority to anyone. We don't say, oh, you are more important or you're not whoever comes first,
gets it. All right. So if I come to the restaurant at five o'clock, I get to see it
sit first. But if you come at five, ten, you're next and after you five, 30. So it's first come first
serve. It depends on when you arrive. That's right. So obviously, this wasn't convenient for us.
So we are going to wait until tomorrow, but the airline will put us up in a hotel. We will put
you up in a hotel. All right. So let's take this as a phrase because we all know that hotel is
it's a place where you stay in your own holiday or business. But to put someone up,
what exactly does this mean? Basically, you are paying for that person to stay at that hotel.
And you made the reservation and you're going to pay for the room. So I will put you up means
I will pay for your room at a hotel. Right. And it's usually only for accommodation for a hotel.
Right. You can say, I will put you up for a meal. No, but you can't say I'll put you up at my house,
which means I will let you stay the night at my house. So not food, but actually sleeping.
Done. Right. So it usually involves sleeping. That's right. So for example, you could say,
he's coming to our hometown for the wedding. I will put him up at my house. Right. Or if you're
company sent you to Japan, you say my company put me up at the high hotel. Who can see nice?
All right. So that's all the phrases we have for you. Let's listen to a dialogue one last time.
Good afternoon, sir. May I please see your passport and reservation? Here you go.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir. This flight has been canceled. Do just some mechanical problems.
Can't hold. What am I supposed to do now? We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this evening. But
it's on a first-come first-serve basis. So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
What are my other options? Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for
today and you can take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning. That's fine. I'll do that then.
Thank you for your understanding, sir. I'll book your flight now.
All right. We're back. I was talking about canceled flights. Usually it's due to bad weather.
Usually you can catch another flight soon. But sometimes you do have this problem.
Like when there was the whole 9-11 thing, I think a lot of flights were canceled or the volcano
that erupted and European flights were grounded for a long time.
Yes, that's right. Sometimes there are natural disasters. Sometimes there are man-made disasters.
But you actually said a very interesting word there and something that I think people who are
learning about this should definitely study. The word is grounded. A flight has been grounded.
Yes, that means that the airplane will stay on the ground. It means the plane will not fly.
Okay. So when planes are grounded because of bad weather or because of a natural disaster,
like a volcano, it's a very serious situation because the people who are going to fly can't
know. Now in our dialogue, we saw that the handle did the airline handle it very, very well.
But I think this is a very rare case. How do you have flights canceled before? How do they handle it?
I have, I've had two or three flights canceled one time because of a blizzard. So all flights were
grounded. The weather was very bad, very dangerous. And the airline company said, well, we're
sorry, there are no more flights, but if you come back tomorrow, we can help you. And I was very
lucky because they did not give me a hope. They did not put me up in a hotel, but I was staying
with a friend, so my friend put me up at her house. But the other time, the flight was canceled,
the airline put me on a flight from another company, another airline company. And so sometimes
they can do that where they have a relationship with another airline company, they can do that.
So usually they do try to handle it relatively well. But they've heard sometimes that they are not
very understanding or very sympathetic to the inconvenience they cause.
Definitely. And I think the worst is when it's bad weather because everyone's angry.
And all the customers need to go somewhere, but they can't because they're in no flights.
And so the people who are working for the airlines get very frustrated or upset.
Right, because basically it's not their fault. It's not their fault. There's bad weather. So there's
not really much compensation the company can give you.
No, definitely not, not really their fault. But it's hard not to get frustrated because you want
to go home, your tired, you don't want to pay for another 9 o'clock hotel. So I can understand both
sides. Right. Well, it's an interesting topic. And I'm sure many of our listeners who have
traveled have had a flight delayed or canceled. So you can come to our website and share your story
with us. And of course, if you have any questions or comments. You can find us at
EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you all there. All right. Bye, guys.