Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco and my name is Catherine and today we're talking about one of my least favorite things Marco
mosquitoes
They're all over the place especially in summer or near water
Exactly
And for me the worst part is when you were trying to sleep and there's a mosquito that just keeps on biting you and won't let you sleep
You
Yeah, you can kind of hear it around your your head. Yeah, I hear you hear
Hate that or when you just get bitten and you're in bed and that just it's so much
In the burn sometimes. Yeah, so that has what we're talking about today fun stuff
Let's jump right into this dialogue and we're back in a minute to talk about what's going on
The mosquitoes are biting me too
Can't stop scratching. They're everywhere sneaky little jerks. Do you have any bugs brain? No, I forgot to buy some
Then we'll have to put up with it
We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they bite us. They'll get drunk and fall asleep
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had. Let's do it
Run there's different more
Yeah
All right, we're back. So let's take a look at some of these words in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, so as we mentioned we're going to be talking about mosquitoes and well these are just little small insects that suck your blood
They do and they're very thin and
And
Not much to say about them. They were very important in the movie Jurassic Park if you remember that
Right now what's the difference between a mosquito and a fly?
Okay, a fly usually is just annoying. It doesn't suck your blood
But a mosquito does it sucks your blood and flies are fatter and and like
Shorter and they're big and black and they're green kind of some black and green and they
Yeah, they just buzz around so mosquitoes actually bite you. Okay, so a mosquito and they fly now if a mosquito bites you
You really really want to scratch that's right. So you feel like you need to scratch your body because you have this bite
You're you know, it's really an allergy and you have a red bump on your arm a red mark
And you scratch and it gets worse and worse. All right, and we'll be on to our next word mosquitoes have a reputation of being
Sneaky okay, so you can say sneaky about a lot of things one, you know obviously we're saying mosquitoes are very sneaky
That means that they can kind of hide and get you when you're not expecting it. Yeah, because sometimes during the day
You don't really see them in your room, right?
They're hiding or they're in a place where you can't really see them and then a night all the sudden they come out
They come out so and they're very hard to see they fly around in a way that's very difficult to catch them or kill them right
All right, we could say thieves are very sneaky like a thief is someone who steals something and they like to sneak
Around and hide in the dark and then when you're not expecting it they come out and they still your stuff
Exactly and now what do we what do we do or what do we use in order to prevent mosquitoes from biting us?
This is essential especially if you're going to the beach. Uh, we bring bugs spray bugs spray
So a spray is something that
Shhh, that you can usually have in a can that you push a button and then it comes out all right
It's like a it's like water, but it keeps the bugs away so bugs break keeps bugs away not only mosquitoes, but like
Slice too flies or any other type of bug now specifically for mosquitoes you would use maybe a
Mosquito repellent right so repellent is it means something that pushes or keeps away things you don't want
So something that keeps mosquitoes away is called a mosquito repellent and usually it's a cream
You put on your arms or legs. All right very good. So interesting words that we've just taken a look at
Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be right back
The mosquitoes are biting me
Me too. I can't stop scratching. They're everywhere sneaky little jerks
Do you have any bugs spray? No, I forgot to buy some
Then we'll have to put up with it. We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they buy us
They'll get drunk and fall asleep
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had. Let's do it
Run the thirsty for more
All right we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of different phrases on fluency builder
Fluency builder
All right, so the first phrase is very very common
The person in the dialogue says that they're going to have to put up with it put up with these mosquitoes because they didn't have any bugs spray
So this phrase to put up with is really important. All right, so if you put up with something
It means that you tolerate it all right that means even if you don't want to you'll still handle it
You'll still have to deal with that you accept it
So maybe you have a little brother that's very annoying and you just have to put up with him
There's no other option
Yeah, or um someone says to you you're just gonna have to put up with it or you say I won't put up with it anymore
I won't handle it anymore. I'm done. All right, so I think this is a great phrase for us to take a look at a couple of different examples
Example one I
Can't put up with the noise any longer turn that music down
Example two
If you can put up with the smell then stinky tofu is actually very tasty
Example three
I've had to put up with him for too long. I want a new roommate
And after this we've got another phrase we're talking about beer, okay, and so the person says oh I have an idea
Instead of bugs spray we can we can cover ourselves with beer
So to cover yourself or cover ourselves
So it means that we put it all over us right so you could even cover yourself with bugs spray
Okay, so every part of your body you put bugs spray on head to toe head to toe
Now you can cover yourself under a tree maybe or you can cover yourself with a blanket
Okay, so to cover yourself to completely hide under something and
Finally we have the response to this idea the answer the person says oh without a doubt that means
Absolutely or definitely okay, so there is no doubt it is true or it is certain
Right, so a doubt is something that maybe you're not so sure about you're not convinced
But you can say this is without a doubt the best mosquito spray or this is without a doubt the best cake
I've ever eaten that means it's definitely the best cake of ever eaten all right
So I think we've covered all the phrases now why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back
The mosquitoes are biting me me too. I can't stop scratching here everywhere sneaky little jerks
Do you have any bugs spray no I forgot to buy some then we'll have to put up with it
We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they bite us they'll get drunk and fall asleep
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had let's do it
Run there's different more
Oh
mosquitoes are very annoying but at times it can be very dangerous right they can there are a couple of diseases that can be passed
By mosquito bites one of them is malaria and that's I think pretty common in Southeast Asia and South Asia
Now there was another situation where people believe that if a mosquito bit a person infected with HIV or AIDS
Be could pass it on to another person. Aha, well, I don't know that that's even possible
Right, there's no AIDS carrying mosquitoes, but there's another disease called dengue fever. Thank you,
favorite and this is another very dangerous one. It's also known as break bone fever and I think it's it's so painful
It feels like your bones are breaking and that's what it comes. It's very common in South America as well
And because we have such a tropical climate that in the rainforests of Brazil, Peru, Columbia
It's it's common to to see this but not so much anymore another eradicating it. Oh, wow all right
So an interesting topic mosquitoes are not only irritating but can be dangerous so if you have any other
Questions or doubts please come to our website English.com and we're there to answer any questions
So we'll see you on the website and until next time everyone bye bye