Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
And I'm Erica
And today with Erica we're bringing you a great lesson about time
You need more of it
We need more time, right?
So we're going to be teaching you how you can ask for more time
If you're working on a project at work and you can't finish it on time
You have to ask your boss for more time
Right
So today in our dialogue Casey needs more time to put together a press kit
What's the press kit?
Good question
A press kit is something the marketing department will put together
Basically pictures, logos, uh, uh, information about the company
So when a newspaper or a magazine wants to write an article about them
So they have something already prepared that they could give the newspaper or a magazine
Okay
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time
And as always it's going to be at a normal speed
So it might be a little bit difficult to understand
Welcome back in one minute and tell you about some of the key language
So Casey, how are things going with the photos for the press kit?
Yeah, I've been meeting the talk to you about that
I might need to ask for an extension on that deadline
You've had over a month to get this finalized
Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is
We ran into a lot of problems
I'm not looking for excuses here
I just want to get this finished on time
I know
And I apologize for the delay
But some things were just beyond my control
I had trouble booking the photographer
And then Michael was sick for three weeks
So I couldn't include him in the photos
And the design team lost all the files
So I had to redo the pictures
I'm not going to put this off any longer Casey
I want those photos
ASAP
Alright, so Casey is in trouble, I think
Yeah, I think her boss is pretty upset
Yeah
Well, let's take a look at some of the language that we saw in this dialogue
In language takeaway
Language takeaway
First word today is deadline
Deadline
So Erica, what's a deadline?
It is the last possible date to do something
So for example, when we were in school
Our teacher would send us homework and say it was for Friday
So the deadline was Friday
Was Friday
Right?
Or when you're at work you have projects that you have to finish by a certain date
That's your deadline
Exactly
Okay, let's look at our next word
Extension
So extension and deadline go together, right?
Exactly
If you can't reach your deadline or you can't make your deadline
You must ask for an extension
Extension, so you ask for more time
Yeah, an extension is moving the deadline in the future
Alright, interesting
Let's look at our next word
Ran into
Ran into some problems
So we ran into some problems in this dialogue
Let's listen to some more examples of
Running to so we can understand the meaning
Example one
We ran into a storm on our way home
Example two
If you're not careful now you're going to run into a lot of problems later
Example three
I
Ran into some trouble with my computer
Okay, good example, so it's clear now, right?
Right, if you run into problems you meet some problems
Right many students say it in that way. I met some problems
Yeah, but that's wrong
Right, so you would say I ran into some problems
I met some problems is wrong wrong wrong
Okay, don't say met some problems. I ran into some problems. I ran into okay
And our last word for language take away delayed delayed delayed delayed delayed delayed
So when something is delayed it's late late and the opposite is on time. Yeah, so your flight was delayed
Or your flight was on time the project was delayed or your project was on time
There alright
So now let's go back to the dialogue. Let's listen to it again and this time it will be a little bit slow
So you can understand some of these phrases we just talked about
So, Casey how are things going with the photos for the press kit?
Yeah, I've been meeting the talk to you about that
I might need to ask for an extension on that deadline
You've had over a month to get this finalized. Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is we ran into a lot of problems. I'm not looking for excuses here
I just want to get this finished on time
I know and I apologize for the delay
But some things were just beyond my control
I had trouble booking a photographer and then Michael was sick for three weeks
So I couldn't include him in the photos and the design team lost all the files
So I had to redo the pictures. I'm not going to put this off any longer Casey. I want those photos ASAP
Okay, so there were some really useful phrases that we saw in this dialogue. Yeah, some wonderful phrases
That you can use when you want to ask for more time. Okay, so let's look at these phrases in fluency builder
Fluency builder. All right, what's our first phrase? I've been meaning to talk to you. I've been meaning to
I've been meaning to
Okay, we have some really great examples of how you can combine. I've been meaning to with different verbs. Yeah, let's listen
Example one
I'm sorry I haven't called you yet. I've been meaning to but I've been busy
Example two
I've been meaning to tell you but John quick yesterday
Example three
I've been meaning to see that film for a while
I've been meaning to go to that restaurant but I haven't had time
So you've been wanting to for a long time
I've been thinking about it. I've got planning to do it but you just haven't done it. I haven't done it
Maybe because I haven't had time or money. Mm-hmm. Okay. Good phrase
Our next phrase is
Beyond my control beyond my control. It's beyond my control. So it means that I can't control it
You can't do anything about it. Can't do anything about it. The weather is beyond my control
Right or relate with this project because Jane was sick for one month. It was beyond my control. Okay. It wasn't your fault. No. Okay
And our last phrase for Fluency builder put this off put this off
Put this off
So let's listen to some more examples of put this off before we explain the meaning
Example one
I've been putting off this project for a week and it's due tomorrow
Example two
Can we put off our meeting till next week? I'm too busy right now
Example three
I've been putting off my email all day and now I have 50 messages to respond to
So Marco when you put something off you leave it for later. Okay, right? So maybe I have to write a report today
But I'm gonna put it off till tomorrow. So you're gonna do it tomorrow. I'll do it tomorrow. Okay, so we've seen some really great words and some really good phrases
So now let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk some more
So Casey how are things going with the photos for the press kit?
Yeah, I've been meaning to talk to you about that
I might need to ask for an extension on that deadline
You've had over a month to get this finalized
Why are things delayed?
Well, the thing is we ran into a lot of problems. I'm not looking for excuses here
I just want to get this finished on time. I know and I apologize for the delay
But some things were just beyond my control. I had trouble booking the photographer and then Michael was sick for three weeks
So I couldn't include him in the photos and the design team lost all the files
So I had to redo the pictures. I'm not going to put this off any longer Casey. I want those photos asap
Marco, do you think that Casey's reasons for being late are good?
I think so because it wasn't really her fault the whole situation with the photographer and then one of her co-workers was sick for three weeks
Yeah, it's not really her fault right right but maybe the boss thinks that she's making excuses
Yeah, maybe she's making excuses. That's really common like for example when we were kids you would say oh
You know my dog ate my homework right but that really happened to me once
Your dog ate your homework. My cat ate my homework. Your cat ate your homework. Yeah, and what did your teachers say?
Well, actually I was a really good student so my teacher believed me
Well, my teacher wouldn't have believed me really no no she would have she would have called my parents most like
I might my cat really did eat my homework and I just left it on the table and it chewed it all up. That's weird
Why would your cat do that? I don't know a lot of weird excuses out there. Yeah, I was abducted by aliens
My mom accidentally mailed my homework to Africa really
Yeah, that's happened to you creative writing creative excuses
Well, I want to hear from our listeners. I want to know what excuses they've used for being late with something
So send us your excuses send us your comments and questions go to our website at englishpod.com
Where Eric and I are always there to answer your questions. That's right Marco and this is an elementary lesson, right?
Exactly, but we also have intermediate and upper intermediate and advanced lessons for you more fluent English speakers
Exactly, so if you're listening to us on iTunes be sure to visit our website and come see what else we have to offer
Well, I think we're out of time, but until next time it's goodbye