Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very descriptive lesson for you.
That's right. We have an elementary lesson for everyone and we are going to talk about facial hair.
Okay so Mark or you don't have any facial hair?
I don't. Well I like to shave every other day but yeah that's what facial hair is.
This is hair that you have on your face.
Okay so we're at the police station in this dialogue. Let's take a listen and find out why.
Okay Sally we have an artist here to help us.
We'll ask you questions about the bank rubber you saw and Paul will draw the picture. Are you ready?
Yes.
Well he had brown hair long hair and he had some facial hair. It was brown too.
Good. Okay the facial hair was it a beard or a mustache?
Both. His mustache was very short and thin just on the top of his lip.
Uh-huh. Hmm like this?
Yes that's the mustache but the beard isn't right. I mean it didn't cover his whole face.
I think it was just on his chin.
A go-team. Was it like paul's?
Uh yes that's it. He had a go-team.
Okay now what about sideburns? Did he have sideburns?
Um yes they were long and thick like yours.
All right there was this the man you saw.
Yes that's him. Hmm it looks a little like you.
Hmm why yes he does. Paul where were you on Friday afternoon?
What? That's ridiculous. He wasn't me. I didn't do anything.
I was over there doing the thing the best bad dude.
All right we're back so as you can see the woman is describing a bank robber and one of the ways that she's describing him is by the facial hair that he had.
So there are a lot of very interesting words and phrases here why don't we take a look at some of them in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay so in language takeaway today we have some really good description words and nouns.
Things that people have on their face.
Facial hair because there's not just one kind of facial hair. There are many different kinds.
All right.
Our first one is are we gonna skip facial hair because we can't really guess.
Our first one is mustache.
Okay a mustache and this is I think one of the more popular forms of facial hair.
I think it's a style right all these styles of facial hair.
That's right and so a mustache is basically some hair on top of your lip.
Hmm it's above your lip and it's usually it can be thin or thick.
It comes in different sizes but this is not your whole face.
It's just above your lip.
All right. So for example a famous person or a famous mustache was Charlie Chaplin right.
That's right Charlie Chaplin had a mustache just a little bit of hair above his lip.
But also Thidor Roosevelt had a very big bushy mustache.
That's right.
Interesting fact you might hear someone say stash instead of mustache.
This is a short way to say it.
So oh he's growing a stash.
And also the spelling can be a little bit difficult to understand how you pronounce it because it's MUST-A-C-H-E.
So there's no really a sage sound like sh.
But you pronounce it mustache.
mustache yeah.
So that's one kind of facial hair but there are many others.
The next one we've got for you is a beard.
A beard.
Okay this is a really good one. A beard.
I think a beard keeps men warm.
I think a beard keeps a man warm in the winter.
Yeah definitely.
This is the most hair.
So basically a beard you have hair on your lip and also all over your face basically.
So a beard you have all over your face.
Right your cheeks your chin and above your lip.
Okay very good.
So a famous person with a beard?
Santa Claus.
Santa Claus has a very big beard.
Yeah Santa Claus has a beard.
Right.
Big white beard.
Okay so that's a beard.
I think that's that's the easiest to have because you don't need to cut anything or
shaving anything.
Oh you need to.
Oh yeah you need to.
If you don't trim it looks kind of bad.
Right.
Well now moving on to our next style of facial hair we have a go-t.
Okay this might be confusing for some people because it's not a beard and it's not a mustache.
It's basically hair around your mouth on your chin and your lip.
So I think a shunconery has a very famous go-t.
And Brad hit right now has a really good go-t.
Okay long go-t lots of hair.
So as you say it's around your mouth so you're lip and your chin.
That's right.
A go-t.
Okay so that's our third style of facial hair and now moving on to our last style we have sideburns.
Okay so think about the word here sideburns side.
They're on your side.
They're on the side so near the ears there is usually some space where a man can grow some hair.
Not with a beard or necessarily mustache though.
It can be just a hair on the jawline.
Near the jaw, near the ears.
Okay.
So I think this was a very famous style in the 60s and 70s.
You would let you would have long sideburns all along your face.
That's right.
Past your ear, right?
And the longer maybe the sex year you were.
The sex year.
No but these days it's not as popular but you do see people who have sideburns.
I think nowadays people have sideburns but they're not as thick.
They're just thin little sideburns.
Yeah that's right.
All right so all of these are the different sorts and styles of facial hair.
Of course there are a lot more.
I think while we were looking for this on the internet we found a lot of other styles that came up like
a mutton chops and things like this but these are probably the most popular ones.
That's right.
These are the ones you're going to hear about the most.
Okay.
So why don't we go back listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
Okay Sally.
We have an artist here to help us.
We'll ask you questions about the bank robbery you saw and Paul will draw a picture.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Well he had brown hair long hair and he had some facial hair.
It was brown too.
Good.
Okay the facial hair was it a beard or a mustache?
Both.
His mustache was very short and thin just on the top of his lip.
Uh-huh.
Like this?
Yes that's the mustache but the beard isn't right.
I mean it didn't cover his whole face.
I think it was just on his chin.
A go-team?
Was it like Paul's?
Uh-huh.
Yes that's it.
He had a go-team.
Okay.
Now what about sideburns?
Did he have sideburns?
Um yes.
They were long and thick.
Like yours.
Alright.
There.
Was this the man you saw?
Yes that's him.
Hmm.
It looks a little like you.
Why yes he does.
Paul.
Where were you on Friday afternoon?
What?
That's ridiculous.
It wasn't me.
I didn't do anything.
I was over there doing the thing.
The best man who to do.
Alright so today in Fluency Builder we are not really talking about phrases as much as
we're talking about adjectives.
So words you can use to describe facial hair.
Okay.
So when the girl was describing facial hair for example she said the mustache was very short
and thin.
Okay.
A short and thin mustache.
So you think about it you can have a very thick mustache.
That's the opposite.
That means very hairy.
Very wide.
A thin mustache is like a line.
Okay.
Okay so for example Charlie Chaplin he had a short mustache but it wasn't thin.
It was a little bit thick.
That's right.
It was kind of wide.
But you think of you know when you see someone who's drawing a mustache on a sign
at a restaurant or in a newspaper.
Right.
That's usually very thin.
Because these are pens.
You know it's very silly looking.
Right.
So those are different adjectives to describe.
Not only a mustache.
So basically we can use these to describe any sort of hair.
For example the hair on your head.
You can say he's got short hair.
That's right.
Or I could say I have long hair.
Long hair.
Or Markler because you have thick hair.
Fick.
Yeah.
So if you have an abundance of hair that you would say it's thick.
That's right.
There's a you know it's like if you put your hand in it it's very.
It feels like there's a lot that's very thick hair.
Okay.
Some people have thin hair.
So they don't have a lot of hair.
Okay.
Good.
And well moving on to the parts of the face.
We described it before us to wear a mustache is where a go-t is.
But let's take a closer look at that.
For example a mustache is on your upper lip.
Right.
So just above your lip under your nose.
That's where a mustache goes.
So that's the upper lip.
But if we're talking about a go-t it's not just on your upper lip.
It's also where on your chin.
Your chin.
So that's the very bottom point of your face.
So you have your chin your upper lip.
And also when we talked about for example the sideburns.
We talked about the job but also it could be part of the cheek.
Right.
So every person has two cheeks.
One on the left and one on the right.
And those are a very big part of your face.
On the sides of your nose.
Okay.
So you have your chin.
You have your cheeks.
You have your upper lip.
I think that's pretty much the only places where you can grow a...
Also on your neck.
Yes.
Some people have it on their neck or on the back of...
Well, no, it's not that bad.
Some people also have it on their neck.
Right.
Okay.
Very good.
So a lot of different words to describe facial hair.
Why don't we go back?
Listen to the dialogue one last time.
And we'll be back to talk some more.
Okay, Sally.
We have an artist here to help us.
We'll ask you questions about the bank robbery you saw
and Paul will draw the picture.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Well, he had brown hair.
Long hair.
And he had some facial hair.
It was brown too.
Good.
Okay.
The facial hair was it a beard or a mustache?
Both.
His mustache was very short and thin.
Just on the top of his lip.
Uh-huh.
Like this?
Yes, that's the mustache.
But the beard isn't right.
I mean, it didn't cover his whole face.
I think it was just on his chin.
A go-team?
Was it like Paul's?
Uh, yes, that's it.
He had a go-team.
Okay.
Now, what about sideburns?
Did he have sideburns?
Um, yes.
They were long and thick.
Like yours.
Alright.
There.
Was this the man you saw?
Yes, that's him.
Hmm.
It looks a little like you.
Why, yes, he does.
Paul.
Where were you on Friday afternoon?
What?
That's ridiculous.
It wasn't me.
I didn't do anything.
I was over there doing the thing.
The best bad dude to do.
Alright, so talking about facial hair, Catherine.
Do you like men that have facial hair?
Yes.
Yeah, you like mustache's beard, go-tees.
Um, well, it really depends.
I really like sideburns, but sometimes people don't do them correctly,
so I don't like them.
But, um, I like beard.
Um, and yeah, go-tee.
I like facial hair.
You like facial hair.
What is it about facial hair on men that you like?
Manly men.
I don't know.
There's something, you know, kind of rough about it.
Rough, yeah.
Yeah, I don't like the very manicured, very carefully cut facial hair.
I don't like it a little bit more on the rough side.
Oh, okay.
It's interesting, because, uh, it's interesting to see also facial hair on, um,
learned long facial hair, like for example, the guys from ZZ top,
like really long beard.
I wonder how long it takes to grow something like that?
I'm sure we could find out on the internet, but, uh, yeah, no, they have competitions.
There's a world mustache competition, for example,
and they have the world's longest mustache.
And so the man, you know, they measure his mustache.
It's three or four meters or something.
Yeah, it gets really long.
Yeah, so I think your hair keeps growing.
It just depends on when you decide to cut it.
I think it's also a very cultural thing, right?
Some cultures are, uh, able to grow a lot of facial hair and like to do it.
Uh, others really don't.
For example, you don't really see many Asians with, uh, facial hair,
with goatese or mustachees.
I think you see more goatese than you see full beard, actually,
but, uh, yeah, definitely East Asia.
It's not as common.
Although India, you see a lot a little bit more facial.
A lot of mustachees there.
Yeah.
Yeah. So this is an interesting question.
Tell us how popular it is in your country, or if you like men with facial hair,
or if you're a guy, do you like to have a beard, mustache, or a go-t.
So come to our website, EnglishPod.com, and we'll see everyone there.