Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco
and my name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you guys out there
that's right today we are going to talk about an interesting topic especially for women
we are going to the nails salon
okay so we're going to get our finger nails painted
alright so let's take a look at vocabulary preview to find out what nails salon means
very cablory preview
alright so if you go to a nail salon it's a specific place where they paint your nails right
exactly so it's a shop or a store where you can have your nails painted so they have special
people to help you if you want to go get your hair cut you would go to the hair salon
exactly so we have hair salon and nail salon in this case that the nail salon they can't cut your hair
okay very good so why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time
honey I'll be right back where are you going? I told you already I'm going to get my nails done
again you just went last week you spend more time at the nails salon than you do here at home
honestly why do you need to manic your every week? well first of all I like to pamper myself
and my nails look great you should come with me why I don't want to have meal polish or anything like that
they don't only paint my nails the manicurists will remove my cuticles, fire my nails and
apply at least four coats of nail polish yeah sounds like something I should definitely do
alright we're back so now we found some very interesting and specific words related to nails
so why don't we look at those now on language takeaway language takeaway all right so this
first word is an important word for every woman to know and I know a lot of men who get this too it's
called a manicure all right manicure and what exactly is a manicure? well a manicure is a service
that you get at a nail salon and that means that the people at the nail salon will cut your nails
and shape your nails that means if you want them to be pointy or boxy and then you get them
painted and dried okay so they basically take care of your of your nails of your fingernails
a manicure exactly and so the important thing to remember here that a manicure is for your hands
right so you can also get your toenails or your feet taking care of right exactly so that's
different that's a pedicure because pedicure means foot so pedicure is for your feet and a manicure
is for your hands all right very good and well we talked about painting your nails and the
that paint has a specific name right exactly so you wouldn't use wall paint on your fingers right
right so you have to use a special paint and this is called nail polish nail polish okay
so a polish is something that makes a surface or a thing shiny okay so nail polish is a
paint that makes your nails very shiny all right very good and well moving on we talked about a
manicure and there's a specific word for the person that provides this service to take care of your nails
okay so the job at a nail salon is manicurist that's the person who paints your nails okay
and so you could say I have a favorite manicurist her name is Sally okay very good and well
manicurist they perform a manicure and well apart from painting your nails they also
push your cuticles or remove your cuticles like in the dialogue what are the cuticles okay
cuticle is a very hard word this word describes the skin around your fingernail okay so
you have skin all over your body but on your fingernail you have special kind of skin and so
a manicurist will sometimes push or cut the dead skin that's the the cuticle from your finger
okay very good so if you look at your fingernails now you will see a little thin layer of skin on
your fingernail that's the cuticle and well apart from removing your cuticles and painting your nails
they will also file your nails and this is a verb to file to file okay so this is a word that's
kind of like cut or trim but a file is a more delicate process so it means that we kind of
shave off very very very little at a time and so to file your nails means to to make them
shaped differently or to smooth them they're not cutting clip clip it's not that it's a little bit
less than that and now there's also a noun for this a nail file and most women will usually have it
it's a it's a long piece of cardboard that has a paper that's kind of like sand on it kind of like
sand paper it doesn't feel good when you rub it with your hand with your hand but if you use it on
your nails it will little by little just take away little parts of your nail yeah like that usually
see it the many secretaries you know and TV shows they're always filing their nails exactly making them
perfect okay so those are the words we have for language takeaway why don't we take a look at our
dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit honey I'll be right back where are you going
I told you already I'm going to get my nails done again you just went last week you spend more
time at the nails along the new do here at home honestly why do you need to manic your every week
well first of all I like to pamper myself and my nails look great you should come with me why I
don't want to have nail polish or anything like that they don't only paint my nails the manicurists
will remove my cuticles find my nails and apply at least four coats of nail polish yeah sounds like
something I should definitely do all right we're back so now why don't we start with some phrases
some very good phrases that we found in this dialogue in fluency builder fluency builder
this first place is really important when we talk about nails because it's the way that we
describe going to the nail salon so I can say I'm going to get my nails done today okay so to get
your nails done mm-hmm that means that you're going to get your nails cut filed painted etc.
I'm going to get a manicure but that's very I don't know I'm serious so you could say I'm going to
get my nails done it's more spoken language okay so I'm going to get my nails and or you got your nails
done very good and well the woman was talking about why she likes to go get a manicure and she said
that she likes to pamper herself okay this is very common especially when women are trying to talk
about why they spend money on hair and nails and clothes is I like to pamper myself to pamper
means to treat very very well okay so if you go get a manicure it's kind of like pampering yourself
or maybe going to a spa exactly or getting massage and so we could say also don't pamper the dog
he's very naughty so a sinnidim would be to spoil to spoil oneself to pamper indulge okay so
and well she was talking about how they they perform a manicure and she talked about
four coats of nail polish so a coat we know that it's kind of like a jacket right but in this case
in this case it means a layer so you paint your nails one time okay
mm-hmm you have color maybe it doesn't look right okay it's very thin so you say okay I'm going to
paint two coats and then you paint one more time and the color gets darker you paint one more time
the color gets very dark and very thick and so these are called coats that means layers of nail
polish and it's a special where we use we're talking about painting our nails right so it's not only
for nails but if you're painting your house maybe you need two or three coats of paint exactly if we
have a red wall and we want to paint it white we definitely need two three maybe four coats of paint
otherwise we'll still see the red mm-hmm okay very good very interesting phrases let's take a look
at this dialogue for the very last time and we'll be back shortly
honey I'll be right back where are you going I told you already I'm going to get my nails done again
you just went last week you've been more time at the nails along than you do here at home honestly
why do you need a manicure every week well first of all I like to pamper myself and my nails look
great you should come with me why I don't want to have meal polish or anything like that
they don't only paint my nails the manicures will remove my cuticles find my nails and
apply at least four coats of nail polish yeah sounds like something I should definitely do
all right we're back so a Katherine are you a big fan of manicures so you get it done often
I didn't use to but I really enjoy them now I think it's a nice way to relax on the weekend
so every couple of weeks I go to the nail salon and I have my nails done all right and I think
one of the words that we didn't talk about here but it's very I don't know for men it's kind of
a strange smell is nail polish remover they pass it's own right it's a it's a very strong chemical
it is really disgusting nail polish remover you know the the word to remove means to take away
and so when the nail polish we want to change the color we have to use this it's like water but
it smells really bad and so my boyfriend always gets angry when I use the nail polish remover because the
whole house starts to stink it's a very strong smell and you get kind of dizzy so yeah it's a
wasn't your head all right well if you guys have any questions any doubts or any suggestions about
this lesson or any other lesson please come to our website EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there
bye everyone