Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we're talking all about animals.
That's right. This is a very interesting topic, very important because a lot of people like to have pets.
That's right. We're not going to the zoo. We're not talking about animals out in the forest or in nature.
We're talking about pets that you keep at home. So let's start right away with today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about
what's going on.
We have been over this 100 times. We are not getting a pet.
One not. Come on. Just a cute little puppy or kitty. Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
I will. I'll feed it, bathe it and walk it every day. We can get a labrador or a German shepherd.
What if we want to take a vacation? Who will we leave it with? Plus our apartment is too small for that
breed of dog. Okay. How about we get a cat? We're a ferret. We're planning on having children soon.
I don't think those animals are a good idea with a baby in the house. Fine. Let's get a bird then.
We can keep it in its cage and teach it to talk. The parrot would be awesome. I'll tell you what.
I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it from there. Yay!
All right. We're back. So obviously pets. Having a pet at home is a very big responsibility.
And well, this is what the couple was talking about. But before we get into that discussion,
why don't we take a look at five key words that we have picked out for you on language takeaway?
Language takeaway. So first off, the couple is talking about whether they should get a dog or a cat
or puppy or a kitty. And when they start talking about dogs, they talk about what kinds of dogs or
the breed of the dogs. Let's look at this word. That's right. They were talking about a German
shepherd or a labored or and as you said, this is the breed or maybe you can say a kind of dog.
That's right. So breed is the technical word to describe the kind of dog that something is. So
like you said, these are two examples. There are many, many, many breeds that we can talk about.
But we'll just leave it at this for now. But we talked about some other kinds of animals today.
But we heard about some other kinds of animals today, not dogs, not cats, maybe smaller animals.
That's right. One of the animals that the person mentioned was a ferrit.
Oh, ferrit. So this is a very small kind of long animal. That's right. You may have seen it
had before. They kind of look like, I don't know, kind of they have the face of a rat maybe,
but they're very long and they're thin. They're very thin. They're not like a rat because maybe
their body shape is very, very different. But they're they're also kind of small and they like to eat.
I don't know. I don't know if they have long tails like rats do. I think they have fur.
They're different. Yeah. So that's a ferrit. But we also heard about a special kind of bird.
That's right. We talked about a parrot. So as you know, there are many different kinds of birds.
You can see birds at your window all the time, but birds that come from tropical places usually
very, very colorful birds are called parrots. That's right. So a parrot usually can talk or imitate
what what you say or sounds, right? That's right. They're actually very famous in the bird world
for having a good ability to reproduce or to mimic the sounds that you make. So if I say,
hello, my parrot says, hello. It's really strange. They're very, very intelligent animals.
So that's a parrot. And our last animal is a very small animal. Very popular also to have as a pet.
We talked about a hamster. A hamster. This is a little bit like a mouse. They're furry. They're small.
They're round. And they like they live in glass cages or fish tanks. Usually. Yeah. They're very
small. They don't really do much. They're just little furry creatures. And they, uh, I don't know. They
just eat all day. Sometimes they get them those little wheels that they can get inside and run
around all day. That's right. Or when I was a child and we had a hamster, we had a special
plastic ball. And you put the hamster in the ball and he would go around the house. Yeah, exactly.
It's very fun. All right. So we took a look at the pets that that you can buy domestic animals.
But taking a look at something very specific when they were describing the responsibilities of
having maybe a dog or a cat. They said that they have to feed it.
Bay that walk it. So obviously we know that feed it is to give it food. But what if
a bat bat bat? Okay. So you might know the word bath. Okay. Uh, that's a thing. It's a noun.
Bay is a verb to bat. And so I can bat myself. That means I take a shower. I clean my body.
Or I can bat something else like an animal. So bathing a dog means basically washing a dog.
Right. So it sounds very, uh, fancier, formal. If you say, I'm going to go take a shower. Or you say,
I'm going to go bat. Yeah. We don't really say that as much. But we often say bat when we're talking
about cleaning other things. Not a table, but cleaning people or animals. Right. So you can say that you
bathe the baby or did you bathe the dog? Okay. So and also remember that even though the dog
may be female or male, we don't give it gender. Right. We describe it as it. That's right.
Animals are almost always considered it in English. Although some people who really love their
animals call it he or she. Right. Right. Uh, so it's kind of your decision. It's not really
incorrect. If you say, oh my dog, she's so beautiful if it's a female. But, you know,
technically you should say my dog. It's very beautiful. Yeah. Okay. So we've taken a look at a lot of
words there. Why don't we go back? Listen to the dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
We have been over this 100 times. We are not getting a pet. One not. Come on. Just a cute little puppy
or kitty. Who's going to look after a dog or a cat? I will. I'll feed it, bathe it and walk it every
day. We can get a lab or a German shepherd. What if we want to take a vacation? Who will we leave it
with? Plus our apartment is too small for that breed of dog. Okay. How about we get a cat
or a ferret? We're planning on having children soon. I don't think those animals are a good
idea with a baby in the house. Fine. Let's get a bird then. We can keep it in its cage and teach
it to talk. A pair would be awesome. I'll tell you what. I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it
from there. Yay. All right. We're back. So now we've picked out four key phrases for you. Let's take a
look at those now in fluency builder. Fluency builder. So at the very beginning of today's conversation
we hear the first person say we've been over this a hundred times. So what does this mean? This
means that they've never talked about this before? No. This is actually the opposite but it's a
way to exaggerate. Right? Because obviously they haven't maybe talked about getting a pet a hundred
times but you're just making emphasis on the fact that we've talked about this many many many times.
And almost like you're tired of it. Like, oh, do we have to talk about this again? Right. It's like
you said an exaggeration to say come on. So we've been over this a million times. We've been over
this a hundred times. These are always of saying, oh, we have to talk about this again. Exactly.
You're emphasizing that well, maybe you've done it too many times already. All right. And
well, when they were talking about the puppy or the kitty, the guy asked, well, who's going to look
after the dog or the cat? Okay. So this is an important phrase. We're going to treat this as a
kind of a chunk. These words go together to look after. So we could look after a baby or look after
the pet. This means to watch or to care for. Right. To take care. So maybe if you're going to go
out tonight, you want to leave your son with a babysitter to look after him. Right. To make sure that
there are no problems or to make sure that he eats and goes to sleep. Exactly. So to look after,
to take care or to make sure he or she is okay. Mm-hmm. All right. And well, obviously, the guy
didn't want to puppy. He didn't want a kitty. So the girl was giving alternative and said, well,
how about we get a cat or a ferret? Okay. The phrase here, how about is very, very common in English.
I think a lot of people who learn English have a hard time knowing when to use this phrase. How about?
That's right. So it's very simple. The phrase, how about is to give an alternative. Right?
Okay. Or a suggestion. So for example, you and I are talking about where to eat lunch. I don't know.
And you give us a suggestion. You say, how about pizza? I say, I don't know. How about McDonald's.
We're giving suggestions or offering alternatives. Exactly. So this is the correct way of using
how about many students make the mistake of using it as to say, how was it or how did it go?
Right. Right. So how was your weekend? That's correct. How about your weekend? That's in
correct. No, do not say that you want to say, how about this? How about that? How about a cook? How
about some food? These are suggestions. But a real question you have to say, how was or how it is.
Right. So never, never, never say how about your weekend. That is incorrect. And it's actually very
common to hear this from students. So remember, it's not correct. How about your weekend? No,
incorrect. So at the very end of the dialogue, we're talking about hamsters. I can get you some hamsters
and we'll take it from there. That's right. The phrase, take it from there. It's kind of a way of saying,
look, let's start with something small or let's start with something simple and we will see how it goes.
So basically, the woman is saying, I don't want to commit. I don't want to agree to get a big animal,
like a dog or a cat because I'm not sure how it will be. I'm not sure if it will be too much
responsibility. So she's saying, okay, we'll get something small and then we'll wait and we'll see
what happens. We'll take it from there. That's right. So it's basically saying, let's start slowly.
So for example, maybe a guy asks you out, right? And says, hey, will you marry me? And you say, whoa,
let's go on a date first and we'll take it from there. Exactly. We'll see what happens. So let's start
slowly. Let's let's take things step by step. All right. So that's all the phrases that we have for you today.
I think we should listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
We have been over this 100 times. We are not getting a pet.
One not. Come on. Just a cute little puppy or kitty. Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
I will. I'll feed it, bathe it and walk it every day. We can get a lab or a German shepherd.
What if we want to take a vacation? Who will we leave it with? Plus, our apartment is too small
for that breed of dog. Okay. How about we get a cat? We're a ferret. We're planning on having children
soon. I don't think those animals are a good idea with a baby in the house. Fine. Let's get a bird
then. We can keep it in its cage and teach it to talk. The parrot would be awesome. I'll tell you what.
I can get you some hamsters and we'll take it from there. Yay!
All right, Catherine. So what about pets? Are you a big pet lover? Do you like ferrets?
Hamsters? All this good stuff? I don't like small pets. I love big pets. So as a kid, we had both.
My brother really loved small animals. Like hamsters and ferrets and things like that. I just think
they're a little bit stinky. I think it's smell funny. So ever since, I've always really liked
big animals like dogs. So you are a dog person? I am a dog person. This is something interesting.
We describe in English. People say I am a dog person. I am a cat person. It's almost like it
says something about your personality. Exactly. So if you're a dog person, it means that you prefer
dogs or you like dogs. If you're a cat person, you prefer cats. And a lot of people really like dogs,
but don't really like cats or they love cats and they can't stand dogs. Right. I think it even
gets to the point where I've heard that maybe on dates, people ask, so are you a dog person or a cat
person? I know that's how I pick dates. But are you a dog person or a cat person? I'm definitely a
dog person. I think cats are nice and they're totally and they're very good indoor pets and a little
bit more fun than maybe a hamster. But I think dogs are a little to have more life and are more
energetic. I think cats are very lazy. And I think sometimes cats like to play mind games.
Like they're so smart that they can control you. That makes me uncomfortable.
Right. So there are a lot of other pets out there. Some people have to ran to some people. Have
a guanas, other people have fish or horses. Horses. If you have enough space, right? So we want to
know what kind of pets do you have or did you have as a kid? That's right. Let us know. Our
website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. All right. Bye. Bye.