Hello everyone, welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
Hi guys, my name is Katherine.
And today we're going to be looking at another lesson as part of our sports series.
And this time, well, it's a debate. Is it a game or is it a sport?
Oh, it's a sport. You have to work your mind.
Yeah, so we're looking at chess. A very old, very popular sport, very difficult to play as well.
It takes a lot of practice and believe me, it's frustrating at the beginning.
It's still kind of in the beginning and in the media stages, but yeah, it takes a lot of practice.
And it takes a lot of time to familiarize yourself with the rules.
Right.
So we're going to be learning a little bit more about the pieces and the rules today.
Okay, perfect. So we're not going to preview anything.
Let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
And then we'll come back and talk about the sport.
Bobby, come here. Look what I got here.
What is that?
But just board. Daddy's going to teach you how to play.
Cool.
Okay. Each player gets 16 pieces. You can be the white ones.
I'll play with black pieces. Now in the front, we'll set up the pot.
Those are the least viable pieces and can only move one space forward.
When you're about to capture another piece, they can move one space diagonally.
What about all these other pieces?
See this one looks like a tower. It's called the rook.
The one with the tall hat is called the bishop.
See this little horsey? This is called the knight.
It's a very important piece. So it's best not to let your opponent capture it.
And these two? They are huff and wife.
That's right. That's the queen. That's the king.
If the other player captures your king, he will say Chuck Mait.
And the game is over. Doesn't this sound fun?
Nah. This sounds boring.
I'm going to go play killer zombies on my PlayStation.
Alright. So the kid is obviously not very interested in learning how to play chess.
Not at all. You know, the arts of these kind of slower games might be your place very soon by video games.
Yeah, I guess it doesn't really appeal to a little nine year old or ten year old instead of
playing something like this versus yeah, shooty.
Exactly. But it's a very great game. It's very difficult. Like we mentioned.
So we're going to look at the name of the pieces and the rules that are related to these pieces in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, the first one you might have heard before because this is a word that is often used in strategy
in general. So they're pawn.
A pawn. Usually means something that is not very important that you can use to distract an opponent.
Alright. So on the chess where you have a pawn. So these are the ones that you have the most.
But their movement is very limited. So they can only move two spaces forward on the first move, right?
Right. Or one space after that.
One space forward. And only when it's going to capture another piece can it move diagonally.
Alright. So you can't just go diagonally. You have to go forward until you're going to take another person's piece to capture it and to go diagonally.
Alright.
But a pawn is funny. You can also use this word when you're talking about other things.
He used her as a pawn in his little game.
So you want to make an analogy. You want to make a comparison from life to these games. You can use the word pawn.
Very good. Now moving on to the other pieces on the chess board. On the very far ends of the board you have the rook.
Okay. You've got two of these and they kind of look like towers from a castle.
And it's a very well, they're very important pieces and actually my favorite pieces because they're not very important at the beginning of a game.
Boom, boom, boom, boom. You can do a lot of damage because they can go anywhere in straight lines.
Right. So they can go forward backwards and to the sides as many spaces as they want.
The whole board. Yeah. So easy pieces to forget about at the beginning, but they're very important.
And now next to the rook we have the bishop.
Because this is very different from the rook because the bishop can also go anywhere, but they can only go diagonally.
Right. So only diagonally. They can also move forward directions, but diagonally, right?
Exactly. So you can go forward and back up it has to be in a diagonal slanted line.
Okay. And now next to the bishop we have the knight.
Ooh, the knight. So he's the one galloping on the horse like those old stories of King Arthur race to hear.
But the knight can go in an L shape. I've never understood this, but it's weird.
It can move two spaces forward and then one to the right or one to the left.
Or it can move two spaces to the right and then one forward. So it's very strange, but it always has to move three spaces and in the shape of an L.
So I thought maybe he was the drunken piece. He can go forward a little bit then, don't don't make it up to the side.
Right. So that's the knight. It's actually a very, very important piece as well.
And now the two main pieces, maybe of the chessboard, the queen and king.
So the king is kind of sad. He can only move one space, but the queen is really the killer because she can do anything she wants.
This is interesting, right? What do they make it like that? The queen can move as many spaces as she wants and any direction.
While the king can do the same and he's direction he wants, but only one space.
I think there's some similarity between real life now. It's like the queen can do anything she wants and the king can kind of do whatever he wants.
Well, maybe it has to do with the fact that he has to stay put and represent the country and she can move around and move behind the scenes and has a little bit more mobility.
Maybe who knows. So, but in the end, the most important piece is the king, right? Once the king is captured, the game is over.
Exactly. So let's listen to today's dialogue one more time and slow it down a bit and find out if the boy understood any of these rules.
Bobby, come here. Look what I got you.
What is that?
A chessboard. That is going to teach you how to play. Cool.
Okay. Each player gets 16 pieces. You can be the white ones and I'll play with black pieces.
Now in the front, you set up the pawns. Those are the least viable pieces and can only move one space forward.
When you're about to capture another piece, it can move one space diagonally.
What about all these other pieces?
See this one looks like a tower. It's called the rook. The one with the tall hat is called the bishop.
See this little horsey? This is called the knight. It's a very important piece.
So it's best not to let your opponent capture it.
And these two? They are husband and wife.
That's right. That's the queen and that's the king. If the other player captures your king, he will say,
Chuck Mete and the game is over. Doesn't this sound fun?
Nah. This sounds boring. I'm going to go play killer zombies on my PlayStation.
Alright, we're back.
And now we don't explain a couple of these phrases that we also use to explain the pieces.
But let's look at some of these more in depth now in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So Marko, one of the first phrases that we heard was the phrase to move diagonally.
Or a diagonal line. And so the pawns can sometimes do this and the bishop can do this.
What does it mean to move diagonally?
Okay, so basically a diagonal line is not a line that goes straight up, right?
Straight up to the sky, for example, or to the side.
Right? It goes at an angle. So it's maybe going at 45 degrees or 30 degrees.
So that's a diagonal movement or diagonal line.
The next phrase we have is very strange.
And this one you might hear from parents or children.
He says a little horsey.
A little horsey. So in many languages we have ways of breaking down words or adding to words to make them sound cuter.
And this is one of those cases. So for example, little puppy or little kitty or kitten.
These are words to make, to make things sound cuter. So in this case horse becomes horsey.
Horsey. So I want to ride the horsey.
It's a pew way of saying I want to ride the cute horse.
Mommy, mommy, I want to ride the horsey.
Exactly.
So baby talk often involves having these rhyming words.
Mommy, horsey, doggy, puppy.
A doggy exactly. Very good. So it's a cute way of saying something.
And now when we were talking about the chess pieces,
when another piece takes or gets a piece, you say it captures it.
Okay, we say capture because maybe it's a bit nicer than killing it.
But capture means taking and keeping for yourself.
So we have a very popular game in America called Capture the Flag.
Right? So where you have to take each other's flag, right?
You're stealing. You're stealing.
So yeah, this is the term that is used in chess to capture another piece.
Sometimes, like for example in Spanish,
we actually say like to eat the other piece.
Really?
Yeah, you eat it. That's true.
Well, we're a little bit more tame.
Yeah.
Those English-speaking countries, but to capture is a very important phrase.
And you're going to hear that in the news as well because you can capture a person.
You can capture a criminal.
Right? And the final word and the way that you end a game of chess, you say,
checkmate.
Checkmate.
So the game's over. Checkmate.
Well, there's two things that can happen at the end of a game.
And well, only one thing can happen at the very end of a game.
But you're going to hear these two phrases.
And one is check and the other is checkmate.
So check means that I can take your king if I want to.
Move.
Right? It's in danger.
It's in danger.
But checkmate is the end all. This means this is the very,
last part of a game where you cannot do anything I've trapped you and I went.
Right? Very good. So the game is over when somebody says checkmate.
Why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time?
And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this very interesting game.
Bobby, come here. Look what I got here.
What is that?
What just board? Daddy's going to teach you how to play.
Cool.
Okay. Each player gets 16 pieces. You can be the white ones.
And I'll play with black pieces.
Now in the front, we set up the potons.
Those are the least viable pieces.
And can only move one space forward.
When you're about to capture another piece, they can move one space diagonally.
What about all these other pieces?
See this one? Looks like they're going to be a little bit more difficult.
See this one? Looks like a tower?
It's called the Rook. The one with the tall hat is called the bishop.
See this little horsey? This is called the knight.
It's a very important piece.
So it's best not to let your opponent capture it.
And these two? They are huff and wife.
That's right. That's the queen. That's the king.
If the other player captures your king, he will say checkmate.
And the game is over. Doesn't this sound fun?
Nah. This sounds boring.
I'm going to go play killer zombies on my PlayStation.
Pop quiz, Marco.
Alright.
The word check and the word mates.
They both have meanings in English, but put together.
What does this phrase come from? What could it possibly mean?
I have no idea. Why don't you tell us?
Because I seriously don't know where it comes from.
Okay. Well, this is actually very interesting.
So I looked it up and I had no idea either.
Because we've always just said this.
Right.
And it doesn't really make sense.
So I looked it up on the internet.
And I discovered that the game of chess is actually very ancient game.
Mm-hmm.
And it did not come from England.
It did not come from France.
It actually came from Persia.
Mm-hmm.
And in Persia, there are some words that kind of became the English words checkmate.
That mean the king is captured or the king is defeated.
Mm-hmm.
Right. Okay. So that's what it means.
It doesn't mean the king is dead.
No.
It doesn't mean that he's dead.
It means that he's been taken.
Okay.
And so over time, the Persia word went into Arabic and Arabic became French and English.
And then now we say checkmate.
Checkmate. Okay. Interesting.
This is a very interesting word.
And I'm sure everybody that's listening has a different translation for it in their own language.
I know for example that in Spanish we would say Hakimate.
Hakimate.
Right. So I guess like Hakimate is something's in check.
It's in danger.
And then Mathe kind of like kill.
Mm-hmm.
So maybe it's probably not translated properly because as you mentioned it,
it should mean defeated or captured not killed.
So listeners, why don't you let us know how you say checkmate in your language.
Come to our website, englishpod.com.
And also tell us if you have questions about the things we talked about today
or if you want to share some stories of your own chess victories.
Please get in touch with us on our website.
Otherwise you can email us at Englishpod at PraxisLanguage.com
but until then have a great day. Bye everybody.