Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another great lesson about appointments
That's right, we've got an elementary lesson about
canceling and appointment
It's a really common situation sometimes you have an appointment at the doctors or something
or at work and you have to cancel it
Yes, so we're going to learn some great language to help you cancel appointments today
Let's go straight to the dialogue then we're going to be listening as
Samantha and Angela have a phone conversation and Angela is trying to cancel an appointment
And it's going to be a little bit fast in the beginning but when we come back we will explain
all the great vocabulary
Hello Samantha speaking hi Samantha this is Angela calling
I'm just calling about our meeting today
I wonder is it possible to riskadual our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency that I need to take care of
Let me see, it shouldn't be too much of a problem
I'm really sorry I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much
It's just this thing came up and
Angela you know what I can't make it to our meeting either
Why don't we postpone it to tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
Sounds great, see you tomorrow
Angela, Angela look up, see that lady over there who's trying on a red leather jacket
Isn't that Samantha?
What?
No wonder she told me she couldn't make it to the meeting
Oh no, I think she saw me
Okay, we have some really interesting words that you probably listened to in this dialogue so let's start with language takeaway
Language takeaway
Today on language takeaway we're bringing you three words, Erica what's the first one?
The first word is reschedule reschedule reschedule reschedule
When you reschedule an appointment you change it for another day or time exactly
Great the second word that we have is inconvenience inconvenience
In convenience in convenience so to inconvenience someone is to to make things not convenient for that person
So to make things a little bit difficult to make things a little bit uncomfortable
In convenience and our third word is postpone postpone postpone
postpone we have some examples of the word postpone that will help you to understand its meaning a little bit better. Let's listen
example one
Since Robert is late again, we have to postpone the meeting
Example two
I'm sorry Simon, but your vacation has been postponed until next month
Example three
Unfortunately the flight will be postponed
Okay, so basically postpone is to delay that's right make it at a later time at a later time
Okay, some great words there and we can listen to our dialogue a second time at a slower speed
Hello, Samantha speaking hi Samantha this is Angela calling oh hi Angela what's up?
I'm just calling about our meeting today. I wonder is it possible to reschedule our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency that I need to take care of
Let me see it shouldn't be too much of a problem. I'm really sorry
I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much. It's just this thing came up and
Angela you know what I can't make it to our meeting either
Why don't we postpone it to tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
Sounds great see you tomorrow
Angela look up see that lady over there who's trying on a red leather jacket isn't that Samantha?
What no wonder she told me she couldn't make it to the meeting oh no I think she saw me
All right, so in this dialogue we had some really great phrases that we should look at in fluency builder
fluency builder we have three phrases for you today in fluency builder and the first one is so common
It's a great phrase what's up what's up what's up
So this is a very common way of saying hi. Yeah, what's up has a going what's going on
Right and now the interesting thing is it many people don't know how to answer this phrase. Yes, I see this all the time with my students
So if you say what's up you should say no much not much nothing nothing so what's up not much
All right, so the next time someone tells you what's up now you know what to answer yeah
Okay, our second phrase is can't make it can't make it I can't make it we use this phrase when you want to say I cannot attend
I cannot make it. Yeah, I can't come right so if you're having a party today
I say oh, I'm sorry. I can't make it mm-hmm. I mean I can't go exactly maybe one more example
So Marco we've got a meeting today at three o'clock. I can't make it. I'm recording today. Oh
Okay, so can't make it our last word for fluency builder this thing came up this thing came up
up this thing came up
This is a great way of giving an excuse or why you can't make it right so I can't make it today because
This thing came up like something something something happened. Yeah, let's listen to a few examples of this phrase
So we can see how it's used in the wild example one
I'm sorry that I'm late this thing came up at work. I had to stage take care of it
Example two
I can't talk right now something came up
Example three
Sorry, I missed the meeting something came up
Okay, great example and I guess it's perfectly clear now. Yes, so let's listen to our dialogue a third time and now we're ready to understand everything
Hello, Samantha speaking hi Samantha this is Angela calling oh hi Angela what's up?
I'm just calling about our meeting today. I wonder is it possible to risk actual our appointment in the afternoon?
I have a bit of an emergency that I need to take care of
Let me see it shouldn't be too much of a problem. I'm really sorry
I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much. It's just this thing came up and
Angela you know what I can't make it to our meeting either. Why don't we postpone it to tomorrow afternoon at the same time
Sounds great see you tomorrow
Angela look up see that lady over there was trying on a red leather jacket is not Samantha
What no wonder she told me she couldn't make it to the meeting oh no I think she saw me
So Eric I have you ever canceled an appointment like this under false pretenses
So for for a fake reason or a fake reason to go shopping um
Well, I may not have you know told my boss so I can't make it to a meeting because this thing came up and then I really
Was going shopping and I've never done that but how about you Marco? Well, you know in Ecuador soccer is a really big thing
Right so when we were playing in the world cup Ecuador was playing and not you
Well, no like yeah the the Ecuadorian soccer team
I canceled an appointment because I was gonna go watch the game really a business appointment a business appointment
Well, I guess that's okay. Yeah, I mean it was like the first time we were ever in the world cup and you know
My boss didn't really put up much of a fight because I guess he also wanted to go watch the game
So very similar to the events in this dialogue
Very similar I guess that's kind of the inspiration behind it
All right guys I hope you found some of these phrases helpful and you useful
And remember if you have any questions about anything you heard and today's lesson
Please visit our website at EnglishPod.com
Right there you'll be able to find more resources and also a large community to interact with yes, including me and Marco right
So we'll see you there until then it's bye