Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to bring you a great lesson about calling the office
Yep, that's right. So in this lesson we're going to teach you some great words that you can use
when you need to call your office to solve a problem
Right. So you are at home, you have a problem, maybe you can't go to the office. So you have to call them
and tell them that you're not going to be able to go. Yes. All right. So we're not going to
preview anything today because the dialogue is relatively easy. So let's listen to the dialogue
for the first time and then we'll come back and look at some words.
Hello hey, annual day, you can stay. I'm a I.L.P.
Hey, we are. I hate you. Hey. I hate you. Hey. I hate you. Hey. I hate you. Hey. I hate you. Hey. I hate you.
Actually, I'm eating fay. I quit. I eat you today. I'm already say you're at the
at Wizongrey. I think today I'm I mean, K on day it's day,
hote, lube. I am a headache or say, hote, honey rate,
osm. And I'm eating fay lightly say, you're a shfay. I say,
osm. Or yay, all in K and X. Hey. Yeah. Yeah. I was way open. Hey.
I take off. Hey. It's a query. Okay. And I, I trade and it.
G. I'm saying, history. All right. So a pretty easy dialogue. Yeah. Pretty simple. All right.
So there are a couple of words that we want to look at. So let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right. Well, today we're looking at three interesting words.
The first one is uflay. Uflay. Uflay. Uflay.
Marco, what is the uflay? All right. So when you have the uflay, it means that you are sick.
You have, um, it's very similar to a cold. Right. But just works, right?
Worst. Yeah. So when you have the uflay, it'll keep you in bed for a while for maybe a
week or two. So you have a fever. Um, your, your body is hurting. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You're just,
you're really sick. Yeah. You're really sick. Okay. So uflay. All right. Well, what about our next word?
Well, actually the next word is, is a phrase that you can use when you're calling the office.
I'll incase in X. All in K in X. I'll incase in X. I'll incase in X. Okay. This is a really
useful phrase. And I think it would help us to hear some examples of what it sounds like. So we can
understand the meaning. Example one. Or if I people pay all K in X, say, would it?
Example two. If ua, okay, in X, say, on one or may I'm, say, or yay, I heard,
say, example three. I'm not in the healing fail away. I'll say I'm all in K in X.
So with this phrase, you're basically saying that you are not going to the office. Exactly.
So let's take a look at our last word for language takeaway. Ecover, gray. Ecover,
Ecover, gray. Ecover, gray. Okay. So it's a pretty simple word. Ecover,
right? Means to get better to start feeling healthy again. Okay. So kind of to recharge your batteries.
Exactly. So this is a great verb to use when you want to say I'm going to feel better.
Okay. Ecover, gray. So some really great words, some really interesting phrases. So let's listen to this
dialogue again and then we'll come back.
Hello, hey, and you're the Eaking Spay. I'll hey, I'll hey, I'll hey, we're hey.
I hate you, you're hey. I hate you, we're Jay. I'll hear you, yeah.
Actually, I'm eating, say, I quit. I'm already say, you're hey, at the, I was hungry.
I think, I'm, I mean, K on day, it's a, I am, hey, I'm at a, or say, hot day,
any rate, I was, and I'm eating, say, lightly say, you're, I say, I say, or yay, I'll
hang hay and xay. S-y-a. I us way, open hay,
outay, outay off, take a query ray. Okay, and I, I tray and at gay, I'm saying,
a stray.
All right, Michael, have you ever found yourself in a situation like this? Well, yeah, a couple of times
that I haven't been able to really make it to the office and I've had to call. So yeah,
I would have to call and tell them that I'm not going to make it, or maybe then I'm going to be a
little bit late. All right, well, um, yep, happens to all of us, and you now, you guys have all of this
useful language. Next time you face this problem. Exactly. So if you have any questions or comments,
be sure to visit our website, EnglishPod.com. Marco and I are there to respond to your questions
and comments, um, as well. There are also lots of other great lessons for you to check out on the
website. Exactly. So be sure to check out some of our first lessons. I'm sure you find them
useful as well. Yes. Okay. Well, thanks for listening everyone and until next time. Bye. Bye.