Hello English learners, welcome back. We are here at EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today we're going to be bringing you a lesson about eggs. That's right.
And who knew there was so much to talk about when we're talking eggs?
We always have eggs for breakfast and there are many ways of preparing them. So we're going to learn
what the different ways are. Yes, and we'll learn some of the language that goes along with eggs.
Okay, so we have three words that we want to take a look at before we listen to a dialogue. So let's look at these in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview. Our preview word for this lesson is picky. Picky, picky, picky.
Picky. So picky is an interesting adjective.
Okay, so if a person is picky, what does that mean?
They're very hard to please.
Okay, so if your boss is picky and you give him a report and maybe it has, I don't know, a couple
of mistakes or something. Yeah, he'll say do it again. Can this, this and this. Okay.
So if you are picky, you want everything to be perfect. Okay. And if there's one small thing that's
not, you won't, you won't be happy. Okay, so picky, interesting word. Now our next word, yoke. Yoke. Yoke.
Y-o-l-k. Yoke. So this word is actually not in the dialogue. It's not in the dialogue, but it's
important that you know, right? Okay, so if you have an egg, the yellow part is called the yoke.
Okay, and what about the other part? The white, the white, or also called the egg white, right?
Yes, egg whites. Okay, so pretty simple. Yoke and egg white. Let's listen to our dialogue.
We are going to be listening to a couple who are having breakfast.
Wow, Europe early today. What's your breakfast? Well, I felt like baking, so I made some muffins.
Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs? Sure. I'll take mine,
sunny side up. I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that.
Ever since I was small, I've had eggs and soldiers. You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning
for 20 years. It drove my mom crazy. You know what really drives me crazy? When I asked for soft
oil eggs and they overcook them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your toast into a
hard-wild egg? Here's so picky sometimes.
Here you go honey, fried eggs. Damn it! I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
Well, she is definitely very picky and has a very bad temper. I know I can't believe anyone
we get so angry over their breakfast. But I guess it is the most important meal of the day. Exactly.
So we heard a couple of different ways of describing how you prepare eggs. So let's take a look at
that in language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay, so our first preparation method.
My favorite. Sunny side up. Okay, sunny side up. Sunny side up. Now this is interesting sunny like the
sun, right? Exactly. So when you fry an egg, right, and the yolk looks like a little sun, right?
Yeah, exactly. So why is it called sunny side up? I think because of what you just said it.
But you don't cook the yolk, right? Yeah, the yolk is still yellow. It's still a little bit
liquid. It's a little bit soft. Okay, because the opposite would be a fried egg. Yes.
And that's our second word. Fried egg. Fried egg. So this you put the egg in the pan and you
cook it all the way through. All the way through. So the yolk is not liquid anymore. It becomes
hard and yes, right? Exactly. Okay. A fried egg. Fried egg. All right. So now let's take a look at our
next set of eggs. All right. Soft boiled egg. A soft boiled egg. Soft boiled. Soft boiled.
Okay, so to boil, you put the egg in water and boiling water. Yes, and make it cook.
And make it cook. So how long would you usually put it in for to be soft boiled?
Three minutes. Four minutes. Okay. So you only cook part of the egg, right? Right. The yolk,
the yellow part, stays a little bit wet, a little bit liquid. Uh-huh. Okay. So again, the opposite would
be a hard boiled egg. Hard boiled egg. Hard boiled. So hard boiled is when you cook the entire egg again.
Yes. So then it's hard like a ball. The entire egg. Mm-hmm. So with this soft boiled and hard
boiled eggs, this takes us to our next form. Eggs and soldiers. Eggs and soldiers. Eggs and soldiers.
Now this is really interesting. I didn't really know about this before. It kind of sounds like
you're having eggs with a group of soldiers from the army. Well, this is a very British way of eating
eggs. So you have your soft boiled egg in a cup and you have a piece of toast. Mm-hmm.
But the toast is cut into long pieces. Okay. And then you take those pieces and you dip them into the egg yolk.
Delicious. It's good. Yeah. Mm-hmm. Typical English way of eating eggs. Okay. So eggs and soldiers
are interesting. And this takes us to our last form of egg preparation and probably the most popular.
Yes. Scramble eggs. Scramble eggs. Scramble eggs. Take eggs, put them in a pan, and then you just
move them all over the place. We mix them all up. Mix them all up. So the yellow, so the yolk and the white
are mixed together. Mix together. Mm-hmm. All right. So we've looked at a lot of egg preparation
and now we can listen to our dialogue for the second time and then we'll come back and look at some
phrases.
Wow. You're up early today. What's for breakfast? Well, I felt like baking so I made some muffins.
Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs?
Sure. I'll take mine sunny side up. Yeah. I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that.
Ever since I was small, I've had eggs and soldiers. You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning
for 20 years. It drove my mom crazy. You know what really drives me crazy? When I asked for
soft boiled eggs and they overcook them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your
toast into a hard boiled egg? You're so picky sometimes. Here you go, honey. Friday eggs.
Demit, I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
Interesting that the man in this dialogue is the one doing the baking. Yeah, well, uh, that's
modern days. I don't know. Men are learning how to cook and uh, yeah. House has been house has been
yeah more popular these. All right. Well, since this house has been felt like baking. I
think we should look at this and one other phrase in fluency, brother. Okay. So great phrase. He said,
I felt like baking. I felt like baking. I felt like baking. So let's take a look at this. He
feels like or he felt like in the past. What does that mean when you feel like? You want to do it.
You have the desire to do it. Okay. And then to bake and now this verb is in the gerund form.
That's right. The ing form. And that's the rule, right? I feel like playing soccer. Right.
I feel like eating lunch. I felt like going to the movies. That's the way you would say this.
You have the desire. You feel like doing something. Exactly. Okay. Very good. And now let's take a look at
this second phrase. Drives me crazy. Drives me crazy. Drives me crazy. All right. This is a very
very descriptive phrase. And I think if we listen to some examples, it will help us understand the
meaning. Example one. This music is driving me crazy. Turn it down. Example two.
Don't leave garbage in my car. It drives me crazy. Example three. Your mom is driving me crazy.
She keeps calling me. All right. So if something drives you crazy, it makes you feel very angry
or annoyed. Irritated. Yeah. Fresh straightest. Okay. But it could also be positive, right?
Like that girl drives me crazy. As then you really, really, really like her. Yeah. I don't know.
It sounds a little bit inappropriate. Really? Yeah. I think it's okay. She drives me crazy. I like she's got
me thinking and she's got me in the clouds or something like that. All right. Well, maybe there's
something about you that I don't need to know. So I'll just let you keep that thought to yourself.
All right. Well, I'm just saying we could use it in a positive form. Okay. Okay. You're just saying.
I'm just saying. All right. So drives me crazy. Really great phrase. And you can use it in all of
these different situations like we heard. So let's listen to our dialogue for the last time. And then we'll
come back and talk a little bit more.
Wow. You're up early today. What's your breakfast? Well, I felt like baking. So I made some
muffins. Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs? Sure. I'll take
mine, sunny side up. I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that. Ever since I was
a small life had eggs and soldiers. You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning for 20 years.
It drove my mom crazy. You know what really drives me crazy? When I asked for soft boiled eggs
and they overcook them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your toast into a hard boiled
egg? Here's so picky sometimes.
Here you go honey. Friday eggs. Damn it. I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
Well, I think there are some people who really really love eating eggs for breakfast and some
people who just can't stand it. Yeah, I don't know who though. I mean, who doesn't like eggs in the
morning? I know. I'm a big fan. Right? Yeah. Eggs bake and toast. Yes. Good stuff. Traditional
American type breakfast. Now you were telling me that you have some traditions when you eat eggs.
I know, I think I'm not sure if this is just in my family, but I think actually it might be
my becoming with other people as well. When you eat a soft boiled or hard boiled egg,
you have to eat all of the egg outside of the shell and then you have to break the bottom of the
shell after you finished. Why? So that the fairies who live in your egg cup can come out.
So it's kind of like a superstition. Yeah, I guess it is. Yeah. So I don't know. You guys,
do you have any egg traditions or any other crazy food stories like that? Well, for example,
I was telling you that when I prepare scrambled eggs, sometimes I like to take some rice.
Some rice that has already been cooked. Put it in the pan and then take some eggs to eggs,
put it on top of the rice and scramble the rice with the eggs. Okay, for breakfast? Yeah,
it could be for breakfast. Really? A little bit, not like a huge plate of rice or maybe at night,
you don't have anything to eat. Okay. It's scrambled eggs with rice. It's a poor man's food.
All right. Well, it's also a quick man's food. Yeah, exactly. So let us know if you guys have any
egg preparations or any special egg recipes or traditions that you practice.
Visit our website at EnglishPod.com where you can leave all of your comments and questions.
Exactly. And as always, we are there to answer them and solve any problems. Well, we're out of time
for today, but until next time, bye.