Hello English learners, welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco
and my name is Katherine So Marco you've been shopping a lot lately
I have and this dialogue or this lesson today is one of my favorite pieces of furniture
maybe appliances that I've bought recently and it's a TV
alright so I'd even go for electronics with that one
the electronics department is somewhere you like to hang out
well I mean I think every guy loves you know like a big screen TV
and a home theater system so you just like go deaf after watching
and why is that? Is bigger really better when it comes to like a 70-inch TV?
oh I don't know I think yeah the whole experience of just seeing this movie on this huge TV
and like having all the sound and I don't know it's just something about that
or watching a football game with your buddies and you can actually watch it
okay that I can appreciate but we've got a couple of great words for you
we're going to preview in today's vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview today we're going to be looking at two words
the first one is to appreciate all right so this basically means to like
yeah you appreciate someone but in this context to enjoy or take advantage of something
maybe you hear this with a couple two people who are fighting and the girl says to the guy
you don't appreciate me so he doesn't really care about her in the way that she wants him to
or you could say this about a TV for example I can't appreciate my PS3 my great
awesome console my gaming system because my TV is not good enough or big enough or big enough
so this means that it could be a lot better if I just bought a better TV right and if you buy
a better TV then you basically are upgrading or to upgrade okay so this verb to upgrade means to
go from something that's okay to something that's better hmm exactly so in previous lessons we've
seen to get a complimentary upgrade for example on a flight or in a hotel I like that well
you can also get an upgrade on a computer you see you say well my computer is from 1994 I really
need to get an upgrade yeah for sure so to upgrade now we're going to be listening to this dialogue
for the first time we're going to be buying a TV so let's listen
seriously I don't know why we need to get a new TV honey I told you already
I can't appreciate the graphics level and detail the games on my PlayStation 3 on our old TV
good afternoon folks how can I be of service today? I'm looking to upgrade to a new
or bigger television cell you've come to the right place what size are you looking for?
Just a normal size TV for a living room I see well this set here is on sale
it's a 46 inch HT TV screen and it has all the works three HDMI connectors USB VGA and SVDO ports
it even has a DVI port so you can hook up your PC or laptop
this is without a doubt decomplete home theater experience this is exactly what I need
can you imagine watching movies or playing video games on this thing?
I think it's a bit too big I don't even think it will fit in our living room
not to worry we will deliver and install it in your home it comes with a wall mount so you can
just hang it on the wall like a picture this is great how much will this set me back
lucky for you this is the last one we have in stock so it's half off I'll take it
all right so I'm going to have to defer to you Marco on some of these words in today's language
takeaway because they're all about TV specifics language takeaway
all right the first word that we're going to be looking at is graphics the graphics level
all right so you might have heard this before with the phrase graphic designer someone who
designs images but in this case we're talking about graphics so the way things appear on your TV
hmm so like basically the pictures right so he wanted to appreciate the graphics of his
PlayStation 3 better and that's why he wanted a new TV all right we could say my computer has
amazing graphics it means games are really fun because they they look good or this game has amazing
graphics so the game has you know places or scenery that looks really really real all right so graphics
but uh some kinds of TVs are made to provide those wonderful graphics and those are called HD TV
right an HD TV or that's an acronym for high definition television all right and I heard some
actors and actresses were complaining about HD TV because this the picture quality is so good
that you can see all of the little problems on their face the little wrinkles and the pimples and the
scars so be careful because one day we're going to be able to see way too much
exactly so on high definition television that's basically what you get is better definition
better level of graphics so more pixels per inch you can see a lot more clarity right so an
the next thing we're talking about is actually kind of related to the back part of your TV where you plug
things in sometimes it's on the sides sometimes on the back well they're different names for
different kinds of plugs so today we're going to talk about two of those one of them is USB right
at this TV has a USB port which basically stands for universal serial bus all right so
port is a place where you plug something in your computer has a lot of ports as well but USB is maybe
more common for people who have iPods or computers because this is how we normally connect
things to our computers so in this case this television you could connect maybe your iPod and
reproduce videos or pictures onto the TV awesome or in the second case we have a DVI port so
DVI you're going to have to tell you about this one Marco because I'm not so sure well a DVI is
basically a digital video input so basically you can connect your computer to the TV and see
what's on your screen nice and so if you have a bunch of movies stored on your computer you can just plug
it into the TV and watch or you can even navigate the internet on a big screen TV.
Yeah cool yeah all right so what are these three HDMI connectors?
All right well this is a new technology basically you know how before you used to get your DVD player your
VHS and you had three cables to for sound in one for video. Yeah the red yellow and white cable. Exactly
so with this new type of cable or technology with one cable it takes all the information to the TV so
just one cable for everything. Oh nice because my problem is I always used to put the wrong cable
in the wrong port so I'd have the red cable in the yellow port and then I'd say where's the video I
can't see all I can do is listen. Yeah it happens so with this now it's easy and well it even
it's a little bit more organized because I remember I used to have a TV and have and I had a lot of
different things connected to it it was just this big spider web in the back with on these cables so
NHDMI high definition multimedia interface connector and what else do we have?
Well last thing we're talking about is actually the place to put your TV so a lot of people now are
putting their TVs on walls like paintings because these TVs are so thin so we call this a wall melt
so a mount to mount something is also a verb right? Yeah it means to put something up with to hang
something up so many people like to mount their trophies to show off. Mm hmm very good so this is
what we're doing with the TV we're gonna mount it on the wall like a painting. Cool so those are
our words for tank language takeaway let's take another listen to today's dialogue we're gonna
slow it down this time and really figure out what's going on.
Seriously I don't know why we need to get a new TV honey I told you already I can't appreciate
the graphics level and detail of the games on my PlayStation 3 on our old TV.
Good afternoon folks how can I be of service today? I'm looking to upgrade to a newer bigger
television set you've come to the right place what size are you looking for?
Just a normal size TV for a living room. I see well this set here is on sale it's a 46 inch
HTTV screen and it has all the works three HDMI connectors USB VGA and S video ports it even has a
DVI port so you can hook up your PC or laptop this is without a doubt the complete home theater
experience this is exactly what I need can you imagine watching movies or playing video games on this thing?
Honey I think it's a bit too big I don't even think it will fit in our living room.
Not to worry we will deliver and install it in your home it comes with a wall mount so you can just
hang it on the wall like a picture this is great how much will this set me back? Lucky for you
this is the last one we have in stock so it's half off I'll take it.
All right so now we're gonna be taking a look at three different phrases that we saw in this dialogue
in Fluency Builder Fluency Builder. All right this first phrase is definitely one that I use a lot
we can talk about food we can talk about electronics we can talk about most different things but uh
the phrase here is the works he's getting the works all right that means any option he could get
any possibility he wants it all right so if you're getting a new car for example right you're
getting the high definition sound system you're getting nice tires leather seats you're getting
the works all right or if you're getting a hamburger and you want the works you're getting it
with cheese and lettuce and tomato and pepper bacon you know it means every option you're getting it all
the works so I think this word is so versatile that we should maybe listen to some more examples
example one the bridegroom was wearing a morning suit top hat gloves the works
example two he spent over ten thousand dollars on his home theater system he got all the works
example three I bought a new car with all the works magnesium rims custom paint and leather seats
so now that we've seen the works on the home theater system he needs to hook it up
all right so this is an important part and a very exciting part of a new purchase so when you buy
something you have to hook it up that means you have to plug things together mm-hmm okay so we plug things
into the wall for electricity but also hook up uh maybe those those cores you were talking about
earlier that HDMI connector that's called hooking up or connecting mm-hmm so you would hook up your
DVD player to your television all right I could ask you did you hook up those new speakers to your
big TV yesterday very good right so to connect it's another way of say to connect and finally the
the big event when you're buying something is the end when you have to actually pay and this guy's
a little bit worried that the things he wants cost a lot of money so he asks a really great question
yeah he said how much will this set me back okay this sounds a little weird at first because you could just
say how much will this cost but he's speaking in a very colloquial way very familiar and he says
how much will this set me back right so how much will this cost me mm-hmm so how much it might
actually going to spend so it's just a different way of saying how much does it cost but um it's like
you say more colloquial it's a lot more native like exactly and so if you're writing your paper
you don't want to write this uh this will set you back five hundred dollars in economics but we'd
say this in spoken language and our normal daily lives with friends mm-hmm so why don't we listen to
a couple more examples of set me back example one this unexpected expense is going to set us back
a couple thousand dollars example two that fancy dinner at the restaurant last night really set us back
example three I feel guilty about buying this coat it set me back over three hundred dollars
all right great so now that we've taken a look at those great phrases and with some good examples why don't we
listen to this dialogue one last time
seriously I don't know why we need to get a new TV honey I told you already I can't appreciate
the graphics level and detail the games on my PlayStation three on our old TV good afternoon folks
how can I be of service today I'm looking to upgrade to a newer bigger television set you've come to the
right place what size are you looking for just a normal size TV for a living room I see well this set here
is on sale it's a 46 inch HT TV screen and it has all the works three HDMI connectors USB VGA and
as video ports it even has a DVI ports so you can hook up your PC or laptop this is without a doubt
the complete home theater experience this is exactly what I need can you imagine watching movies or
playing video games on this thing I think it's a bit too big I don't even think it will fit in
our living room not to worry we will deliver and install it in your home it comes with a wall melt
so you can just hang it on the wall like a picture this is great how much will this set me back
lucky for you this is the last one we have in stock so it's half off I'll take it
okay so a big TV I think I don't know I think it's just a great thing to have at home not to you know
spend too much time in front of the TV but it's good to sit down and watch and booby it's nice because
you know now there's so many different things you can you can do with it you can hook up your computer
you can buy a projector you can play your PS3 or your Wii so I think there's a lot to do and
it's just wonderful how great graphics have come in in just like the last five years
hmm what do you think about having a television set for example in the bathroom
I would say it's a really bad idea but I think I would well if I have a bathtub I think it'd be
really cool what about you know some people don't like having a television set in their bedroom
I agree with this I agree because I think it's really important that you have
peace and quiet in your bedroom because it's kind of like for me it's an important space where I can
just relax and be quiet and I like reading a lot so if I have a TV maybe I'll watch more TV but
I've wrote much rather read a book before bed true yeah I definitely agree but you know I've
seen people who have that have TVs in their living rooms in their dining rooms even in their kitchen
so they're watching something while they're cooking and even in the bathroom we like you say in a
bathtub well it's nice but some of them I've seen in front of the toilet or something like that
I would say that the one in the kitchen is nice because if you spend a lot of time in the kitchen
you can watch the news while you're cooking or you can actually watch cooking shows and try and practice
or so pop-riss so I guess it depends on the person it depends on how much you watch TV but
I'm curious to know what our listeners have to say about TVs and big electronics purchases
right so come to our website englishpot.com if you have any questions or any doubts regarding the
lesson or any suggestions you can let us know otherwise we'll be there to just talk and practice that
English and of course send us your suggestions for future lessons we love to know what you're interested in
learning about all right we'll see you guys there all right bye everyone