Hello English learners, welcome back. We are here at EnglishPod. I am joined with
Erica and my partner in crime. Marco. Alright, so today we're going to be talking about a really
great topic. One of my favorites beer beer. So beer is a very popular drink, especially in bars
and when you go out. Yes, it's very common with students, I think. Yes, and it's also not very strong
like a vodka or whiskey. Yes, okay. So we are going to be at a bar today and we're going to be
looking at some of this vocabulary that you would find. Yes, I mean, you've got to know this
beer vocabulary. Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and
look at these words.
Hey, man, what do you have on top? Hi, Nick Cannon Budweiser. We have a two-for-one happy-hour special.
Cool. Give me a pun on hi, Nick Cannon and half a pun on bud. Okay.
Fine, how do you like it? Kind of how you like it? Half a pun on bud for table six. What about some appetizers?
Sure, let's have some, let's have some not chosen mozzarella sticks. Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
Well, it's pretty expensive for two beers and some foods. Yes. Well, it happens sometimes you
go to these very exclusive bars and they charge you like if it was gold. I mean, that's crazy.
Well, let's take a look at some of these great words that we saw in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Our first word is on tap. On tap. On tap. So he asked, what do you have on tap?
Now this is a strange sentence. What exactly does it mean? Okay, well, he's asking
about what beer is the bar has, but not in a bottle or not in a can, right? Right. So you know, in a bar,
there's often this machine, right? That will pour a very fresh beer right directly into the glass.
Into the glass. This is a very popular thing because like you say it's fresh beer. Yeah, it tastes better.
I'm taste better. Okay. So what do you have on tap? What do you have on tap? All right. Let's take a look at
a second word. Happy hour. Happy hour. Happy hour. Now this is very common in popular with bars.
Yes. What is it when they have a happy hour? Okay. A happy hour is a period of time
where the drinks are very cheap. Okay. So happy hour could be from 5 pm till 10 pm 50% off.
So if the drink is $4, then it is now $2. In happy hour. Perfect. And this brings us to our third word,
a special, a special, a special, a special. So this is a noun and what does it mean when a restaurant
or a bar has a special? It's like they're having a sale. A sale. So things are cheaper. So it could be
for example a Monday night special or like in the dialogue a happy hour special. Okay. So it is
a promotion. Yes. All right. Very good. And now they ordered a pint of Heinrichin and half a pint
of Budweiser. This is a very very special beer word. So a pint is the size of your glass.
Okay. So we understand how much a pint is. What would be the equivalent in leaders? A pint is
0.4 liters. Okay. So almost half a liter is one pint. Yes. Okay. It is very common when you go into a
bar you can order a pint of beer. Yes. Exactly. In English we don't say I'll have half a liter of beer.
Right. Right. So let's take a look at our next word on language takeaway.
Appetizers. Appetizers. Appetizers. Appetizers. Okay. So what is an appetizer? Well it is food. You eat
before your dinner or before your lunch. Okay. So it's usually maybe like a salad or a soup or something
small that you can eat right before your big meal. Okay. So some common appetizers at a bar and we
saw them in our dialogue. Not chose and mozzarella sticks. Not chose. Not chose. Not chose. Not
chose. So not chose are little chips right? Yeah corn chips. And it has cheese and maybe some tomatoes
and maybe some beans. Uh-huh. Okay. So those are not chose. They're very common in the United States.
Yes. Yeah. And what about mozzarella sticks? mozzarella sticks. A travesty on the
world and humanity and everyone's arteries. Well mozzarella is a cheese right? Mm-hmm.
mozzarella cheese. And this cheese is what what is it? How is it prepared? You put it in some breadcrumbs
and then you fry it in oil. You deep fry it. Uh-huh. And you don't like this. No it's just terrible.
Why? They're so good. Oh my god. Because then you can dip it in a little sauce. Oh delicious.
Marco there are so many reasons why this is wrong. All right well mozzarella sticks are very
popular bar food. All right well why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be able to
hear these words in context at a slower speed.
How you doing?
Hey, man. What do you have on top?
Heinekin and Budweiser. We have a two-for-one happy-hour special.
Cool. Give me a pun of Heinekin and half a pun of Bud. Okay.
Pun of Heinekin, half-pun of Bud for table six. What about some appetizers?
Sure. Let's have some uh, let's have some nachos and mozzarella sticks. Okay? That'll be 80 bucks.
What? What?
Okay, so we saw some really good vocabulary words there and now let's take a look at putting it together.
Put it together.
Well in this lesson we are going to look at one phrase that sometimes causes problems.
So let's listen to this phrase that we're talking about.
What about some appetizers?
Okay, so this phrase what about?
Yeah, I often hear people use it to ask a question.
So a common mistake is asking, what about your weekend?
What about your new job? Now this is incorrect, right?
You cannot use the phrase what about to ask a question about information.
So you cannot ask for information. Okay, because in our dialogue the bartender said
and what about some appetizers?
Right, because he is making a suggestion.
Right, so he's saying, well, why don't you have some food?
Yes, the phrase what about can be used to make a suggestion.
Okay, so I can say, what about going to the movies?
Hmm, you know what, let's hear a few more examples of this because I think it's really useful.
Example one, what about these dirty clothes?
You said you would wash them days ago.
Example two.
What about going to the mall instead?
I'm tired of going to the movies.
Example three.
What about a pizza instead of noodles?
All right, so really good examples and the same thing we can apply to how about exactly.
So again, how about cannot ask for information?
Okay, so you can't say how about your boss.
All right, perfect.
Okay, so let's listen to this dialogue one last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
bit more about ours and beers.
Hey man, what do you have on top?
Hi, Nick Cannon Budweiser.
We have a two for one happy hour special.
Cool.
Give me a pun on hi, Nick Cannon and half a pun on bud.
Okay, find a hi, Nick Cannon, half a pint of bud for table six.
What about some appetizers?
Sure, let's have some, let's have some nachos and mozzarella sticks.
Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
Well, Marco, I know you're a big fan of beer and actually I think everyone here at
Praxis is a big beer drinker and this is a perfect opportunity to tell everyone about the
world renowned beer shake.
Oh my gosh, okay, Marco.
All right, so everyone that listens to this recipe is a non-believer.
They say that it is not possible for it to taste good.
Okay, but here's the recipe.
You take a liter of beer or maybe half a liter.
So a pint or a pint and a half and you put it in the blender.
Okay, all right.
Now you take two eggs.
Uh-huh.
Okay, not cooked, not boiled, anything.
You take two eggs and put them in the blender.
It could be one or two.
Okay, and then you take about half a cup of sugar.
Put it in the blender.
What?
And you mix all that together and you get this really good foamy delicious beer shake.
So a beer milkshake.
Well, it has no milk.
Okay, but it's actually really good.
I've prepared it for some people.
They're like, no, that's not possible.
It can't taste good.
And in the end they're like, wow, this is actually pretty good.
So did you invent this recipe?
It's actually really common in Ecuador and Peru.
I've even seen it in Chile.
Usually with a dark beer.
Okay.
Right?
So like a Guinness or...
It could be a Guinness or yeah, if it's that...
A dark beer is a little bit sweeter.
Yeah.
So you wouldn't add so much sugar.
But if you have another beer like a like a logger or a stout,
you could still do it.
But just add a little bit more sugar because that beer is a little bit more bitter.
Okay.
Well, I am not going to try this recipe.
But maybe you guys are.
You should try it out and let me know how it works.
Yeah, you can tell us all about it on our website, EnglishPod.com.
Yeah, and we're definitely there to answer all your questions.
And I'll be posting the recipe as well on the website.
All right. Well, we're out of time for today.
But thanks for listening and until next time, bye.