Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and it's
the holiday season Marco. People are eating large meals with their families and I think often
times when you cook a lot of food you have something extra at the end. What do we call that?
That's right today. We're going to talk about left overs, left overs. That's the extra food after
your meal that you eat later, maybe the next day. Exactly. So you know during Christmas or during some
holidays we cook so much food that obviously we can't eat it all. So we put it back in the refrigerator
and then we eat it later. So those are called leftovers. All right. So let's listen to this dialogue
about leftovers and we'll be back in a moment to discuss what's happening in the dialogue.
What's for dinner? Left overs? What? Left overs of what and from when? From last night.
I'll talk to the left over Turkey. Mix it with some dice, peppers, onions, just add a little bit
of mayonnaise and make some sandwiches. It's not dangerous though. I mean bacteria and germs we
producing on food that was left out or reheated. Well I didn't leave the turkey out of room
temperature for more than an hour. Now I refrigerated soon after we finished eating. Also when
reheating I put it in the oven for 15 minutes at 100 degrees Celsius. Well okay. I'm just afraid
of getting food poisoning. Don't worry about it. Making a new meal out of leftovers is almost
an art. Not only do you save money but you also get to be creative and have something different to eat.
All right. So a lot of vocab there. Let's take a look at it in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right. So Marko there's one cooking term really in this dialogue that is
it's a little bit different from the others. So let's start with that. It's diced. That's right.
We were talking about taking some peppers or diced peppers. So when you dice a vegetable or anything
that you're cooking basically you're making little little pieces little squares almost. That's
right. So you can cut something many different ways. You can cut big pieces in small pieces but
diced peppers diced is a specific way to cut something in small like you say small squares.
And so in recipes you will often see this instruction dice the peppers or in this case
the peppers are diced. That's right. All right. So we took some turkey mix it with dice peppers and
a lot of things and the roommate was a little bit concerned about bacteria and germs. All right.
So bacteria and germs these sound like very scientific words. Um bacteria is something that grows
on well everything really but if you leave food out for example it gets bacteria or germs are
things that can make you sick. That's right. And so we need to avoid these things in the kitchen
because they make us unhealthy and that's why we wash our hands and things like that. But when you
have food that's left out the risk is what Marko? Is that you get bacteria or germs on it? Yeah.
So it's dangerous like especially with meat to leave it out it's very very dangerous because you can
get some bacteria that will make you sick. And the reason why we're a little bit concerned is
especially with meats is if you leave it out after cooking it at room temperature. All right.
So room temperature is the temperature of a normal room maybe it's um 65 degrees or in what's 25 degrees
Celsius. Celsius yeah. It's the temperature of the the inside of a room and so um it's not cold.
It's not hot. It's just normal and when we leave food out especially meat like you're saying
we have to be careful. You can't leave it out for very long if it's something like eggs or milk or
what we call perishables. That's right. So actually here comes the other two words that are
a little bit of a contrast. We're going to talk about food that is reheated or refrigerated.
All right. So the room made is explaining don't worry. We have done these things to this food so it's safe.
So one thing you can do to food to make it safe to kill germs is to reheat it. That means
well you know the word heated right? It's to to make something hot. But how is that different from reheated?
Well because you cooked it already so it was warm. Now it went a little bit cold because it's
at room temperature. So in order to make sure that it's safe to eat and you kill that bacteria,
you reheat it so you kind of cook it again a little bit. Yeah you cook it again. So with left
over as we often have to reheat things because they were hot then they were cold and now we
want them hot again. That's right. So we reheat them. The opposite of that would be refrigerate.
Right and this is what you should do if you take something and put it in the refrigerator what you
are doing the verb. The action is to refrigerate it. That's right. So to refrigerate something
means to make it cold. You know there are important things that we refrigerate. We refrigerate eggs.
We refrigerate milk. We refrigerate butter. These are things that can make us sick if we don't
make them cold. Exactly. So those are the two words now. Obviously it's a little bit different because
the prefix to reheat means to do it again. Well to refrigerate means you're just making it cold.
Yeah well they're important terms and again we also have the adjectives. This is reheated or
refrigerated. But there are another couple of phrases that are really important. So let's take
listen to those in fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right so the first phrase we're going to
take a look at is when one of the roommates says hey what's for dinner? What's for dinner? All right this
is a very very standard phrase. This is something you'll hear at home. You'll hear with your friends.
It's usually something we say that when someone is cooking food for dinner. That's right. We're
asking what are we going to eat for dinner? Mom what's for dinner? Mm-hmm. Exactly. I used to say
that every single day when I came home from school. Well obviously you don't want to say the long
phrase what are we going to have for dinner tonight? So you just say what's for dinner? What's for dinner?
What's for dinner? And then the answer would be Lazagna or Turkey sandwiches. Right exactly.
Now when they started talking about the leftover turkey he was a little bit concerned as we said
about bacteria and germs because it usually happens that you get this on food that was left out.
All right so the verb here is to leave out to leave something out. Mm-hmm. It means to leave
something or put something at room temperature. Right. So Marco you and I are eating turkey it's
Thanksgiving and we start to have coffee and dessert and the turkey is still in the room at room
temperature. We did not refrigerate it. That means it was left out. How long was it left out?
Well maybe two hours. Right. Right. That means so it's not in a refrigerator. That's right.
That's exactly what it means. So maybe you go to sleep and you left the turkey out. It's still
on the table maybe at room temperature. Oh no we can't eat it if we left it out for like 12 hours. Exactly.
All right so it's not good to leave food out. And now what happens is if you do eat food that was
left out for too long you could get food poisoning. Now this is very serious and it's something
that you should be very careful about when you're cooking food poisoning is getting sick from your
food. Right. There are different kinds of food poisoning but usually it makes you throw up.
It makes your stomach hurt. It's quite painful. That's right. And so this is why we say you know you
should wash your hands before you cook. You should make sure that you refrigerate meat because you
want to avoid food poisoning. That's right and it comes from the noun poison a poison which is
something that is harmful for your body. That's right there are many different kinds of poison
but food poisoning means becoming sick your body getting sick after you eat something bad. That's right.
All right so a lot of great stuff here we can review everything one last time.
What's for dinner? Leftovers? What? Leftovers of what and from when?
From last night. I took the left over turkey. Mixed with some diced peppers and onions just
add a little bit of mayonnaise and made some sandwiches. It's not dangerous though I mean bacteria
and germs reproducing on food that was left out or reheated. Well I didn't leave the turkey out of
room temperature for more than an hour. Now I refrigerated soon after we finished eating.
Also in reheating I put it in the oven for 15 minutes at 100 degrees Celsius. Well okay.
I'm just afraid of getting food poisoning. Don't worry about it. Make a new meal.
A lot of leftovers is almost an art. Not only do you save money but you also get to be creative and have
something different to eat. All right so this is actually a good advice about leftovers
about having something to eat. But at the same time I don't know how many people actually
are very careful with these things. For example pizza. Sometimes you leave pizza out on the table
all night and the next morning you have some pizza. I always refrigerate my pizza. Really. I know
people who leave their pizza out and then eat it but there's cheese and sausage and you know you
want to refrigerate that stuff. So I always wrap it in plastic and put it on a plate in the fridge.
Okay you wrap it in plastic. Well because in the refrigerator there's also germs so you need to
make sure you cover your food. Right right right. And what about have you ever had a bad case of
food poisoning because of having leftovers? No. I've had food poisoning but not because of leftovers.
Because as I said before you know I wrap things I put them in the refrigerator. I'm very careful
because I don't want to get sick or I don't want to get other people sick because you know
Thanksgiving or Christmas you have to give food to many other people and you know I don't want to
make anyone sick. And actually you can't get food poisoning not only from leftovers but from maybe
food that maybe was expired like sometimes cheese maybe can be expired you didn't realize it and
you know you get food poisoning. Or from people who are cooking with things that are not clean.
So you have something that's not clean or food that's not fresh and it makes you very sick. That's
poisoning. That's right. So it's an interesting thing especially with like I said so many holidays
where you cook so much food that people have a lot of leftovers and not only that but even at restaurants
maybe you you order too much so you have leftovers you want to take home to your dog or to have later.
I love leftovers. Well let us know do you have leftovers in your country? Are there
things that you shouldn't do with when cooking? Let us know or our website is english.com. All right we'll see you
next time.