Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another sci-fi lesson for all of those fans out there
of Star Trek and Star Wars.
That's right and today we're going to focus on some phrases.
We're not going to do any vocabulary today.
We're just going to learn some phrases that you'll find relating to science fiction.
Okay, very good.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time and we'll come back and look at all these
phrases?
Captain, we are under attack by an unidentified ship.
Damage report.
We've sustained heavy damages to the engines.
We've lost our work drive.
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
We don't wish to engage.
What is the nature of this attack?
It's why you've kept a core of the ship kultals.
Your ship attacked that will search party.
No, you're not doing it right.
Card doesn't sound like that.
His voice is deeper.
I am Captain Core of the ship kultals.
You're sure.
No, if you can't do an authentic lingon voice, I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek
fan who can actually act.
Okay?
What, what?
I already fought the lingon soup and the wig.
Alright, very good at Star Trek fans.
Apparently they were trying to act out one of the famous episodes where the clingsons
attack the Enterprise.
My goodness.
I don't know a lot about Star Trek, but I do know a lot about language.
We've got some great stuff here that will help you understand sci-fi movies and TV shows
in English a little bit better.
So what do we go now to fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
Alright, so the first phrase that we have today on fluency builder, unidentified ship.
Unidentified ship.
If we break it down and look at the first word, unidentified.
You don't know which one it is.
Okay, you don't know the identity.
Yep.
And a ship.
I guess that's short for a rocket ship.
A rocket ship.
Or a spaceship.
Okay.
So we're not talking boats here.
Alright, we're not talking about boats.
Very good.
And to our second phrase, the enterprise lost its warp drive.
warp drive.
Warp drive.
So the warp drive of the enterprise is actually something like an engine that allows
it to go faster than the speed of light.
So super fast.
Super fast.
But why warp?
Alright, well if we take a look at the word warp, that actually means to bend.
Yep.
So like when you warp wood, it bends.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Bend wood or you warp metal.
And well that's kind of the theory behind it is that they're going so fast that they bend
or warp time.
Okay, so warp drive.
I think a very sci-fi specific phrase here.
Right.
Alright, and for our third phrase today, search party.
Search party.
A search party.
Okay, so what is this?
Are we having a party?
What's going on?
Well, when somebody gets lost, you know, maybe in the woods or something, you send out
a search party to find them.
So a party would be a group of people.
Exactly.
So that also happens in restaurants, I think.
Right.
Sometimes you might say how many people in your party.
And your party very good.
So party group of people.
Alright, so in the dialogue, we saw that actually these were not real star trek characters,
but they were just acting.
But it didn't sound quite right.
Right.
That his voice is deeper.
So a deep voice, deep voice.
A deep voice.
Alright, we're going to hear an example of what a deep voice sounds like.
The one constant through all the years, Ray, has been faced both.
The mark has ruled by like an army of steamrollers.
It's been erased like a blackboard rebuilt in the wrist again.
That is a deep voice.
Now because his voice wasn't deep enough, he didn't sound authentic.
Authentic.
Alright, so authentic, very easy word.
Real.
True to life.
Real life, right?
Not fake.
Exactly.
So Marco, is that an authentic Rolex?
No, it's not.
But thank you for noticing.
Alright, so authentic.
And our last word for today.
A wig, a wig, a wig, wig, w-i-g-wig.
So a wig is pretend hair, right?
Right, fake hair.
So the hair is not authentic.
Very good.
Alright, so a wig.
Alright, we've got some great language here.
And why don't we listen to it one more time, slow down a little bit, and the dialogue.
Captain, we're under attack by an unidentified ship.
Demage report.
We've sustained heavy damages to the endons.
We've lost our warp drive.
We'll have to attempt to make contact.
This is Captain Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
We don't wish to engage.
What is the nature of this attack?
I am Captain Cole of the ship, Clothos.
You all ship attacked our Surt Party.
No, you're not doing it right.
The report doesn't sound like that.
His voice is deeper.
I am Captain Cole of the ship, Clothos.
Y'all ship.
No, if you can't do an authentic, clingon voice, I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek
fan who can actually act.
Okay, but I already bought the clingon suit and the wig.
Alright, now it's time for us to take a look at more phrases today in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Alright, so we've got some phrases here that you can use together with a number of different
words, right?
Exactly.
So the first one, we heard that data said we're under attack.
We're under attack.
Under attack.
Alright, so if we're under attack, it means that we are being attacked.
Attack.
Someone is shooting guns at you or trying to hurt you or something like that.
Okay, so we are under attack.
Very popular phrase that you would hear in War movies or something.
Definitely.
Now you can change this by changing the last word.
We are under fire.
Under fire, which basically means the same thing.
Yeah, except when you're under fire, there are guns involved.
Okay, so they're shooting it.
Yep.
Alright, we're under attack.
We're under fire.
Hmm.
Alright, moving on to our second phrase.
We've sustained heavy damage.
So when you sustain something, you receive it or you undergo this thing.
So usually it's related to injury or to receiving some type of negative thing.
Okay, so why don't we listen to some examples of how we could use sustain in context?
Example one.
One had a car accident and sustained a fatal injury.
Example two.
The boxer sustained a severe neck injury in the championship fight.
Example three.
Luckily the worship didn't sustain any serious damage.
Alright, so you see we typically sustained something like an injury.
Or damage that is negative.
Very good.
And the last phrase for today.
What is the nature of this attack?
What is the nature of?
Okay, so basically he's just asking, why are you doing this?
Right, why what is the reason?
Yeah, what is the purpose?
So again, we have some more examples of how you could use what is the nature of in different
situations.
Example one.
What is the nature of your visits the United States?
Example two.
What is the nature of the threat against our country?
Example three.
The nature of my visit is personal.
So great phrase you can use not only when you're talking sci-fi but in everyday life.
Exactly.
So why don't we listen now to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
Captain, we are under attack by an unidentified ship.
Dammer's report.
We've sustained heavy damages to the engines.
We've lost our work drive.
So have to attempt to make contact.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Starship Enterprise.
We don't wish to engage.
What is the nature of this attack?
I've kept a core of the shipcultals.
Your ship attacked our search party.
No, you're not doing it right.
Cork doesn't sound like that.
His voice is deeper.
I've kept a core of the shipcultals.
You're show.
If you can't do nothing to gling on voice.
I'll have to find a more serious Star Trek fan who can actually act.
What?
I already fought the Klingon suit and the wig fan.
Well, Marko, I already admitted that I'm not much of a sci-fi fan.
I don't really know anything about Star Trek or Star Wars.
Well, it is a very popular show.
I think it started around the six-piece or seventies.
Yep.
The first version of Star Trek.
And well, many, many people follow it now.
They dress up.
They know the secret language that is used on the show.
They know the spaceships.
It's a big culture.
That's true.
Speaking of culture, I think we've got a Star Trek movie coming out pretty soon.
Some of this language can help you guys understand it a little bit better.
Very good.
Yeah.
So, if you have any other questions or comments related to not only to science fiction,
but anything in general, please come to the website, englishpod.com and leave your questions
or comments.
Well, thanks for downloading you guys and until next time.
Bye!