Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got an elementary level lesson for you all about getting up in the morning.
That's right today we're making breakfast and well of course many people have different things when they're making breakfast.
Some are very big. Others are small. So but this is what we're going to talk about today. So
why don't we listen to the dialogue and see what they're having for breakfast today.
Smells good. What's for breakfast? Well since we're getting up so late I decided to make a big breakfast.
Nice brunch. Kind of. So I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs some French toast and buttermilk pancakes.
Wow you really went all out. Did you make any coffee?
Yeah just the way you like it. I also put out some cereal and mostly if you feel like having something more light.
Looks good. I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
Get the jam and butter while you're in there. Oh and don't forget to serve.
Alrighty.
Alright we're back so a lot of interesting things are huge breakfast.
Way too big for me. I don't like to eat a big breakfast because I feel like it's
makes me tired and then I don't have any energy.
Especially if you just get up right. Exactly. You need to shower and maybe have some fruit and
then go to work but we can talk about it at that at the end. There were a lot of interesting
words and phrases that we heard that we would benefit from taking a closer look at.
Language takeaway.
Alright so on language takeaway today we're going to take a look at our first word and
it's an interesting word. It's kind of a mix of two things. Brunch. That's right so this word
comes from two different words. Breakfast, Buh, Bruh, Breakfast and Lunch. That's right.
So, Bruh, Bruh, Bruh, So if you have brunch what is exactly a brunch?
Well there's two ways to look at brunch. One is the time element. Usually brunch is later than
breakfast but maybe a little earlier than lunch so 11 o'clock or maybe even noon.
But the other thing is size because you're putting two meals together. Usually brunch is
very big. You eat a lot of food. Okay so it's a perfect combination of breakfast and lunch.
I'm the type of person that likes having scrambled eggs at noon so this is a perfect solution.
Bruh, Right. You don't have to only eat eggs at breakfast. You can eat them at lunch as well.
Exactly. This is actually something we do a lot in America for Mother's Day.
So mom wakes up late. We take her to brunch. It's a very big special meal.
Very good. And talking about eggs and the types of eggs that we can have.
I mentioned scrambled eggs and in the dial-up we also heard soft boiled eggs.
Okay these are two very important kinds of eggs. Usually if you're in a restaurant
they will ask you how do you want your eggs cooked or done.
And my answer is always scrambled scrambled. This means someone mixes the eggs before they are cooked
and then when they cook they are hard. They're yellow. Okay there's no white it's just yellow
and it's it's a little hard mixture. But soft boiled eggs are very very different.
That's right soft boiled eggs. You actually don't break the egg or open the egg to cook it.
Like scrambled eggs. You actually put the entire egg and boiling water.
I think it's for two minutes and then you take it out and then you open the shell and the eggs are
kind of cooked. It's kind of hard in some parts but it's also kind of
liquidy in other parts. That's right. So the outside the white part is hard but the yellow part the yolk
is liquid. It's not hard. That's right. And actually if you want the whole egg to be hard
you can ask for hard boiled eggs. That's right those are cooked for much longer. That's right.
Okay so we have scrambled eggs soft boiled eggs. We have French toast and we have buttermilk
pancakes. Okay so you can ask for just pancakes. But if you want to be specific you want to give
instructions about what kind of pancakes you can ask for buttermilk pancakes. And what exactly
is buttermilk? Buttermilk is a very very creamy eggy milk that's very very high in fat.
That makes everything taste better. I think this is used a lot in baking. Not really in other
kinds of foods. So you can have buttermilk muffins or buttermilk biscuits. But usually you have buttermilk
pancakes and so these are very rich, very fatty pancakes. Awesome yeah they taste delicious.
All right so now if we want to eat a little bit more healthy we do have some cereal and some
musely. musely is a funny word. It's not a sound we make very often in English musely.
I think it actually comes from German. It does look German because actually the spelling is MUE.
So you would kind of want to say mu-e-es-ly musely or something. Yeah and we say musely and it's basically
a mixture of granola or different kinds of fiber grains. Yeah so just think of having like
raisins and maybe some almonds granola all mixed up and you have this nice thing that is goes well
with yogurt musely. It's very very tasty and also very good for you. Okay and now well actually
going back to pancakes. No pancake is possible to eat unless you put syrup on it right? Well some
people might disagree. I know a lot of people who eat pancakes with honey or butter. True. But the best I
think is with syrup and syrup is basically liquid sugar and you put it on your pancakes to make them sweeter.
Okay actually it's the same thing as honey basically except that it doesn't come from bees.
Right so real syrup we say maple syrup comes from maple trees and you tap the tree and it
comes out. It's very very sweet but we also have syrup you can buy at the store which is
our demand made. Yeah it's basically just sugar. Okay very good so that's what we have with pancakes
usually but why don't we go back listen to our dialogue again let's review all of these yummy
breakfast treats and we'll come back in a bit with flinty builder. Smells good what's for breakfast?
Well since we're getting up so late I decided to make a big breakfast. Nice brunch. Kind of so
I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs some French toast and buttermilk pancakes. Wow you really
went all out did you make any coffee? Yeah just the way you like it. I also put out some cereal and
musely if you feel like having something more light. Looks good I'll squeeze out some fresh orange juice.
Get the jam and butter while you're in there. Oh and don't forget to syrup. Alrighty.
Alright so now on fluing seabilder why don't we take a look at a couple of phrases.
Fluency builder. When the guy was kind of surprised he said wow you really went all out.
Okay so this comes from the phrase to go all out so he went all out or I'm going to go all out
and this means to give something your best to do more than is expected. That's right so
if you go all out when you're making breakfast it means you just you cooked a lot or really good
and you spend a lot of time doing it. For example if it's someone's birthday and I know it's
their birthday I go all out by buying gifts and a cake and lots of decorations and calling all
their friends and having a party so this is doing everything for them. That's right okay and he was
really surprised and he really seemed to enjoy breakfast and he said looks good. Okay this is
this is a way to say good job or nicely done. It's almost a way to say I'm happy about this.
Alright yeah and obviously you can also say that the food looks delicious so it looks good. It
looks good so it's a way to say you know well done looks good or in this case looks very tasty.
That's right okay and now this is an interesting part he says our squeezes some fresh orange stew so
let's take a look at this verb squeeze. To squeeze uh this is something you usually do with your hand
when you tighten something. So for example your toothpaste. Yes you squeeze your toothpaste so the
toothpaste will come out. So in this case we are squeezing the orange just to extract the juice.
That's right so you you hold the orange right tight you make the juice come out and then you have fresh
squeezed orange juice and this is different from orange juice you buy in a store. Okay so you can say
our squeezes some fresh orange juice that means you're going to make fresh orange juice and this
fresh orange juice that you make is called fresh squeezed orange juice. Fresh squeezed. You probably
seeing this in the store like some bottle they say 100% fresh squeezed orange juice. Yeah it's good for
advertising. All right so very good a lot of great interesting phrases there why don't we
listen to our dialogue one last time. Smells good what's for breakfast? Well since we're getting
up so late I decided to make a big breakfast. Nice brunch. Kind of so I made scrambled and soft
boiled eggs some French toast and buttermilk pancakes. Wow you really went all out did you make any
coffee? Yeah just the way you like it. I also put out some cereal and mostly if you feel like having
something more light. Looks good all squeezed out some fresh orange juice. Get the jam and butter while
you're in there. Oh and don't forget the syrup. Alrighty. All right so talking about brunch and
breakfast what is your typical or ideal breakfast? Oh that's a hard question breakfast is my favorite
meal of the day so I could eat breakfast all kinds of breakfast anytime but one of my favorite kinds
of breakfast is a Greek diner breakfast. Greek diner what does this have? Okay well we have a lot of diners
or small restaurants that are very very cheap and fast in America and this usually involves some
scrambled eggs that are made with cheese and toast and potatoes and bacon and sausage and a coffee.
Wow big breakfast. Very big. But delicious. Nice. What's your favorite? Um I also in really,
really like breakfast and I actually like having places that you can have 24 hour a day breakfast.
All day breakfast is called so I can have breakfast for dinner. Right that's usually in America you
go to a diner because they have breakfast at four o'clock in the morning or seven o'clock at night.
Um I'm not really a coffee person I actually enjoy either juice, orange juice or hot chocolate. I really like
my chocolate and definitely pancakes three buttermilk pancakes stacked and as you sit before syrup but I
actually also put butter on it so gross I know a lot of people do that they put butter on first.
Yeah and then they pour the syrup. Yeah of course. So it's like complete very very fatty and
hash browns. I'm definitely a fat enough hash browns. Those are potatoes that are chopped very very finely
and you fry them together so it almost becomes like a potato pancake. Okay yeah exactly.
So a lot of great stuff and obviously breakfasts around the world are different. I know for example in
some countries they have the Fisherman's breakfast so in the morning you have black coffee, rice and fish. That's right.
Because you're gonna work all day. So we're really curious about how breakfast is in your country.
What a typical breakfast is like. Yeah what are traditional breakfasts and what is your favorite
breakfast? Let us know on our website EnglishPod.com we hope to see you there. All right bye bye.