Hello everyone, welcome back to another lesson with us here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're going back to school.
That's right. We're talking about my least favorite subject.
That would be math. That's right.
Okay, so we're going to be talking about math.
Now I know that many of you, of course, no math.
Right.
But do you know the operations in English?
Many people find it hard to find the right words to talk about math in English.
Right. So that's what we're going to be looking at today.
And we'll also look at some names that you can call people who are really, really, really smart.
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
And then we'll come back and look at those math words.
Alright, children. Let's review.
Tommy, pay attention.
Sorry, Miss Cadillac.
Okay, Crystal, now tell me.
What's four?
Plus you love him.
Um, 15.
Miss Cadillac always has crystal. She's such a teacher's pet.
Okay. And what about 56 minus 60?
Um, negative four.
Very good.
12 times 12?
Very good. Sock up.
14.
Zero divided by one.
Zero.
How did you know that?
Okay, smarty pants.
The square root of two.
It's you're not going to get that one. Do it all.
Um, um, well, four, one, four, two, one, three, five.
Alright, so that's one smart little girl, huh?
Yeah, pretty smart. Actually smarter than me.
Alright, so let's take a look at some of those words that the teacher used to ask her about certain operations in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so like we said, you guys know how to do math.
And you know the words in your language, but maybe in English, it's a little bit harder to find the right words.
So let's look at those now.
Okay, so let's look at the first question that she asked.
What's four plus 11?
Four plus 11.
Okay, plus plus.
Alright, so four plus 11 Erica is, let me take a look at here.
Um, 15.
15. Okay. So we are adding, right?
Yes. So that's how you would say.
Let's go with an easy one.
Two plus two. Four four, right?
Or five plus five.
Ten. Ten. Okay.
You're really testing my skills.
So that's how you would add numbers.
Now what about taking away numbers?
So taking away or subtracting.
Alright, let's test you again.
In the dialogue she said, 56 minus 60.
equals negative four.
Okay.
Minus. So that's negative, right?
Minus.
So and of course, if you have 56 apples and you take away 60, you are left with negative four.
Well, actually your left was zero apple.
Exactly.
Now that answer is also interesting.
Negative four.
That means minus four, right?
Four less than zero.
Very good. Negative four.
Okay. So now for our next operation.
12 times 12.
Now Marco, don't ask me the answer.
Alright. 12 times 12 equals 144.
Now that's multiplying.
Right.
Or multiplication.
Multiplication.
Okay. So this times part.
It's very easy to remember because for example, four times four.
You can just say four, the number four, and you add it, right?
Four times four plus four plus four plus four.
Right. So times times.
Uh-huh.
Now the opposite of times.
Alright. The opposite of multiplication is division.
Division.
Okay.
So in our dialogue, the teacher said zero divided by one.
Zero divided by one.
Any number divided by zero is zero.
Alright. So let's give another example.
15 divided by three.
Alright. So 15 divided by three equals five.
Five.
Exactly.
So divided by divided by.
Very good. So after division, the teacher was very impressed.
And now she asked a very hard mathematical operation,
especially for a girl at this age.
The square root of two.
The square root of square root of square root.
So let's give some examples to show what is the square root.
Okay.
So if I ask you the square root of nine.
Three. Three. Right.
What about the square root of four?
Two. Two. Okay.
So now one more.
The square root of 16.
Four.
Okay. So you notice the pattern.
I'm sure everyone knows this in their own language.
So you would get a square root.
Exactly.
So this language is pretty simple.
You all know it in your own language.
But let's hear it again in English one more time with the dialogue.
Alright. Children. Let's review.
Tommy.
Pay attention.
Sorry, Miss Cadillac.
Okay. Crystal. Now tell me.
What's four?
Plus you love him.
15.
Miss Cadillac always has crystal.
She's such a teacher's pet.
Okay. And what about 56 and minus 60?
Um, negative four.
Very good.
12 times 12?
Sock up.
144.
Zero divided by one.
Zero.
How did you know that?
Okay. Smarty pants.
The square root of two.
It's you're not going to get that one.
Do it all.
Um, one point four.
142.
25.
Okay.
So we understand the mathematical operations that we saw here.
Very easy.
Mm-hmm.
But now there was another little kid in there who was very, I think,
Envious or jealous.
Yeah. Tommy.
Tommy, right?
Mm-hmm.
So he called her a couple of different names.
Well, let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Okay. So the first one that he called Crystal the little girl.
He called her a teachers pet.
Teachers pet.
A teacher's pet.
So Erica, what exactly is a teacher's pet?
It is the favorite student.
The teacher has in that class.
All right. So it's always a student that's helping the teacher.
Yeah. The smartest students.
Yeah. Yeah.
The teacher's pet.
Yeah. And it has a negative meaning and English.
Yeah. I wouldn't say that it's a good thing to be the teacher's pet.
Like the teacher thinks it's good.
Yeah. But all of the friends and the classmates, they think it's bad.
Yeah. Exactly.
Teachers pet.
And similar to Teachers pet is a suck-up.
Suck up.
Again, suck-up. What is this? What is a suck-up?
A suck-up is a person who tries really, really hard to make the teacher like him.
Okay. Now, we can also use it outside of the classroom, right?
Yeah. At work, maybe.
Okay. There is always at work. There is always one person who's the suck-up, right?
Yes.
Now, again, this has a negative meaning and English.
Yeah. I guess in the workplace, the rest of your colleagues don't really like that person who's considered to be the suck-up.
Was always trying to please the boss.
Exactly.
All right.
All right. So the teacher calls Crystal a Smarty Pants.
Smarty Pants.
Okay. So this is also a little named calling, right?
So what is a Smarty Pants?
Somebody who is too smart.
Who tries too hard to be smart?
Now, this is only for little kids, right? I wouldn't call you a Smarty Pants.
No. It's definitely for children.
Adults don't say this.
Unless maybe you are joking or having fun with someone.
Yeah. But if you say it, you are suggesting that you're being like a child.
Right.
Yeah. Okay. Smarty Pants.
And our last one, and this is also a very good phrase and a way to describe someone.
No it all.
I know it all.
Sometimes you say, Mr. No it all, right?
Yeah. That's right.
Okay. So what is a No it all?
Somebody who tries to show everyone that they know it all.
They know everything.
Yeah. They're so smart.
They have the answers to everything.
Yeah.
But they really, really try and show everyone that they know everything.
These people can be sometimes a little bit irritating, right?
Yeah. Very, very annoying.
No. Yeah.
All right. So it's not a good thing to be a No it all the time.
Yeah. Actually all of these phrases are not good things to be.
Okay. So let's listen to our dialogue one more time.
And then we're going to come back and Eric is going to tell us how much she hates math.
All right. Children. Let's review Tommy. Pay attention.
Sorry, Miss Cadillac.
Okay. Crystal. Now tell me what's 4 plus 11.
15.
Miss Cadillac always has crystal. She's such a teacher's pet.
Okay. And what about 56 and minus 60?
Um, negative four.
Very good. 12 times 12.
Very good. So good.
144.
Zero divided by one.
Zero.
How did you know that?
Okay. Smarty pants. The square root of two.
But you're not going to get that one. Do it all.
Um, um, well, 4, 14, 21, 35.
All right. So Erica, you were telling me that you hated math or you still do?
Well, yes.
I really do hate math and even even doing a simple, um, you know, like 16 plus 32.
Mm-hmm.
It's too hard for me.
So you were never really that type of person that it's good with numbers.
No. I'm terrible with numbers. I can't even remember my own phone number.
Really.
That's true.
Like I really if someone asked me for my phone number, I have to look on my phone in the address book to find it.
Well, yeah. Sometimes numbers can be difficult.
I kind of liked math when I was younger. It's, uh, it just made sense.
Mm-hmm.
Well, I guess there's a reason why I'm an English teacher.
Yeah.
I'm not a math teacher.
And I was actually not very good at language.
But here you are.
Exactly.
Well, I mean in Spanish, I had like grammar.
Oh.
Not very good at that.
Hold those rules.
Yeah, but you're pretty good at English.
Oh, that's all right.
That's all right.
What about you guys tell us what your favorite subject or your least favorite subject in school was?
What about you? Do you have any favorite subject?
Or did you have a favorite subject?
History.
Yeah. Okay. I liked chemistry for a while.
Oh, God.
Chemistry involves numbers.
Well, a little bit.
But it was interesting as well.
So come to the website, everyone. Englishpod.com.
And you can find lots of other resources there.
And also be sure to check out our activity stream where you can answer and, uh,
ask very quick questions depending on your level.
So you can choose if you're an elementary student, then you would be talking to other
elementary's.
That's right. Well, thanks for downloading this lesson and until next time.
Goodbye.