Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we have a delicious Italian food lesson for you today.
That's right. We are at an Italian restaurant and we are ordering food. So this is going to be
very helpful. Next time you are at an Italian restaurant with your friends and you're ordering up some dishes.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your servant tonight. May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations?
Well, I personally like the chicken panner with cream mushroom sauce but the prawn fit the
china is also very nice. No, no, no. I'd like to have the grilled chicken but can I have
spaghetti instead of spinach? Of course, man and for you. I, uh, I'll have the horse strike.
All right, we're back and now let's take a look at all those delicious Italian dishes on
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So first of all, we have two different kinds of sauce really. The first is cream mushroom.
So what's a cream sauce, Marco? A cream mushroom sauce. So basically this is a cream from like milk
and you have mushrooms in it and it's, I don't know, I think everyone has seen it's a very thick white
sauce. It has little slices of mushrooms in it. It's kind of a sweet. That's right. And so
oftentimes you see there's cream sauces which are white and tomato sauces which are red.
Right. And this here is a cream sauce so it's white and it's got chunks of mushroom in it, right?
It's tasty. And the waiter also offered prawn with the pasta. So what is a prawn?
prawn for the chini. So prawn is like a big, it's like a word for shrimp. I always think of
jumbo prawns, which are these big, big shrimp big shrimps. So they're basically the same thing shrimp
and prawn are basically the same. That's right. And they're they're a seafood that when they get
cooked they curl. Yeah. So they look like a circle but they're pinkish or red. That's right.
They're they're very tasty. Okay. So now let's take a look at the different types of pasta. So we
have three different types of pasta that the waiter suggested. So the first one is, okay,
we're going to say all three in the American way. But I'm going to tell you the Italian way
is quite different. So I'll say that afterwards. The first is penny. Okay. So this is a type of pasta.
What does it look like? It is like a small tube. So maybe maybe three centimeters long.
And it is round and it has a hole in the middle. And so it's a kind of pasta. And what about the
Fetuccini? So Fetuccini is a long noodle but it's flat. It's flat. It's flat.
Okay. So it kind of looks like a like a shoelace. Yeah. It's long and flat. Okay. And then we have
spaghetti which I think many people know and this is probably the most popular one. That's right.
Spaghetti is very long. Just like Fetuccini but it's very very thin and round. So it kind of looks like
maybe a pencil, a very long pencil. But very thin. We're like hair actually. And there are thin
kinds. So they have a special name but this is this is just a normal pasta that you will see everywhere.
It's very long and you can twirl it. You can spin it around your fore around your fore. Okay. So
that's what we have. We have Pente, Fetuccini and Spaghetti. Now the other woman ended up ordering
horse-tripe. Now this is also another Italian dish. What is this exactly? Well horse is the animal.
So this is a this is a this is a tribe that comes from a horse but tribe is a certain part of the
animal that we we it's a food name actually. So when we eat the stomach lining the part of the
stomach that goes around the stomach it's kind of squishy. Okay. Soft. That is called
tribe and you can have tribe from many different animals like cows or pigs. But in this case it's
horse-tripe. So it's basically that thick piece of like spongy material around the animal's
stomach. Okay. And when you cook it it looks very funny. So this is and this is actually a famous
Italian dish as well right? I think so I think they eat it in the south more but you can definitely
get tripe in a lot of different places in Italy. Okay very good. So there you have it. A lot of different
dishes Italian dishes. We've taken a look at a couple of pasta dishes. What we take a break
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your servant tonight. May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations? Well I personally like the chicken panor with cream mushroom sauce
but the prawn fit the tuna is also very nice. No no. I'd like to have the grilled chicken but
can I have spaghetti instead of pinnay? Of course man and for you. I uh I'll have the horse tripe.
All right we're back so now we're going to give you three key phrases. Fun fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So the phrases we have selected for you today are phrases that you are sure to
hear anytime you go to a restaurant in America or any other English speaking country. But basically
you have a waiter who comes to you if you sit down and and this is what they'll say. The first thing
they'll say is I'll be your server. I'll be your server tonight. So he introduces himself. He says
good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight. So when he's saying I'll be your
server it's another way of saying I'll be your waiter. They're waiter that's right but server can be a
man or a woman. Uh huh. And a waiter can only be a man if it's a woman it's a waitress. Okay so
waitress for a woman waiter for a guy but if we use server it's for men and women. Yes I'll be
your server and I just like to remind you that this is more common in America because in America
waiters and waitresses or servers they have to earn tips and so they're very nice. Uh huh okay so
this is why they they introduce themselves they are very nice to you and then they ask
may I take your order? May I take your order so the verb to take here doesn't mean to take it from
you it means to to ask you and then they'll write it down. Okay so the server will ask you what you
want to order and then we'll write it down and the order is what you have decided to eat so that's
the food that you order. Now this next phrase is very very handy especially if you're in a country that
maybe you don't know the dishes well or if you're in a restaurant that you want to see what they
recommend it you can just say do you have any recommendations? Do you have any
recommendations? Okay so this is a way to ask the server what's good? So what he thinks is good
or what the restaurant serves very well? Okay so you could say I've never been to this restaurant
before do you have any recommendations or maybe even you know Marco we're having dinner and I
know that you really like Italian food and I don't know much about a time food so I can ask you
do you have any recommendations? Okay so this is a way of asking what is good here what is the
what is what is delicious in this restaurant? That's good to eat okay all right so three phrases
there for you and we take another short break and let's listen to the dialogue for the last time.
Good evening ladies my name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight may I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations? Well I personally like the chicken pen with cream mushroom sauce
but the prawn fit the tuna is also very nice. No no I'd like to have the grilled chicken but
can I have spaghetti instead of pene? Of course man and for you? I uh I'll have the horse trite
All right so talking about pasta now one thing before you mentioned that all these different types
of pasta they're basically the same thing that just different shapes right that's how you distinguish them.
Well yeah they're they're basically made from the same ingredients and so you have most of them
are kind of a yellow color but sometimes you have pastas that are a dark like a brown or a green
that depends on what kind of things you put into the dough right but generally they're the the same
ingredients but they are different shapes like they have curly ones and they're long ones and short ones.
All right so how do you pronounce uh we said pene in an English and American English but in
proper Italian it would be pene so you you double pronounce the consonant. What about
Fetuccine? Fetuccine. Oh it's Fetuccine. Fetuccine um in an American we say uh
Fetuccine. Fetuccine. Fetuccine Alfredo is a very common American Italian dish right in the
time to be Fetuccine so you might hear it differently and what about spaghetti? Spaghetti. Spaghetti.
Oh you pronounce the double T as well. That's right okay so uh you said that uh obviously there
are a lot of other types of pasta what about this pasta that's uh I think it's made of spinach it's green.
Yeah that's uh that's just a spinach pasta basically you just put the spinach in the dough
but you can also find very many um shapes like the angel hair pasta that's very thin. It's very
then that's the one I was saying is it's almost like hair it's so thin it's very it's long as well.
What about those little curly tubes um you they look like pene but they're kind of curved like
they look like little ends or you. Oh you have um macaroni macaroni. Elbo macaroni we call them
in America and they look like your elbow on your arms we call them elbow macaroni. What about the ones
that are um they have like a spiral they kind of look like springs. Those are called fucilli.
Fucilli. Yeah and you also have one that's very special this is my favorite pasta by the way it's called
or a kitte or a kitte and they look like your ear and that's what that means in a time it means
your little ear. Oh really yeah so earpastas. Wow and what about ravioli this is probably one of the
most famous uh dishes ravioli what it what is this? A ravioli is like a square it's like a square
pasta but it's more like a pocket or a pillow and inside you have ingredients like meat or cheese usually
it's very popular. Right so you have this cheese inside this little little packet. This little yeah
it's a little dough it's very soft and very warm and then on top sometimes people like to put butter
or tomato sauce. Okay really delicious. So that's the main diff like this was obviously all the
pasta that we mentioned they're just uh they don't have anything inside them. No they're just dough
but a ravioli is a special kind of pasta that's like a it's almost like a dumpling in a way it's
it's stuffed. There has to be a season-side. All right really interesting I think Italian cuisine is
among one of the most famous foods in the world and well you should let us know if what is your
favorite Italian dish. Please let us know our website is englishpod.com and when you're there you
could find out what our favorite dishes are. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.