Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have a
new lesson in our series about interviewing for a new job. This is of course at the elementary level.
That's right. So this is part four of our interview series. Remember we are taking a look each week
at giving you tips and also the proper language for when you have an interview in English. And on this occasion
we're going to talk about our work experience. Okay you remember we talked a little bit about
educational experience and educational background. Well today is all about your last couple of jobs.
All right so I think we should just listen to the dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a bit
with language takeaway.
Right Rebecca. Now I see that after graduating from university your first job was
for a local paper in York called the York Harold. Actually I started with them as an in-term.
I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good first step.
Certainly. And after your internship they seemed impressed and offered me a position as a
junior local news reporter. I ended up staying two years there actually. I was in charge of the
sports news section of the newspaper. I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills.
Yes I see. But you decided to leave them in 2006 right?
Yes that's right. My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a
national newspaper based in London. It's a London weekly right? Yes. In some ways it was a step down
from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects for the future.
All right we're back so now we've picked out a couple of keywords and we're going to take a look at
those now on language takeaway. Language takeaway. So Marco a lot of people don't start out
as a professional with a job. They have something else first what is this? That's right a very
popular way to begin your work experience. You become an intern or you work as an intern.
Okay so the name of the job we could say is intern. I'm an intern or he's an intern at my company.
Exactly. So usually interns work at a company. Usually they're not paid and
or if they are it's a very very little pay and the purpose of an intern ship or to work as an intern
is to gain experience. That's right so it's basically like a study opportunity for a job that you
know you want. I could be an intern at a media company and I could learn all about media but it's
not really a full job. Exactly and usually it serves as an opportunity to maybe continue working
at that company in the full-time job. So you become an intern and the noun or what you are doing
is called an internship. So I'm an intern but what I have is an intern ship. Right. It's like saying
I have a job. I have an intern ship but I am an intern. Exactly. All right so we've covered those two
words. Now let's move on to when she's describing her work experience in the York Harald and she
described it as a very good first step. Okay so a first step you think about your foot, your step,
your moving. It means the very first thing you do when you're heading in some direction.
Right and professionally I guess your first steps are maybe becoming an intern. Right or you could say
my first step was working in the mail room at this big movie studio but later I became you know
famous movie producer. Exactly so that's the kind of like the way that you begin your professional life.
And well then they started talking about the newspapers and actually Rebecca was offered a position
as a junior local news reporter. Okay so junior means usually lower ranking or not
experience. Someone who is just starting out and of course after junior we have senior. So
a senior news reporter is someone who's worked for many many years as a reporter.
Mm-hmm. Usually I guess a junior news reporter would like make less money than a senior news reporter.
Exactly you could also say junior executive or senior executive. Junior manager. These are ways of
describing length of experience. Mm-hmm. And in this case she's junior but what kind of job
does she have? Well she is a news reporter for local issues. Okay so she's a local news reporter.
Now what exactly does that mean if you're a local news reporter or for local issues?
Well if I live in Chicago and I'm a local news reporter I only write or report the news about Chicago.
It's it's a way of describing the things in my area. So it's the opposite of our next phrase
National news reporter. Okay so if you are a national news reporter or a national manager
of maybe a company then that means that you oversep things in the whole country. That's right so
local is my city or my county but in the case of national we're talking about the whole country
nation national so national is an adjective but we could even go further than this. What if I
am a reporter and I talk about foreign countries I talk about France and South Africa and even Iceland.
Mm-hmm. Then I guess you would be an international news reporter. Exactly. And I guess also at the
executive level you can have an international marketing manager right? That's right international
marketing manager, national marketing manager. These are very important ways to divide work to say
he is the international manager. Here's the national manager. This tells you the kind of the size
of this person's job. Exactly. Okay so now more or less you know how these jobs can be divided
junior, senior, national, local, etc. So I think we should go back to the dialogue. Let's listen to
this dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Right Rebecca. Now I see that after graduating from university your first job was
for a local paper in York called the York Harald. Actually I started with them as an
intern. I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good first step.
Certainly. And after your internship? They seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior
local news reporter. I ended up staying two years there actually. I was in charge of the sports
news section of the newspaper. I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills.
Yes I see. But you decided to leave them in 2006 right? Yes that's right. My husband and I moved
to London and so I managed to find a position with a national newspaper based in London.
It's a London weekly right? Yes. In some ways it was a step down from my previous job but it did
offer me much better prospects for the future.
All right so now let's start with a couple of phrases and a phrasal verbs on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay and today's dialogue we heard a lot of really wonderful phrases Marco.
Some of them are ways of making your experiences sound better. More professional even.
For example this first one. So I Rebecca's talking about her first job in York and she says
I was in charge of the sports news section in charge. Okay so that phrase I was in charge of or to
be in charge of what is this described? This describes responsibility. Basically she's saying I was
responsible for or I had to manage the sports news section. She's taking credit for this job that was
okay so this is a key phrase because this is the typical phrase that you used to describe your
responsibilities or to describe what you did in your previous job position or your previous job.
So I could ask you when you were in marketing what were you in charge of? Right and then you say well
I was in charge of and then you explain your responsibilities or what you did. I was in charge of
national accounts or I was in charge of the local news. Exactly. So this is a very simple phrase
just remember it. I was in charge of and then you can start explaining what were your responsibilities.
What you did in your previous job. All right moving on now towards the end of that paragraph.
Rebecca says that well being in charge of the sports news section was really fun and it really helped
her build my skills. It really helped me build my skills. So to build your skills or in this case I build my
skills means that I have some skills but maybe they're not really developed. Maybe you know I just
finished college I want more experience. Well in that time during my first job I build my skills.
I become better at writing or making having interviews things like that. Exactly. So when you build
your skills you kind of improve your abilities or you gain more experience. All right and another
interesting phrase coming up here when Rebecca talked about moving to London with her husband she said
I managed to find a position with a national newspaper. Okay so I managed to or you could say
to manage to do something. This is a really interesting phrase because it's another way of saying
to be able to or to succeed at something. Okay so don't confuse it with a manager or to
manage people. That is also correct to obviously it exists but to manage to do something is to
as you said to be able to do something. Right so for example I was running really late yesterday
and I had a ticket for a train at five o'clock. I thought I would miss the train but I managed to
get to the train on time. That means I was able to get on the train on time. Exactly okay so
you managed to find a job but I managed to get to the train on time. I was able to. All right and
towards the end Rebecca talked about her job at the London weekly and she described it as a
step down for my previous job. Okay so good thing you're a bad thing Marco. To be a step down
in something is a bad thing it's to reduce in level or to decrease. Okay so basically she's saying
listen I have this really great job in New York and I took a new job in London and the new job
it wasn't as good in many ways because maybe she had less responsibility or maybe it paid less.
So this is a way of saying it wasn't as good as my last job. Okay so her new job was a step down
from her previous job. You could say I think his new girlfriend's a bit of a step down if you
know what I mean. Exactly so usually you're comparing right you're making a comparison between
something from the past to now. Exactly. Okay so a step down. Why don't we go back and listen to the
dialogue for the very last time and we're back to talk to you in a bit.
Right Rebecca now I see that after graduating from university your first job was for a local paper in
York called the York Harold actually I started with them as an intern I was really keen on getting
some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good first step. Certainly and after your internship
they seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter. I ended up staying
two years there actually I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper. I really enjoyed
it there and it really helped me build my skills. Yes I see but you decided to leave them in 2006 right?
Yes that's right my husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a
national newspaper based in London. To London weekly right? Yes in some ways it was a step down
from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects for the future.
All right so talking about internships and interns it seems that usually they get it's not
very exciting to become an intern because it ends up that the office people just make you
make coffee or or copies and stuff like that you're not really gaining much work experience.
That is the reputation in the United States for internships so basically when you agree to do an
internship sometimes you have to apply to do an internship it's a very long process you end up like you
say making coffee for people or photocopying reports and this is really boring work. Right I think
yeah that is the reputation that many places have like you say in the United States but also
I don't know I guess it does seem in a way the only opportunity in order to be able to get into an
industry or a company maybe it's a really good company like I don't know like like proctor and gamble
and how else are you going to be able to get in there with no job experience? Well that's right and a lot
of people know that an internship doesn't really give you work experience but they'd still give it
they still think that it gives you some edge or some advantage when you're looking for jobs later
because if I write down on my my resume we were talking earlier but resumes if I write down on my
resume that I was an intern at Proctor and gamble wow that's really impressive. Right it looks good.
All right so this is an interesting topic let us know if you were ever an intern maybe you
started out as an internship or maybe you're doing one now. Was it better than we say did you do
anything else? So that I'm making coffee we really hope so and that we look forward to hearing
about your experiences. All right we'll see everyone at EnglishPod.com and until next time bye bye