Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we have another great elementary lesson for you all
that's right we've got a lesson for all you sports fans out there
alright we're doing a podcast on sports today
we're starting off with basketball
so we've got lots of language about basketball and sports in this lesson today
great so let's take a look at our vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
two words for you today the first one is foul
foul
a foul
basically it's an action in a game that is not allowed
right so if you're playing basketball and you kick the other player
that's a foul that's a pretty big foul
yeah if you're playing soccer and you pick up the ball
that's also a foul
our second word is
rf rf
also known as a referee
right
so a referee is
basically like the judge of a game
the judge of the game so he's the one that will say that was a foul
that was a foul
yeah
rf also known as referee
okay so two great words we're going to hear them in our dialogue
and we're going to be listening to two guys who are watching a basketball game on TV
and
hey is the game started yet
yeah about five minutes ago
who's running
bulls of course
what that wasn't a foul
come on raf
sorry
shack always screws up free throws
you were right he didn't make a shot
you're a bit of a deal
but smoking down at the hoop
yeah that was a great shot
three pointer yeah
did you see that he traveled to the raf didn't even call us
raf needs glasses
hey raf open your eyes
can't believe you can see that
okay
I did the first quarter
alright I'm going to make a beer run
alright a really common situation
whenever you're watching games with friends right
you need to get a beer
we'll talk about that in a little while
let's take a look at language takeaway
language takeaway
okay let's take a look at our first word on language takeaway
free throw free throw free throw
this one's a bit hard to say isn't it it's a little bit hard to explain
but if you're playing basketball
and if someone fouls you you get a free throw
so that's when all the players line up around you
and you can throw the ball
to the basket without anyone blocking you
right a little bit complicated but I'm sure the basketball fans
understand what a free throw is
alright our next word is
make the shot
let's listen to some examples and we'll understand the meaning of
example one
I can't believe it you made the shot from the other side of the court
example two
there's no way he's going to make that shot he's way too far away from the net
example three
if gritsky makes a shot they're going to win the Stanley Cup
so it's clear now to make the shot is to successfully
make the ball in the basket you can use this expression in other sports as well
yeah you could use it in hockey to make the shot
could also use it in golf in a lot of different sports that use the term to shoot
shoot the ball so at any time you shoot the ball you can make the shot
exactly
okay our next word today three pointer
three pointer
it's a shot in basketball when you get three points
yes usually this shot is taken from further out
yeah farther distance yeah so it's a little bit more difficult to make the shot
you know sometimes people might say a three point shot or something like that
but our English pot learners they know
it's a three point
yeah you'll sound really knowledgeable really cool
you can out one three pointer
and our last word today
travel
to travel
when you walk with the basketball
well technically you're allowed to take two steps in basketball
okay so when you take more than two steps in the basketball
so yeah traveling means to take more than two steps with the ball
let's listen to the dialogue a second time
this time it'll be a bit slower so that we can understand some of these great phrases we just talked about
and we're going to talk about the first time
hey has the game started yet
yeah about five minutes ago
oh who's winning
the bulls of course
what that wasn't a foul
come on Raff
don't worry
shack always screws up free throws
yeah you were right
he didn't make this shot
yeah that was a great shot
three pointer
oh did you see that
he traveled and the Raff didn't even call it
this Raff needs glasses
hey Raff open your eyes
I can't believe he didn't see that
okay then to the first quarter
hey I'm going to make a beer run
sweet
all right sports fans
so now let's take a look at blue and sea builder
blue and sea builder
okay today on blue and sea builder we have two really common words that you would listen to while you're watching a game
yeah these are sort of slang words
yeah they're kind of a common like informal
informal
the first one that we have is screw up
screw up
yeah so this is a good way of saying
to make a mistake
let's listen to some examples of how this word is used
example one
jail you really screwed up this time you fired
example two
this game is important
you screw it up
out of the finals
example three
I'm sorry I know I screwed up
we forgive me
okay so screw up is mess up
yeah make a mistake
great and our last word on blue and sea builder today
a beer run
beer run
you run to get beer
you go to the store and get beer
okay more beer
so it's just an expression to meaning to go and get more beer
yeah usually you're watching a game or you're at home with your friends
you run out of beer so somebody has to make a beer
go get some beer make a beer run
yeah
hey is the game started yet
yeah about five minutes ago
who's running
oh balls of course
what that wasn't a foul
come on raf
sorry
shack always screws up free throws
you were right
he didn't make a shot
yeah that was a great shot
three pointer yeah
did you see that he traveled
the raf didn't even call his
raf needs glasses
hey raf open your eyes
can't believe he didn't see that
okay
any of the first quarter
alright I'm gonna make a beer run
okay guys I hope you enjoyed our lesson today
we'll be bringing you more sports lessons in the future
yes
so if you have a particular sport that you want to learn about you can tell us
and we'll have to our website
englishpod.com
yeah and leave us your comments or your suggestions
or any doubts that you have
and we're always there to answer it so we'll see you there
yes until next time
bye