Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to bring you a great lesson about calling the office
Yep, that's right so in this lesson we're going to teach you some great words that you can use
when you need to call your office to solve a problem
Right so you are at home, you have a problem, maybe you can't go to the office so you have to call them
and tell them that you're not going to be able to go
Yes, all right so we're not going to preview anything today because the dialogue is relatively
easy so let's listen to the dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and look at some words
Hello hey, annual date eating spay, out hey, am a, I hope hey we are
All day i hate you are, hey have Hey are we, yo actually i'm eating spay i
kway illegal today i'm already say it, you're, hey Etsy27
I was hungry
I hugged
I'm imоко getting to the Ande
or say hotel, any rate, always make and I'm eating fail,
lightly say, you're a shfay.
I say, I say, or yay, all in K&Xay.
S-J-A. I ask why open-Hey,
U-T-A-T, off-the-E-K-R-A.
Okay, and the I-T-R-N-E-K, I'm saying, S-T-R-A.
All right, so a pretty easy dialogue, right?
Yeah, pretty simple. All right, so there are a couple of words that we want to look at, so let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right, well, today we're looking at three interesting words.
The first one is U-flay. U-flay. U-flay.
U-flay. Marco, what is the U-flay?
All right, so when you have the U-flay, it means that you are sick.
You have, um, it's very similar to a cold.
Right, but just worse, right?
Worst, yeah, so when you have the U-flay,
it'll keep you in bed for a while, for maybe a week or two.
So you have a fever, um, your body is hurting.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're really sick.
Yeah, you're really sick. Okay, so U-flay.
All right, well, what about our next word?
Well, actually the next word is a phrase that you can use when you're calling the office.
I'll incase in E-xay.
All incase in E-xay.
Okay, this is a really useful phrase, and I think it would help us to hear some examples of what it sounds like so we can understand the meaning.
Example one.
Or if I people pay all K and X, would it?
Example two.
If U-a, all K and X,
on one or May, I'm Tay, or Y, Iard Fay.
Example three.
I'm not in the E-ling fail away.
O-say, I'm all incase in E-xay.
So with this phrase, you're basically saying that you are not going to the office.
Exactly.
So let's take a look at our last word for language tickling.
E-cover, gray.
Okay, so it's a pretty simple word.
E-cover, right?
Means to get better to start feeling healthy again.
Okay, so kind of to recharge your batteries.
Exactly.
So this is a great verb to use when you want to say I'm going to feel better.
Okay, E-cover, gray.
So some really great words, some really interesting phrases.
So let's listen to this dialogue again, and then we'll come back.
Hello, hey.
And you're the king's say, I'm the, I'm El-Pay, we're.
I'm the, we're, hey, we're.
I'm E-ring, I'm the, we're, hey.
I'm E-ring, I'm the, we're, we're, we're, we're.
Actually, I'm E-ring say I quit E-ring today.
I'm already say E-ring you're, hey at the.
That was hungry.
I think that I'm, I'm going to K-O-n-day.
I am a headache or say,
I'm eating fatally, say, you're a headache.
I say, or you're an ex-a.
I say, I always say,
I say, I say, I say, I say, I say, I say,
okay, and I try and it gay, I'm saying, I say, I say.
All right, Michael, have you ever found yourself in a situation like this?
Well, yeah, a couple of times that I haven't been able to really make it to the office,
and I've had to call.
So yeah, I would have to call and tell them that I'm not going to make it,
or maybe that I'm going to be a little bit late.
All right, well, yeah, it happens to all of us,
and you now, you guys have all of this useful language.
Next time you face this problem.
Exactly.
So if you have any questions or comments,
be sure to visit our website EnglishPod.com.
Marco and I are there to respond to your questions and comments,
as well, there are also lots of other great lessons for you to check out on the website.
Exactly.
So be sure to check out some of our first lessons.
I'm sure you find them useful as well.
Yes.
Okay.
Well, thanks for listening everyone, and until next time.
Bye.
Thank you.