Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine. Today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you. If you're interested
in buying furniture for your house you should like this lesson.
Exactly. We are going to talk about a ton of different furniture items that you can get to decorate
your house to make it all nice. So we're going to talk about a lot of a vocabulary today. Pay attention
while you're listening to some of the pieces of furniture that we talk about. We'll be back
in a moment to talk more about them.
How about this floor lamp? Fine. Just get it. We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired. We still need to find an arm wire and a dresser. Fine. I'm going to go home and
drop off this nice stand coffee table and let's see while you look for the rest of the things.
Great. Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
Well you're at it. Can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I can watch TV.
Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
Alright we're back. So now what we're going to do is since we have so much of vocab, we're going to
take a look at this language in two parts. So now let's go to language takeaway part one.
Language takeaway. Okay so everyone's heard of a lamp a light. This is something that you use to
read in the dark for example to see in the dark. But in this case we have a floor lamp.
Floor lamp. So this is a lamp you put on the floor. Yes exactly. So usually this lamp would be
a lot taller. It'll maybe be like a meter taller, a meter and a half maybe. Okay so for example in
your living room next to your sofa you might have a very tall floor lamp. This allows you to get
more light in the room. Right so sometimes you know the center light in your living room is not
enough. You want maybe more light in the corners you get a little floor lamp. Okay so that's the first
item. Now that we go to the bedroom we are getting an arm warm. Okay and arm warm. This is kind of
like a wardrobe. It's a it's a piece of furniture we use to keep clothes in but usually they're
hanging clothes. Okay so a closet is usually inside a wall right? Right so closet is a part of your house.
It's not furniture. Right so an arm warm is the same as a closet but it's not in the house like
in the walls. It's outside it's a piece of furniture. I could pick it up and move it. Okay. Yes so
an arm warm is a tall place to keep clothing. Usually you hang your clothes. You hang your shirts
and your dress up and your coats. And moving on we have a dresser. Now this seems pretty straightforward
to get dressed. You have a dresser? Yeah it makes a lot of sense but there is a big difference here
between an arm warm and a dresser. A dresser is usually drawers. So you keep your sweaters your shirts
your socks. You're underwear in a dresser. Okay so at an arm warm as you said usually you hang
your shirts or your pants. It's for hanging stuff only. A dresser is you have different drawers
where you can put your socks your box or shorts and any other things that you keep. Exactly. Okay
very good so two very handy words and that's what makes the difference between a closet. So many
people say oh it's just a closet. No closet is different. No closet is actually part of your house.
It's a part of the wall. Maybe has a door and yeah there's a big difference there. Okay.
So moving on we have a nightstand that's also usually in the bedroom. That's right so I always
wondered why is it called a nightstand and not a daystand? Well a nightstand it makes sense.
It usually has a lamp on it, a light on it. So when you're in bed and you want to read
you have a nightstand next to you to put your lamps so you can turn the lamp on.
Usually I also keep my books here. So when I'm reading I put my books down then I go to sleep.
Some people also keep their glasses and they're alarm clock on a nightstand. Okay it's a small
table that stands next to your bed. Very good and our last word for language takeaway part one
we have a coffee table. Okay so with the coffee table Marco we're moving back into the living room
and in the living room you have a sofa you have some chairs you need a table but you don't want
a big table you want a small table or a very short table. This is a coffee table. It's called a
coffee table. I'm not really sure why I guess because if you're having coffee in the living room this
is where you put the coffee. That's right and we even have something called coffee table books. These
are big beautiful books, hard-back books that have many pictures that you put on your coffee table to
look nice. It's not for you to actually read all the time. Well I read them but it's more
important to use these books to look nice. Yes and this is interesting though because in many other
countries they're not really called a coffee table so the direct translation wouldn't really help
you in many cases. I think in Chinese it's called a tea table not a coffee table. It makes sense.
Right. I know in Spanish you just call the center table. Okay so this is basically the low
table you have in your living room next to your sofa in front of yourself actually so you can
have tea or coffee and read books or put your feet up while you're watching TV. Not in my house
when I was a kid. All right so now why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again and we'll
return in a little bit with more vocab. How about this floor lamp? Fine just get it. We
have been shopping for furniture for five hours. I'm so tired. We still need to find an armware and a
fine. I'm going to go home and drop off this nice stand coffee table and love seat while you look
for the rest of the things. Great. Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a
bean bag and a dining set. Well you're at at it. Can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I
can watch TV. Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway. Coming up we have one of my favorite phrases in the English language. I don't know
why I like it so much but it is a great name for a piece of furniture. A love seat. Love seat. Okay.
Okay so it sounds it sounds very romantic. It does. Well think about a sofa. A sofa can be very
large. You can have four or five people on a sofa. Right. But a love seat is a small sofa for two people.
Okay so that's what makes the difference. Right? It's a sofa but only two people can sit on this.
That's right so if it's a big sofa it's not a love seat. And what about if it's one because
usually a sofa sets you have a love seat, a big one and you have one sometimes an individual one.
Do you just call that a chair? Yep a chair. Okay. Exactly. We'll come to it in a minute. There's
a special kind of chair that it might be but we're not quite there yet. First we have another
kind of chair which is very special and it reminds me a lot of the 1970s. Right. We have a bean bag
and this is actually a piece of furniture that's still very popular in many places and it's called a
bean bag because it's a huge bag that is filled with beans. Right. Beans are something soft
and when you sit on it it looks like it looks like a ball but when you sit on it it can change shape.
Right. It molds to how what shape you are. And usually they're very light and a lot of times I
hate to say it a lot of times bachelor's apartments have these. That's right. It's actually
very cheap piece of furniture and it's comfortable sometimes if you're watching TV you can just sit
on your bean bag and watch TV even I know some people may you know fall asleep on a bean bag
as as guests. I've never slept up well maybe once but I don't remember sleeping on a bean
bag. I imagine it's quite uncomfortable back but moving on after a bean bag which is a good
informal piece of furniture we have he dining set which is a lot nicer. Okay dining set. All right so
a dining set has many pieces. You have a dining room table. Right. You have chairs. So a set is basically
a collection of a table and chairs together. Sometimes I think it will also include some type of
piece of furniture that's next to the dining table where you can keep your plates and you can keep
your teacups and all that what's that called. That's called a buffet and that's basically
it's like a dresser for your dining room. Right exactly. It's got like drawers and stuff for your
plates, your cups like you said and it's next to the dining room table but the dining room set or the
dining set is for the dining room. It's the table where you eat dinner. Okay very good. And
now moving on to that special chair that I am a big fan of. It's very comfortable sit on and it's
called a recliner. Recliner. So we have a word here recline. It means to lie back to put your head
back to get comfortable. So a recliner is a chair that you can change the shape of to make you lie
down. So when you sit down you're sitting but what if you want to lie down in a chair? This chair
lets you do that. And it also from the bottom part where your feet are a little thing pops up so you
can rest your feet on top of this little extension of the chair. Okay so it has a built-in foot
rest. What rest exactly? So it's very comfortable. It's very popular if you ever watch the series
friends. They have the recliners. It's very comfortable to watch sports for example. You have
your bejoey has his recliner. And remember when Joey and Chandler lived together they have the two
recliners in front of the TV. Those chairs are recliners and they're very popular. Actually they're
I think in the United States they're very commonly known by the brand, lazy boy. That's right
there's a brand. It's not a kind of furniture but it's the name of the brand. It's lazy boy and they're
very very famous. You're right Martha for their reclining chairs. Exactly so a lazy boy is
you may hear it but the real word for it is called a recliner. So a lot of interesting pieces of furniture
there. I think our house is going to look amazing. So when we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time.
How about this floor lamp? Fine just get it. We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired. We still need to find an arm wire and a dresser. Fine. I'm going to go home and drop
off this nice stand coffee table and let's see while you look for the recidder things. Great.
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
While you're at it can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I can watch TV.
Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
All right we're back. So talking about furniture is very interesting. How do you take it home?
What do you do? In this case they were transporting it themselves. The guy said I'm going to go home
and drop off this night stand coffee table and love seed. So to drop off. This is a great verb.
To drop off. It's a verbal phrase. So the preposition there is off. Not on. Right. So I could say for
example Marco, I'm just going to drop off my bag at home and then I'll meet you guys for dinner.
That means I'm going to go to my house and put down my bag and then I'll leave. So to drop off
is basically to go somewhere so you can put something in that place. But it doesn't mean that you're
going to go to that place and stay there. Right. So if I say I'm going to drop off the kids at
school, that means I'm going to take the kids and leave them at school and then go away.
It doesn't mean you're going to school. You're right exactly. So can you drop off the laundry
at the dry cleaners please? Very good. So I'm going to take the laundry to the dry cleaners,
leave it there and then go somewhere else. So what happens at three o'clock when the kids are still
at school? That's right. Now we use the opposite verbal phrase and that is to pick up.
Okay, drop off. Pick up. So you go pick up the kids. You go pick up the laundry. So this isn't
just about some picking something up from a table or the ground. You can actually use your car
to pick something up. Right. You go and retrieve it. So I'm going to the post office to pick up my
package. Very good. So phrases that you're going to have to use if you're talking about furniture,
if you're talking about buying something. And what are on the topic? I know that
one of the most popular places to buy furniture is IKEA. Are you a big fan of IKEA?
I like IKEA and I love what they've done for people who don't want to spend too much money on furniture.
It's expensive. Furniture is very expensive. You can spend $5,000 on a sofa. And so IKEA is a
wonderful brand and I think a wonderful company because it makes good looking furniture affordable.
And it's because you put it together yourself, right? That's right. A lot of things you have to
assemble or put together by yourself. So you buy it in a box and then you make it. And it's
a little bit frustrating sometimes. But for people like me and I'm sure people like you,
it's part of the fun is putting stuff together. Yeah, because it kind of feel like you
kind of built it, but you really didn't. So it kind of gives you that false sense of accomplishment.
It's like I'm in the 19th century and I can make my own furniture. So it's a very popular. I've
actually and apart from having great furniture, I understand that they have amazing meatballs.
They do. Well, I'm a Swedish. I never get to eat Swedish meatballs and here in China,
they do have some of the better meatballs around. So I would recommend if you haven't tried them.
Try them. They're pretty good. Yeah, good. I like it. Good. I like here. Have some dinner.
Let me know. Our website is EnglishPod.com. Do you like IKEA and do you love their meatballs?
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.