Hello English learners, welcome back. We are here at EnglishPod. I am joined with
Erica and my partner in crime. Marco. Alright, so today we're going to be talking about a really
great topic. One of my favorites beer beer. So beer is a very popular drink especially in bars
and when you go out. Yes, it's very common with students, I think. Yes, and it's also not very strong
like a vodka or whiskey. Yes, okay. So we are going to be at a bar today and we're going to be
looking at some of this vocabulary that you would find. Yes, I mean you've got to know this
beer vocabulary. Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and
look at these words.
Hey, man, what do you have on top? Hi, Nick Cannon Budweiser. We have a two for one happy
hour special. Cool. Give me a pun on hi Nick Cannon and half a pun on bud. Okay.
Hi Nick Cannon, half a pun on bud for table six. What about some appetizers?
Sure, let's have some, let's have some not chosen mozzarella sticks. Okay, that'll be 80 bucks.
Well, it's pretty expensive for two beers and some foods. Yes. Well, it happens sometimes
you go to these very exclusive bars and they charge you like if it was gold. I mean, that's crazy.
Well, let's take a look at some of these great words that we saw in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Our first word is on tap on tap on tap. So he asked, what do you have on tap?
Now this is a strange sentence. What exactly does it mean? Okay, well, he's asking
about what beer is the bar has, but not in a bottle or not in a can, right? Right. So you know, in a bar,
there's often this machine, right, that will pour a very fresh beer right directly into the glass.
Into the glass. Mm-hmm. Yeah, this is a very popular thing because like you say it's fresh beer.
Yeah, it tastes better. I'm taste better. Yeah. Okay. So what do you have on tap? What do you have on top?
All right. Let's take a look at our second word. Happy hour. Happy hour. Happy hour. Happy hour.
Now this is very common in popular with bars. Yes. What is it when they have a happy hour? Okay.
A happy hour is a period of time where the drinks are very cheap. Okay. So happy hour could be
from 5 PM till 10 PM 50% off. So if the drink is $4, then it is now $2 in happy hour. Perfect.
And this brings us to our third word, a special, a special, a special. So this is a noun, and what does
it mean when a restaurant or a bar has a special? It's like they're having a sale. A sale.
So things are cheaper. So it could be for example a Monday night special. Mm-hmm. Or like in the
dialogue, a happy hour special. Okay. So it is a promotion. Yes. All right. Very good. And now they
ordered a pint of Heinekin and half a pint of Budweiser. Mm-hmm. Pint. This is a very, very special
beer word. So a pint is the size of your glass. Okay. So we understand how much a pint is.
What would be the equivalent in leaders? A pint is 0.4 liters. Okay. So almost half a liter is one pint.
Yes. Okay. It is very common when you go into a bar you can order a pint of beer. Yes. Exactly.
In English we don't say I'll have half a liter of beer. Right. Right. So let's take a look at our
next word on language takeaway. Appetizers. Appetizers. Appetizers. Okay. So what is an
appetizer? Well it is food. You eat before your dinner or before your lunch. Okay. So it's usually
maybe like a salad or soup or something small that you can eat right before your big meal.
Okay. So some common appetizers at a bar and we saw them in our dialogue.
Not chose and mozzarella sticks. Not chose. Not chose. Not chose. Not chose. So not chose are
little chips, right? Yeah corn chips. Mm-hmm. And it has cheese and maybe some tomatoes and maybe
beans. Uh-huh. Okay. So those are not chose. They're very common in the United States. Yes.
Yeah. And what about mozzarella sticks? mozzarella sticks. A travesty on the world and humanity and
everyone's arteries. Well mozzarella is a cheese, right? Mm-hmm. mozzarella cheese. And
the this cheese is what what is it? How is it prepared? You put it in some red crumbs and then you
fry it in oil. You deep fry it. Uh-huh. And you don't like this. No, it's terrible. Why? They're so good.
Oh my god. Because then you can dip it in a little sauce. Oh delicious. You mark other so many reasons
why this is wrong. All right. Well mozzarella sticks are very popular bar food. All right. Well why don't
we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be able to hear these words in context at a slower speed.
Hey, man. What do you have on top? Heinekin and Budweiser. We have a two for one happy hour
special. Cool. Give me a pun of Heinekin and half a pun of Bud. Okay. Pond to Heinekin, half
pint of Bud for table six. What about some appetizers? Sure. Let's have some uh let's have some
not chosen mozzarella sticks. Okay. That'll be 80 bucks. What? What? Okay. So we saw some really good vocabulary
words there and now let's take a look at putting it together. Put it together. Well in this lesson
we are going to look at one phrase that sometimes causes problems. So let's listen to this phrase
that we're talking about. What about some appetizers? What about some appetizers?
Okay. So this phrase, what about? Yeah. I often hear people use it to ask a question.
So a common mistake is asking, what about your weekend? What about your new job? Now this is
incorrect, right? You cannot use the phrase what about to ask a question about
information. So you cannot ask for information. Okay. Because in our dialogue the bar tender said
and what about some appetizers? Right. Because he is making a suggestion. Right. So he's saying,
well, why don't you have some food? Yes. The phrase what about can be used to make a suggestion?
Okay. So I can say, what about going to the movies? Hmm. You know what? Let's hear a few more
examples of this because I think it's really useful. Example one, what about these dirty clothes?
You said you would wash them days ago. Example two, what about going to the mall instead?
I'm tired of going to the movies. Example three. What about a pizza instead of noodles?
All right. So really good examples and the same thing we can apply to how about exactly. So again,
how about cannot ask for information? Okay. So you can't say how about your boss. All right. Perfect.
Okay. So let's listen to this dialogue one last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
bit more about ours and beers. Hey man, what do you have on top?
Hi, Nick Cannon Budweiser. We have a two for one happy-hour special. Cool. Give me a pun on
honey, can you have a pun on bud? Okay. Fine, I'll hide it again. Half-pun of bud for table six.
What about some appetizers? Sure. Let's have some, let's have some notchos and
mozzarella sticks. Okay. That'll be 80 bucks. What? What?
Well, Marco, I know you're a big fan of beer and actually I think everyone here at Prakxis is a big
beer drinker and this is a perfect opportunity to tell everyone about the world renowned beer shake.
Oh my gosh. Okay, Marco. All right. So everyone that listens to this recipe is a non-believer.
They say that it is not possible for it to taste good. Okay. But here's the recipe. You take a
leader of beer or maybe half a leader. So a pint or a pint and a half and you put it in the blender.
Okay. All right. Now you take two eggs. Uh-huh. Okay. Not cooked, not boiled,
anything. You take two eggs and put them in the blender. It could be one or two. Okay. And then you take
about half a cup of sugar. Put it in the blender. What? And you mix all that together and you get this
really good foamy delicious beer shake. So a beer milkshake. Well, it has no milk. Okay. But
it's actually really good. I've prepared it for some people. They're like, no, that's not possible.
It can't taste good. And in the end they're like, wow, this is actually pretty good. So did you
invent this recipe? It's actually really common in Ecuador and Peru. I've even seen in Chile,
usually with a dark beer. Okay. Right. So like a Guinness or it could be a Guinness or yeah,
if it's that a dark beer is a little bit sweeter. Yeah. So you wouldn't add so much sugar. But
if you have another beer like a like a logger or a stout, you could still do it. But just
add a little bit more sugar because that beer is a little bit more bitter. Okay. Well, I am not going
to try this recipe. But maybe you guys are. You should try it out and let me know how it works.
Yeah. You can tell us all about it on our website, EnglishPod.com. Yeah. And we're definitely there
to answer all your questions. And I'll be posting the recipe as well on the website. All right. Well,
we're out of time for today. But thanks for listening and until next time. Bye.