Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're going to be helping you set up an answering machine basically.
That's right. So somebody's calling you. You can't answer the phone. So you leave a message.
And we're going to teach you all about that today. That's right. So let's take a listen to our dialogue.
And we'll be back in a moment to figure out just what's going on.
Can you help me set up my voicemail message? I just got the service and I'm not really sure what I'm supposed to say.
Sure. You just basically got to let the caller know who they called and asked them for the contact information so you can call them back.
Okay. So I can say this is Abby's voicemail. I will call you later. So leave me your name a number.
That's more or less the idea. But try something that sounds more friendly.
Okay. So how about this? This is Abby and I'm really happy you called. I promise I will give you a ring.
As soon as I can. So please leave me your name a number. Talk to you soon.
A little too friendly Abby. Just say this. Hi. You've reached Abby. I'm unable to answer your call right now.
But if you leave me your name in phone number, I will get back to you as soon as possible. Thanks.
That's perfect. Can you say that again and record it for me?
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at some language. Take away.
Language takeaway.
All right. In the first sentence, we are asking someone to help me set up my voicemail message. So we got two
keywords there. That's right. So let's break it up. The first one is a phrasal verb to set up. Okay.
You can set a lot of things up. But just remember that set and up. These are the two words that go together.
In this case we're setting up voicemail. It means to establish or to start or to
put together. Yeah, to install. Like for example, you get a new computer and you have to connect all the cables
and you have to connect the monitor. So you said, can you help me set up my computer? That's right. So he always helps me set it up.
So my computer, for example. That's right. And what we're setting up is a voicemail message. So what exactly
is voicemail? Well, you know what mail is with email and regular mail. Voicemail is the kind of message
you receive on your phone, your cell phone or your home phone when you don't answer the phone.
That's right. So basically a way for people to leave you a message even though you can't answer them.
That's right. So this is something that's not text. It's actually a voice. That's why it's called voicemail.
And you have to set it up. Okay. So there's no automatic voicemail message. You actually have to make your own
or you can choose one. And today we're making our own. That's right. And so we're explaining that we
actually just got this service. And we don't really know what we're supposed to say or how to set up
that's right. So voicemail messages are kind of service. And now who would offer this kind of
service Marco? Probably your telephone company. That's right. So telephone company will offer
many different services. And these are things that you can pay extra for. And they're useful.
They can help you in some way. So another kind of service is three way calling. That's right. So
actually we're taking a look at this word service as a noun. So we have a service or this service.
So the company offers this service. And well, why are we setting up the voicemail and our
friend explains that we just basically doing it to let the color know who they called.
Okay. So if I call a number and it says, hey, leave a message. I don't know who I'm leaving a message
for. Did I dial the wrong number? Right. What do I say? Do I say my phone number? So this is
basically instructions for what to say. That's right. And you become the color. Right. So whoever is
making the call is called the color. And this is why we are setting up our voicemail to let the
color know who we are calling. And of course, we have to ask the color for their contact information.
All right. Now, this is important because it's not just something you have with
voicemail messages. You have contact information from many different things. For example,
your medical care, your school, you have to include contact information. Now, this would be your
phone number, your address and or your email. That's right. So your contact information is not only
useful for an voicemail message, but for example, in a business meeting or a business lunch,
you want to get maybe someone else's contact information, so you can call them later. That's right.
So don't forget, it's all see your name as well. So that's right. Your contact information must
have your name. All right. So that's that's pretty much all we have for the first part of language
takeaway. Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder.
You can call them back. Okay. So I can say this is Abby's voicemail. I will call you later. So leave me your name and number.
That's more or less the idea, but try something that sounds more friendly. Okay. So how about this?
This is Abby and I'm really happy you called. I promise I will give you a ring as soon as I can.
So please leave me your name and number. Talk to you soon. A little too friendly Abby. Just say this.
Hi, you've reached Abby. I'm unable to answer your call right now, but if you leave me your name and
phone number, I will get back to you as soon as possible. Thanks. That's perfect.
Can you say that again and record it for me?
All right. Here we are in fluency builder and the first phrase we've got is how about this. So
we're saying we've got an example for you. How about this? That's right. Then the example.
So we've talked about how about many times already. So for example, you know,
how about we go to the movies or how not to say how about your weekend because that's completely wrong.
In this occasion, we're talking about how about this and this is like setting it up for an example.
That's right. So for another example, we could say so Marco, I'm trying to figure out how to say
hello when I answer the phone because I don't like the way I say it now. Because I have about this.
Hello. Is that good? No. Yeah. That's all right. That's right. Hello. Nice to strong. Hello. Yeah. That's good.
All right. So basically, I'm setting up an example. Right. I'm saying, okay. So keep listening. I will
give you an example. Yeah. Just imagine that you're trying on different clothes and someone is
giving you their opinion. So maybe you try on a black shirt and you say how about this one.
Boring. And then you try on a green one and you say now how about this better. Right. So then you're
giving them other options and examples. And this is why we say how about this. And then we give the
example like Abbey did. And you're also asking for a response. You're asking for an opinion.
And so what Abbey's saying is, I promise I will give you a ring as soon as I can.
Now this phrase, give you a ring is very British English. But it's also something you should know
if you want to be in America because you'll hear it in TV and stuff. That's right. It's actually
a colloquial term for saying I will call you. I will call you. I will call you back or I will give you a call.
So the telephone rings. That's the verb that goes with what the phone. Right?
Ring ring. So I will give you a ring means I will call you just like you just said Markham. That's right.
So remember this phrase. It's actually it may seem a little bit confusing but remember it has to
do with calling someone. I will give you a ring is I will call you or if you say, hey, give me a ring
later on this afternoon. It's called me later this afternoon. All right. And then moving towards the end
of the dialogue. Abbey says, hi, you have reached Abbey. Okay. This is weird because she is Abbey.
But she saying you have reached Abbey. Right. Just be about yourself and the third person. That's
right. So this is a message. So you're telling people what to do like I said they're instructions.
And so this is basically the first thing you say. You have reached Katherine. That means the number
you dialed is Katherine's phone number. Right. So you reached that means that you've contacted.
Right. Exactly. So as you say it's important if you ever call a bank or in any type of company
it will say you have reached Wells Fargo bank or something and it'll give you, it'll tell you
what number you called because maybe you put in your finger wrong and you just called the wrong number.
That's right. Or you could use the word reached in a different way. For example yesterday I was
very angry at Marco because I couldn't reach him by phone. I called and called and called and
could have reached him and I realized that his phone is broken. That's right. So actually this
verb to reach someone also has to do with with in general with calling. I was trying to reach
you all afternoon but I couldn't get a hold of you. That's right. And I was so frustrated.
Well actually if I had voicemail I would continue by saying I am unable to answer your call right now
because maybe my phone is off maybe I am busy. So we say I am unable to answer your call right now.
All right. Now this seems really long. Okay. And a little bit strange. But this is basically the
standard for how to record a message. I am unable to answer your call right now. So you answer
the phone right or you answer a phone call. But in this case I am unable to. That means I can't
talk to you. For whatever reason I'm out of the house. I'm busy. So I'm unable to answer your call right
now. Just remember that that means I can't talk to you right now. I can't be on the phone.
And actually this word unable sounds a lot more polite and a lot more formal than saying I can't.
That's right. And that's why we use it on messages like this because it is so polite and so nice.
That's right. All right. So that's all the time we have for Fluency Builder. Let's take a
listen to our dialogue one last time.
Can you help me set up my voicemail message? I just got the service and I'm not really sure what I'm supposed
to say. Sure. You just basically got to let the caller know who they called and asked them for
the contact information so you can call them back. Okay. So I can say this is Abby's voicemail.
I will call you later so leave me your name and number. That's more or less the idea. But try
something that sounds more friendly. Okay. So how about this? This is Abby and I'm really happy you
called. I promise I will give you a ring as soon as I can. So please leave me your name and number.