Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a wild lesson for you at the elementary level.
That's right, we are actually going to visit a farm.
So yeah, it's going to be fun. We're going to see a lot of animals.
And not only that, but we're going to learn a lot of interesting words and phrases in English today.
But before we get started, let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview.
Well, McDonald had a farm.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What?
You had a duck.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We're not going to be teaching you this song today.
Don't worry.
You don't have to listen to us saying,
we do have a great word to start us off.
It's called the word is country.
The country.
Okay, so you know country as like the United States,
Mexico, Mexico, China, etc.
But in this case, we are going out to the country.
Not out of the country.
We're going out to the country.
To the country, okay, the country, or you might hear the countryside,
is is a place that's not like a city.
Right.
So it's the opposite of city.
It means there's lots of grass.
It's very natural.
There are very, very few houses and people.
It's very quiet.
So it's the opposite of a busy city.
Right.
And you have a lot of animals.
So usually farms are found on the countryside or at the countryside.
In the countryside.
So usually farms are found in the countryside.
That's right.
And I personally am a big fan because it's so quiet and peaceful.
Very good.
We can talk about that in a minute.
Let's listen to today's dialogue first.
And then we'll be back to talk about some of the words and phrases.
Isn't this great?
I always wanted to own a farm, live out in the country, grow my own food.
This is very beautiful.
Though I have to confess, I don't know the first thing about farming.
That's fine.
Don't worry about it.
What was that?
Relax.
It was just a goat.
And that?
It's just the cows that are grazing over there.
We can milk them later.
What was that?
Honey, seriously.
It's just a sheep.
The lacks.
Relax.
That was just the horses and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what?
I don't think I can hack it out here in the countryside.
I'm going back to the city.
Alright, we're back.
So obviously, some people cannot go to the countryside.
That's right.
Some people get very, very upset.
In fact, there was a whole TV show in America that was about city people living in the countryside.
And the country.
And they can do it, right?
That's right.
But before we talk about that, why don't we take a look at four keywords in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
The first word is the name of an animal.
Okay, so you've all heard of cows.
But have you heard of goats?
A goat.
Alright, so a goat is a strange looking animal.
It's kind of skinny and what do you get from a goat?
You can actually drink goat's milk.
And many people like to eat goat's cheese, which is cheese made from goat's milk.
Okay, so a goat, can you?
And we heard that the sound that a goat makes.
So I think it's pretty clear what a goat is.
And they're very common as we say in farms such as sheep and horses, cows, etc.
That's right, and normally when they're in the wild, they like to live in rocky places,
like mountains.
Right, that's why they say they're very good climbers because they don't fall.
True.
The mountains.
Alright, and well, if you have cows, then they're probably going to be grazing.
Okay, so two grays is a verb.
It's something we do.
Well, we people don't do it.
Animals do it.
Way for us to describe how animals like cows eat.
Means to eat grass.
Okay, so if your cows or horses are grazing, that means they're eating grass somewhere
out.
That's right, they're walking, they stop, they eat some grass, they walk, they stop again.
It's very slow process.
Alright, so cows are usually grazing out in the countryside.
And, well, once they finish grazing and they get all fat, then in the mornings, you have
to milk them.
Okay, so we drink milk, milk is a thing, but it's also a verb.
So two milk something.
Alright, and if you milk a cow is when you extract the milk, the liquid from them.
Right.
That's right, so underneath a cow, there's an utter, or there are uneath a cow, there
are utteres, which you have to squeeze with your hands to make the milk come out.
Okay, interesting word as well, utter.
Like that big bag full of milk.
Exactly, so two milk a cow.
Alright, and you have cows out in the fields grazing and probably your horses and donkeys
are going to be in the stable.
The stable is a place, okay, so this is something that's often found on farms, where
the horses or the cows live.
It's a structure, it's a building for those animals.
Okay, so they're probably separated in different little rooms or compartments and that's
called a stable.
So as you say, usually find horses and cows and donkeys in there.
That's right, so stable is a way to protect animals from the weather.
Alright, very good, so four key words there as we just saw.
Why don't we listen to this dialogue again and we'll be back soon.
Isn't this great?
I always wanted to own a farm, live out in the country, grow my own food.
This is very beautiful.
Although I have to confess, I don't know the first thing about farming.
That's fine, don't worry about it.
What was that?
Relax, it was just a goat.
And that?
It's just the cows that are grazing over there.
We can milk them later.
What was that?
Honey, seriously, it's just a sheep, relax.
Relax, that was just the horses and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what, I don't think I can hack it out here in the countryside.
I'm going back to the city.
Alright, we're back, so now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
You know, Marco, I have to confess.
I love Fluency Builder.
Alright, and that's our first phrase for today.
I have to confess.
Okay, so to confess is to tell someone something that's a secret.
Okay, so we can confess with a priest.
No.
I can confess to a priest.
We can confess a secret to a friend.
Okay.
But I have to confess as a very common phrase.
It's a way for us to start a sentence.
I have to confess.
Right, so you're saying I have to be honest with you.
I have to tell you the truth.
Exactly, so I have to confess.
I'm not a huge fan of that sweater.
Okay.
So I have to be honest.
I really don't like your sweater.
This is a way for us to be more polite when we're saying something that's negative.
And in this case, it was a girl who was confessing and what she confessed is her second
key phrase.
I don't know the first thing about farming.
Okay, so I don't know anything about farming is another way we could say this, or
I don't know a thing about farming, but I don't know the first thing about farming means
I don't even understand what a farm is.
Okay, the first thing is what is a farm?
I don't even understand what a farm is for.
This is a way for us to say I don't know anything at all.
All about this.
And if we change the noun, right, and we can say for example, I don't know the first thing
about cars.
So I have no idea what models they are or what type of engine they have.
I don't know the first thing about cars.
All I know is how to turn them on.
Right?
Or I don't know the first thing about wines.
I'd love to learn about wine, but I don't know the first thing about it.
Okay, so it's a phrase that you can use with many, many different nouns.
I don't know the first thing about architecture.
I don't know the first thing about English.
Right, well, we do a little bit of that so we're here to help you, but this is a really
great phrase to describe not understanding anything at all about something.
Right.
So this is a really great way to describe not knowing anything at all about something.
Okay, and well, obviously, since she didn't know the first thing about farming, she ended
up leaving and she said, you know what?
I don't think I can hack it out here in the countryside.
Okay, so I can hack it.
He can't hack it.
We use this with the verb to be able to.
And it means I don't think I can do this.
I think this is too hard.
Or maybe if somebody quit right after a week at the office and you can say he can hack
it.
He can hack the pressure and he left.
Exactly.
So that means to handle or to be able to handle or to withstand.
So I just don't think I can hack the cold.
Right, I can't handle the cold.
It's too cold here.
I'm moving somewhere warm.
All right, so I'm sure you guys will be able to hack our dialogue one last time.
So let's listen to it and we'll be back.
Isn't this great?
I always wanted to own a farm, live out in the country, grow my own food.
This is very beautiful.
So I have to confess, I don't know the first thing about farming.
That's fine.
Don't worry about it.
What was that?
Relax.
It was just a goat.
And that?
It's just the cows that are grazing over there.
We can milk them later.
What was that?
Honey, seriously.
It's just a sheep.
The lacks.
Relax.
Yes, the horses and donkeys that are in the stable.
You know what?
I don't think I can hack it out here in the countryside.
I'm going back to the city.
All right, we're back.
So as you said, you're a fan of the countryside and about farming, right?
That's right.
Well, I wish I knew more about farming.
I don't know the first thing about milking a cow.
But I do come from a part of the world in Illinois near Chicago where we have a lot of
farms and I appreciate the quiet.
And it's nice.
I'll have animals around and being able to go on long walks without cars and horns and bicycles.
It is actually a little bit refreshing to be out in the countryside sometimes and not even
have internet or cell phone coverage or anything.
So it's just basically you can't do anything else but relax, read a book, talk to people.
Exactly.
Now an interesting thing about this is a lot of people take for granted the countryside
because I've met many people who live in the city who grew up in the city and have never
seen for example a life chicken.
And when they see it, they just freak out and take pictures with the chicken or a cow or
something that's amazing.
That's really funny.
Well, I think it's very valuable.
I think they're very valuable skills that you learn being out in the countryside like
how to cook for yourself.
There's no one else who can cook for you or how to get food from animals.
Or maybe you can't even use a microwave.
So how do you cook without a microwave or something?
That's right.
I think the biggest problem for city people when they come to the countryside is that it's
dirtier.
You know, you get mud in their bugs and I imagine some of our co-workers here having a
very hard time in the countryside.
Yes indeed.
So why don't you guys come to our website EnglishPod.com?
Let us know what you think about this.
Maybe you're very familiar with the countryside or have a relative who's a farmer.
It's great.
Visit us in EnglishPod.com and if you have any questions or comments, you can leave them
there as well.
Can't wait to hear from you.
Happy studies, bye, everybody.
Bye.