Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and we've got a great lesson for you today. What level is this?
This is an elementary lesson and we're going to be touching one of these medical topics.
Today we're going to talk about chickenpox.
Gosh, I hated the chickenpox. They're horrible and they each and you can't do anything about it and your parents say don't scratch.
So chickenpox is a illness that you get usually as a child.
And what happens is you start getting these little red dots all over your body, like little mosquito bites.
Exactly and they come all over your body. Arms, legs, face.
And you can only get this disease once unless maybe you didn't really get it too seriously.
So most people get this one there, children.
Exactly and what makes you very uncomfortable when you get chickenpox, as you said, it's these little red dots.
They itch just like mosquito bites, but you can't scratch because if you do, then you get your skin gets like marked right you have like,
Parents ever for it like scars.
So it's best not to scratch.
And that's what we're going to talk about today. Somebody has the chickenpox.
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and then we'll be right back.
What's wrong with you? Why are you scratching so much?
I feel itchy. I can't stand anymore.
I think I may be coming down with something. I feel like headed in Leek.
Let me have a look.
Whoa, get away from me.
What's wrong?
I think you have chickenpox. You're contagious.
Get away. Don't break it on me.
Maybe it's just a rash or an allergy.
We can't be sure and die see a doctor.
Well, in the meantime, you're a biohazard. I didn't get it when I was a kid and I heard that you can even die if you get it as an adult.
Are you serious? You always bloat things out of proportion. In any case, I think I'll go take an oatmeal bath.
Ew.
All right, we're back. So I think this kid does have the chickenpox.
Definitely. And well, he's got a funny solution for it.
Before we get there, we've got a lot of great medical words.
It's not just basic body words for you and today's language to take away.
Language takeaway.
All right, so let's start with our first word.
He mentioned that he felt itchy. I feel itchy.
Itchy. So, okay. This is often confused.
Even among children who are native speakers of English,
they're two words to itch and to scratch.
This person is itchy. So it means that your skin, you want to scratch it.
It's maybe uncomfortable.
Like a mosquito bite is itchy.
Okay. So itchy would be the adjective, right?
To the noun and itch. So if you have an itch, you feel itchy, right?
Exactly.
So, and that's when you scratch.
All right, so he feels itchy.
And he also felt a little bit lightheaded.
Okay. So, you know the word head. You know the word light.
So here we have a person who feels lightheaded.
It means that you kind of feel a little bit strange.
And your head is a little bit, well, what's a good word to describe it?
Yeah, almost dizzy or faint.
Right. So, you usually feel a little bit weak.
You don't really feel very well. Your head is lightheaded.
The complete opposite of having a headache, right?
Exactly.
Okay. And well, then the girl got scared.
And she said, get away. You are contagious.
Oh gosh. Now this is a dangerous one.
Someone who is contagious can pass their illness to someone else.
So, for example, the flu is very contagious.
And if I have the flu, Marko doesn't want me to, you know, come over and touch all this stuff and sneeze and cough into his food.
Right.
Exactly. So that's contagious.
It's an adjective and that means that you easily pass your illness to another person.
Exactly.
All right. So why don't we take a look at a couple of different examples using this word contagious?
Example one.
Don't get near me. Chickenpox are very contagious.
Example two.
The sickness that is going around the office is very contagious.
Example three.
Each one in one flu is very contagious.
All right. So you want to avoid contagious people, but you might also want to avoid people who have this next word.
It's called a rash.
A rash.
Exactly. So why do you want to avoid people who have a rash?
Well, they might have contagious rash.
Who knows.
But you can get a rash for a number of different reasons.
A rash is just basically a part of your skin that becomes irritated or uncomfortable.
And sometimes it turns red or pink.
Exactly.
So as you said, it happens for different reasons.
Sometimes you may be have bad seafood and your skin and you have, you start to have rash is all over your body.
Other times you can touch some plants that are dangerous like poison, ivy or poison oak.
And then you get a big rash.
And our last word for today is a little bit dramatic.
He called him a biohazard.
Biohazard. Well, let's take a look at these words individually.
The first word bio comes from the word biology.
So that's something that is life, an animal, plant or person.
And hazard is something that is dangerous.
So biohazard is a, well, something that's alive that's dangerous.
Right.
Or that's dangerous towards a living person, right?
Or organism.
For example, you don't want to be near an area that has a lot of radiation.
It's a biohazard.
Exactly.
Or some of these diseases like Ebola virus.
These are very dangerous towards living things.
And so biohazard is the name for.
Exactly.
And usually it's, there's a symbol, a very clear symbol that kind of looks like a triangle and it's red.
And even in movies, it's appeared right.
I think in that movie.
Yellow.
It's red or yellow.
Yes.
And that's blue.
All right. So biohazard.
I think we've taken a look at a lot of words.
So why don't we listen to this dialogue again.
Let's slow it down a little bit.
See if we can understand a little bit more.
What's wrong with you?
Why are you scratching so much?
I feel itchy.
I can't stand it anymore.
I think I may be coming down with something.
I feel like headed in a week.
Let me have a look.
Whoa.
Get away from me.
What's wrong?
I think you have the chickenpox.
Your contagious.
Get away.
Don't breathe on me.
Maybe it's still the rash or an allergy.
We can't be sure until I see a doctor.
Well, in the meantime, you are a biohazard.
I didn't get it when I was a kid.
And I've heard that you can even die if you get it as an adult.
Are you serious?
You always blow things out of proportion.
In any case, I think I'll go take an oatmeal bath.
You.
All right.
We're back.
So now why don't we take a look at fluency builder and start taking a look at all these phrases.
Fluency builder.
Well, the first one is something that we often say when we're starting to feel ill.
This phrase is coming down with.
So I could say, I think I'm coming down with a cold, for example.
So basically, you say I'm coming down with something.
So a cold or I think I'm coming down with the flu.
So you're saying that I think I'm getting ill.
Exactly.
It means I'm just starting to feel sick.
And so you could say, I've had a cold for a week.
You wouldn't use the phrase.
I'm coming down with the last situation.
You don't only use it when you're starting to feel sick.
Very good.
So you could ask your boss, eh, I think I'm coming down with the flu.
Can I go home early?
Right.
And I think this is a very useful phrase.
It's very natural to say.
So why don't we listen to a couple of other examples?
Example one.
Honey, really take my temperature.
I think I'm coming down with something.
Example two.
You must be coming down with a cold.
Example three.
Tommy came down with a flu.
All right.
So coming down with coming down with the flu, coming down with a cough, et cetera.
What's our next phrase?
Well, this one's great.
It's a filler phrase.
So in the meantime.
In the meantime.
So I could say, all right.
I'm going to go cook dinner.
In the meantime, Marco, can you please clear the table?
Okay.
So while you are cooking dinner, I am doing something else.
I'm playing the table.
So two things happening at the same time.
In the meantime.
Very good.
So it's a filler you say.
Because usually it follows another phrase.
So I'm going to be doing this report for a while.
In the meantime, can you just wait here on the sofa, please?
Okay.
Very good.
So in the meantime, so you're connecting two different actions, two different ideas.
Exactly.
Very good.
In the meantime.
And what about our last phrase?
All right.
There are some people who really like to do this.
Uh-huh.
And I might be one of them.
It's called it to blow things out of proportion.
All right.
And you're going to hear this phrase a lot with native English speakers.
But to blow things out of proportion.
Well, pretty much means that you're exaggerating or you're making a really big deal out of something that's not very serious.
So for example, if you come over to my house and you break a glass and I start freaking out and yelling at you because you broke my glass.
I say, Marko, you're blowing things out of proportion.
I'll just buy you a new one.
It's not that serious.
All right.
So don't exaggerate, right?
Right.
Often times you feel like this with with with siblings spouses or bosses who react very seriously.
So you can say, hey, stop.
Stop yelling like you're blowing.
You're blowing things out of proportion.
This is not a really big deal.
Exactly.
All right.
So blowing things out of proportion.
Let's not do that.
But let's listen to our dialogue for the last time.
And then we'll be back.
What's wrong with you? Why are you splashing so much?
I feel itchy.
I can't stand it anymore.
I think I may be coming down with something.
I feel lightheaded and weak.
Let me have a look.
Whoa.
Get away from me.
What's wrong?
I think you have chicken packs.
You're contagious.
Get away.
Don't break it on me.
Maybe it's just a rash or an allergy.
We can't be sure and die.
See a doctor.
Well, in the meantime, you're a biohazard.
I didn't get it when I was a kid.
And I've heard that you can even die if you get it as an adult.
Are you serious?
You always blow things out of proportion.
In any case, I think I'll go take an oatmeal bath.
Ew.
All right. So Catherine, have you ever had the chicken packs?
I did. I have very, very clear memories of when I was a child.
And I had the chicken packs because I believe it was Thanksgiving.
And I was about four or five years old.
And I couldn't. I didn't have an appetite.
So I was not hungry.
And I like to do was itch and drink.
And so I still have little scars like you mentioned from where I couldn't stop myself.
I'm scratching my, my little marks.
Right.
And well, why does this little boy say that he's going to go take a oatmeal bath?
And oatmeal bath. Okay. Well, this is one of the home remedies.
One of the home cures for the itchiness.
All right. So it doesn't make your chicken packs go away.
But it does make your skin feel better because it's very calming and smooth.
So you can have some creams or some lotions, but other other people like to take an oatmeal bath.
Right. So then you're not itching anymore.
Right. But it's gross because you're sitting in an oatmeal.
It is kind of gross.
Have you had the chicken box?
I did. I didn't know.
But because I couldn't remember. So I actually my brother had it recently.
So I was afraid that I didn't get it. But call my mom. She said I got it.
So I'm good.
You're safe.
Yeah. So that's the thing. Right. You can only get it once.
So once you get it, you don't have a problem.
Well, we're curious to know. Have you had the chicken box?
And if you did, was it was it really itchy or were you a lucky one?
And it wasn't so bad. So let us know when I was citing.
Pushpot.com.
Right. And if you ever had any other common childhood illnesses like the
months or the measles, right? You can also tell us about that.
So we'll see you guys there. And until next time.
Bye. Bye.