Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're tackling a very difficult issue for many English learners.
We're talking about taking things from other people and giving them back.
That's right. So today we are going to talk about money and we're going to lend money and
borrow money. We're going to talk more about this after we listen to the dialogue.
Can I borrow five books? No. Come on. I'll pay you back on Tuesday.
Last time I went to your money you never paid me back. I promise if you let me $5 today. I will
repay you in full next week. Okay, but I'm taking your skateboard as collateral. Fine.
Can't believe you don't trust me. It's nothing personal. Just business.
Alright so now let's take a look at that language on language takeaway.
So first up we have the key verbs for today. The verb to borrow and to lend.
Right. Now this is a really important difference to make because many people make this mistake
where they use the wrong verb. Now if I ask you Marco, can I borrow your bicycle?
That means can I take your bicycle from you and then later I'll give it back.
But I want to use it. Right. So the verb is kind of reflexive. It's going on to you. You want to borrow.
Right. I want to borrow. I want to take it from you for a short time and then I want to give it back. So to borrow.
Right. Now the other verb is to lend and then on the other hand goes from me to you. So you borrow my
bicycle. I lend you my bicycle. I give it to you. That's right. So another way of asking
can I borrow is can you lend me? Right. Your bike. That means can you act? Can you do this thing for me?
So there's two of different ways of saying it and it's very important to remember who is doing what?
Exactly. So remember the person taking is borrowing. The person giving is lending. So it's not
correct and remember to and it's not correct to say can you borrow me your bicycle?
That's not right. Now can you lend me like can you lend me a hand? Can you help me?
Right. So remember this to borrow is something I do. I want to borrow from you.
It's the person the subject in the sentence but in the case of lending someone else is doing it. So can you lend
to me or can you lend it to him? You have to say who it's being lent to? Exactly. And as you said
who it's being lent to? So the past tense of lend is lent. Yeah. So Marco lent me his bike last week
and I broke it. So now I have to pay him a lot of money. You have to pay me five bucks and that's
that our next word. Books. Now this is a slang term. So this is something we say very casually in
America when we want to talk about dollars. Right. So one book is one dollar. A hundred bucks is
a hundred dollars. All right. Now as you say it's very American you wouldn't really use it like
I don't know if you're in Britain you wouldn't say a hundred bucks. No you would say quid quid. Exactly.
So they don't have dollars so they don't say bucks not in England. All right. Very good. So we
wanted to borrow five dollars and well he's and that person promised to pay you back on Tuesday. I'll
pay you back on Tuesday. All right. So this is a lot like that verb to lend to lend him to pay you.
You have to say who you're going to pay. Right. So Marco I'm sorry about your bicycle. I will pay
you back tomorrow. Okay. That means I will give you money for it tomorrow. So if you borrow money
you have to pay it back. All right. So I want to borrow five dollars. I promise I will pay you back
Thursday. Very good. Okay. And now lastly we will lend money but of course we need to guarantee
we need something to make sure that you will pay me back. So that's called collateral. All right.
Now collateral is important because sometimes you can't you can't trust someone like you say Marco.
And so for example if I want to rent a bicycle so I want to use it for the day maybe there's a
store that they rent bicycles to people. I would give my passport or my driver's license as collateral
because I will definitely return to take my that driver's license or passport back. So that's that's
basically a sign of a promise money or identification or some object. That's right. So usually for
example if you're going to get a very big loan at the bank they will ask you for something as collateral
so maybe you will have to give them your house as collateral. So you're saying if I can't pay you back
then you can take my house. That's right. So collateral is the last word in language take away but
we do have some great phrases for you coming up in fluency builder.
Can I borrow five bucks? No. Come on. I'll pay you back on Tuesday. Last time I went to your money
you never paid me back. I promise if you let me five dollars today I will repay you in full next week.
Okay but I'm taking your skateboard as collateral. Fine. Can't believe you don't trust me.
It's nothing personal. Just business.
All right we're back so let's take a look at these phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So Mark are these are two friends talking and the way they talk to each other is very casual.
Right. So we hear at the beginning can I borrow five bucks? No. Come on.
Right. So what does this come on? It's a persuasive phrase. It's one of those phrases where you're
trying to convince or persuade Pete and you can use it as an interjection in many situations.
So for example here come on. Lend it to me. Lend me some money. I'll pay you back. You're trying to
convince that please. Exactly. But what about this situation? I'm running late. I have to go and my friend
she's still sitting at her desk maybe at work and just taking forever. I say come on let's go.
Right it's like hurry up move it. All right so it's a way of getting someone to do something.
You want them to follow you. Exactly. And now talking about money again the person promise to
repay the money. He said I'll pay you back on Tuesday. But then it also said I will repay you
in full next week. In full now remember this is important. I will repay you in full. That means
I won't repay you a little bit and then a little bit later. I will repay you everything next week.
Right exactly. So if you have to pay or repay someone in full you have to give them the entire
amount and that just a part of it. That's right in full full means everything. And the final
phrase is the very last line of today's dialogue. It's nothing personal. It's just business.
I think this is a common phrase when the people use when maybe doing business with friends or people
you know you know maybe you're asking for collateral and the guys like I can't believe you don't trust
me and I'm your brother and she's like it's nothing personal. It's just business. It's a way to say
listen. This is not about you and me. This is about my rules. When I give something to someone I always
ask for collateral. So it's just business. It's just my way of doing this. Exactly. So it's a good phrase
to use if you're doing maybe business with a friend and of course maybe you're setting these rules
and the friend maybe your friend feels a little bit offended. You say hey it's nothing personal. It's
just business. Nothing personal. So as the last phrase let's take a listen to the dialogue again.
I will be right back.
Can I borrow five books? No. Come on. I'll pay you back on Tuesday. Last time I went to you
minute you never paid me back. I promise if you let me five dollars today I will repay you in full
next week. Okay, but I'm taking your skateboard as collateral. Fine. I can't believe you don't trust
me. It's nothing personal. Just business.
All right. So lending money borrowing money now as you as we mentioned sometimes you have people
that ask you for money now. Did you ever have that friend that always ask you for money and never
repay you? Yes. Like a dollar at a time like a dollar or a dollar or a dollar or a dollar or five dollars.
Yeah, always and actually this friend he would borrow ten dollars and he would say oh I'll buy
your coffee tomorrow. I say what a ten dollar coffee? I don't think so. So it was always uneven. I paid
more and he never repayed me in full. Yeah and actually I think if you add up all those little
amount of money that maybe some friends borrowed for you would be a quite a decent amount. I had many
friends who would be like hey can I have a dollar or you know even like 25 cents at a time.
It would add up over ten. After a couple years? Yeah, that's that's like a whole dinner exactly.
So what do you call these people? The word in English that's a slang word is called a mooch.
A mooch, right? He's a mooch. It means he's always taking money from people or asking other people
to pay for his dinner or staying at someone's house. So a mooch is someone who tries to get
things for free. Right. That's exactly it. I had friends like this that would for food as well. Like
maybe I brought my lunch. This is in school obviously and they would mooch off me like half my
sandwich or have my cheese. Can I have some chips? Can I have some cheese? Exactly. That's yeah,
that's mooch behavior. So that's the verb to mooch off someone. Yeah, to mooch off someone but it's
also a noun. He's a mooch. He's a mooch. Very interesting stuff. Maybe you have a friend that was a
mooch or maybe even yourself back in the day. So let us know how it works in your country. If you
lend money to people, family members, do you ask for collateral? Or do you just forget about it?
Let us know our website is englishpod.com. We'll see you guys there. Bye.