Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today
we're going to continue in our series about job interviews. That's right. And on this occasion
we're taking a look at part five or an interview series where we explain why we left our previous job.
Okay and so in an interview this is a very popular question. Why did you leave your last job?
Learn some tools for answering this question in today's dialogue. We're going to take a listen to it
first and we'll be back in a moment.
Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job. I see you spent almost four years at the
London weekly. Is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest the first year was quite tough for me.
I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it
quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor
liked me so he promoted me to Features writer. Wow a real step up. Yes I was responsible for
restaurant and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position but to be honest it wasn't
an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why did you decide to leave finally?
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities. I really needed a more
challenging role to be honest. All right we're back and as we saw Rebecca handled it quite well
explaining why you left your last job because obviously you don't want to say something like
I just really didn't like my company or you know the boss was a really bad guy.
Or I was fired for being lazy. Exactly. So I don't we take a look at a couple of different words
on language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay so we've got some great descriptive words here.
These are some adjectives. The first one is tough. So Rebecca said to be honest the first year
was quite tough for me. All right so she's describing that her first year at that company where she was
working it was tough and that means hard. Difficult. That's right so you could say this is a really
tough situation. I mean it's it's a difficult situation. It's hard because there's no easy answer.
Exactly so if you describe something as tough it means that it's very difficult. Now there is
another meaning to this where it can be that you are a strong person. Right so that's different
because we're talking about a person not a situation but if you're talking about a job or an experience
or even homework like this homework is really tough it means that it's very hard. Exactly. Well
apart from her job of being a little bit tough she said that it was also a little bit frustrating.
Okay so usually these things go together. If something is tough like it's difficult it's usually
frustrating too. And so in this case something is frustrating when it makes you unhappy or for example
it makes you feel stressed. So something that's frustrating is not a good thing. Exactly so as you
gave the example with the homework assignment if you have maybe a math assignment that's very
difficult and you can't solve it you don't find the solution then you get frustrated you get maybe
angry at yourself or you get very angry for not being able to solve it so that's when you
when it's something is frustrating. I hate being frustrated. Exactly well it's not a nice feeling but
she said that well it was frustrating it was tough but you know after a while I proved myself.
Okay so that means that she was able to show someone that she can handle
difficult things, difficult work, difficult situations and so she said I proved myself and the new
editor liked me so basically she did a really good job. Exactly so if you prove yourself you're
showing someone that you have great ability or capabilities of solving a problem or being able to
handle a difficult job. That's right for example I could say you know last year Bob didn't do very
well at school but this year he really proved himself he studied hard and he got really good grades.
Exactly and well Rebecca what she got in exchange for proving herself she got promoted.
This is great so promotions are good things the verb here is to promote or to be promoted so in
this case she was promoted you could say last year I was promoted or he will be promoted next week
he doesn't know yet. Exactly now remember that to be promoted means to get a better position in
your job. Now as we mentioned the verb is to promote and you may be asking yourself why you're using
the verb to be in the past was promoted and this is because it's an ED adjective it's an adjective
that's ends in ED so you may think it's a verb but it's not it's actually an adjective.
The verb here is to be. Exactly so I was promoted was is obviously our verb here the verb to be
but promoted is an adjective that ends in ED. Okay and so if I'm the boss the action I do the
verb I do is I promote someone so this can be a little bit tricky but we recommend that you
check out the website for more details because we have lots of examples of how to use this. Exactly
well she got promoted and well she was really happy for a while but then she said you know what I
really needed a more challenging role a more challenging job. Okay challenging is a great adjective it
means something is difficult or it gives you a challenge so that means it's not easy.
Mm-hmm yeah so she found that her job was a little bit too easy so she wanted something a little
bit more challenging. Okay and so this is a really great word for job interviews in particular
because you're basically saying I want hard work. I want to prove myself that we go again prove.
I want to show you that I'm a good employee or hard worker and so I want a challenge something that's
hard. Exactly so uh is something that is hard is a challenge or you want something challenging.
So why don't we review these words that we've taken a look at now let's go back to the dialogue
and listen to it again.
Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job. I see you spent almost four
years at the London Weekly is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest the first year was quite
tough for me. I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have many responsibilities
and I found it quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new
editor liked me so he promoted me to features writer. Wow a real step up.
Yes I was responsible for restaurant and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position
but to be honest it wasn't an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why
did you decide to leave finally? I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities.
I really needed a more challenging role to be honest.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of phrases we picked out for you on
fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase is unusual because it actually
happens at the end of sentences. This is very very common with people who are making small
talk or who are doing interviews. This is the phrase is that right. So basically you saw that in the
first line Mr. Parsons was talking to her and said well I see you spent almost four years at the
London weekly is that right? So he's ending the sentence with this phrase. So he's making the sentence
a question. I see that you did this is that right? So he's asking her to confirm the fact that he
knows about her because maybe they've never really talked before so this is a good way for him to ask her
to give more details. Exactly. So for example Marco I hear that you're from Ecuador is that right?
That's right. So apart from ending the sentence like this if maybe somebody asks you is that right?
You have to confirm you have to say yes that's right or yes. It's also good to elaborate to
give more details. Yes I'm from Ecuador I was born there but I've lived in the United States.
This is a way to give more information because that's basically what the person's asking.
Yeah I think it wouldn't be very good if you're at a job interview and the person says is that right
and you say yes that's right and then you don't say anything else. So yeah the basically the point is
you have to confirm or deny it to say yes that's right or no that's not right and then you have to
give some information about the question. Exactly. All right now moving on when Rebecca again was
talking about her job she was saying it's tough and I didn't have many responsibilities and they
found it quite frustrating. Okay so this is like lost and found like I lost my hat and I found it later
no no this is what's interesting about this verb find we are not actually looking for something
or we didn't actually find something we were looking for. This is kind of a realization right?
That's right it's like a feeling. So I find this movie boring. That means I think this movie is
boring. It's the way that you're thinking about something. That's right or you can say I found
Paris to be quite an expensive city. Yeah pretty expensive so this is your impression this is the
way that you feel about something. Exactly so this is another way that you can use this word to find.
Now again when Rebecca talked about proving herself she used a very interesting I would say phrase
a very popular well known phrase slowly but surely. Okay so slowly but surely is the opposite
of right away. So something that happens right away is immediate like I got promoted right away
but slowly but surely means after lots of time and even hard work this good thing happened or
it's usually a good thing actually. Yeah yeah it's you're basically saying that you didn't do anything
very quickly but you did it very well so slowly but surely I finished building my home.
Right so it didn't happen overnight but it did happen over time. You can also say it's about studying
a language. You know at the beginning learning English was really hard but slowly but surely I
became fluent. Exactly okay so slowly but surely and the last phrase that we have for you today
you may have seen that Rebecca used this phrase to be honest a couple of times before
explaining something so why does she say to be honest? To be honest is sometimes something we
say in English to fill some space or some time we call it filler but it's also a way to
introduce something that's negative. So for example in this dialogue she's talking about her
negative experiences you know my job was tough my experience was bad so she says to be honest
it wasn't the best experience but I learned from it. She's saying this to introduce some things that
are maybe not positive not happy things. That's right so it's another way of saying look I'm going
to tell you the truth and it may not be something positive but you know this is what happened so to be honest
I didn't really like my last employer or something like that. Right we can even talk about this
to your friends so hey Marco did you like that movie, shutter island? To be honest I didn't really see it.
Oh fell asleep. Or you could say to be honest I didn't love it I didn't really like it.
Exactly so it's a very it's a very good phrase but don't overuse it I think sometimes
you get into the habit of using it all the time and just like like you know like I went to the
movies like yesterday like and like to be honest like so try to keep these fillers as you describe them
to a minimum so don't really use them too much. Yes say thoughts and ideas nice action verbs not too
much fillers because sometimes especially in an interview it makes people think that you don't really
know much to say. Yeah exactly okay so let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll
we'll be back to chat a little bit more. Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job.
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest
the first year was quite tough for me. I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have
many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved
myself and the new editor liked me so he promoted me to Features writer. Wow I real step up.
Yes I was responsible for restaurant and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position
but to be honest it wasn't an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why do
you decide to leave finally? I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities.
I really needed a more challenging role to be honest.
All right so talking about your last employer this is a pretty ideal thing and now do you have any
advice that you can give our listeners about describing your last job? Why did you leave your previous
well I do have a little bit of basic job advice. I would say don't complain about your last
employer. Don't say my boss was mean, my co-workers were lazy, my company was terrible because
usually as a as a person doing an interview that makes you think that this person if they work for you
will complain about you and so I think it's important like what Rebecca does in this dialogue to keep
positive. Every negative situation can become a positive experience so the job was tough but
it was a good challenge right or but she learned how to do many new things exactly. I think this
is important for anybody in any language but an English especially to use some of these phrases
and to say you know I really like a challenge or I didn't feel this was challenging enough
things like this as opposed to my old boss so mean he may be working on a weekend that company is
so terrible. I mean that kind of stuff no one wants to hear. Yeah exactly and I think it's not really
useful because even if the company is the competitor so you're really getting the extra points
for forgetting them like the dirty secrets of what was going on the company may be saying oh my co-workers
they were just so mean to me and stuff like this. Yeah no it makes you seem like a complainer and no
one wants to hire a complainer. Exactly all right so this is an interesting topic we would like
to hear from you so come to English.com and tell us why did you leave your previous employer or just
let us know about some of your interview experiences or some of your interview questions. We're
happy to help you out. We'll hope to see you at the website. All right we'll see you there. Bye.