Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and Marco. I can tell you right now. I'm already hungry just thinking about our lesson today.
That's right. Today we have another food lesson. Our world cuisine lesson for today is all about Mexican food.
Okay, Mexican food comes from the country Mexico but also parts of the United States.
Like Texas has something called Tex Mex. So you're going to hear a lot about these kinds of foods there.
Let's check out today's dialogue.
Hello sir. Welcome to Pistolera Restaurant. May I take you order?
Yes. I would like the chicken cheese and chilados with a side of guacamole.
Sorry sir but we ran out of chicken. May I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese case?
Both include a side of guacamole and jalapenos.
Sure, I'll have the burrito. Do you have nachos? Of course sir. Our nachos come with melted cheese and chili.
Sounds good. Would you like anything drink? Sure, I'll have a corona.
All right we're back so a lot of great dishes from Mexico. Let's take a closer look at some of those on language takeaway.
Language takeaway
So first up Marco we have the word enchilada. That's right we have some chicken cheese and chilada. So this dish has
chicken and cheese but in enchilada what is that? Okay so it's basically a wrap that is covered in cheese, right?
That's right. So it has a base of a flower tortilla so a tortilla is like a wrap as you said.
Let's consider it as flat bread. Mm-hmm very thin and it rolls up and it's covered with cheese and
inside it has chicken very very good. That's right and just a warning you're going to hear me say the American
pronunciation enchilada and you're gonna hear Marcos say a more appropriate a little bit with a more Hispanic accent to it.
That's right so the second one we've got is guacamole.
Wacamole that's right we say guacamole and this is from the avocado fruit. That's right avocado's are green fruit.
They have a skin so you take the skin off and you usually mix guacamole with other ingredients.
Right it has a little bit of lemon on your tomato. Maybe a little spice. Really good stuff.
So yeah it comes from that fruit that you say and it's kind of like a paste right?
It's yeah it's something that we often use as a dip so I can dip my potato chips or my tortilla chips in it
or I can use it as a sauce. All right very good and our next and probably one of the most popular
dishes in the Mexican cuisine world is a beef burrito burrito. So burrito is another kind of rap.
We have a tortilla like you said earlier and inside there are many different things. So usually
some rice and some beans and some meat maybe beef or chicken. That's right so consider it kind of like a
a sandwich more or less. But in a blanket instead of in bread. Exactly in a blanket and then also we have cheese
casadillas. Now also these are made from the same blanket of tortilla. That's right so this thin tortilla
this flour tortilla is put on top and on bottom and inside you have some cheese some melted cheese
or other times you can have cheese and chicken and usually you find it it's a circle but it's cut into
four pieces so it looks like a pieces of a pie. That's right and actually what you do is you
heat it up in a pan so the cheese inside melts and it's very very delicious. It is and sometimes you
have this with a side of jalapeno. Okay this is a some type of vegetable I would guess. It's a pepper.
Right so this is a very very spicy pepper that people often use to make things taste hot. That's right
so you can see them they're usually green and they're very very spicy so if you bite into it'll it'll
burn your mouth. It will and sometimes people like to put these on our next dish what's the next dish
Marco? We have some nachos. Okay this is a classic Tex Mex dish like I was saying so a lot of
Americans love to eat this and nachos are basically a plate of tortilla chips with what on top.
Usually it has melted cheese and maybe some chili like we see in the dialogue so it will kind of
just consider a plate full of these chips kind of they look like potato chips but they're made out of
flour and on top a lot of cheese and maybe some meat or some chili on top. And Americans also
like to put sour cream on top. Oh yes sour cream is very popular on this dish. So a lot of dishes these
are probably the most popular ones that you can find at most Mexican restaurants and also in Tex Mex style
cuisine. So why don't we take another look at everything and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder.
Hello sir welcome to Pistolet restaurant may I take you order?
Yes I would like to chicken cheese and chilados with a side of guacamole. Sorry sir but we ran out of
chicken may I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese case ideas? Both include a side of guacamole and
jalapenos. Sure I'll have the burrito. Do you have nachos? Of course sir are nachos come with melted cheese and chili?
Sounds good would you like anything drink? Sure I'll have a corona.
Alright so Marko today we have only three things to talk about in fluency builder. The first one is
something that the waiter said to the customer. It was to run out of. That's right he wanted some chicken
cheese and chilados but unfortunately they ran out of chicken so the phrase over here is to run
out of. That's right and we heard the past tense so unfortunately we ran out of chicken this means that
we no longer have chicken we sold all of the chicken. That's right so for example if you're in your car
and all of a sudden you run out of gasoline it means your car will stop running. That's very bad
situation so to run out of means to not have anymore. That's right so you ran out of money maybe you
have no more money. Another bad situation. So instead he ordered a burrito that included a side of
wakamoli and jalapenos. Okay so the reason we included this is because it's important to remember
this as a phrase a side of. That's right. So this burrito comes with a side of guacamole or this
burrito has a side of beans. So a side of means a small portion a little bit. That's right the most
important part of a side of is that it doesn't come in the dish or inside the burrito let's say it
just comes separately on a separate little plate or it can come next to next to the main dish. So
if the main dish is tacos you can say I want tacos with a side of black beans you would get the
black beans in a little bowl next to but that's not the main thing. Exactly exactly so a side of
now for our last phrase when we talked about the nachos they came with melted cheese and chili so
what do we mean by they come with melted cheese and chili? Okay so this verb to come with means
that they have as a part of the dish. So this is not a side. Right. Not like before when we're
talking about a side of this means that in the case of nachos the nachos have on them on top cheese
and chili. That's right so sometimes if you go about a McDonald's and you buy a meal you get a burger
and the burger comes with french fries and a coke included in the meal or you can say
unfortunately this meal does not come with a drink so you have to order the drink extra. That's right.
Okay so a lot of great stuff let's take another look and we'll be right back.
Hello sir welcome to pistolet restaurant may I take you order?
Yes I would like the chicken cheese and chilados with a side of guacamole. Sorry sir but we ran out of
chicken may I suggest our delicious beef burritos or cheese case ideas? Both include a side of guacamole
and jalapenos. Sure I'll have the burrito. Do you have nachos? Of course sir are nachos come with melted
cheese and chili? Sounds good would you like anything drink? Sure I'll have a corona.
Alright so Mexican food very very delicious and as we see it has a lot of cheese and most dishes.
It does a lot of cheese and also a lot of tortillas so tortillas are these usually round
flats pancake like things they're not sweet they're savory and I usually put things in them like tacos
or fahias or burritos. That's right and there's two kinds right? That's right so you have tortillas that
are made from flour that are usually white and then you have corn tortillas that are made from corn and they're usually
a little bit more yellow. That's right so it's actually Mexican food is very very good but usually it's a
little bit spicy so if you don't really like a spicy food you should tell the waiter or waitress
to not make it spicy. That's right if you if you don't eat spicy food you certainly don't want to eat
any jalapeno peppers. That's right I'm actually not really a fan of spicy food so for example I really
cannot eat jalapeno peppers. See I'm the opposite I love spicy food so I often order green and
chiladas which have a spicy jalapeno green sauce. Yeah they're very very spicy so this is part of our
mini series that we have all about world foods we've already taken a look at Italian food we have
Mexican food next we'll be looking at Indian food Korean food a lot of great international foods coming
up. Yeah me so let us know do you like Mexican food have you ever had Mexican food and if we left off
some kind of Mexican food like tacos let us know that's right. Our website is englishpod.com we'll see you there.
All right bye.