Hello English learners, welcome back to English,
part of my name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we have another romantic lesson,
kind of romantic. A little romantic. We got a boyfriend and a girlfriend and they're apologizing
to each other. Okay, so it's a very common situation and we're going to be talking about love.
We're also going to talk about different pet names that are commonly used in English.
That are used with your boyfriend or girlfriend. Okay, very good. So let's listen to this dialogue
for the first time and see what's happening with her couple.
You
Can we talk? Sure, honey. We're talking now, aren't we? You know what I mean. Yeah, I know.
I want to know where this relationship is going. I mean, love with you. And I need to know
you know, I think you're awesome. I'm awesome. Well, I guess that's my answer, isn't it? Honey,
look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing, all right? We've had our laughs, but I don't
appreciate, well, maybe it's just time we. Baby, I love you so much. You do? I love you. And I think
you're awesome. Oh, I love you too. Come on, put the gun down. Oh, baby. I'm so sorry.
Okay, so romantic and dramatic. Yeah, I think she really needed to hear that. Right, so I think
she really wanted to hear. I love you. Yeah, that's right. And there's some interesting phrases here
in this in this dialogue. And today we're going to focus mostly on phrases. So why don't we start
with fluency builder? Fluency builder. Okay, on fluency builder today, we're going to take a look
at some of these phrases. And the first one is very important and very different. So obviously,
this dialogue is about love. And we heard two different ways that this word is used. And the first
one is to love someone. Right. So he said, I love you. Yeah, I love you. We all pretty much
understand what that means. Right. But they also mentioned to be in love with someone. Okay, so
he said, I am in love with you. I'm in love with you. In love. Okay, so what's the difference between
two love and to be in love? To be in love with someone means that you have these strong romantic
feelings towards somebody. That's right. So you can only be in love with your boyfriend,
your girlfriend, your husband or your wife. So you can love your parents. You can love your family,
but you can be in love with them. You can only be in love with your girlfriend, boyfriend,
husband, wife. That's right. Okay. So moving on to the next phrase. Now the girl asked her boyfriend,
can we talk? Can we talk? Can we talk? This is a very simple sentence. Right. We know the meaning,
but why does she say can we talk? Okay, so you use this when you want to start a conversation about
something serious. Okay, so if you wanted to talk to me about my new shirt, I wouldn't ask,
I wouldn't say, hey, Marco, can we talk? Oh, I really like your shirt. What'd you get it?
Exactly, right? So it has to be serious. So usually if somebody says, hey, can we talk?
It means that there's going to be a serious topic. Yeah, it's going to be probably bad news. Maybe that's
yes. So can we talk? So if your boyfriend or girlfriend tells you this, well, it's not a good sign.
That's right. All right. And the last phrase that we have on fluency builder,
you know what I mean. You know what I mean. You know what I mean. You know what I mean.
You know what I mean. All right. So again, this phrase is very simple to understand, right? That's right.
So you know what I'm talking about. You you understand me. But the interesting thing is that
we can also make it a question. And it's all about the change in tone. Okay, so with this in
mind, let's listen to two examples of the same phrase, but with different tones, and you try to see
which one is the question? Example one. I'm tired of doing nothing all day here at home. You know what I mean?
Example two. Come on Charles. You know what I mean when I say that I don't like your friends?
Example three. I hate this class. It's so boring and tedious. You know what I mean?
All right. So we heard the examples and well, maybe you guessed it right. The second example
was the question. That's right. You know what I mean? Right. So basically you're asking the person
if they understand your idea or they understand what you're talking about. So maybe you can say,
so the professor wasn't very clear on his instructions. So how was I supposed to do the homework?
You know what I mean? So you're asking me to confirm that I understand you. My idea. You understand what I'm saying.
Okay. And if it was a statement, I might say, hey, I don't like going to your mom's house.
So I would say, what do you mean? Why? You know what I mean? Right. So I perfectly understand or know
the reasons why you don't like going to my mom's. Like I don't have to tell you. You know what I mean?
All right. Very good. So you know what I mean? Great. So we've taken a look at these
four phrases. They're very simple, but the way that you use them gives them different meanings.
That's right. All right. So let's listen to our dialogue for the second time. Let's slow it
down a little bit and then we'll come back and look at some more phrases.
Can we talk? Sure, honey. We're talking now, aren't we? You know what I mean? Yeah, I know.
I want to know where this relationship is going. I mean, love with you and I need to know.
You know, I think you're awesome. I'm awesome. Well, I guess that's my answer, isn't it? Honey.
Look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing, all right? We've had our lives, but I don't
appreciate. Well, maybe it's just time we. Baby, I love you so much. You do. I love you. And I think you're
awesome. Oh, I love you, too. Come on. Put the gun down. Oh, baby. I'm so sorry.
Okay, so now it's time for us to take a look at some more phrases, but this time we're going to look at them
and putting it together. Put it together. Okay, we're going to see how we can use these phrases in a
few different situations. So the girl wanted to talk to her boyfriend because she wanted to know
where this relationship is going. Right. Where is this relationship going? Where is this relationship
going? So she wants to know what's going to happen or what's the future of this relationship.
Are we going to get married or just what are what's happening? Yeah. So why don't we listen to
some examples with different nouns and how we can use this phrase? Example one, I don't know where
my career is going in this company. I don't see any potential for growth. Example two.
This movie is so confusing. I have no idea where the plot is going. Example three.
We have been in this meeting for over two hours and I still don't know where it's going.
Okay, so again, this phrase is just asking about the future of something. Right. So where the
future of this movie, where is this movie going? Yeah, what's happening? Right. What's going
to happen? Yeah. Or your career, et cetera. Yeah. Okay. And so the girl, um, you know, she was talking
a little bit about her feelings and she said, maybe it's just time we. Okay. So this phrase isn't
complete yet. Yeah. We need to finish it. Yeah. But she is basically saying, maybe we should do this.
How can we finish the phrase? All right. So so she could say, maybe it's just time we break up.
All right. Or I can say, maybe it's time we have a baby. Oh, my God.
All right. Even maybe it's time we go home. Okay. So it's getting late. Let's go home. Maybe it's time
we go home. Yeah. So this is how we can finish this phrase. And what about our last phrase?
She also said, we've had our laughs. Okay. So that means we've had our good times. Yeah. Okay.
But we can change this to we've had our ups and downs. Okay. Or we've had our moments. Mm-hmm.
Right. So that means we've had our good moments and our bad moments. That's right. Or we've had
our issues. Okay. So that means we've had some problems. Yeah. We've had some difficulties.
Mm-hmm. Or even we've had our moments. Okay. So that means we've had special times. Yeah.
So that means we've had our special times, special occasions, that we will always remember. That's right.
Okay. So a really useful structure is that you can change the words a little bit to slightly change the
meaning. Okay. So it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the last time. Now we're ready to
understand everything. And then we'll come back and give you some examples of pet names and English.
Can we talk? Sure, honey. We're talking now, aren't we? You know what I mean. Yeah, I know.
I want to know where this relationship is going. I mean, love with you. And I need to know.
You know, I think you're awesome. I'm awesome. Well, I guess that's my answer, isn't it? Honey.
Look, if you don't love me, it's not a thing, all right? We've had our laughs, but I don't appreciate.
Well, maybe it's just time we... Baby, I love you so much. You do? I love you. And I think you're awesome.
Oh, I love you too. Come on. Put the gun down. Oh, baby. I'm so sorry.
All right. All right. Omar, could you mention this word pet names? And what exactly is that?
All right. So pet names aren't names for your dogs or your cats, right? They are those sweet names
that you would call your boyfriend or girlfriend. Okay. So like baby. Okay. In our dialogue, we heard baby.
Yep. Right. So we're not talking about a little child. A little child, no. This is usually how you would
call maybe your girlfriend or boyfriend. They would be. Or honey. Honey. Yeah. Hey, honey or honey. I'm home.
Yeah. Right. But we also have other ones like sweetheart. Mm-hmm. For darling darling. Yeah. Or what about
sweetie or cutie? Cutie. Oh. So some of these phrases can be a little bit like cheesy, maybe like
yeah, a little too too much. Yeah. Smokens. Smokens. Smokens. Like snokens. Okay. Or honey bunny. Oh, yeah.
We also have sweetie pie. Yep. Yeah. And some of them will make some up, right? Maybe they'll call
their their boyfriend, um, poo bear. Oh, yeah. Right. Like, you know, like, we need a poo poo bear. I heard
dumpling and they call it on. Also, it could be you can make up your own for it. You can make up your
own pet names, right? Yeah. So I want to hear from our listeners. Are there any common pet
names in your language? I know that in Spanish we sometimes call the we can sometimes call our
girlfriend, Gorda, which actually means fat. But it's not in a bad way. Really? It's a sweet way of
calling your your girlfriend. And I know in French you can say map poo switch basically means my
flee. Yeah. So some of them if you translate, you wouldn't really use an English, but let
us know translate from your language or other ones that you've heard maybe in movies or talk shows
and come to our website, EnglishPod.com. Yep. Leave your questions there as well as your pet
names and Marco and I are always happy to see you there. Okay. Until next time. Goodbye. Bye.