Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we have a cold lesson.
That's right. It's the winter season and of course it gets cold in a lot of different places around the world.
And so we're going to talk about heating.
Okay, this is very important but before we do get started we have a very important word to preview in the
vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview. All right, so we're going to preview the word freezing.
It is freezing today, by the way. So this is very appropriate.
Freesing means very very very cold. Okay, it is freezing. Okay, so it's very cold. It's freezing today.
It's so cold. In fact, you can't have water outside because the water will become ice.
It will freeze. Okay, great word. So let's listen to our dialogue for the very first time.
It's freezing in here. Can I turn up the heat?
Don't touch that thermostat. You don't pay the bills around here.
Dad, are you serious? What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it? Look,
I can see my breath. Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill.
Just because it's a bit chilly. Dad, I'm going to catch a cold. When I was your age,
my parents didn't have central heating like you do. We had a furnace in the center of the living room.
And that was it. We used it to cook, heat the house and even dry our clothes. We never caught a cold.
You should be grateful.
All right, we're back. And this is actually what a lot of dads are like. I think we're on the world.
Yep, my dad definitely like to keep the heat low. Really?
Yeah. All right. So we'll talk about that a little bit later. But let's take a look at some
four words on language takeaway today.
Language takeaway. Well, this first word is important for anyone who has a home with heating,
it's called a thermostat. All right, a thermostat. What is a thermostat? A thermostat is a dial or
like a device on the wall that tells you how hot or how cold the house is. It's like a thermometer for your house.
Okay. So you can move the thermostat, the temperature to make the house warmer or colder, right?
Right. So if it says it's 20 degrees and I think that's too cold, I can turn the thermostat up to 23 degrees.
All right. And well, very much related to a thermostat and what this device does is
our next word, central heating. Right. So if you have central heating, you have a thermostat. That's the
way to control the heat. And central heating means that you have one heater for the whole house.
And so the air comes into all the different rooms. So not many places in China have this, but for
example, in the United States and Canada, it is very common. Okay. So your house or your apartment building
will have central heating. And then you can control how cold or warm the house is with thermostat.
Exactly. Very good. And well, our next word is related to temperature and it's chilly.
Chili. Okay. So there's a big difference between chilly and freezing.
Freezing means very, very, very cold. Chili means a little cold. Right. So it's a little cold.
It's a bit chilly. Right. So it's a bit chilly today. I'm going to wear a hat.
Okay. If it's freezing, I'm going to wear hat, a hat and mittens and a scarf and coat and boots.
All right. So if it's a bit chilly, it's not very cold. And while moving on, the dad mentioned
about him having a furnace. Right. That's right. The dad had a furnace in his house. And the furnace
is a way to heat your house. It's like a stove. So yeah, just consider it like a big oven.
Right. Maybe you've seen it in the old movies where you would have to throw firewood into the furnace
to make it heat up the house. Exactly. And so this is very common in older homes.
And not very common in apartments. Right. And well, that's all the words we have for language
takeaway today. Why don't we listen to this chilly dialogue again?
It's freezing in here. Can I turn up the heat? Don't touch that thermostat. You don't pay
the bills around here. Dad, are you serious? What's the point of having central heating if we
can't use it? Look, I can see my breath. Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you run up
my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly. Dad, I'm going to catch a cold. When I was your age,
my parents didn't have central heating like you do. We had a furnace in the center of the
living room and that was it. We used it to cook, heat the house and even dry our clothes. We never
caught a cold. You should be grateful. All right, we're back. So now we have prepared for you
three key phrases on fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay. So this first phrase is related to
thermostat. Okay. So thermostat like we said is like a thermometer but we can control the
temperature. So if we want to make the temperature hotter, we turn up. Okay. So this is a phrase
over to turn up the heat. You could say this about heat. You could say this about noise too.
Can you turn up the radio? Turn up the volume. So it's to increase. To increase to make bigger or warmer
or louder. All right. And if we wanted to decrease the temperature in the thermostat, you would say
turn down the heat. Exactly. So it's too hot in here. Can you please turn down the heat?
All right. Very good. And our next phrase is well, the dad was talking about the bills and how expensive
it is to use the thermostat. And he said, I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill.
Okay. So a bill is like you know something that you pay. It's money. And so in this case, I don't
want you to run up the bill. That means to increase the amount of money, I have to spend.
So maybe if you leave your television on all night, you're running up your electricity bill.
Exactly. Or if you talk on the phone 10 hours a day, you run up the phone bill and your mother
kills you. All right. All right. And well, the daughter was complaining about her catching a
cold to catch a cold. All right. So remember this, a cold is when you have maybe a runny nose and the
cough and the sore throat. It usually happens when the weather changes. But we don't get a cold.
You catch a cold. Okay. And remember like in baseball, you throw in catch. It's something that's
fast. All right. So you catch a cold. What about the flu? Do you get the flu or catch the flu?
So you can't catch a flu, but you can't catch a cold. Just remember this phrase to catch a cold.
I caught the cold. No. To catch a cold or I caught a cold. It's almost like if I have it, I could
throw it to you Marco. I knew catch it. Right. Because it's in the air, the virus.
Passes very quickly. All right. Very good. So an interesting dialogue. Let's listen to it one last time.
It's freezing here. Can I turn up the heat? Don't touch that thermostat. You don't
pay the bills around here. Dad, are you serious? What's the point of having central heating if we can't
use it? Look, I can see my breath. Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you run up my
heating bill just because it's a bit chilly. Dad, I'm going to catch a cold. When I was your
age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do. We had a furnace in the center of the
living room and that was it. We used it to cook, heat the house and even dry our clothes. We never
caught a cold. You should be grateful. All right. We're back and well you mentioned about the
thermostat and your dad actually controlling the heating at home. Was this the case like this
in this scenario? It was sometimes would have to wear more clothes because we didn't want to run up
the bill. But we had a special situation in my house because I'm from Chicago and it's very cold
and the winters in Chicago. But we had a fireplace. Okay. So even if it was very cold, we always had
firewood and we could put on the fire in the fireplace to keep warm. So everyone would stay in
the living room and read and listen to music and just you know, relax. No, I heard that because
you know, when you're burning wood it causes some pollution and some cities it's banned right to
actually turn on or we'll to have a fireplace. That's right. Yeah. So but in Chicago you can still do it.
Absolutely and in most of the states you can. Although a lot of people in new houses they don't have
real fireplace. They have electric fireplaces and so you can use a light switch to turn on your fire.
It's not a real fire. It's just a glowing light. Yeah. All right. Well, very good. This is an
interesting lesson especially because the winter season is coming up and everyone is cold. So
we hope you enjoyed it and if you have any questions and he doubts you can come to our website
EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. Happy studies and stay warm. All right.