Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we've
got another lesson all about food and eating. So today we're going to talk about all the tools that we use
when we're at the table. So what we use when we're eating. That's right. So let's take a listen to today's
dialogue and when we come back we'll talk about some of these words and some of the great phrases you're
learning today.
Honey can you set the table? I'm sure. What are we having for dinner? Do I need to put anything out in
particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers. I don't know if your brother is
coming tonight. So set an extra-place match just in case. Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead. Forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy bone serving dishes. Just be careful because
the wine glasses are also there. Oops.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of words in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So our first word is a very important one. You might have heard it before
the word is silverware. Okay silverware now this means that it's usually made something that's made
out of silver right? It could be. Maybe traditionally it's made out of silver but it doesn't
have to be. You could have wooden silverware or other metals. It's basically the things that you
use to eat food with. Okay so we're going to take this as a category. Silverware are all the tools
that we use to eat food with and in this so for example a fork is some part of a silverware.
It's a kind of silverware fork. A fork is the one that you usually put in your mouth with a piece of
lettuce or meat or something. Okay so it's pointy it has a like four little points. Now the one
that we use to have dessert or to have soup with we call that a spoon. A spoon that's right so to
eat yogurt or ice cream you use a spoon and finally to cut things you use a knife. Okay so in
the dialogue we saw the plural form knives but singular it would be knife. That's right and sometimes
there are foods that are very very hard to cut. For example steak is very hard to cut because it's
a tough meat and so in that case we use a steak knife to cut it. Okay so we have a knife or a
steak knife. Steak knife more specifically is used to cut meats. All right so these are three kinds
or actually four kinds of silverware. Of course there are other kinds but those are the most
important. After that that we have something that's important for making your food taste better.
So what if I want to add salt or pepper? What are those things called? Those are called salt and
pepper shakers. We saw them in the dialogue that we need to put out the pepper and salt
shakers. So the little thing where you keep the salt is called a shaker. That's right because the
action the verb is to shake. That means moving your hand up and down so some salt will fall
out onto your food. Exactly so usually it's only salt and pepper that we keep in these things
and these little shakers. But apart from salt and pepper shakers when all the silverware were
putting out we're also putting out some saucers because we're going to have coffee later on.
Oh say okay so there's not only goes together with cups cups and saucers but everyone knows
what a cup is. What is a saucer? So a saucer is this little plate that you put under the cup
when you're having coffee. So usually that's where you keep your spoon or maybe the little bag of tea.
Okay so a saucer is important because it also helps in case you spill some coffee or tea so
the coffee or tea doesn't go on the ground it goes on the plate. Exactly so that little plate
is called a saucer. Now where do we keep all the plates all the silverware? We usually keep them
in a cupboard. Okay so you might want to say cup board because it's cup CUP, CUP, CUP,
O, A, R, D that's not right. The word is pronounced covered. Okay so even though it may seem like you
should pronounce cup board the correct pronunciation is covered. Covered. Covered and a cupboard
like you said is usually in the dining room or the kitchen because it houses it keeps all of our
plates and bowls and sometimes our silverware. That's right okay so actually in the cupboard we
also have some other things dishes. Well specifically we have a gravy boat in there. Okay so I'm
not even sure why they call it a boat but a gravy boat is basically a special dish. It's like
us it's a cattal bowl with a spout so you can pour it that keeps gravy so gravy is like a liquid
or a sauce that goes on top of meat or potatoes. I guess it kind of looks like a boat just imagine a
boat but inside it's empty so then that's where you put the gravy in. You can pour it. All right and
so we can find that we can also find serving dishes which are basically big plates or bowls that we use
when we're having dinner at the dinner table to keep for example a turkey or a roast. And specifically
we were also looking for wine glasses. Well maybe we weren't looking for them but they found us because
the person getting stuff out of the cupboard dropped some wine glasses. These are very, very easy to break.
Wine glasses are basically just glasses that maybe are tall and you drink wine out of them.
That's right so there's specific type of glass usually used to drink wine so wine glasses I
guess normal glass that you used to drink maybe juicer water is just called a glass.
Right you wouldn't say wine glass only when you're drinking wine. Okay so we've taken a look at a
lot of vocab here a lot of tools that we use at the dinner table when we're having dinner. So let's
listen to the dialogue again and review. Honey can you set the table? I'm sure what are we having
for dinner. Do I need to put anything out in particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and
salt shakers. I don't know if your brother is coming tonight so set an extra place mat just in case.
Okay should I use the fancy silverware? Yeah go ahead forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so
be sure to put out some steak knives as well. I also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after
dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls? They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy
bone serving dishes just be careful because the wine glasses are also that oops.
All right we're back so now we have four key phrases that we've prepared for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay so this first phrase is very important especially as a child your mother or
father might ask you to do this the phrase is to set the table. Okay so that's a a phrasal verb to
set the table and what does it mean if you're asked to set the table? It means you will put down the
plates and the silverware and the bowl so that everything is prepared for dinner. Okay so this is
actually what we were doing and a complimentary phrasal verb to this. When you're setting the
table as you said you are putting down or putting out the different spoons knives dishes all that's
stuff. Right so the verbal phrase to put out means to place down or to to make sure that you get
something out on the table. In this case my mother would usually ask me to put out extra glasses
for water okay or don't forget to put out the wine glasses in case we're drinking wine. It just
means to place down. Exactly so just remember that it's we use it because all these things that are
inside the cupboard so you have to take them out so you have to put them out on the table.
All right and sometimes we may have a guest or we may need an extra chair or an extra seat
because we're having company and the person in dialogue said to set an extra placement just in case.
Okay so a placement is basically a piece of plastic or maybe fabric that you put in front of a
person when they're at the table so it's on the table and it's something that protects the table.
So it's small everyone has one and the bowl and the silverware will go on top of that
placement but it also indicates that that is where someone will sit. Okay so to put out or to
set out an extra placement means to prepare an extra place for someone else who will be coming.
So if you have a guest for example you'll set out an extra placement for him or for her.
Okay so we can say set an extra placement because this is by this we are referring that somebody's
going to sit down at the table or you can just simply say set an extra place for someone.
That's right set an extra place your older brothers coming home from college tonight.
Okay so we can set an extra place for him at the table and well in this case we didn't know if
the brother was really coming or not so she said just in case. This is a great phrase one that you'll
hear all the time. It means I'm not sure what the result will be or what the outcome will be but
in case something happens or just in case we should do this. So for example Marco I think it's
going to rain today you should bring an umbrella just in case. Okay so this is a way of saying
you're preventing something you're prepared. Maybe if it does rain you'll have an umbrella just
in case bring your umbrella. Okay so a lot of great phrases there, a lot of vocab so why don't we
listen to the dialogue for the last time?
Honey can you set the table? I'm sure what are we having for dinner. Do I need to put anything
out in particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers. I don't know if your
brother is coming tonight so set an extra place mat just in case. Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy bone serving dishes just be careful because the
wine glasses are also there. Oops.
All right we're back so talking about dinner and silverware there are also a couple of other
names that we didn't mention. For example many people refer to ceramic plates as China.
Yeah these are usually the the fancy kinds of plates and dishes that you have in your house.
Obviously if you have just kind of the cheap ceramics that you can throw away or even paper
paper plates. Those aren't very important but at a wedding or in a special occasion a person or
family might receive Chinaware China and that is very nice very pretty porcelain plates or
just lacquerware. Okay so you can call it Chinaware which is basically plates that are either very
fine ceramic or porcelain as you said. That's right or what was the other word that you said before?
lacquerware lacquerware is a certain kind of plate or ceramic that has a kind of sheen to it. It's
very special kind of basically pink job. Oh okay yeah because it's always been kind of
strange the fact that a name like China would also now be related to plates but apparently I
guess because Chinese porcelain is renowned as being such high quality I guess this is why
we just have a word for it called China or Chinaware. I think it actually has to do with the fact
that the Chinese and the old days sent sold what most of the British bought their porcelain from China
and so it was very very invoked it's very popular and it was basically the only thing that the
British wanted they just wanted all of this China and it became a part of the vocabulary then.
Yeah it's really strange though that you would call something China. It's like I don't know any
other country that you call something you know like French this is a French or a Frenchware. I
don't know I can't think of any. Lee Moj is a name of a city in France and it's a certain kind
of ceramics. Oh there you go. All right so an interesting topic there are many other tools that we
didn't mention would like salad fork and ice cream spoon I don't know there's so many as sometimes
if you go to a fancy dinner you will have maybe three spoons, three knives, three forks and you
don't know what to do with it. Start on the outside and go in that's my one recommendation. Exactly
so we're really curious to know what you have to say come to our website EnglishPod.com if you have
any questions you can leave them there or if you also want to suggest a topic for a lesson or anything
you want just let us know. All right we'll see you then. All right bye.