Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
Hi guys, my name is Catherine and today we're talking about something that is a little bit
private. That's right, but very necessary to learning English because it's very, very useful.
That's right. So we're talking about clothing more specifically underwear. So the clothes you wear
under your clothes. That's right. Okay. So let's just jump into the dialogue. Let's see what happens today
and we're back in a bit.
Lily, I found a pair of men's boxes in the laundry machine this morning.
What? That's weird. That's your boyfriend's. Now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is
extra small. What do they look like? They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh, and
there's Snoopy on it, which is hilarious. There's my undies. All right. So a lot of great
vocab there. Let's take a look at that now on language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So the first thing we have here in language takeaway is actually very interesting Marco because we don't
say one underwear or one boxers. We say a pair of just like pants, a pair of pants, or a pair,
of underwear. A pair of pants, a pair of shorts, of socks. The same thing goes for underwear. So
I really don't know why because it's one piece. So our pants, but basically you have two holes,
two places for your legs. So anything with your legs, your socks, your shoes, your pants,
your underwear. You need a pair. Let's say a pair because you've got the both sides left and right.
Okay. All right. So you got a pair of a pair of men's boxes. Now before we describe the underwear
let's take a look at this other machine, a laundry machine. Okay. So you know what a machine is.
It's usually something that uses electricity to help us with a with a task or a job. But a laundry
machine is special because it helps us clean our laundry. What kind of things are laundry? So
anything that's your clothes. So basically it's also called a washing machine.
Right. So laundry machine or washing machine. Same thing. It uses water and soap to wash your clothes.
That's right. Okay. So now let's get into the type of underwear here specifically for men.
Usually we have boxers, boxers shorts. That's right. So shorts means that they're they're not
long. They're short, but boxers or boxers shorts, as you say, are usually pretty loose. They're
not very tight and they're longer than the other kinds of underwear we have. Okay. So boxers are a
type of underwear that men wear under their their their clothes. And as you say they're pretty much
shorts, but they're called boxers or you can call them boxers shorts. Now the I guess the classic or the
common. The common form of men's underwear are called briefs. Briefs. Now these are smaller than
boxers and they're tighter. Okay. And they are usually made out of some kind of material that
stretches. You can pull them a little bit. And this is this is again a smaller version. Well a
smaller kind of underwear. That's right. So boxers are more like shorts briefs are kind of
and briefs are not really shorts. They're more like a I guess kind of like a swimming suit they look
like a bathing suit bottom for men. Okay. Now that's it right. Okay. And these. Okay. So
both these things we could actually describe as undies. That's right. So undies is a common
spoken language way of saying underwear. Okay. So it's very casual. And it's usually something that we
say with our family or friends, especially moms like to say this with their kids. And these.
All right honey. I'm gonna buy you some new undies this. Okay. As a child you feel very embarrassed.
Undies is a way to say underwear. All right. Okay. So that's all the folk have that we have for
you on language takeaway. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again? And we're back in a bit with fluency
builder.
Lily. I found a pair of men's boxers in the laundry machine this morning. What? That's
weird. You're boyfriend. Now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is extra small. What do they
look like? They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh and there's Snoopy on it which is hilarious.
There's a my undies. All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at some descriptive words
in fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right. So as you said Marco we have a lot of great phrases
today and some words for describing underwear. And you can describe other things with these words as
well. The first one we have is phrase extra small. Okay. So when you buy underwear the sizes
you sometimes get small extra small large medium. But it's just the way of describing how big it is.
Right. So you know the S the M and the L are small medium on large. But if you see the X S that's
extra small it means it's very small. All right. We also have X L which is extra large. That's right.
Okay. So now that we've described the size now we're going to describe a little bit of how they
look like the colors and maybe any characteristics. So the first thing that we see is the color is light
Okay. So we've got blue which is normal blue. We have light blue which is maybe the color of the
sky on a beautiful summer day. There's also we didn't hear it in today's dialogue but there's another
color. It's dark blue which is almost more like purple or black. That's right. So this is the way
of describing a color. Now it can be for any color except white. You don't really say light white or
dark white. Yeah you don't. So you could say light green, dark green, light orange, dark dark orange.
Okay. And now some characteristics. They had some thin pink stripes. So we have the word here thin.
So not fat thin. Pink. We have the color but what are stripes? Okay stripes are a very common
design for clothes and you often see stripes. They're like lines. Okay. And so that means that you have
different lines that are pink. You often see stripes on flags. So for example the American flag
has red and white stripes. Okay. Very good. So as you said they're lines and yeah usually in clothing
you can find maybe shirts that have vertical stripes or sometimes even horizontal stripes. Yes.
But these these undies are quite unique. They're very special because they have pink stripes.
That's right. Okay. So that's all the language we have for you. We want to listen to our dialogue
one last time and we're back in a little bit.
Lately I found a pair of men's boxes in the laundry machine this morning.
What? That's weird. That your boyfriend's. Now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is
extra small. What do they look like? They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh and there's
a snoopy on it which is hilarious. There's a my undies.
All right. So in this case we're talking about men's box of shorts because there was a confusion
about the boyfriend but women also wear boxer shorts. It's very popular now among women.
Yeah it is. It's usually something that women wear over their underwear.
Uh huh. Women don't really wear boxer shorts as underwear.
Women's underwear smaller. It's like men's briefs.
There's small. Okay. So if a girl wears boxers and it's usually for maybe if they're just
around the house and you don't want to wear pants and you don't want to wear shorts you can just
wear a pair of comfortable boxer shorts. Exactly like they were pajamas. Uh huh. Okay.
And actually I think a lot of girls also use boxer shorts as pajamas, right? That's right.
Okay. They're comfortable and they're light and you know they're they're made usually made from
cotton which is a nice material to sleep in. Now when we're talking about briefs there is also
another way that I've heard that they're called sometimes a more uh maybe funny way of calling them
that some people say they're called tidy whiteies. That's right. This is usually something we say
to joke because in America at least many men like to wear young men like to wear boxers.
Right. So they call briefs tidy whiteies because usually their briefs are just white. They're
plain. They don't have any design or any other color. Now they're plain and they're white usually
or gray and they're tight not like boxers. So the the casual name this is not something you want to
say to your English teacher. The casual name or the funny name is tidy whiteies. tidy whiteies.
And actually this is a very interesting because with newer generations I think
men are wearing boxers instead of briefs. Before I think the only option was briefs. Exactly.
But now boxers have grown more and more popular and I think when you're a little kid your mom
always buys you little briefs and everything but then when you're a teenager I think you just switch
over to boxes. It's not as cool anymore to wear briefs. Yeah I think it's it's the whole
fact of how kids sometimes dress with a saggy or baggy pants and so they like to show their
boxers. That's right. And I don't really understand that but if you do let us know our website
is EnglishPod.com. We're going to have all the vocabulary and stuff on the website so check it out.
All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.