Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about something that has always been very confusing for me.
For me as well, I don't understand very well what this is about.
We're going to be talking about time zones and a little bit about daylight savings time.
Before we get started though, let's take a look at this phrase and today's vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
All right. So the phrase is daylight savings time.
Okay. So we're trying to save daylight pretty much.
That's right. So this is the time of year when we change our clocks.
What does that mean? That means in the fall, there's a special day and everyone has it on their calendar
and we change the clocks. We put them back one hour.
So if it was eight o'clock now, it's seven o'clock.
Okay. So everything is earlier. Starts earlier.
Yes.
And that's basically to take advantage of the daylight. Right.
That's why it's called daylight savings time.
Exactly. And so that's for the winter.
And then when the winter is passed, we change the clocks again.
We have the spring daylight savings where we change our clocks ahead.
Okay. So it sounds kind of complicated.
Many countries don't have daylight savings time.
They don't change their clocks at all.
But we're going to be talking about this in a little bit more.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time?
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time?
What? Why do we have to do that?
Well, at the start of the spring, we usually have more daylight in the mornings and lessen the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth.
In any case, to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving our
clocks forward one hour. I see. That's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMT.
I never know what time zone we are in or wind it change my clock.
That just stands for Grinnage mean time. Here in California we're in Pacific Standard Time.
That is 8 times zones west of Grinnage. Remember when we were in Beijing?
Well then we were in China Standard Time and that's 8 times zones east of Grinnage.
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the huge time difference.
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than 8 hours,
we still arrived in LA the same day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right we're back. That was a pretty clear explanation of why we do these things.
But maybe there were a couple of words that you didn't understand. So let's take a look at those
now in language takeaway. Language takeaway. Well Marko what you were hinting at before this idea
that we have shorter days in the winter and longer days in the summer has to do with the rotation
of the earth. So the rotation of the earth is our first phrase. Okay. So the earth
rotates. What does that mean if it rotates? It means to spin around. But not just to spin around
anywhere. It means that if you draw a line through the middle of something, it never leaves that line.
It just kind of turns. Okay. So it's spinning like the wheels on a car. They rotate. That means
they go around but they are fixed to the car. Right. So this is one of the reasons why we need to
compensate our clocks because of the rotation of the earth. And that's our next word to
compensate. This is a verb to compensate. And it's often used with money but it can be used with
time as well. Time or sunlight. So with money you'd say I paid him a hundred dollars but I owe
to him a hundred fifty. So I'm going to compensate him for the extra fifty. Okay.
It means I'm going to fix it. Okay. So two compensate would be the verb and compensation would
be the noun. Now in this case we're talking about time. So how can we compensate time?
Well that means that if we have lost an hour because we changed the clocks we have to compensate.
We have to try and gain an hour back. And so that's why in the spring after the day is
start to get longer and longer with the compensate for that by changing the clocks again.
Okay. So we're compensating time. Now related to daylight savings and this whole time thing
is time zones. We have time zones all over the earth and you've probably noticed this if you've
traveled you have to change your clocks or many times you see in hotels what time it is in
London and Hong Kong and Berlin etc. And this makes a lot of sense because like we said the earth
is rotating and so if it's daylight in Moscow and it's nighttime in New York obviously it's not the
same time. Right. So to compensate for this difference we have different time zones and each time zone
is pretty much an hour or so and you know half an hour different from the next one. Right. So most
countries actually have different time zones throughout their country unless they're small that
they don't really need to compensate any change or for example China just to unify everything. It's a
big country but they have one time zones, China standard time. Exactly but in the United States we have
four times. Right. All right so that's time zone and out related to time zone is time difference.
Okay well think about math here difference is a word that we use in math and a time difference is the
amount of time that means how many hours there are between one time zone and another time zone.
So for example Beijing and New York City. These are very very far away from each other. If it's
day in New York it's night in Beijing. So that means if it's seven in the morning in Beijing it's
probably around seven at night in New York. So the time difference would be more or less 12 hours.
Exactly but when it's daylight savings time it's 13. So be careful. Right okay I think that's
pretty clear. I think we should go back and listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back soon with
Fluency Builder. Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time? What? Why do we have to
Well at the start of the spring we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less in the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth. In any case
to take better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
I see that's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMT. I never know what
time zone we are in or winded change my clock. That just stands for Greenwich Mean Time.
Here in California we're in Pacific Standard Time. That is eight times zones west of Greenwich.
Remember when we were in Beijing? Well then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight
time zones east of Greenwich. That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the
huge time difference. Even though we left Beijing at noon in Flu for more than eight hours we still
arrived in LA the same day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at three key phrases in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. All let's go back to the beginning of this dialogue. The person who's
explaining all of these interesting things is saying that well in any case to take
better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
So this is an important phrase you could say to take better advantage of or to take advantage of.
Let's talk about this. To take advantage of something. So to take advantage of something is to use it
efficiently right or to take better advantage. So for example if you drive to work every day
and your neighbor drives to work every day and you work at the same place you could take
better advantage of your car and the cost by sharing the same car to work.
Exactly or when people started to use computers you could say well they were taking
better advantage of their time by speeding things up by making things faster with the computers.
Right or many mothers say take better advantage of your time and read something instead of playing
those video games. Exactly so it means like you said to be more efficient to do useful or
important things. That's right and now when we talked about what daylight savings time means or
GMT with that stands for. This is an interesting phrase it stands for. Well think about it as a picture.
So if something stands for something else that means the original thing it's not there anymore.
And so in words and phrases like GMT you GMT doesn't mean anything by itself but the G stands for
something that M stands. It's an acronym. Okay so this is an acronym that stands for that represents
three big long words. Okay. Grinch mean time. Right. So we use this a lot when we are defining words or
when we are defining an acronym like GMT stands for Grinch mean time or for example USA stands for United
States of America or we can even say someone's name stands for something. So Marco what is the
M in your last name stand for? So your Marco M what is the M stand for? Right and then I would
say well it stands for me here. Your last name. Right. So you can use this when you see things that
you don't understand maybe an acronym or an abbreviation like does Kathy stand for Katherine? Yes,
Kathy stands for Katherine. It's a short version of Katherine. Cool. All right and well now talking a
little bit more about time you may be seeing the movie back to the future and this is what it's all
about to go back in time. To go back in time so we went back in time. This is what the person says
about the flight from Beijing to LA. What's interesting is that to go back in time is kind of a fixed
phrase. We always say like this. So we could say if you went back in time where would you go? What
time what place? Right. So to go back in time usually use it like this now what if I wanted to say
to go into the future could you say go forward in time? You could go forward in time or you could
go into the future. Right. Go into the future. So remember if you want to talk about going back
in time is usually traveling to the past. Exactly. All right so that's all the phrases we have.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the very last time?
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time? What? Why do we have to do that?
Well at the start of the spring we usually have more daylight in the mornings and lessen the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth. In any case
to take better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
I see that's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMT. I never know what
time zone we are in or wind it change my clock. That just stands for Greenwich meantime. Here in
California we're in Pacific Standard Time. That is eight times zoned's west of Greenwich. Remember
when we were in Beijing? Well then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight times zoned's
east of Greenwich. That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the huge
time difference. Even though we left Beijing and noon and flew for more than eight hours we still
arrived in LA the same day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right we're back and now this is actually something that really does happen right if you take
off in an airplane from Beijing you fly for a certain amount of hours and you reach California
and it's still the same time you reach it in the same day. It's very strange the same thing happens
to me when I go home so I leave Shanghai and I arrive in Chicago and I arrive at the exact same time
I left on the same day. So it's like a time never pass. It's the longest day of your entire life
because it's not 24 hours. The flight is 14 hours. It's really 24 38 hours long right so it's
really intense and exhausting. And then what happens is when you do the opposite you go from Chicago
to Shanghai then you go into the future pretty much right because you left on a Sunday but you arrive
on a Tuesday or in my case yeah you leave on a Sunday and you arrive on a Monday and you lose
half a day of your life. You're just sitting there and all of a sudden it goes past you.
Right. Yeah so it all evens out in the end. Right right so when you go back or when you come it all
evens out you you recover you you get those hours of your life back pretty much. They're not gone forever.
All right so if you guys have any questions any doubts you can send us an email at English
Potted PraxisLanguage.com or come to our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there.
Ask away and until next time everyone. Bye.