Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we have a great elementary level lesson all about having fun.
That's right. Today we are going to have a lot of fun and well before we explain what exactly we're going to do.
Why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very vocabulary preview. Okay so the word we're previewing today is a noun. It's a thing.
It's a roller coaster. All right. A roller coaster. So that's what we're going to do today.
We're going to get on a roller coaster. But what is a roller coaster? Well a roller coaster is something that
we see often times in parks. I'm using parks and it's it's like a little train but it can go upside down
and it goes very fast and it turns and it's supposed to make you scared and happy. Okay. So it goes very fast
and yet many people have probably seen it. It goes very fast and it is a up and down.
And well you just get on it because it's fun. You go fast and you get scared because you're going so fast
and sometimes you're going upside down. Exactly and for some reason I don't know why. But in many
romance languages the name is Russian mountains. Exactly. It's also in Spanish. It's also a Russian
mountain. Yeah. So I think the reason is because back in the day back you know a hundred years ago when
you were starting the the first roller coaster came from Russia. Oh wow. Yeah. So that's why it's
called it. Well that's a theory. I'm not sure but take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll hear it
one time and when we come back we'll be talking about more interesting and exciting phrases and words
about roller coaster. I'm so excited! We're finally here! Six flags magic mountain. This
is the best amusement park in the world. All right settle down now you're going to give yourself
a house attack. I can't believe they charge us thirty five dollars each. Seems like such a ripoff
don't you think? It's not like I'm going to get on these things. Whoa. Bliper that's the world's highest
and fastest roller coaster. You go out more than one hundred miles per hour. I want to go on that one.
Can I mom please? Can I? Chris I'm not sure you should get on that. It seems a bit too much for you
and we just had breakfast 30 minutes go. I don't think it's a good idea. Well come on mom.
I can handle it. I promise I won't ask for anything else besides it's not like I'm
going to throw up or anything. Then I'm going to go. He'll be fine.
All right! Yeah this is amazing! See how I ever go?
All right we're back so interesting that I think this is very common. You get on one of these
things you go so fast that you just throw up. Have you ever thrown up? I'm a roller coaster
no never. No, maybe it's not that common but let's take a look at some of the words that we hear
in this conversation between a boy and his parents. All right so as we mentioned this word
throw up two throw up. Why don't we take a look at that one first although it's almost at the end of
the dialogue. What is it to throw up? Okay well to throw is different than to throw up. So remember
that these two words go together to mean to vomit. That means that the things in your stomach
come out your mouth. So like we heard in the dialogue they came in like, well yeah it's very it's a very
disgusting sound. Yeah and so sometimes people throw up when they eat too much. Sometimes they
throw up when they're sick and sometimes they throw up after riding a roller coaster and so this is
this is an important phrase to know. Or like when you're on a boat you get seasick and you throw up
or in the car sometimes you get car sick. All right so as we mentioned we're also visiting
an amusement park so why don't we explain this word a little bit amusement park? Okay first of all
everyone probably knows the word park you know it's a public place but in this case an amusement park
is a park of fun. A amusement means fun and so it's usually a place that you go to and you pay a price
and they give you a ticket and you can play all day long. So you have roller coasters and food and
shows. So probably the most famous or well known amusement park is Disneyland so that's an amusement park.
Exactly and there's lots of fun things to do for people of all ages.
All right and now the kid was so excited that the mom said all right you're going to give
yourself a heart attack. Okay well a heart attack is another serious health issue we talked about
throwing up before is when your heart stops beating. Right. Okay so maybe something is stuck or
there's there's some problem with your your your heart and there's no more blood going through your heart
and so there's a very very serious issue but in this case she's saying you're so excited
you might hurt your heart. You might have a heart attack. You might hurt yourself because you're
so excited. Right so she's exaggerating that's not really going to happen but she's trying to
warn him. All right and now the father mentioned that they paid $35 for each of their tickets
and he thought it was a ripoff. Okay ripoff is a great great phrase that we use in spoken English
to describe something that's uh unfair so a price that's unfair. Okay so you can maybe go to the market
right and you ask how much a sweater is and they'll tell you it's $100. You think that's a ripoff.
What a ripoff I can buy a sweater for $20 so a hundred is definitely a ripoff.
All right so that's a ripoff it was a ripoff he's not very happy with how much money he paid.
Not at all. All right and now the kid was talking about the roller coaster that is the highest
in fast as roller coaster and he said that the speed was at more than a hundred miles per hour
so what about this miles per hour? Okay this is very important if you go to America you'll see
that the speeds on the road are all in miles per hour so mile as a distance and per hour means
how many miles you can travel every hour so in one hour you can go a hundred miles. So we have the
equivalent right we have like kilometers per hour. Exactly and so miles per hour kilometers per hour
these are both called speeds. Okay and well this is called the imperial system right you use miles
you use inches in feet whereas the uh kilometers or or centimeters or meters you would use
the metric system right. Exactly because the counting um the counting is done by meters
meters metric so in this case we're in America we know that because the speed limit is a hundred
miles or the speed here is a hundred miles an hour. A miles we know that we're in America because
the speed the boy is talking about is miles per hour. Very good and I think yeah use it in
North America and that's pretty much it right. I think they use miles in Britain really.
Yeah I'm not positive I'd have to check with my British friends. All right okay so that's all the
words we have for language takeaway let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to
explain some phrases. I'm so excited we're finally here six flags magic mountain this is the best
amusement park in the world. All right settle down now you're gonna give yourself a horse attack.
I can't believe they charge us thirty five dollars each it seems like such a rip-off don't you think?
It's not like I'm gonna get on these things. Whoa, Viper that's the world's highest and fastest
roller coaster you go out more than one hundred miles per hour. I want to go in that one can I mom please
can I Chris I'm not sure you should get on that it seems a bit too much for you and we've just
had breakfast thirty minutes go. I don't think it's a good idea. Come on mom I can handle it I promise
I won't ask for anything else besides it's not like I'm gonna throw up or anything.
Let them go, Carol he'll be fine. All right yeah this is amazing! See how I have for
guy whoa. All right we're back so now what we start with three phrases that we have prepared for you
today in fluency builder fluency builder. Okay this first phrase Marco is definitely a parent phrase.
Okay so this is something that you often hear parents sing to their children they say
settle down now. settle down now. Teacher say this too yeah. All right everyone settle down.
That means if I'm really excited and I want to talk and I'm running around the room and my teacher says
settle down now that means quiet down go slowly sit down don't talk it means calm down calm down yeah
so to come down to relax settle down. All right and now the next phrase is a very
kids phrase I think right that you would use on your parents so if they say no you can't go to your
friends house you oh come on please. Oh mom come on. All right so what do you mean with that phrase?
What come on come on what? So in this we have a child who's asking something he's saying can you please let
me do something please come on that means I'm encouraging you to change your mind or to let me do something
so please let me have my way. All right all right so come on and you don't only use it as a child or
with your parents right you can encourage your friends to like come on come with me to the bar come on let's go.
Come on. All right you want to and our last phrase I can handle it. Okay this is next to the phrase
all come on so the boy is trying to explain that he's big enough and old enough to go on a roller coaster
but his mother doesn't know she says oh I don't know you know you're you're too young and so he says
I can handle it. That means I am big enough and old enough to go on a roller coaster I won't have a
problem so you can do it right basically I am good enough to do it so for example if I give you a very
hard project you can say I can handle it I can do it you could also say I'm very busy right now I can't handle
it okay I can't I can't do it I'm sorry I can't do it all right very good interesting phrases there
they're very useful and very very common in spoken English in North American well a lot of places
so when we listen to the dialogue for the third time and we'll be back.
I'm so excited we're finally here the next flag magic mountain this is the best amusement park in the
world all right settle down now you're gonna give yourself a house attack I can't believe they charge
just thirty five dollars each seems like such a rip off don't you think it's not like I'm gonna get on these things
whoa bliper that's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster you go out more than 100 miles per
hour I'm gonna go on that one can I mom please feel like Chris I'm not sure you should get on that it
it seems a bit too much for you and we just had breakfast thirty minutes go I don't think it's a good idea
well come on mom I can handle it I promise I won't ask for anything else besides it's not like
I'm gonna throw up or anything then I'm going I'll help you find
all right yeah this is amazing see how I ever got it
all right so this amusement park magic mountain it actually exists in the United States right
it does and six flags is really a brand so there are many different parks amusement parks called
six flags and each one has a different name I'm not sure where magic mountain is but that one's in
California yeah and you have like six flags greater America yeah that's my Chicago that's a little bit
black yeah so they're basically amusement parks and their famous because they have a really great
or intense roller coasters right exactly so the one that we heard about in today's dialogue is called
Viper like the snake and that one is at the the amusement park in in California you mentioned
but the famous ride in Chicago is Batman the ride oh really because you sit on a seat but there's
no place for your feet so your feet swing in the wind and it's very fast and you don't actually
sit on a train right the track is on top of your head exactly so you're hanging so you see
you and downstairs yeah well not downstairs down at the bottom and I hear they have a very serious
problem with people losing their shoes I heard about this people wearing sandals and they just fly
off exactly so I I want to warn everyone if you go to Chicago you go to these upside down
these flipped roller coasters you should bring real shoes not signals well as we mentioned it's
uh it in many languages in the romance languages they're called Russian mountain so I wonder for our
Russian listeners do you have any intense or great roller coasters in Russia I mean if they come from
Russia they should have amazing roller coasters there right that's right or do you have any idea why we
call them Russian mountains in other languages please let us know our website is englishpod.com
we also welcome your questions and comments and other issues so until next time everyone bye bye