Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got a great informative lesson for you.
That's right. We are going to talk about an emergency situation.
So what do you do when you have an emergency?
You dial 911. Exactly.
All right, well maybe not in your country but today we're talking about emergencies in America
and jobs so people who can help you in an emergency.
So before we get into those words and phrases let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
All right class. Now that we're all dressed up let's see what professions you chose.
I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic and a lifeguard.
Can anyone tell me what these people have in common?
They save people from bad things.
That's right. Now class if something bad happened and you had to get help.
Do you know what phone number you would call?
911. Yes. You would pick up the phone and down 911. What are some emergency
situations in which you would need to dial 911?
If my grandpa had a heart attack, if there was an accident,
if the robber broke into the house, if the fire alarm went off.
I wouldn't call 911 if the fire alarm went off in my house. The only time that ever happens is
when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns the garlic bread as usual.
All right. We're back. So now we have a couple of different jobs for people that are working
specifically in emergency situations. So let's take a look at those now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right. So we have a teacher in today's dialogue who's talking to
her students about jobs. So probably these students are very young and she says another word
that means jobs. What's the word she uses? Profession. Profession. That's the plural.
So profession is a job. Let's say for example, a lawyer is a profession.
Mm-hmm. Or a doctor. A doctor, a lawyer. So what's your profession? It's another way to ask
what's your job. All right. So they're talking about professions and some of the kids dressed up as
different as different people. The first one was a fireman. A fireman. So you know the first word
fire. A fireman is a person who puts out a fire. That means he uses water to stop a fire.
No, very good. So a fireman puts out fires. Now apart from a fireman, we also have a police officer.
A police officer. So an officer is someone who works in an official capacity. So in a job.
So we could say he is a police officer or a policeman or a police woman. Okay. So three ways to say this.
So officer is for both vendors, right? A man or a woman could be a police officer. That's right.
So you're going to hear this very often because police men doesn't explain a woman police officer.
So we use police officer to be general. Okay. So we have a fireman, a police officer, a medic.
Now what is this medic? A medic is a kind of doctor. Someone who will look at your health
or help you if you've hurt yourself who usually works on the road, like driving to an accident or
driving to to a fire with police officers. So these people help police officers in fireman
when there's an emergency. Okay. So a medic is not really a doctor. He's more of a specific person
that can help you if you have maybe some cuts or bruises or will help you out. Right. So this
person will stop your bleeding or will help take you to the hospital and they'll make sure that
your healthy when you get to the hospital. But they are not really like a doctor where you work
in a hospital or a doctor's office. Okay. And our last profession is a lifeguard.
Well think about these two words. We have life and we have guard. Guard is like protect.
So a person that protects your life. Hmm interesting. Well this is someone who usually works
at the beach or at a pool. They have a special chair and usually they have a cross on their
bathing suit or on their towel. And this means that they're going to help protect people who are
at the beach. So if someone can't swim, the lifeguard will run or swim to get them and save them.
Okay. Very good. So you have a lifeguard. Now this is for men and women as well. Right. A lifeguard.
Exactly. Okay. So interesting professions. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be
back shortly.
All right. Class. Now that we're all dressed up, let's see what professions you choose.
I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic and a lifeguard. Can anyone tell me what these people
have in common? They save people from bad things. That's right. Now class if something bad happened
and you had to get help. Do you know what phone number you would call? 911. Yes. You would pick
up the phone and down 911. What are some emergency situations in which you would need to dial 911.
If my grandpa had a heart attack. If there was an accident. If a robber broke into the house,
if the fire alarm went off. I wouldn't call 911. One of the fire alarm went off in my house.
The only time that ever happens is when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns
the garlic bread as usual. All right. We're back. So now let's start with fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Our first item in fluency builder we've already talked about. The number in America
to call when you have an emergency is 911. So we usually say, hey dial 911. Okay so that's a
verb there to dial. Exactly. To dial means to select the numbers for a phone call. To telephone
someone. To telephone someone to dial. So you can dial 911 or dial my office number. Or I tried to
dial your home number but no one answered. Okay. Now you can call 911 for many different situations
or emergency. One of the kids said, well, if my grandpa had a heart attack. Okay. So this is an example
of an emergency. A heart attack is a medical problem. It's when your heart cannot receive oxygen.
Okay. So your heart stops meeting sometimes. That's right. Uh, sorry. It's when your heart does not
receive enough blood or oxygen. So it's when your heart stops beating. Okay. Very good. So that's
a heart attack. Now another possible emergency situation is if the fire alarm goes off. This often
happens in office buildings and schools. So you hear a tea. Okay. There's some kind of strange noise.
Well, that's because there's maybe a fire or some smoke in your building. And so usually when this
sounds goes off, it's it automatically calls the police and the fire department. Okay. Now there's
an interesting phrasal verb that is used along with this word, phia alarm. We say the fire alarm goes
off or the fire alarm went off. So that means it started to sound to emit a sound. So the verb here,
as you said, it's a phrasal verb is to go off to go off. We could say my alarm went off.
Or every morning at seven o'clock, my alarm goes off. Okay. That means your alarm begins to
make a sound. A very annoying sound. All right. You know, the worst sound. But a lot of things
can go off. We could talk about a bell or an alarm or fireworks. Fireworks go off. Okay. And
well, the last emergency that we were talking about is if a robber broke into the house. So if a
robber breaks in. To break into, this means to enter to go inside without permission or without a key.
It legally. It legally. So you don't have to break something but usually you break a window or a door.
But this means that someone comes into your house looking to steal something. So usually you have to
use force. For example, if I forget my keys inside my car and I have to break into my own car,
that means maybe I have to force the door open or maybe break the window. Yeah, it's not not fun. I
think it usually ends up being very expensive. Yes, it does. All right. So those are all the phrases
we have for today. Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the very last time?
All right, class. Now that we're all dressed up, let's see what professions you chose.
I see a fireman, a police officer, a medic, and a lifeguard. Can anyone tell me what these people
have in common? They save people from bad things. That's right. Now class, if something bad happened
and you had to get help, do you know what phone number you would call? 911. Yes, you would pick up
the phone and down 911. What are some emergency situations in which you would need to dial 911?
If my grandpa had a heart attack, if there was an accident, it's a rubber broken to the house.
It's the fire alarm went off. I wouldn't call 911 if the fire alarm went off in my house. The only
time that ever happens is when we're having spaghetti for supper and my mom burns the garlic bread as usual.
So Marco, when you were a kid and your teacher said, what jobs are there, what professions
are there, what profession would you like? What did you answer? I always wanted to be a pilot.
Oh, pilots, you wanted to fly airplanes. Yeah, I wanted to be a jet pilot. Actually, I collected a
books about it. I read up about it. So even till now, I probably still remember the capacity of
certain jets or what types of weapons they have. I was really, really into it. Wow, I never knew
this about it. What about you? I could never decide, as a kid, I remember we had to draw pictures
what I will look like in 20 years. And everyone had these pictures. I will be a doctor. I'll be a
veteran-nerian. I'll be the president. I have everything what to draw. So, you know, I think I copied
my friend. She wanted to be a lawyer. I don't get up there. I'm okay. Yeah, I think it's hard. And usually
what you want to be as a kid, you don't do it when you're older. I could do it because of my vision.
I didn't have 20, 20 visions to actually join you, of course. Well, and a lot of kids don't know
how many jobs they're out there. You know the big ones, doctor, lawyer, fireman, police,
astronaut, astronaut, right? So I guess the question for you is what's your profession? Tell us about it,
especially if it's one of the less famous professions out there. Right. There's a lot that I don't
know about those. Our website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. And until next time. Bye.