Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have part two of our series about small talk in English
That's right. So as we mentioned small talk are very short, quick conversations about everyday things like the weather and usually have this with a colleague very quickly or a friend maybe
Yeah, maybe not someone you know very well too. Mm-hmm. Exactly. So we're going to take a look at part two. Why don't we listen to the dialogue and see what's going on?
So Michelle let me introduce you to Maria. She's my colleague from Brazil Maria. This is Michelle
Hi Michelle. So what do you do here in Shanghai? I mean what work do you do? I work in advertising right now
How about you? I'm actually in the wine business. Oh, that sounds really great. I love wine myself
Is this your first time to Shanghai, Maria? No actually I have to visit
I usually come to China for business at least once a year also I love the restaurants in Shanghai
So that's a good reason to come me too
Actually, there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend I mean the food is delicious, but the services and so good
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there. We should go there together some time
Wonderful idea. I'd love that
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of these very interesting phrases we find in the
dialogue and language takeaway
Language takeaway
So the first phrase we have today is from the first sentence of this dialogue
James says so Michelle let me introduce you to Maria. That's right. So we have the phrase
Introduce someone to or introduce you to okay, let me introduce you to this person. So Marco let me introduce you to my friend
Right and this is something that you say when you want to tell the person look
I'm going you're going to meet someone new. Let me introduce you to my friend Sally
And this is very important because it's polite and it's a way for you to say okay you two don't know each other
Here this is you know this person's name. This is this person's name. Right. It's very important when you are introducing people or
When you're in a situation with two people who don't know each other. That's right exactly. So let me introduce you to someone now
Another key question here. I think probably one of the key questions when you meet someone new
You're talking small talk short conversation
What do you do here or what do you do? What do you do? So this might sound like a very strange question. What do you do?
Do you watch TV? Right like to eat food? No, but this means what job do you do? Right what type of work
Do you do? Okay, so Marco what do you do? I host an English podcast. All right. Me too
So this is the question now don't get confused and remember that this is the typical way of asking someone
What is their job if you say what is your job or
What is your occupation what is your occupation it's too formal and it's kind of awkward
I don't think anyone has ever asked me what is your occupation now? I rarely say that I almost always say what do you do?
Or maybe what type of work do you do or what business are you in?
So this is our next phrase actually right
If someone asks you what business are you in or what industry are you in you would say like in this case Maria
She is in the wine business. Okay. I'm in the wine business that means that my job has to do with
Selling or buying wine
So if we replace the noun wine with something else for example clothing. I'm in the clothing business or I'm in the
She's business exactly. You can basically change it with anything with any product
I guess if if you sell computers I'm in the computer business or if you have anything to do with computers
You can say I'm in the computer business. All right, so that's great. I'm in the
Business exactly
All right, so now we know what the person does
We're we continue asking questions. You know we were interested we want to keep the conversation going a little while longer
We say oh wow that's really great. I love one myself
Then we ask is this your first time to Shanghai?
Okay, so is this your first time
To Shanghai or in Shanghai?
This means is this your first time to visit Shanghai?
That's right now the preposition here is always confusing for an ESL learner because sometimes do you say
Is this your first time in Shanghai is this your first time on Shanghai now we're saying two Shanghai
So in this case or in this type of question both are correct. Is this your first time in Shanghai?
Is this your first time two Shanghai?
All right, so I could also say you know if we're in Chicago. Hey Marco is this your first time in Chicago?
But I have to ask if we are in that city. I can't say okay. I'm in Chicago today
But Marco is this your first time in New York because we're not in New York
Exactly that could be confusing so remember when you ask this question you're asking about where you are today right now
Exactly very good so on that note, let's take a break. Let's listen to the dialogue again and boy back with some more phrases
So Michelle let me introduce you to Maria
She's my colleague from Brazil Maria this is Michelle
Hi Michelle, so what do you do here in Shanghai? I mean what work do you do? I work in advertising right now
How about you? I'm actually in the wine business. Oh, that sounds really great. I love wine myself
Is this your first time to Shanghai Maria? No actually I have to visit
I usually come to China for business at least once a year also I love the restaurants in Shanghai
So that's a good reason to come me too
Actually, there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend I mean the food is delicious, but the services isn't so good
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there. We should go there together sometime
Wonderful idea. I'd love that
All right, let's take a look at three more key phrases on fluency builder part two
Fluency builder
So one phrase that we heard from this when things started to get a little bit more personal
Michelle said I often like to get together with friends so this phrase here is to get together with friends
So to get together means to be united or go with friends somewhere
That's right. So we could also use the phrase to hang out this means you're not doing anything in particular
You're not cooking or swimming or you know going shopping, but it just means you're together with your friends
You could be doing anything right exactly so even if you want to ask your friend or colleague
Hey, do you want to get together after work and have a couple of drinks?
All right, that means would you like to hang out or would you like to go somewhere for a drink?
It's very informal and it's not romantic right. It's it's just with friends exactly so if you ask someone to get together
Sometimes it doesn't mean let's go out on a date. Let's just means you know let's hang out let's hang out. Let's be friends. Okay
Now so they were talking about a Brazilian restaurant and James said hey, you know we should go there sometime
Okay, we should go there together. Sometimes even like more personal
This is a really common phrase and one that you guys should remember as a phrase. Okay, we should go there sometime
That means that I would like to make plans with you to go to this restaurant right exactly now
If you notice the word sometime
Is separated you have some and then apart the other word is time
So it's very different from sometimes don't confuse it what we're saying here is when you have time when I have time we should go there
It's almost like saying one time or in the future sometimes is different. It's like I brush my teeth sometimes
Exactly not very often. No, that's not sure
But I would like to go there sometime means you know it's it's a little bit vague
I don't say when but I would like to in the future exactly and Michelle agrees
She says well it's a wonderful idea. I'd love that. Okay. This is another great phrase
Remember this as a phrase
Would you like to go see a movie? I'd love that. I'd love that. So I'd love that. I'd love to. These are ways of saying I like the idea
Let's do it. Mm-hmm exactly. So it's usually in response to an invitation of a suggestion yeah
Very good. All right, so let's take a look at our dialogue again and review everything and we'll be back in a bit
So Michelle let me introduce you to Maria
She's my colleague from Brazil Maria. This is Michelle
Hi Michelle, so what do you do here in Shanghai? I mean what work do you do? I work in advertising right now
How about you? I'm actually in the wine business. Oh, that sounds really great. I love wine myself
Is this your first time to Shanghai Maria? No actually I have to visit
I usually come to China for business at least once a year also I love the restaurants in Shanghai
So that's a good reason to come me too actually there's a great Brazilian restaurant I recommend
I mean the food is delicious but the services isn't so good
I often like to get together with friends and have a great barbecue there
We should go there together sometime wonderful idea. I'd love that
All right, so as we can see it's very quick small conversation
But very good phrases to talk to a stranger to start up a small conversation. I think use a great two Marco because if you're learning English
And you want to
Practice your speaking skills you're not going to have many people to talk about deep things with so it's great to
Use with strangers or what people in your office. That's right and these are
Comentive equal questions and there are also appropriate to ask someone so
Obviously if you meet someone new you're not going to ask them how much money they make because that's kind of
Inappropriate and Western culture that's right. So what we've taught you here are very polite very common phrases
We hope hope hope that you'll go out and practice these if you have questions or comments
Don't hesitate to leave them for us our website is englishpod.com. All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye