Hello English learners, welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica and today we have a fun and scary dialogue
That's right, this lesson is full of language you can use to talk about being scared
Alright, so we're going to be looking at a scary lesson today and we have nothing to preview so let's listen to this dialogue and see why everyone is so scared
Very scary lesson
Hey, why are we out of the sky looking motion? It's like all-true spooky
I told you already, Shabby the owner of the house says there's a ghost hunting his house
So we have to go in and investigate
I don't like this
Come on guys stopping such powers. It's a mystery and adventure
Let's play it again me the creeps seriously guys. Let's get out of here. I'm getting goosebumps just being here
Shabby is a scaredy cat
That luck came from this room. Let's go and check it out
Well, a ghost run
Well, that sounds really scary, but actually it kind of reminds me of another TV show
Very similar to another TV show, but it's different
Okay, but some interesting language that you can use to talk about things that are scary
So why don't we look at that now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway
So let's start with the very first line of our dialogue
Shabby described the mansion to be ultra spooky
It's ultra spooky
Spooky
So, okay, we've got two interesting words here. Ultra and spooky
Now spooky is scary, right?
It's a little bit scary. It maybe makes you feel a little bit uncomfortable
Or maybe it makes you feel a little bit scared
Okay, so not very scared
Not super scared
But ultra spooky
So ultra is another way of saying super or very or really spooky
So if it's ultra spooky then it's very scary
Okay
All right, so our next word
They said that in the house there is a ghost
Hunting the house
Okay, there is a ghost haunting his house
Okay, so the verb two haunt
Okay, two haunt
So the ghost is coming to the house frequently and not letting them live in peace
When a ghost haunts something it visits it often and scares it
Exactly
Now they were all afraid and they didn't want to go in
And so Wilma called everyone coward
Stop being such cowards
Cowards
So a coward
A coward is a person that's not brave
A person who's scared of everything
My exactly so they were being cowards
They were afraid so that's why they didn't want to go in
Well speaking of being afraid
Shabby said I'm getting goosebumps
Goose bumps
To get goosebumps
All right to get goosebumps
Now goosebumps
It may sound a little bit strange
But it's very easy when you're scared or maybe you're cold
The skin on your arms or on your back gets a little bit bumpy
So your skin looks like chicken skin
Exactly chicken skin
And that's actually how we call it in Spanish chicken skin
But this is goose bumps
So I guess it's kind of similar a goose
Yeah, same idea
Goose bumps
All right, and finally
Scruffy said shabby is a scaredy cat
A scaredy cat
You're a scaredy cat
Well a scaredy cat is not really a cat, right?
No, no, no, no
It's a person who's afraid of everything
Okay
Similar to a coward
But more informal
More much more informal
So somebody is a scaredy cat
And I think even a little bit more juvenile
As a dog
Children use it
Yeah, as adults you wouldn't say
He's a scaredy cat
All right, great
So some interesting scary language
I think we need to hear it
One more time
Slowed down in the dialogue
Eddie, why are we out there scary looking mansion
It's like ultra spooky
I told you already shabby
The owner of the house says there's a ghost hunting his house
So we have to go in and investigate
I don't like this
Come on guys
Stop being such cowards
It's a mystery and an adventure
Let's play and get me the creeps
Seriously guys
Let's get out of here
I'm getting goosebumps just being here
That's a scaredy cat
That laugh came from this room
Let's go and check it out
Look a ghost run
Okay, so now that we understand all the vocabulary
We saw in language takeaway
Why don't we take a look at two phrases
Now in fluency builder
Fluency builder
Well, shabby said
Where at this scary looking mansion
Scary looking mansion
So a scary looking mansion
Okay, so the mansion looks scary
All right, so a mansion is a big house
That looks very scary
Now this is a really useful and helpful pattern
You can use with English
Something looking
So adjective looking
Right, so you can say
Good looking
And there's lots of examples
So why don't we hear a few more now
Example one
That guy is making me nervous
He's really creepy looking
Example two
I saw the craziest looking house today
It was built upside down
Example three
What a nice looking dog
Can I pet him?
All right, great examples
And now we know how we can combine
Looking with different adjectives
Our next phrase, shabby said
This place gives me the creeps
All right, gives me the creeps
To give someone the creeps
So if something gives you the creeps
It makes you feel uncomfortable and scared
Maybe scared, maybe nervous
Okay, so why don't we give some examples
I could say
Hey, Marco, see that guy over there
He keeps looking at me
He's giving me the creeps
Okay, all right, can say
Clowns give me the creeps
Oh, that's right, you're afraid of clown
I'm afraid of clowns
Okay, give me the creeps
All right, well, it's a really helpful useful phrase
To use when you're talking about being afraid
Now why don't we listen to the dialogue
One final time
Hey, why are we out of the sky?
Looking man, it's like all true swooking
I told you already, shabby
The owner of the house says there's a ghost
Hunting his house, so we have to go in and investigate
I don't like this
Come on, guys, stop being such cowards
It's a mystery and an adventure
Let's play with the game
Let's play a game of the creeps
Seriously, guys, let's get out of here
I'm getting goosebumps just being here
He's shabby's a scaredy cat
That luck came from this room
Let's go and check it out
Look, a ghost run
Okay, so an interesting dialogue about ghosts and haunted houses
So what do you think, Erica?
Do you believe in ghosts?
Have you ever seen a ghost?
No, I totally do not believe in ghosts
But I understand that you disagree with me
Well, I've experienced strange things
But I don't know if it was a ghost or an alien
I don't know, it could have been anything
An alien
An invisible alien
Okay, so what happened?
Well, once I was having dinner with my parents
And we had a table in on top of the table
There was a glass full of water
And all of a sudden it started to move across the table
And then it started to spin while it moved
So was there an earthquake or something happening?
No, nothing
We were just the only thing on the whole table
That was moving was that
And we all just kind of stared at the glass moving
And we didn't know what to do
And then my mom started kind of giggling and nervous laugh
And we really didn't know what happened
I understand that in Latin America
People are more superstitious
They're more, they believe more in ghosts, right?
Exactly. In Latin America, people are very superstitious
They believe in ghosts or in spirits
Or we have a lot of urban legends about like a leprechaun
That lives under a bridge
Or somebody's grandma that comes and haunts them
Or visits them at night and stuff like that
So yeah, Latin American people are very superstitious in this sense
Yeah, I think in Anglo countries it's a little less common
To say that you believe in ghosts like maybe inside you
You think ghosts are true but you wouldn't really tell people that
Right, I think the difference would be that you have a different type of superstition
Like people are afraid of black cats
Or the floor or the number 13
Yeah, or opening your umbrella in a house
Exactly. Yeah, so because they consider it to be bad luck
But not because something like a ghost or an alien is going to come out and eat them
So listeners, why don't you tell us what you think about ghosts
Are people superstitious in your country?
Did they believe in ghosts?
Come to our website EnglishPod.com
And let us know and we'll see you guys there
Well thanks for downloading and goodbye