Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a very popular kind of movie.
That's right. Today we're talking about twilight and all the creatures that you can find in this
new movie. Okay so the name of the movie is twilight. Let's take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll be
back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure. What's playing? The new twilight movie!
Twilight? As in the vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand what
everyone is so excited about these films about vampires. It doesn't make sense. Of course it does.
It's like a modern tale of Romeo and Juliet. You have a couple that is in love but can't
be together because they're so different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength
is really sexy and there you have it. Plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie even
more enticing. I don't buy into that. I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and
everyone will be into where wolves are zombies.
All right we're back so now let's just jump into some vocab but let's take a look at what we've chosen
for you on language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay so language takeaway today Marko we have
three different kinds of creature or monster. That's right so if anyone knows about the movie
Twilight it's mostly about vampires. That's right so vampires are a kind of imaginary creature
that like to suck people's blood. Right. They have long teeth. That's right so they look like
people and they go out at night and they drink people's blood and they can't stand in the sunlight
because they will die if they're in the sunlight. That's right. All right so we have vampires and also
another type of imaginary creature that we find here is uh, where wolves we can find where wolves.
Okay so you know the word wolf, a wolf is an animal but a where wolf is a man or a woman who turns
into an animal when the moon is full. Right so you're a man or a woman by a day but then at night
when there is a full moon you transform into a wolf so you are a where wolf. And we have one other
kind of monster here this is a very disgusting kind of monster called a zombie. All right also
very popular in the movies you have zombie so they're people who are dead but they're still alive.
That's right so they can't think all they want to do is each other people and they're usually
very very stupid and you have to cut their heads off to kill them. That's right so zombies are also
a very popular type of creature in this movie so we have three creatures vampires, where wolves and
zombies but now let's move on to some of the other vocab that we found. When the friend was
explaining about the movie and how it's very cool she said that the cast is hip. Okay so something
that is hip is also very cool so a hip person is someone who's really interesting or cool or maybe
up to date current. Right very popular. So for example you can also talk about a place a restaurant
or a club as being very hip. That's right so you can say these days bell bottom pants are not
hip anymore they were hip in the 1970. That's right so they're not cool they're not popular they're
not up to date. Now moving on to the end of that paragraph we see that the explanation
continued and saying that the movie makes it even more enticing having a hip cast and a sexy theme.
So something that is enticing makes you want it okay so an enticing movie attracts people.
So I find a warm apple pie very enticing it makes me want to eat it. Okay so something that is
enticing basically makes you want to have it or it makes you desire it. Exactly. All right and
our last word for language takeaway when the friend was kind of skeptical and said you know what
I think it's just a fad. Okay something is a fad if it is a passing trend so it's not always
popular it's only popular for a short time. So the word is fad if a d it sounds very similar to fad
but it's not it's a fad fad. So we can say that twilight is a fad it's something that's popular now
but that might not be popular in two years. Exactly so it's something that's very popular now
but maybe later it won't be like way before example Harry Potter was a fad. Exactly so that's
language takeaway for today but don't go anywhere we still have some great phrases for you coming
up in fluency builder.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure what's playing? The new twilight movie. Twilight
as in the vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand what everyone is so
excited about these films about vampires it doesn't make sense. Of course it does it's like a modern
tale of Romeo and Juliet you have a couple that is in love but can't be together because they're so
different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength is really sexy and there you have it.
Plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie even more enticing. I don't buy into that.
I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and everyone will be into where wolves are zombies.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of phrases we've picked out for you on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. The first phrase that we have today is related to this idea of going to the
movies and so one of the characters today said sure I want to go to the movies what's playing?
That's right now this question is a key question and you can use this whenever you want to know
what movie is currently being shown at the theater. Alright the cinema. Okay so you put what
movie is playing there are many movies playing or there are no good movies playing tonight.
That's right. So movie plays at a theater. Exactly so you want to know what movie is playing? You
say what movie is playing tonight. Alright so now for our next phrase this is actually going back
to the qualities of vampires one of the people in the dialogue described vampires is having superhuman
strength. Okay so in this case super means more than so superhuman strength is more than
what's normal for a human being so maybe a human can pick up a table but superhuman strength means
that if I have it maybe I can pick up a car or something that's very unusual they're very heavy.
That's right so superhuman strength we're talking about how strong you are and then you can also
mix it up with other qualities of a person so for example you can have superhuman speed
very very fast. Superman is someone who had both superhuman strength and superhuman speed.
That's right so it's a way to describe a person having a quality that's more than normal.
And for our next phrase after superhuman strength and something that's really sexy that person
says and there you have it. And there you have it. So how do why do you end that sentence where and
there you have it. And there you have it means and that's the explanation why. Okay. So let's think of the
question. The question is why do people like these vampire movies and the other person said well
vampires are sexy and they're immortal and they have superhuman strength and there you have it.
So that means and that's why. Okay so it's usually of this phrase and there you have it.
You have to explain something or give a couple of ideas before you say it before you use it.
All right and exactly and the key here is that and there you have it comes at the end of that statement.
So always well you know why is Jim popular? You can say well he's funny he's smart. He's good looking
and there you have it. Right perfect. So you're basically saying and that's the reason why.
All right and for our last phrase when we were talking about a fad the person said pretty soon
this will pass and everyone will be into where will or zombie. So this might seem a little bit confusing.
What does it mean by everyone will be into where will be zombies? Okay so let's take a look at
this as a phrase to be into. I am into something you are into something. This means I am interested in.
Okay so I could say I am into books and movies. Marco what are you into? So if I say I am into
surfing and bungee jumping I would say it sounds like you're interested in or it sounds like you like
sports. Extreme sports. So you can be not only into activities but you can be into a specific type of
movies for example. I'm really into horror movies. And I could say I'm not into horror movies. I am
into romantic comedies. Okay so it's another way of saying that you enjoy it or you like it or you
realize some type of activity. Exactly. All right that's it for fluency builder. Let's take
another listen to today's dialogue and we'll be right back.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure what's playing? The new Twilight movie.
Twilight as in the Vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand what everyone is so
excited about these films about vampires. It doesn't make sense. Of course it does. It's like a
modern tale of Romeo and Juliet. You have a couple that is in love but can't be together because
they're so different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength is really sexy
and there you have it. Plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie even more enticing.
I don't buy into that. I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and everyone will be
into where wolves are zombies. All right we're back so obviously the dialogue revolves around
Twilight and Vampires but mostly it's all about as we said something that's hip.
That's current that's popular now but many times is also a fad. That's right so let's think
what was a fad from the 1980s? I think the 80s the fad was. Maybe you can talk about the
hairstyles. Men and women had those big kind of hairstyles long in the back and very tall in the
front. That's right so in the 80s as far as fashion fads things that were only popular for a
short time we had big hair and we had bright colors like electric pink and green and blue
and also those t-shirts that would change color when it was hot or cold. Oh those are really cool.
I think those should come back. Those were super hip. Well now it's hip to wear 80s clothes.
So it's another fad. Right because then that's called that you're being like what is it like retro?
Retro. Yeah. Retro means you like to use styles from a long time ago so yeah.
70s and the movies now before was magic and sorcerers you had Harry Potter. Now it's turned to vampires.
That's right. I wonder what the fad will be in a couple of years. I don't think I don't
agree with the person in today's dialogue. I don't think zombies will be a fad. There was a short
period a couple of years ago when there were many many zombie movies. Yeah. For example resident
evil or Sean of the dead. Yeah. But I wonder in the future if we're going to be seeing movies
about other things. Yeah I imagine maybe not in these these creatures. I don't know. I guess vampires
have always been kind of sexy if you're as you know they they're immortal and they're good
looking. They're usually very good looking and charming and that's how they get their victims. That's right.
But it's interesting to see let us know we really curious if there are any local fads in your country
because sometimes fads can be regional. That's right. So let us know what you're into. Say I'm into this.
Our website is EnglishPod.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.