Hello everyone and welcome back to English,
Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and it's the holiday season.
That's right, it's almost Christmas and so we are bringing you one of the most typical
Christmas songs with Christmas carols, I guess, in all over the world probably.
That's right and I've heard it in many different languages, even Chinese.
Yeah, even Chinese.
Ding dong, ding.
Okay, I'll have to ask.
Yeah, yeah, I have to ask.
But yeah, we're talking about jingle bells today.
So the famous song, jingle bells, you'll hear it everywhere, especially during the Christmas season.
I only during the Christmas season.
And so let's listen to the song.
The song is pretty long.
It has like a couple of different verses.
But we've taken the main one, the first one and the chorus, which are like the most famous
ones.
And so let's listen to the song.
This is going to be stuck in my head.
Oh, they are going to be so good.
I know, it's kind of catchy though.
How can you not get into the spirit with this song?
Well as you said, a carol, a Christmas carol is a song and they're meant to be catchy.
You know, you get them in your head and they stay there forever.
I think it's also because every mall or shopping center you go to, they're playing
these songs so they just kind of get stuck in your head.
In the background, all that I did is exactly.
Makes you want to shop more.
Or kill someone.
Alright, so there were probably a couple of different words that you didn't understand
here.
So we're going to go through the whole song, a little by little and we'll explain it.
So starting out with the first line is as dashing through the snow.
Well, okay, this is interesting because in sports, there's an event called a 100 meter
dash.
Okay, so a dash is a very quick run.
Very fast, right?
That's right.
So dashing through the snow is you're kind of running or going through the snow very quickly.
Alright, we don't know who is running through the snow, but we know something or someone
is going very quickly through the snow.
And in the second line, it says, you know, one horse opens the sleigh.
Okay, so now we know who's dashing through the snow.
It's a horse.
It's a horse in a, and you're in a sleigh.
Okay, so an open sleigh means that there's no roof.
So you're sitting under the stars and there's a horse pulling your sleigh through the snow.
Okay, so a sleigh is kind of like a vehicle for the snow, right?
There's no wheels.
Okay, because it's hard to drive and snow.
And so this is an old kind of vehicle that has maybe wood or metal underneath to make
it slide to make it slide very good.
Alright, and then we have this strange word here.
It's oh apostrophe, are over or the field we go.
Or the fields we go.
Well, this is very, very common in poetry.
Okay.
So this is a way to make the word over shorter because over, you can hear it two syllables
over, but sometimes we only want one.
So we say, or okay, or the fields we go over.
Okay, interesting.
Laughing all the way, bells on Bob Tails ring.
Now what are Bob Tails?
What are these bells on Bob Tails?
Okay, well Bob Tails are the tails of certain animals.
Okay.
So we can say we have a bunny rabbit with a Bob tail.
That means the tail sticks up, but it's also maybe reindeer have Bob Tails because their
tails stick up, you can see them.
Okay, so I guess in this case, because it's Christmas, these animals like reindeer and
rabbits have little bells on them.
That, and according to the next line, making spirits bright, right?
So you're making people happy.
That's right.
Spirit is your attitude or your soul.
And in this case, you're being made happy.
You're happy because it's Christmas, you're outside.
Very good.
And well, he says, what fun it is to laugh and sing a slaying song tonight.
Now slaying, we know that slay is this vehicle to go through this.
No, but a slaying song, I guess is.
Is the song we sing when we're in a slay?
So this isn't a real word, but this is something that makes the song kind of makes you
think that these people are just singing a special song for being in a slaying.
All right.
What are the chorus?
Jingle bells, jingle bells.
So this word, jingle.
It's a verb, right?
Yeah, two jingle.
We can do it with your keys, too.
To jingle is to make noise when metal is touching metal.
So we have bells and they think, thinking, thinking, they get each other.
I got some keys here.
I'll show you what jingleing is.
So we go like this.
Oh, jingle your keys, right?
Yeah, exactly.
So you can use it with keys with bells.
Can use it with anything else.
Anything that makes the sound like that?
Chimes, jingle.
Okay.
All right.
Very good.
So the way, oh, what fun it is to ride again in a one horse open slaying.
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle.
All the way.
So all the way, maybe we're going someplace.
All the way, wherever you're going, right?
Home or to dinner.
And oh, what fun it is to ride in a one horse open slay.
So the chorus is not very hard, and either is the first, the first, but you know, sometimes
the song is pretty fast.
So sometimes you don't really understand what they're saying.
Personally, I did not know the lyrics of Jingle bells until we started doing this part.
Really?
Well, because when we sing it, we mumble.
You know, you can't hear all the words.
You don't know the words, but dashing through the snow.
Sometimes you have to think of it very clearly.
Very good.
So that's all the words we have for this podcast.
It's a very good Christmas Carol.
It's very catchy and I don't know how old it is.
I've heard it since I was small.
Well, probably old enough to come from a time when there weren't cars because there
is a slay.
And when they use ore because I don't see people use ore anymore.
Now I think it's mostly just songs and poems.
You see it a lot in the 19th century.
Right.
And but it isn't interesting.
Also, I guess the relationship between the slaves and snow.
When Christmas is always related to this, even though, you know, in some places you don't
have snow during Christmas.
That's right.
It does.
I mean, we're here in Shanghai and we can hear people singing a song.
And there's no.
So I think it's just a way to think about the season of Christmas and the attitude of
people when it's Christmas time.
Right.
So I hope you enjoyed our lesson.
If you have any questions about this Christmas Carol, you can let us know on English
pod.com.
And we'll also post the other verses, the less known verses of jingle bells because it's
actually a pretty long song.
Very long.
And I don't know any of the other verses.
It's the biggest.
Exactly.
That's why we chose the first one and the chorus because it's the most popular one.
So we'll see you guys there and Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Bye.