Hello English learners. Welcome back to another edition here with us at EnglishPod.
My name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we are doing the third part of our old English
series. And today we're transported back to the 1970s. That's right. So we're going to learn
some 1970s slang. Some phrases that were really popular back in the 70s, but are also still
in use today. Exactly. So it's going to be a very cool lesson today. And before we start
with the dialogue, let's take a look at some of the words that we're going to find in
vocabulary preview. Very cablory preview. Well, we have two words for you in vocabulary
preview. And they're both found in the dialogue. The first one, roller rink. A roller
rink. A roller rink. Okay. So a roller rink. Let's break that down and let's look at the
first part. All right. So roller. We might recognize this from roller blades or roller
skates. Okay. So yeah, when you go roller blade in roller skating, those things that you
put on your feet to skate. Right. Wheels not not like a blade or a knife. Exactly. So that's
roller. And what about rink? Rink is the place where you do skating. Okay. So if you go to a
roller rink, it's this big area where everyone can roller blade or roller skate. That's
right. Okay. And what about the next word? A block. A block. Okay. So this is a noun, a block.
And a block is a part of a city that is surrounded by four streets. Okay. So a city is made
up of many blocks. Yep. And everyone lives on a block. Exactly. So it's a square within
the city. All right. Very good. So these are the two words that we previewed. And we're
going to listen to them now in the dialogue. We're going to hear two guys just talking
about normal everyday things, but we're going to be listening to them in 19 seven.
Hey man, how's it hanging? Hey man. Hey man. Everything is just groovy baby. Does
you cut the roller rink on Saturday? I heard it was far out man. I wanted to, but I ran
into this fuck city lady that just moved to my block. I was chatting her up a bit and
then we milled out at her plate right on right on. Well Jim went to the rink with
Sherry and he said it was done. No my it's he was low on bread but Sherry paid for everything.
Great. Jim is such a jive turkey man. He's always hitting me up for cash. Anyway, you
want a book and go grab some grub. Yeah man, I'm starving.
Okay groovy dialogue. Yeah, really nice huh? All right. So some interesting language in here
and like I said, it sounds a bit strange, but a lot of this is still used today in modern
English. So why don't we look at some of these words in language takeaway?
All right. On language takeaway today, we have the first word far out.
Far out. That was far out. To be far out. Okay. So it's just another way of saying cool.
Cool. That was nice. Yeah. It was really cool. So they went to the roller rink. It was
far out. It was really cool. But the other guy couldn't go because he saw a fuck city lady.
Okay. Foxy lady. Okay. Foxy lady. So basically a Foxy lady is a really good looking or sexy woman.
Right. Commonly, you would hear some men refer to a attractive woman as a fox.
Okay. So Foxy lady. Now, Marco, can we say a Foxy man? No. This is a phrase that you
would only use for women. Okay. So Foxy lady. Foxy lady. So after he met up with the Foxy lady,
they both just decided to mellow out at her place to mellow out to mellow out. Okay.
So mellow out. What does this mean, exactly? Basically just to relax. Right.
So to relax to take it easy to mellow out. So what did you do on the weekend? Oh,
nothing. I just stayed at home and mellowed out. Okay. All right. And so the response to that was
right on right on right on right on right on right on. And so basically they're saying,
okay, good. I agree. Yeah. This phrase is you can say as good. Yeah. That's nice or you can
also say it as well. Correct. Correct. I agree. So why don't we listen to some examples of
how we can use this word in other situations. Example one. Right on. You got a high
score. That's amazing. Example two. You got the job right on. Example three.
Jenny was right when she told me she thought Rick was no good for me. I should have
listened to her. Okay. So I think that's pretty clear. We can see how it means correct or
also okay. Good. All right. Right on. And now we also have another word that's similar to
far out. He said gravy gravy gravy. Now if you look it up in a dictionary, it's going to tell
you something else. Right. gravy is a sauce you put on meat. Right. But in this case, we say gravy
is cool. It's nice. Yeah. Right. So gravy. That was gravy. Mm-hmm. Now finally, at the end of their
conversation, they said, one a book. Okay. Let's book. So two book. It's a verb. Yeah. Interesting
verb. It basically means to leave a place quickly. Okay. So we have to book the police are
coming. Right. Or I got a book guys I'm late. So book to leave quickly to leave suddenly.
Yep. And that word is used quite commonly today, isn't it? Yeah. Yeah. It's used among like
younger people. You would say, yeah. Let's book this party is dead. Okay. Great. So there's a lot of
pretty cool phrases in this dialogue. Pretty groovy phrases. Why don't we hear them again in context?
Hey, man. How's it hanging? Hey. Everything is just groovy. Baby, did you go to the
roller rink on Saturday? I heard it was far out, man. I wanted to, but I ran into this
Foxy lady that just moved to my block. I was chatting her up a bit and then we
melod out at her place. Right on, right on. Well Jim went to the rink with Sherry and he said it
was done no matter. He was low on bread, but Sherry paid for everything. gravy. Jim is such a
giant turkey man. He's always hitting me up for cash. Anyway, you want a book and go grab some grub.
Yeah, man. I'm starving. All right. So now that we understand these six words that we saw in
language takeaway, it's time for us now to take a look at some great phrases that we can use today
in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay. So at the start of the conversation, there was an
interesting way he started talking to his friend, right? All right. He said, how's it hanging? How's
it hanging? Okay. So basically, how is it going? How's it going? How are you? Now you notice
in the spelling that we do have a G at the end, I and G, right? Yeah, but usually you don't really
pronounce the G in this context because it's very informal. So how's it hanging? How's it hanging?
So he said everything was just groovy and then he started telling him about how he met a girl and
he chatted her up a bit to chat her up. Okay. So to chat somebody up. So when you chat someone up,
you talk with them, right? Yeah, you're making conversation. But it's sort of it's more than just
conversation, isn't it? Yeah, you're trying to be a little bit flirty and maybe say nice romantic
phrases or something like that. Yeah. So usually it's between a woman and a man, right? And it's
the man who chats up a woman. Yeah, exactly. So a little bit of a sexist phrase here to chat someone
up or to chat up a girl, right? Okay. So he was chatting her up. That's right. And so they were talking
about how Jim went to the roller rink. But he didn't have any money, right? Because Jim is always
hitting his friends up for cash. Okay. So to hit someone up. To hit someone up. So before we explain
this word, let's listen to some other examples. So then we can maybe understand the meaning.
Example one. Can you believe Patrick? He came up to me a month ago and tried to hit me up for
some money. Example two. When I was a kid, I used to always hit my dad up for lunch money.
Example three. This is the last time I lend you money. Don't even try to
hit me up for more. All right. So when you hit someone up for something, you ask for it.
So usually it's to ask for money, right? That's right. Okay. So to hit someone up. And now for our
last phrase, let's book and it's go grab some grub. To grab some grub. Grab some grub. Okay. Let's
break this one down. With the final word, grub, what are we talking about? Grub is an informal way of
saying food. Okay. So to grab some grub is to get some food quickly. Yeah. Let's go get some food.
All right. So maybe it's time for us to grab some grub. And while we're doing that, you can
listen to the dialogue one last time.
Hey man. How's it hanging? Hey man. Everything is just groovy baby.
Did you cut the roller recon Saturday? I heard it was far out, man. I wanted to, but I ran into
this fucksy lady that just moved to my block. I was chatting her up a bit and then we milled out
it her plate right on right on. Well, Jim went to the Rinkley Sherry and he said it was
done. No my it's he was low on bread but Sherry paid for everything. Grimpy. Jim is such a
jive turkey man. He's always hitting me up for cash. Anyway, you want a book and go grab some grub?
Yeah man. I'm starving.
All right. So some interesting phrases and even though some of these words, you may not really
commonly hear anymore, they might still be using movies or something that's related to the
disco era because it's very very popular still, right? Yeah, that's right. Some of our more advanced
users could even use a lot of these phrases in a kind of funny way to reference back to 1970.
Yeah exactly. So it's fun and well you will use them or you will hear them from time to time
even today. And remember if you have any questions about the language you hear in these lessons,
check out our website at EnglishPod.com. Exactly. We're there to answer any questions and we'll see you
guys there. Thanks for listening and until next time. Goodbye. Bye.