Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're traveling a little bit and we need to book a hotel room.
That's right so today we're going to learn all the words and phrases that will help you talk to the receptionist
in order to book a hotel room. Let's check out our dialogue.
Yes, I am calling for Mexico. I will be in town next week and would like to know if you have
availability. Okay man can you tell me the date you expect to check in? Yes, July 9th. I will be there for
7 nights. We have a junior single suite or a superior double suite available for those dates.
What's the difference? The junior suite is smaller and has one twin bed. Well, the superior
suite has a double bed in mini bar. Okay. I would like to reserve the superior suite. It's breakfast included.
Yes, but faith breakfast is served every morning. I will need your name and your credit card
details in order to complete the reservation. Sure. My credit card number is.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So we've got a lot of great phrases and words today in language takeaway. The first one
that comes from the beginning of the dialogue, it's availability. All right so the woman wanted to know
if the hotel has availability. So what does that mean? That means do you have free rooms? Do you have
any rooms I could rent? So instead of saying do you have any free rooms or do you have rooms available?
You can just say do you have availability? That's right. So you're basically asking the person
do you have anything available? So what's your availability? Very good. Okay. All right. So we
ask the hotel if they have availability and obviously the receptionist needs to know when we expect
to check in. So this is a noun and a verb but in today's dialogue it's used as a verb. So it's
something we do to check in. So the person on the phone would like to know what date you expect to
check in. That means when will you arrive at our hotel? That's right so maybe we will arrive
to the city a couple of days before we check into the hotel. So we really specifically want to know
when are you going to start sleeping here? That's right and the opposite so when you leave the hotel
is called check out to check out. That's right. Okay so we want to check in on July 9th and the
receptionist tells us that we have available a single suite or a double suite. All right so these are
two different kinds of rooms. Now a suite is different from a room because it actually means that
the space you're going to use is more than one room. Maybe two rooms or three. That's right so it's
a little bit bigger than just a standard room. It might have a sitting area or a kitchen area so
that's what a suite is. Very expensive rooms are suites as well. They have a sitting area and a
kitchen and maybe even an extra bedroom. That's right. Okay so we have a single suite that means
that we have one of these big rooms that is only for one person. Yeah and a double suite means that
two or more people can sleep there. That's right so single will be one person and double will be two
people and we also heard similar words with the beds because sometimes the rooms aren't really
clear about what kind of beds they have. So this person asked what's the difference between these rooms
and the hotel employee answered while the junior suite has one twin bed. All right what's a twin bed?
So a twin bed is basically a bed that's only for one person. Only one person fits in there.
All right so it's a single it's a single bed basically we call it a twin. It's a standard size so
everywhere you go a twin is always for one person. That's right. All right and if you want to have
another person in bed we have to get a bigger one and what's that bigger bed called? It's called a double bed.
A double bed so again double double room double bed. So this means that two people can sleep on the
one bed. That's right so this is important because sometimes you want to book a hotel room and
it will be a double suite but it will have two twin beds. All right so it's a double room so it's
for two people but each person has their own small bed that's right. Two twin beds. Okay
and lastly the superior double suite not only had a double bed but also had a mini bar.
A mini bar so you know what a bar is it's a place you go to get some alcohol or some drinks
but a mini bar is a little bit different right? It's a little refrigerator or a little area where
you will have snacks and drinks that you can just basically take freely but obviously you will
have to pay afterwards. That's right so you can take them when you're staying there but when you
check out when you leave you have to pay for everything you ate or drank. That's right. Okay so a lot
of words there on language takeaway today let's take a break and listen to the dialogue again.
Madison sweet tell me I hope you. Yes I am calling for Mexico. I will be in town next week and
would like to know if you have availability. Okay ma'am can you tell me the date you expect to check in?
Yes July 9th I will be there for seven nights. We have a junior single suite or a superior double
suite available for those dates. What's the difference? The junior suite is smaller and has one twin bed
while the superior suite has a double bed in mini bar. Okay I would like to reserve the superior suite.
Is breakfast included? Yes but faith breakfast is served every morning. I will need your name
and your credit card details in order to complete the reservation. Sure my credit card number is.
All right so now it's time for some phrases let's start with fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So the first phrase in fluency builder might seem a little bit strange it's I will
be in town next week. I'll be in town and what town? That's right. If you say I will be in town
that basically says I will be in this town. I will be there. I will be here. So I'll be in the town
your in. This is interesting. So when I'm talking to someone maybe Marco is in Chicago and I'm in New York.
I call I say hey Marco I'll be in town next week. What are you doing? Right. You want to have a drink?
That means I'm going to be where? You're going to be in Chicago. That's right I'll be in Chicago
like Marco is. I'm not going to talk about where I'm now. This usually means I'm going somewhere else.
That's right. So actually you can tell your friends that you're going to be in town or
sometimes you have to tell someone you're going to be out of town. I'll be out of town. That means
I won't be where I am now. I won't be in New York. I'll be somewhere else. I'll be in Chicago.
That's right. All right so now moving on where when we were talking specifically about the hotel
and maybe the what is included with our suite we asked a very important question is breakfast and
included in what in the price. All right so this is a very common question like you're saying Marco.
But it's not obvious. So when you ask is breakfast included that means do I have to pay extra for breakfast?
Hmm. If breakfast is included I don't have to pay. If it's not included that means I have to pay extra for breakfast.
That's right and in this case breakfast is included but not just any breakfast it's a buffet breakfast.
My favorite kind of breakfast. So this is pretty common with hotels. They they will serve a buffet breakfast
from 7 a.m. to 9 a.m. or whatever. A buffet means that there's a room with tables and food on the tables.
Right. So you don't order food. You just take whatever you want. That's right. So you can take
whatever you want and usually as much as you want. That's the best part. Okay so now we know that
breakfast is included. We know what a room is like so we're gonna make the reservation and the hotel
employees says that he needs our credit card details to complete the reservation. Credit card details.
Now you might be wondering what details. Credit card details means the specific information on your
credit card. All right so this is pretty common when you're making a purchase on the phone or on the internet.
You have to enter. You have to provide your credit card details. Right. That means your name.
Your credit card number. And the expiration date which is when the card will no longer be useful.
So it's necessary because obviously you can say yeah I'm gonna be there tomorrow and then you don't
show up in the hotel loses money so they need to make sure that they have you somehow. Yeah that's
their way of protecting themselves. They want to give you the room but they also don't want to lose money.
Okay so let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
You're going to be a little bit more.
Madison sweet. Tell me I help you. Yes I am calling from Mexico. I will be in town next week and
would like to know if you have availability. Okay man can you tell me the date you expect to check in.
Yes July 9th I will be there for seven nights. We have a junior single suite or a superior double
suite available for those dates. What's the difference? The junior suite is smaller and has one
twin bed. Well the superior suite has a double bed and mini bar. Okay I would like to reserve
the superior suite. It's breakfast included. Yes but fate breakfast is served every morning. I will
need your name and your credit card details in order to complete the reservation. Sure my credit card number is.
All right so talking about the hotels I think one of the most important things out of this
well not important but also something you should know is that the mini bar is always so expensive.
It is expensive. Be very careful when you're going into that mini bar. Sometimes it seems like
a really good idea. You're hungry in there crackers or you want to beer. But you have to look
at the menu because the menu will have the prices and maybe something that's really cheap in
a store outside is really expensive at a hotel. Yeah and I think sometimes I don't know sometimes
it's even hard to find that little menu so you don't even know what the prices are but you
so thirsty you just want to have something to drink now and it ends up costing you $10.
That's right so be careful anytime you're in a hotel room expect the prices to be pretty high
for the things in the hotel. Unless of course there's a sign or a piece of paper that says
that something is free or complimentary. Yeah that's right complimentary water is very common in
hotels. There'll be two free bottles of water. That's right so complimentary means you don't
have to pay for it but if there's no sign then expect to pay a lot. That's right. Okay so if you
guys have any questions or any doubts or you want to suggest any other lesson topic you can visit us
at EnglishPod.com. We'll hope to see you there until next time. Bye bye.