Hello English learners, welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be bringing you a very useful lesson about being sick
Yeah, we're going to learn how to tell your boss that you can't go to work because you're sick
Exactly, this is really important because we all get sick and sometimes you just can't go to work
Yes, or maybe sometimes you just don't want to go to work
Exactly, maybe you're lying, but we're going to be teaching you how to do it anyways
So before we start with our dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
In this vocabulary preview, we have two words for you
The first one is quite ill
Quite ill
So quite ill
Very sick
Very sick, quite is a synonym of very
Exactly
Okay, yeah, ill
Sick, sick
Yep, so they both mean the same thing no difference no difference at all
I just think ill is more common in British English
Hmm, exactly
All right, let's take a look at our second word flu the flu the flu
So the flu is a virus
Yeah, it's a sickness
Okay, and it's very similar to a cold
Yes, but just a lot worse a lot worse so it's stronger
Yeah, yeah
It's also called influenza
influenza
Exactly, so the flu
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue. What's going to happen here today?
Well, we're going to listen as Julie calls her boss to tell him she's sick
All right, but is she really sick?
I don't know, let's find out
Hello Daniel speaking, how may help you?
Hi Daniel, Julie here
Well, hi Julie, how are you?
Actually, I'm feeling quite ill today
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that, what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu
I have a headache
So throat
Everybody knows and I'm feeling slightly feverish
See, so you're calling in sick?
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off to recover
Okay, then try and get some rest
All right, so Julie didn't really seem to be sick, huh?
Yeah, I don't know that cough was just a little too much
It seemed like she was acting. Yeah, all right, so let's take a look at some of this full
Cavalry in language takeaway
Language takeaway
We have five words for you here and these are all great words to describe a sickness, right?
All right, the first one, headache
headache, headache, headache
So when you have a headache, you have a sore head, right?
Your head hurts, so it's pretty simple. Yep, you have a headache
It's the way you feel after
Being at the bar too late. Yeah, when you drink too much, you get a headache. Yeah, all right, let's take a look at our next word
sore throat sore throat sore throat sore throat
So basically we have two words here. Let's look at the first one's sore
Herding it hurts, right? And your throat is well, it's you know it's the part right here with a bat
You can't see me
Well, it's the part at the back of your mouth that goes down to your stomach. All right, that's your throat. Yeah, so you use your throat to swallow
Okay now we can use the word sore with different body parts, right? Yeah, like a sore back a sore back, right?
Or maybe you were playing tennis all weekend, so you have a sore arm
Or even a sore neck, right?
So the word sore let's take a look at our third word
Roney knows
Roney knows this is a very strange word. I know
But it doesn't mean that your nose is running, right? No, but okay
No, but when you have a runny nose
There's lots of water coming out of your nose, right? Right? So it's interesting though because when you run
You go fast, right?
So a lot of water is coming fast out of your nose
You know, it's runny nose. Yeah, okay our fourth word today slightly feverish slightly feverish
slightly feverish slightly feverish
So again slightly is a little bit a little bit right a little bit and feverish well, let's break this word down
We know fever, right?
So when you're when your body is very very hot because you're sick
So feverish is the feeling of your body being very very hot
Okay, so you have a high temperature. It's not that you have a high temperature, but you feel like you have a high temperature
Okay, so slightly feverish and our last word
To recover recover recover recover
So this means to get better, right?
Can you only use it when you're sick? So when you recover you get better and you rest so maybe you can say
I was so busy this week. I need to recover this weekend. Okay, so yeah, if you feel tired
You feel sick you can recover
Okay, let's listen to our dialogue again and we can listen to these words that we've just talked about
Hello Daniel speaking how my help you
Daniel Julie here
Hi Julie how are you actually I'm feeling quite ill today. Oh, I'm sorry to hear that what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache
So throat
Everybody knows and I'm feeling slightly feverish. I see so you're calling in sick
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off
To recover okay then try and get some rest
In this dialogue we listen to some really interesting phrases of how you can tell your boss that you are feeling sick, right?
Yeah, some great phrases. So let's look at these and fluency builder
Fluency builder okay. Let's take a look at our first phrase on fluency builder
I'm coming down with I'm coming down with
I'm coming down with I'm coming down with all right, so let's listen to some examples and then we'll come back and explain this interesting phrase
Example one my throat really hurts. I think I'm coming down with a cold
Example two
You have a runny nose are you coming down with the flu?
Example three
I don't feel well. I think I'm coming down with something
Okay, so basically coming down with means starting to get sick I'm beginning to feel sick. Yes, okay
So you can use it with I'm coming down with the flu. I'm coming down with a cold
Coming down with a cough. Yeah, or I'm coming down with something with something you don't know what it is exactly
Okay, let's take a look at our second phrase calling in sick calling in sick
Okay calling in sick
So this phrase is great, you know when you say I'm calling in sick you're saying hey
I'm not going to come to work today because I am sick
Okay, so literally it means that you call your office. Yeah, you say you're not going to work. Yes
But it's great because it's three words that show such a long idea right because otherwise you would have to say
I'm calling because I don't feel well
So I'm not going to go to work. Yes, but if you say I'm calling in sick everyone knows everyone understands that you're not going to go to work
Yep, okay now let's take a look at our last phrase take the day off take the day off
Take the day off take the day off. Now. This is a great phrase to take the day off is to
Not go to work on that day. Yes now you can say take the week off. Take the month off take the month off or take the year off
If you are so lucky
All right, so take the day off means to not go to work on that day
All right, let's listen to our dialogue again now and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more
Hi Daniel juli here
Hi juli how are you? Actually I'm feeling quite ill today. Oh, I'm sorry to hear that what's wrong?
I think I'm coming down with the flu. I have a headache. Uh, a sore throat.
Everybody knows and I'm feeling slightly feverish. See, so you're calling in sick.
Yes, I was hoping to take the day off to recover. Okay
Try and get some rest
Well Marco have you ever done what juli did? Did you ever call your boss to say you're sick when you're not really?
Yeah, of course. I mean sometimes you just don't feel very well
But you're not really sick. You just don't feel like going to work. Yes, or sometimes you have something to do
Right, yep, you know what we call those in Canada
We call them personal days personal days. Yeah, so you say oh, I'm gonna take a personal day. I mean I'm gonna call in sick
But then go shopping
We used to do that a lot because for example soccer games are such a big deal. Oh, yep, and you know
Sometimes you would have a soccer match between I don't know Brazil and it would be maybe a 10 a.m. or 11 a.m.
So everyone would call and sick on that day. Yes, so the boss at least could plan that you would have an empty office
Yeah, or sometimes you would take half the day off
So you would just go you say well, I'm not gonna make it in the morning, but I'll come in the afternoon
So you would recover very quickly. Yeah, I'm feeling a little bit sick, but I'm going to be better and you have to
New
All right, so
Well if you have any questions or comments, please come to our website and if you have any calling in six stories
Please let us know yes you can visit us at EnglishPod.com and Marko and I are always there to answer your questions
All right folks, so we'll see you next time. Thanks for listening. Goodbye