Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson with us here at EnglishPod. My name is Marko
and I'm Erica and today we're going out to eat. Yes, good thing too because I'm hungry.
It's almost lunchtime. So today we're going to be talking about eating at a restaurant and giving some great
recommendations and suggestions. Yes, we have language for describing food for describing restaurants
and for making suggestions. Great. So let's start with our vocabulary preview for this lesson.
The vocabulary preview. We have two words today from our dialogue, which you'll need to know to
understand the dialogue. Great. The first one that we have today is food poisoning. Food poisoning.
Food poisoning. Food poisoning. So food poisoning is not a good thing. Not a good thing. It is
when you eat some bad food and that food makes you sick. So you get food poisoning. Okay, so
food poisoning. Yeah, not a good thing. Okay, the next word. A allergic allergic allergic.
So when you're allergic to something, it makes you sick. That one thing makes you sick. Right.
For example, I'm allergic to seafood. Right. If I eat seafood, I cannot breathe. Okay, so you
definitely want to stay away from fish. Yes. Yes. Some people are allergic to nuts like peanuts. Or maybe
milk, milk. Yeah. Cool. So when one type of food makes you sick, you are allergic to that food.
Okay. Great. So with this in mind, now we can listen to our dialogue for the first time at its
normal speed, but don't worry if you don't get everything now because we'll come back and teach you
the important language. Do you have any plans for the evening? We were thinking of checking out a
restaurant in the neighborhood. Do you have any suggestions? I know there's really nice Italian place.
The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful. I'd recommend giving it to try. Actually,
I'm not all that crazy about Italian food. I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter.
In that case, I know a great little bistro and they could really taste your seafood platter.
The fish is outstanding. It sounds fantastic, but I'm allergic to seafood so. Okay. Well, let me think.
Oh, I know this great little place is just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing
sandwiches. You can give them a try. Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning.
Remember?
Well, I'm getting hungry just thinking about all of those great restaurants. Yes, some really good
recommendations except for food poisoning. I know. That's okay. Let's start with our language
for this lesson. Language takeaway. Our first word on language takeaway is
check out. Check out. Check out. Check out. Check out. So we have some great examples on how we can use
check out in different situations and then you can understand the meaning. Example one.
Have you been to New Café next door? Yeah, I checked it out yesterday. The food was great.
Example two. Hey, check out my new car.
Example three. I'm going to check out the new shopping mall these weekends.
So I can understand that it just means look at. Yeah, look at. Or yeah, or go see. So let's go check out
that new bar in town. Yeah, okay. Cool. Next word is bistro bistro bistro bistro. So what's a bistro?
It's kind of complicated but it's like a small restaurant that's not really cheap though. Not so
cheap but not so expensive. And it's usually French. Yes, so it's small informal restaurant. Yeah,
bistro. Mm-hmm. Okay, so our third phrase for today is not all that crazy about. Not all that crazy
about. I'm not all that crazy about. Okay, again kind of a funny phrase but we've got some examples
that will help you understand the meaning. Example one. Do you want to go shopping with me tomorrow?
I'm not all that crazy about shopping. I don't like spending money. Example two.
I'm not crazy about jazz music. I changed the song.
So this is just a really polite way of saying you don't like something. Exactly. But now the
opposite of this would be tasty. That's our fourth word tasty tasty. So when something is tasty,
it's good. It's good. Like delicious delicious. Yeah, you know what? In English we almost never say
the food is delicious but we always say it's really tasty. Yes. This is really tasty. Yes. Okay.
tasty. And our last phrase for language takeaway in the mood for in the mood for in the mood for
let's listen to some examples of this phrase and we'll understand the meaning a little bit better.
Example one. We always eat hamburgers for dinner. I'm in the mood for something different.
Example two. Let's watch movie. How about Texas, Chainsaw, Massica? I am not in the mood for a
horror movie. So if I'm in the mood for something I feel like doing or eating or watching or
watching. Yeah, it means you want to do that now. Yeah. I'm in the mood for. Okay.
Some great language we just looked at and I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time.
Do you two have any plans for the evening? We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the
neighborhood. Do you have any suggestions? I know this really nice Italian place.
The food is fantastic and the decor is beautiful. I'd recommend giving it a try.
Actually, I'm not all that crazy about Italian food. I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter.
In that case, I know a great little bistro. They make a really tasty seafood platter.
The fish is outstanding. It sounds fantastic but I'm allergic to seafood so...
Okay, well let me think. Oh, I know this great little place. It's just a hole in the wall
but they do the most amazing sandwiches. You've got to give them a try.
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning. Remember?
Okay, some really great and useful phrases there and I know you want to talk about specifically
some of these phrases. Yes, today's lesson is all about making recommendations, right?
Right. So let's look at some useful phrases in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So in the dialogue, we heard a great way of asking for a suggestion. That's right. Let's listen.
Do you have any suggestions? Do you have any suggestions?
So that's how you would ask for a suggestion or you can say something else like, do you have any ideas?
Yeah, or you might say, do you have any thoughts?
Okay, so that's great ways.
Asking for a suggestion. Yep. In response to this, you can say something like this.
I'd recommend giving it a try. I'd recommend giving it a try.
We also heard another phrase that we use for giving suggestions.
You can give them a try.
You've got to give them a try.
So these two phrases are great. I'd recommend or you got to give them a try.
Great ways of suggesting. Yes. Now what's really important here is the pronunciation of these words, right?
Yeah, you'll notice that we don't say I would recommend.
Right. We use the contraction I'd. I'd. I'd recommend. I'd recommend.
Similarly, in the phrase you have got to, we shorten that to say, you got to. You got to give them a try.
You got to. You know what guys, if you can shorten your phrases like this, if you can push the sounds together,
you'll sound a lot more natural. And also you'll be able to understand because in movies or
in shows, they will never say you have got to give them a try. Yeah. So if you know how to use this
form, you'll understand what they mean. Exactly. Okay, great. Well, why don't we listen to the dialogue
a third time and you'll hear some of these contractions in the dialogue.
Do you have any plans for the evening? We were thinking of checking out a restaurant in the neighborhood.
Do you have any suggestions? I know there's really nice Italian place. The food is fantastic
and the decor is beautiful. I'd recommend giving it a try. Actually, I'm not all that crazy about
Italian food. I'm in the mood for something a bit lighter. In that case, I know a great little
bistro. They make a really tasty seafood platter. The fish is outstanding. It sounds fantastic,
but I'm allergic to seafood, so... Okay, well, let me think. Oh, I know this great little place.
It's just a hole in the wall, but they do the most amazing sandwiches. You can give them a try.
Ella, you took me there last time I visited and I got food poisoning. Remember?
Okay, great dialogue and Erica, I know that you have some food poisoning stories for us.
I don't know about stories, but I've definitely had food poisoning before. One of the worst times
that I ever had food poisoning was when I was traveling in Morocco. Okay. I had some really
amazing orange juice, really fresh squeeze that day in the morning and then I got on a bus.
Okay, I think you can see where this is going. Yeah, so I was on the bus and then I started to feel really
sick and I was just hoping and hoping and hoping that the bus ride would be over soon,
but unfortunately it wasn't. Oh, no. All I can say is that I was sick and I can say is that I was
pretty sick and really, really unhappy. Yeah, I bet. Well, that's very strange that you got sick
from an orange juice, huh? Well, yeah, maybe it was with some dirty water or something like that. I don't
know, it was just, it was a terrible situation. Yeah, it's always complicated when you're traveling
to other countries. It could be the water. It could be the way they prepare things. Yeah, yeah,
food poisoning. Guys, I hope that you don't get food poisoning. And if you have any food poisoning
stories, it would be great for you to share them. Yes, at our website EnglishPod.com. And we'll see
you there to answer all your questions and comments, but now we have to go. Okay, guys, thanks for
listening. We'll see you there. Bye bye.