Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and as you probably notice on our website this is one of many different parts
of a series all about having an interview in English. This is a job interview and at this point
we're at about part 7. That's right. So today what we're going to talk about is the key question
whenever you're having a job interview is they ask you to describe your key strengths and this is
our word of for vocabulary preview today. So let's take a look at it.
Very cablory preview. Okay so you might have heard the word strength before this is something
that you're good at and so key strength or key strengths plural would be things that you think are
most important about you as far as the things that you do well. That's right. So as we mentioned
that your boss or your potential boss might ask you to describe your key strength. So you're
going to mention a lot of adjectives positive adjectives saying how good of a worker you are.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue? Let's see what Rebecca has to say about her key strengths
and we'll look at those in a little bit.
Okay Rebecca now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background but what about
you as a person? How do you describe your key strengths? Well Mr. Parsons as I mentioned before
and someone who needs new challenges I'm really focused and hard working. I think my academic
results prove this. Yes true but how about other personal qualities? Well I believe I'm a good
team player but I can also work well independently. I'm very enthusiastic and well I hope my colleagues
would agree and fun to work with. What would you say is your most positive quality? Hmm that's
a tough question but I would have to say my passion. I'm really passionate about journalism
and passionate about my career. All right so she obviously has a lot of good key strengths why don't
we analyze a couple of those on language takeaway? Language takeaway. So one of the first things
that Rebecca mentions is that she's really focused. Okay so this this word focused what does
this mean? All right so if a person is focused basically you're saying that you concentrate on your work.
That's right and someone whose focus might be very good in a noisy office or in a place that
is full of distractions like you said because they don't stop their work and think about the
noise or move around or go talk to people. Someone who is focused just sits down and can do a lot
of work all at once. That's right so she describes herself as focused and hard working.
So hard working means basically what it sounds like that someone works very hard that means they
put in a lot of hours they get their work done. They're really really dependable. That's right so
as you as you can see we use the word hard working together. So if you work hard you don't say I
I work hard. You can't say that but if you want to use it as an adjective you say I am hard working.
The opposite of course would be lazy. That's right okay so we're focused we're hard working
and she also said that she is a good team player. Okay this is a really key phrase here because
it's something that employers so people who are hiring new staff like to look out for because most
jobs you don't work alone. You work with other people and so a team player is someone who works well
in a group or works well with others. That's right so a team player. Everyone wants to have a good
team player working for their team for their company and apart from being a good team player you also
want to be enthusiastic. That's right so this means that you are interested in what you do you
are excited about it. It's not like oh god I have to do this report. It's like oh wow I get to do
this report. I'm enthusiastic. I'm really interested. I'm going to put a lot of energy into it.
That's right okay so an enthusiastic person not only can be about working you can be enthusiastic about
anything about I don't know painting your house about going on a trip. Exactly enthusiastic.
All right and our last word for language takeaway is also a good quality to have if you are
passionate about what you do or what you're doing. So someone who is passionate about something
really really likes that thing. That means that they love to do it or love to see it.
Passion is the opposite of not interested okay so you're really really emotional and excited and
interested in something. That's right so you are passionate about something. It comes from the
nouned passion so you have a passion for painting maybe you love to paint so you're very
passionate about painting. So a lot of great adjectives there to describe it yourself in a good way.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Okay Rebecca now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background but what about you
as a person? How do you describe your key strengths? Well Mr. Parsons as I mentioned before
I'm someone who needs new challenges I'm really focused and hardworking. I think my academic results
prove this. Yes true but how about other personal qualities? Well I believe I'm a good team player
but I can also work well independently. I'm very enthusiastic and well I hope my colleagues would
agree I'm fun to work with. What would you say is your most positive quality? Hmm that's a tough
question but I would have to say my passion. I'm really passionate about journalism and passionate about
my career. Alright so on fluency builder today we've picked out three key phrases. Let's
look at the first one when Rebecca said I'm someone who needs new challenges. Okay so this
structure I'm someone who is something that you hear a lot of and you can actually fill in the end of
that sentence with a number of different phrases so in here we heard I'm someone who needs new challenges.
We could also say I'm someone who needs structure. Alright so we can also change the verb right
from needs to. I'm someone who likes a challenge or maybe Tracy is someone who requires a lot of
attention. Alright so this is a way to introduce a characteristic of yourself so you're telling people
something about yourself. Okay very good so moving on we also saw that Rebecca said that she is fun
to work with. I'm fun to work with. Okay so let's just treat this like a little fixed phrase.
We say this about people all the time he's fun to work with. She's fun to work with or this group is
really fun to work with. They're all really fun to work with. So that means that it's not serious that
you really enjoy doing it. So it's a little fixed phrase that you can use to say that you know it's nice
to work with with Rebecca or that she's very you know not serious not a mean person. That's right
and finally we have a phrase at the end. Rebecca gets a here's a question she thinks is very
difficult. She calls it a tough question and so a tough question is something that is very hard to answer.
That's right she says hmm that's a tough question. So she's basically acknowledging the fact that
the question is difficult a tough question. Now we can combine this word tough with other things.
That's right you can say it's a tough situation. That means it's a hard situation to handle.
You could also say he's having a tough time. That means that right now in his lives there are
many things that are difficult for him and so tough means difficult or hard or unpleasant.
Okay very good. So a lot of good stuff coming from Rebecca mentioning all the positive things about
her. Why don't we listen to her dialogue one last time?
Okay Rebecca now you've given me a good idea of your work and academic background. But what about
you as a person? How do you describe your key strengths? Well Mr. Parsons as I mentioned before
I'm someone who needs new challenges. I'm really focused and hard working. I think my academic
results prove this. Yes true but how about other personal qualities? Well I believe I'm a good
team player but I can also work well independently. I'm very enthusiastic and well I hope my colleagues
would agree and fun to work with. What would you say is your most positive quality?
That's a tough question but I would have to say my passion. I'm really passionate about journalism
and passionate about my career.
Alright so talking about key strengths I think it's always difficult to talk about yourself
and still sound a little bit humble to not sound like arrogant. Like saying I'm the best.
Right well that's the key here I think you want to say really good things about yourself because
you're a salesperson and you're selling your personality but at the same time you don't want
to sound like a jerk. Like I'm the best I'm so smart I'm so clever. That's a little bit off-putting
it makes people uncomfortable. So I think the trick is a balance. Right and I guess if you use
words such as this like you know I'm focused I'm hard of working. I am independent. I have
a passion for this. It makes you sound like you're really good worker but you're not arrogant.
You're not saying oh well you know I'm the best of what I do or something like that. Right so
you're basically saying these are my skills but you know obviously I'm not the only person who
has these great skills. That's right okay so that's all the time we have for today be sure to
join us next week we're also going to have kind of part two of this when we talk about our
weaknesses so this this time we talked about our strengths then we'll talk about weaknesses.
That's right so we hope that you will check out our website Englishpad.com if you have questions
or comments leave them there for us and we'll be in touch very soon. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.