Hello everyone, welcome to another lesson at English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine, so Marco, what are we talking about today?
Today we're going to be talking about a popular topic all over the world and that is smoking.
Well, not so popular in the States right now to be honest.
Well, that's the thing. And every country in the world now they are becoming more strict on
smoking and where you can smoke, so it's becoming very difficult for smokers nowadays.
Well, it's a good reason to want a quit. And that's what we're going to be talking about today is
is quitting smoking. Well, before we get going, we do have a really important phrase that we should
preview in today's vocabulary preview. Very cablory preview. All right, so on vocabulary preview,
we're going to take a look at this word pack of smokes. Pack of smokes. So a pack of smokes. So
smokes is a word for cigarettes. It's the same thing. Smokes or cigarettes. Right. But a
pack is like 20 cigarettes. It's a box of cigarettes. You buy them in a pack. You don't just buy one at
a time. So again, the phrase is pack of smokes. Pack of smokes. So why don't we listen to our dialogue
for the first time and see what's going on with this smoker?
Oh, it smells like an ash train here. Hi honey. What's wrong? Why do you have that look on your face?
What's wrong? I thought we agreed you were going to quit smoking. No, I said I was going to cut
down, which is very different. You can't just expect me to go cold turkey overnight. Look,
there are other ways to quit. You can try the nicotine patch or nicotine chewing gum. We
spend a fortune on cigarettes every month and now laws are cracking down and not allowing
smoking in any public place. It's not like you can just light up like before. I know, I know.
I really am trying, but I don't have the will power to just quit. I can't fight with the urge
to reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee or after lunch. Please understand.
Fine. I want to divorce.
Sorry. I just smoked the pack. I said,
you do smoke. Don't you? Well, we'll talk about that later. All right. So it is a little bit
extreme that I mean he's divorcing her because she won't quit. Well, some people really are health
conscious and are afraid of the negative side of smoking, which has a lot of health side of
that. Yeah. Well, as he was complaining about all the negative effects and the negative aspects of
smoking, he did mention both of them mentioned a lot of great words and phrases. So why don't we
take a look at them now in language takeaway? Language takeaway. Well, this first word is a word that's
very important for any smoker who goes to a bar or restaurant and needs to put the ash somewhere.
Right? So when you smoke, there's some ash. There's some messy dirty stuff. And you need an
ash tray to collect it. And ash tray. So an ash tray is something that's usually round or square
and you put it on a table and it's just very helpful to keep the house clean or restaurant clean.
So if you're in a restaurant, you say, hey, can I have an ash tray, please?
So the residue or the the stuff that when you're smoking, it comes out the gray, I don't know,
like dust, it's called ash. Right. And this is a tray. But the complaint here is, oh, it smells like
an ash tray in here. That means it smells really, really bad in here. Yeah, it smells like cigarettes.
Yeah. So that word again is ash tray. Ash tray. All right. Well, and the guy was complaining and he said,
well, I thought you were going to quit smoking and she said, no, no, I said I was going to cut down.
She says it's very different from quitting smoking. So Marco, maybe we should talk about how
cutting down and quitting are different. All right. So if I say I'm going to cut down on smoking,
it's just I'm going to smoke less. Mm. Okay. So let's take an example. I smoke 10 cigarettes a day,
but I want to cut down. How many should I smoke later? Maybe like two or three? Three, two, three.
Instead of quitting. So if you quit smoking, that would mean zero zero cigarettes. No smoking anymore.
Right. All right. So you can also cut down on carbs like carbohydrates. So some people who cut
down on carbs eat less bread. They don't eat any pasta. So these are really good ways of
trying to talk about dieting as well as smoking. Right. And I think we have a couple of examples of
other ways we can use this phrase cut down. So let's listen to them now.
Example one. Our company has decided to cut down our workload. So from now on, we leave it
3 pm every Friday. Example two. You should really cut down on the amount of salt you eat.
It's not good for you. Example three. My doctor told me I need to cut down on fatty foods because
of my heart condition. And when you want to smoke a cigarette, you have to do something first
with some fires. We call this lighting up to light up. So lighting up, it doesn't mean turning on the
light. It actually means using a lighter or some fire to start your cigarette. Right. So you want to
light up with the lighter matches or some sort of fire. The the man says the husband says it's not
like you can just light up like before that means it's not like you can just smoke like before.
So in some cases light up means to smoke a cigarette. We're in a movie theater and someone likes a
cigarette. And I say, oh, you can't light up in here. Right. So you can't smoke in here. You can't smoke
again. It's another way of saying smoking. Mm-hmm. Very good. And she was explaining how difficult it is
and she's trying to quit. But she said I don't have the wheel power to just quit.
Ooh, wheel power. So this is an important word. Wheel power. Wheel power. You think of the main
part of this word is will. That means the desire to do something. You want to do something. So if I have
wheel power, I have strong wheel power. What am I saying? You're saying that you can make a decision
and you can follow your decision. So I decide not to eat cake. I have very strong wheel power. So I
never eat cake. Mm-hmm. If I don't have strong wheel power, maybe I sometimes eat cake.
Secretly eat cake in the middle of the night from my refrigerator. So that happens, right?
Sometimes you don't have strong enough wheel power so you kind of eat a little bit of cake.
Yeah. Nobody's watching. Exactly. And you can have wheel power about lots of different things.
So this is a great word again to use when you're talking about dieting or smoking or drinking.
Any type of maybe temptation. Mm-hmm. Exactly. All right. And well, she said she had this urge
to reach for her pack of smokes. Ooh, urge is another good one. It's very similar to wheel power,
but an urge is kind of like a physical feeling that makes you want to do something.
So you have like this strong desire. Mm-hmm. So I have the urge to go swimming today. I don't know
why, but I really want to. All right. You have an urge. Interesting word.
Pragnant women often have these kinds of things too. I have the urge to do something.
We also call them cravings. Oh cravings are urge to do something. All right. Interesting.
So you're taking a look at these five great words and I think we should listen to a dialogue again.
We're going to slow it down just a little bit and then we'll come back and talk some more.
Oh, it smells like an ash tray in here. Hi honey.
What's wrong? Why do you have that look on your face? What's wrong? I thought we agreed that you were
going to quit smoking. No. I said I was going to cut down, which is very different.
You can't just expect me to go cold turkey overnight. Look, there are other ways to quit. You can
try the nicotine patch or nicotine chewing gum. We spend a fortune on cigarettes every month
and now laws are cracking down and not allowing smoking in any public place. It's not like you can
just light up like before. I know. I know. I really am trying, but I don't have the will power to just
quit. I can't fight with the urge to reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee or
after lunch. Please understand. Fine. I want a divorce.
And we are back. So we have a great part of our show. We like to talk about some phrases that help you
attain fluency. That means sounding like a native speaker of English and today's phrases are
wonderful. All right. So let's take a look at them now in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So on fluency builder today, let's take a look at two different phrases and let's start with the
first one. She mentioned something about going cold turkey overnight. What is that phrase? Gold
cold turkey. Now this is a very strange phrase. Okay. So first of all, why would a turkey be cold?
They have lots of feathers. And second of all, why would it? What does it have to do with cigarettes?
Right. So if I say I'm going cold turkey, what is that? So just take this as a phrase. Don't
think about the actual words because they won't make sense in this context. But we're talking
about is quitting smoking entirely. You're not going to cut down. That means today, I'm not going
to smoke at all. And I'm never going to smoke again. That means never ever will I smoke another
cigarette. So it's cold turkey. So if I go cold turkey means I stop doing something immediately
and suddenly and forever. And it's entirely. All right. So you can use this phrase for different
habits, different things that you do like drinking, for example, or cutting down on sugar.
But generally we just say this about cigarettes. So it's mostly related to smoking. Yeah. So
going cold turkey. Some people like to smoke less like one cigarette a day or one cigarette a week.
But going cold turkey is supposed to be the hardest. Right. Okay. Going cold turkey. All right. And
well, he was explaining the different negative aspects of smoking. He said, well, you know,
they spend a fortune on cigarettes every month. And he said, laws are cracking down. So if the
laws are cracking down, what is he trying to say there? Well, this is actually a very interesting
point because in America right now, it's very hard to smoke in public places. So this means that
the government is trying to stop people from smoking. So they say no more smoking in public places,
no more smoking in restaurants, no more smoking in bars. And so this means they're cracking down.
They're making it harder to do something. So they are becoming more strict. I think for this phrase,
we should listen to a couple of more examples just to make sure we understand it.
Example one. The police are cracking down on drunk driving in our city.
Example two. Our school has really started to crack down on tardiness.
Example three. The prison has passed a law that will crack down possession of legal substances.
All right. So the government is cracking down laws or cracking down.
Yeah. Exactly. So this is an important one because you read this in the newspapers as well about
certain laws and police action. All right. Great. So I think it's time for us to listen to this
dialogue for one last time. And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this
face.
Ah, it smells like an ice train here. Hi honey. What's wrong? Why do you have that look on your face?
What's wrong? I thought we agreed you were going to quit smoking. No. I said I was going to cut
down which is very different. You can't just expect me to go cold turkey overnight. Look,
there are other ways to quit. You can try the nicotine patch or nicotine chewing gum. We
spend a fortune on cigarettes every month. And now laws are cracking down and not allowing
smoking in any public place. It's not like you can just light up like before. I know. I know.
I really am trying but I don't have the will power to just quit. I can't fight with the urge to
reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee or after lunch. Please understand. Fine. I want to
divorce. So do you have a problem with this advice as you call it? Are you a smoker?
I'm really not. I'm the type of person that could maybe smoke socially. Like if we go out to a bar
with drinks, a social smoker like they call it right? Yeah. I'm jealous. But not really. You're a
habitual smoker, right? Right. Well, I was. I'm trying to cut down. So as a habitual smoker,
often smoked every day. Sometimes I smoked a lot. Sometimes I smoke less. But right now I'm in a
period where I'm mostly quit. Okay. Almost. Yeah. Well, I haven't smoked in a while. When I do,
it's just one cigarette. Now, it is interesting because like we mentioned laws are cracking down
and where you can smoke. But also taxes and cigarettes are becoming much more expensive, right?
Absolutely. Especially where I'm from in Chicago. It's easy to spend maybe 10 US dollars or 12
US dollars on one pack of cigarettes. On a pack of cigarettes, imagine that. So and you have people
that can't help smoking one or two packs a day. So how much is that a month? It's just an amazing amount of
money. Well, and I have to say though, a lot of my friends who used to smoke in America have quit.
So this is maybe working. The whole thing of making cigarettes more expensive. Yeah, making them
much more expensive. Now, another interesting thing and what I was reading recently is that you know
those warnings that come on cigarette packs. It says, you know, smoking chaos, smoking causes
cancer. Actually a study has proven that it's not effective that people don't mind it or even worry
about the costions on the cigarette packages. Well, as a smoker, I could say that yeah,
you generally, if you're going to smoke a cigarette, don't look at the label that much. You just,
you know, you throw it in your bag and you forget about it. But it's actually gotten to the point
where people choose the cigarette pack based on the picture. So they're like, oh yeah,
give me the one with the black lungs or give me that one. Oh, God. Yeah, it's interesting. So
it's not really working. I guess we're going to have to find other ways to make people more
conscious about this vice. We should. But come to our website at english.com. Tell us what you think
about this vice smoking. Is it good? Is it bad? Are you a habitual smoker or just a social smoker?
Yeah, we also have lots of great stuff tools for you on our website and expansion sentences and all
that stuff that it helps you continue your studies outside of, well, the car or your house.
So check it out. Let us know what you think and until next time. All right, we'll see you there. Bye.