Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have an
elementary level lesson for you. This one is especially for people who are interested in babies.
That's right, maybe you have a baby, you will have a baby, maybe you're pregnant and this is a great lesson
for that because we are talking about a baby shower. Okay, so before we get started, let's take a look at the
capillary preview and learn what exactly a baby shower is. Very cablory preview. Okay, so a baby
shower, you would think that this is about bathing the baby about giving the baby a bath. No,
not a real shower, a baby shower or a bridal shower. These are parties. Okay, they're parties. And on
this case, a baby shower is a party that you throw for a woman, for a woman that is pregnant, right?
That's right. So if my sister is going to have a baby, I throw her a baby shower. It's a
party where all of her friends give her gifts. Okay. Yeah, it's a way to celebrate having a baby.
Okay, so they give her gifts. You'll play games as well as to like maybe guess the name of the baby
or guess the sex of the baby. Exactly. Stuff like that. Okay, so it's a very common thing. I think it's
mostly for a women. I don't really, I don't really know if men have baby showers as well.
I don't think so. I don't think so either, but it's a very popular tradition in the United States
and many other parts of the world. So we're going to talk about that. Let's listen to the dialogue
for the first time. Thank you for organizing this great baby shower for me. I've always been
to baby showers, but never actually had one held for me. Let's get started. Okay, let's start
opening some presents. Oh look, what a great little bib for the baby. This will definitely come
in handy. Oh wow, you also got me a stroller. That's so great. Thank you. This next one is from Betty.
Oh hi, Chair and the car seat. Wow, Betty, thank you so much. I really appreciate it.
One more from Carla. A playpan and crib. Thanks, Carla. This is just what I needed.
Okay, that's all of them. No more gifts. Now, who wants to guess when the baby is new?
Um, I think my water just broke. Get me to a hospital.
All right, so very interesting. All the gifts that they got and definitely very useful because
this is a very common items that you get for babies, right? That's right. All of this stuff is
really, really valuable because if you have baby or if your brother or sister has a baby, you'll
notice that these are very common items. So let's go through a couple of them in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay, so the first word that we're going to take a look at, the most common one
and useful one for a baby is a bib. So babies are messy. When they eat food, they get their
food on their clothes. So to protect the clothes, babies wear bibs. This is a piece of cloth or fabric
around their neck. Okay, a bib. And also, sometimes you want to go out with your baby to the mall,
you're walking and you don't want to carry him in your arms all the time. So you need a
stroller. Okay, so basically a stroller is a chair on wheels for a baby.
Um, babies are heavy and as they get older, they get heavier. And so this is a way to push the baby
around, not carry the baby. Right. And maybe the baby falls asleep so they can possibly be in the
stroller. Exactly. Okay. And well, talking about chairs, we're going to take a look at two
different types of chairs. First one is a high chair. Okay, high chair, think about the word
high. That means tall in this case. A high chair is a chair for babies at the table.
Mm-hmm. So if you put a baby on a regular chair, they can't eat with adults. They're too small.
So we give them a high chairs so that they can sit a little bit higher and they can be at the
table with adults. Exactly. So they're very common. For example, you go to a restaurant, they will
have a little high chairs if you have a baby or a small child. So if you're at a restaurant,
you have a baby. You ask for a high chair. You say, do you have a high chair, please? Yeah, perfect.
And well, if you're going to the restaurant or you go anywhere in your car, you need to have the
baby be safe. And obviously they can't fit on a normal, you know, seat, right? No, with the seat belt
no, I don't think so. So that's why you get them a car seat. Okay, car seat is a special chair
that goes on the seat of the car. And usually it's very, very safe. It's protecting. It's made to
protect the baby. Right. So if you are ever in a car accident, the car seat will help protect the
small baby. Right. And car seats are supposed to go in the back of the car, not the front. Yes, always.
Very good. And now moving on to our last two words. If you're at home, you sometimes want to have
the baby play and you get them a play pen. So basically, this is a way for parents to leave
the baby playing, but not look at the baby the whole time. Right. A play pen is like a cage for a
baby, but it's soft and it's cute and it's pretty. And so it's basically like an open area that's
protected on the sides and the baby can go inside, but the baby can't leave. Right. It's like a
cage basically and it has little toys and that's the way you just keep them in there for all.
All right. And now when you want to put the baby to sleep, it can't obviously sleep in a big bed
because it might roll over and my fall off. There's a lot of things that can go wrong so you get
them a crib. Right. So crib is a bed for babies. This is usually high off the ground. And it's usually
quite small and the baby can't climb out of it. Right. Yeah. So it's a very safe bed. So the baby can't
fall out and can climb out. Exactly. Very good. So very interesting, very useful things for you.
If you're having a baby planning on getting these things, so why don't we go back, listen to the
dialogue again and we'll be back with Lewin's He Builder. Thank you for organizing this great
baby shower for me. I've always been to baby showers, but never actually had one held for me.
Let's get started. Okay. Let's start opening some presents. Oh look, what a great little
bib for the baby. This will definitely come in handy. Oh wow. You also got me a stroller. That's
so great. Thank you. This next one is from Betty. Oh hi, Chair and the car seat. Wow, Betty. Thank
you so much. I really appreciate it. One more from Carla. A playpan and crib. Thanks, Carla.
This is just what I needed. Okay, that's all of them. No more gifts. Now, who wants to guess when the
baby is due? Um, I think my water just broke. Get me to a hospital. All right, we're back. So now let's
take a look at two key phrases. Fluency builder. Okay, so at the beginning of the dialogue,
the woman receives a bib for the baby and she says, this will definitely come in handy to come in
handy. Right. So when something comes in handy, it means it will be useful. Okay, so something that's handy
is useful. Yeah. To come in handy means to be useful. It will be useful in the future.
So for example, you should take a flashlight with you in the car just in case
because it could come in handy. That's right. Or if I know that Marco was traveling to
India, I can get a map of India. I say Marco, this map might come in handy. Exactly. Very good. So to come
in handy or in something that is handy, something that's useful. And towards the end of very
popular phrase, you probably heard in every movie that has like maybe a pregnant woman
there. Oh yes. My water just broke. My water broke. Okay, so the woman says, ah, my water broke
take me to the hospital. Right. Okay, so this means I'm having my baby right now. So why do
the, what do they say that the water broke? Because actually water kind of breaks, right? I think
there's a protective water cushion. Yeah, basically there's a sack of water protecting the baby.
It's not just water. It's all sorts of like fluids, fatty fluids. And basically when that
breaks, it comes out and you know that you're going to have the baby. Because that means the
baby has to come out now because that protective fluid is gone. Maybe the baby just kind of kicks
that water out and just like I'm ready to come out. I have no idea how it is. All right, so very
interesting stuff. Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time?
I'm going to be back with the video.
Thank you for organizing this great baby shower for me. I've always been to baby showers,
but never actually had one held for me. Let's get started. Okay, let's start opening some presents.
Oh, look, what a great little bib for the baby. This will definitely come in handy.
Oh wow, you also got me a stroller. That's so great. Thank you. This next one is from Betty.
Oh, hi, Chair and the car seat. Wow, Betty, thank you so much. I really appreciate it.
One more from Carla. A playpan and crib. Thanks, Carla. This is just what I needed. Okay, that's all
of them. No more gifts. Now, who wants to guess when the baby is due? I think my water just
get me to a hospital.
All right, so talking about baby things and baby showers, it's a very interesting
tradition. I understand that in other countries, they don't really celebrate baby showers like this.
Really? Yeah, or that if they do, they do it in different ways. I know, for example, that
sometimes in Latin American countries, they usually do it after the baby's born. Oh,
so like a congratulation shower. Exactly. And then obviously you know if the baby was a boy or a
girl, so then you get them like pink things or blue things, so it's a little bit more. That's what's
really funny about these. People often want to have the surprise of not knowing if the baby
will be a boy or a girl. So when they have the baby shower, they say, oh, I don't know what the
gender is. And so you end up buying all of these yellow things. His yellow is neutral. It's good for
boys and girls. I don't know how many yellow gifts I've got. I think it's a very interesting thing
because, for example, I know that in China, I think you can't ask the doctor for the gender of the
baby on before it's born, right? I think that's a way to, I'm not sure if it's a ruler not, but it sounds
right. I mean, it's a way to protect female babies. I think it would be always great to
have just have it be a surprise. Do you never know? Yeah, just like, oh, you know, whatever comes out.
Can you imagine not knowing it and you have twins? That would be great for me, I think, if I
had a boy and a girl, bam, all at once. All at once, never have the worry about it again. Exactly.
And then you have best both worlds, right? You're done. All right, so a very interesting topic. Let us
know if you have baby showers in your country or how do you celebrate a baby's birth or before
it's born. What do you do? Very good question. Let us know. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there. All right. Bye. Bye.