Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about a topic very close to my heart, music.
That's right, we're going to be talking about music and more specifically, we are going to
talk about musical instruments that you would use in a band.
All right, and so some people like to make their own music get together, hang out, play music
together, so that's what we're talking about today.
I've got a new band that's going to start.
And before we get going, we've got a word to talk about and let's check this out in
today's vocabulary preview.
Very cabbiery, preview.
All right, so as I mentioned, we are going to talk about instruments.
Instruments, so you could say musical instruments, but what is an instrument generally speaking?
Basically, it's similar to a tool, right?
So an instrument is something that you use to help you realize a task.
In this case, musical instruments is more specific, right?
Right, so we're talking about things that you use to make music, a piano, for example.
Is a musical instrument or the drums?
All right, so this is what we're going to be looking at today in the dialogue, so let's
listen to it for the first time.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Uh, yeah, I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had to musical talent, right?
Yes, I'm a singer.
Perfect!
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Great!
Wait here?
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones, or even your drums.
By the way, where if you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
All right, we're back, so apparently the band wasn't really a real band.
It wasn't, but I have to say I'm very familiar with this because I have an Nintendo Wii
and I often play the game rock bands so I can sympathize with the character.
So you also have your own band?
I do, well, virtually speaking.
And I know you dudes, too.
That's right.
We are both a fans of this game and this gaming console and that's why it's such a fun dialogue.
But let's take a look at some of the language that was used in this dialogue in language
takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Oh man, so I've been in a lot of different ways.
A lot of bands and I've been in a lot of musical groups.
So I can say that the first instrument we want to talk about is maybe the most obnoxious.
The most louscious.
Wow, I'm not sure.
Hard to listen to.
Probably, probably.
And that instrument is the drums.
Right.
So the drums, it's plural because you have many drums, right?
You don't just have the dumb, don't, don't, don't.
The bass drum.
You have many different drums together.
And so we could also call this a drum set.
A drum set.
All right.
So why don't we listen to an example of what a drum set sounds like?
We're back.
So I think that's clear moving on to our next instrument.
This one's maybe the most popular for young people to start because you can...
Play pretty much anything with it and it's also good for sing along.
Right.
And that instrument is the guitar.
Can you play the guitar?
No, I can't.
I actually wish I would have learned, but I never got around to it.
Well, this is a really beautiful instrument and there are many different ways to play it.
But generally, it's either wooden with some strings or electric.
So it's plastic with some metal strings.
Right.
Exactly.
So they have a different sound.
But why don't we listen to an example of what a guitar sounds like?
All right.
So great example of a guitar pretty clear.
What's our next instrument?
The bass.
And this one, it doesn't look like the word that's written BAS.
So we say bass.
Bass.
It's actually very low instrument.
It's usually used to help keep the rhythm.
Don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't don't.
It's similar to a guitar, right?
Very.
It's the same form, but as you say, it's lower and it makes a lower sound.
Exactly.
All right.
So let's listen to an example of a bass now.
Pretty clear.
Moving on to our next word, we have an amplifier.
Okay.
So amplifier, an amplifier is a thing.
It's usually a box that we plug in.
It's electric or it's electronic.
And it's a tool to make electrical instruments like the electric guitar or the electric base
louder.
Right.
Exactly.
So any amplifier is any device that makes a sound become louder.
All right.
So this is really important for rock bands, the world over.
Very good.
Our next instrument or actually more of a tool is very useful for the singer.
Yeah.
And it actually goes with the amplifier in many ways because the microphones is our next
word.
The microphone is something that you use to sing into to make your voice louder.
So right now, Marco, you and I are both using microphones.
Exactly.
So a microphone.
Very good.
And we have one last word and this is a verb to audition.
All right.
So, to audition means to show someone your talent.
So oftentimes when you start a play or an opera or a musical group, you want to have auditions.
You want to audition people to see how much talent they have.
All right.
So it's basically an opportunity to demonstrate your skills and abilities.
Exactly.
So a job interview wouldn't really be an audition.
No, a job interview has its own, it's own word.
But here we're talking about your singing ability, your acting ability, your reading ability.
And sometimes we even have auditions here at English Pod to see how people, how come
to people are on the microphone.
It's a way to have people show what they've got.
Very good.
All right.
So a lot of interesting words here.
Many instruments.
I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again.
We're going to slow it down a little bit and we'll be right back.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Uh, yeah.
I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had some musical talent, right?
Yes.
I'm a singer.
Great.
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Wait here.
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones, or even your drums.
By the way, where you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
All right.
We're back.
So moving on with our lesson.
Why don't we take a look now at some phrases in fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right.
So on fluency builder, we have four phrases.
What's the first one?
Well this first phrase is really important, Marco, because we're talking about bands
and starting bands.
And so there's often a phrase we use to describe this.
We say two form a band.
All right.
So you form a band.
It's like forming something.
Two form is to shape it, to make it look like something that you want.
So we can form artistic projects also.
But he were forming a band.
We're choosing people to bring together to make great music.
All right.
So we can say form a band or you can say as well, start a band.
Yeah.
All right.
So we're forming a band.
And well, his friend was surprised that the other guy knew
had a plane instrument.
So he said, I've told you a thousand times.
Wait, wait.
So he told him 1,000 times.
No, not literally.
I played an instrument.
This is a phrase and it's a little bit of an exaggeration to emphasize that I've told
you many, many times already.
Great.
So this is something we say when we're trying to exaggerate like Marco said or to really
emphasize the point that like I've told you this before.
Right.
So mothers often use it.
I feel like we talk about mothers like mothers often use this phrase when kids do
something wrong.
I told you a thousand times not to wear your shoes in the house.
Exactly.
So it is a great phrase to really make your point that you've said something many,
many times.
Moving on, we have a kind of like a conjunction that you can use and it's by the way,
to change the topic maybe by the way.
By the way.
And so by the way, we keep these words together.
It's a fixed phrase.
By the way, something we add on.
So I say, you know, today I went to school and I saw a lot of people.
Oh, by the way, John says hi.
Right.
So while I'm talking about this, I want to add that this thing happened or that this
person said something.
Exactly.
So it is a conjunction to put together two different ideas.
By the way, or you can start off your sentence with it.
By the way, how is the new house?
No, because it's like it's like saying, oh, this thought just came into my head.
Exactly.
By the way, that a little bit.
Right.
And our last phrase on Fluency Builder is we are set.
All right.
All we need is my Nintendo.
We and we are set.
All right.
So what are we set?
We are set.
All right.
We are set is another one of those phrases that's fixed.
And it literally, it means.
And we are ready to start.
We're ready to go.
And everything is ready.
Yeah, we don't need anything else.
And so Marco, I could say to you, just bring the salad to the table and we're set.
We're ready to eat.
All right.
We are set to listen to our dialogue for the last time.
And we'll be right back and talk a little bit more about this great topic.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Uh, yeah.
I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had to musical talent, right?
Yes, I'm a singer.
Perfect.
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Great.
Wait here?
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers of microphones or even your drums.
By the way, where if you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
All right, we're back so rock band.
Now, I know that you play a real instrument.
Not only instruments on the Wii.
True.
What do you play?
I play the trumpet.
I was classically trained.
I started when I was 10.
Now is this the trumpet that has the three buttons on the top?
Three pistons.
Because there's another one that doesn't, right?
There's one that has four pistons.
It's a pick-alot trumpet, has four.
And there's one that's a large and it slides in and out.
And that's a trombone.
That's much lower.
Right, right.
But the trumpet is kind of a mid-range instrument.
It can go quite high in a little bit, though.
And it's brass.
It's not what it's made of a metal.
Right, it looks like gold.
Right.
Thumb Thumb Thumb.
All right, so you play the trumpet.
Did you play in a band or in a...
Yeah.
I played it.
In high school, middle school and high school
I played in bands and orchestra.
Mm-hmm.
And in college I played in orchestra.
And I've also played in rock bands
because sometimes people want to, you know,
have a trumpet and go a little crazy.
Nice.
Interesting.
This is interesting because I'm sure a lot of our users out there
actually play instruments and maybe a lot of them are also good at it.
So come to EnglishPod.com.
Leave your questions in comments and let us know if you play any instruments
or maybe some strange instruments like the Xylophone.
Or if you like to play, we rock band because we certainly do.
And we can support you on our own.
We can give you some tips.
Yeah.
All right, so we'll see you guys there.
Until next time.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.