Hello English learners, welcome back to English Pod, my name is Marco
and my name is Katherine.
So what are we talking about today Marco?
Well we're talking about one of my favorite topics which are computers.
Yes, you're a little bit of a nerd.
A little bit.
I love computers and technology and everything that's related to it.
So that's what we're going to be looking at today.
Maybe we're buying a new computer.
Well I anticipate learning something from this because there are a lot of those fancy
big words that I don't know that have to do with processors and giga of the giga of
the giga thing.
So that's going to be coming up in a minute here but first let's just jump right in and
take a listen to today's dialogue.
So can you fix it?
I'm sorry sir.
This computer is not broken or damaged.
It's simply just too old.
That's why your programs and applications are running slow.
There really isn't much I can do.
What do you mean?
I bought this computer just three years ago.
Yes, but technology is ever changing and technology is becoming obsolete faster and faster.
Okay, I know where this is going.
How much will it cost me to get a new computer?
Well this desktop over here is our latest model.
It has a 4 gigahertz processor with 16 gigabytes in RAM and a hard disk with one terabyte.
Of course it includes a mouse, keyboard and desk speakers.
I have no idea what you were talking about.
I just want to know if it's good and if I'll be able to play solitaire without the computer
crashing or freezing all the time.
This PC is top of the line and I guarantee it will never freeze if it does, we'll give
you your money back.
Alright we're back.
I think it's a very typical case you go in to get something fixed and they say we can't
fix it.
You need a new one.
Yes and not only a new one but a bigger and better and faster one.
And more expensive obviously.
Called the upsell.
The upsell.
Yeah.
Alright so there were some very difficult words I think because they're very specific related
to technology and computers.
So why don't we look at those now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Alright so the first word we have today is when something is no longer in use.
Okay so this word is obsolete.
It's obsolete.
We're not just talking about like oh I haven't touched that pen in like 10 years.
We're talking about a piece of technology that is no longer useful because there's something
else that can do a better job.
Right and actually not only with technology we also have words that are obsolete right?
Exactly like thy or thy.
You or yours.
Classically English.
We don't use thy anymore.
No.
It's very summary today Marko.
The we don't use that anyway that's obsolete English right?
And obsolete words.
Exactly so obsolete means it's no longer of use we have better and newer things in its
place.
Alright and now moving on when the salesman was describing the characteristics of the computer
he had he used some pre fixes that were a little bit strange right like for example Giga.
Giga?
Alright so these are actually pre fixes that have to do with numbers and so this is
not just a computer thing this is a math thing or science thing so okay so we've got
three different pre fixes a pre fix is something we tack on at the beginning of a word
so we've had we have hurt or bite right these are little bits of a computer bite right
so you have like megabytes megabytes we've all heard before that's smallest here
we've got megabytes but bigger than megabyte we've got Giga bites.
A giga yeah so now for example the the hard drives are 250 giga bites.
You might even hear someone say gigs it's got a gig's 250 gig hard drive but what's
bigger than giga?
Now it's the terabyte.
Oh, tera sounds like boom boom.
Yeah I actually wondered what would happen after gigabyte because it's so much information
already and now it's the terabyte so it's like 1,000 gigabytes.
So that's like 200 movies.
That's probably more than that it's amazing the amount of storage you can have and how small
it actually is.
So mega giga tera going from littleist to biggest.
All right and well he described for giga hurts processor.
Okay so the processor is our next word and this is actually something that determines how fast
your computer is going to run.
So it comes from the word to process right?
So like how do you like or to think do even to do so you have different examples like
a word processor.
Right so it's like Microsoft Word it allows you to make word documents.
You can also say to process that up you're trying to calculate it.
But in this case a processor is like a little brain that's the center of the computer
and that's where all the information gets processed.
Yeah so it's the brain at the computer essentially and the bigger it is the faster it
can go.
Exactly and well if you don't have a very good processor your computer is bound to freeze.
Okay so freezing is another keyword especially when I'm at computers this one drives me nuts
to freeze it means to stop moving.
Right so well it has a couple different meanings you might have heard it about ice before
but to freeze here we're talking about stopping moving so we have a game called freeze tag
for if I touch you you have to stop running.
But here we're talking about a computer freezing I'm moving my mouse and I'm typing and
all of a sudden my mouse doesn't move I can't close or open or do anything and it's
really frustrating.
Especially if you're doing something and you didn't save your work it's not on.
So if your computer freezes then usually you have to restart it or turn off or not.
So that is about it for those words but let's take another listen and slow the dialogue
down this time so you can catch some of those big words.
So can you fix it?
I'm sorry sir this computer is not broken or damaged it's simply just too old.
That's why your programs and applications are running slow there really isn't much I can
do.
What do you mean?
About this computer just three years ago.
Yes but technology is ever changing and technology is becoming obsolete faster and faster.
Okay I know where this is going.
How much will it cost me to get a new computer?
Well this desktop over here is our latest model it has a 4 gigahertz processor with 16
gigabytes in RAM and a hard disk with one terabyte.
Of course it includes a mouse, keyboard and desk speakers.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
I just want to know if it's good and if I'll be able to play solitaire without the computer
crashing or freezing all the time.
This PC is top of the line and I guarantee it will never freeze if it does we give
you your money back.
Great so we are back so now let's jump into today's fluency builder fluency builder.
Alright so on fluency builder we're going to take a look at three different phrases.
For example the salesman was describing technology and said that it's ever changing.
Okay so this is a sort of poetic line here so ever changing means always changing.
Always.
Always changing and so we can say that the ocean is ever changing.
You know the waves are always changing but in this case he's saying that technology is always
changing it's always progressing into something new and so exactly.
That is a key selling point for this guy.
So this is actually a very interesting word we can use it like in your example beyond
technology like the wave like the sea is ever changing so why don't we listen to a couple
of other examples.
Example one.
There's always something new in this ever changing world.
Example two.
Times are ever changing and we must prepare ourselves better every day.
Example three.
The flu is an ever changing virus that continues to claim many lives.
Alright we're back so now we understand the ever changing.
So the man who's trying to buy this computer or at least get his computer fixed really
starts to get frustrated with the salesman and he says okay I know where this is going.
So he hears the sales pitch.
He hears this guy trying to loosen him up a little bit.
He says I know where this is going so what does this mean is where something is going.
So basically what direction a conversation or a topic or a situation is taking.
Okay so he's saying I know why you're telling me these things.
I know you're motive.
Alright know what's happening.
I know what you're going to say.
Okay so he's essentially saying I know you're going to try and sell me a computer.
Right.
So you can use it in other circumstances.
For example, the relationship.
I don't know where this is going.
Alright what is going.
Classic break up line.
I just don't think I know where this is going anymore.
So in reference to the relationship right?
We don't know what's happening or we serious or we maybe going to get married.
I don't know anymore.
I can't tell where this movie is going.
It's so like, ooh, that here and there and boring.
I don't know the plot.
Yeah.
Alright so it's a very common phrase and it sounds very natural when you say it right.
It does.
It really helps you sound like a more native English speaker when you use these kind
of phrases.
And the next one is also very, very good when he describes the condition of the
computer.
He says it's top of the line.
Top of the line.
Now what line we're talking about?
I do not know.
But this is above average line.
Right so this is the best of the best.
This is the top model or the top computer and you can definitely imagine a car sales
when using this.
Yeah.
So the best money can buy.
Yeah that's another good one.
So basically top of the line is the best of the best above average.
More than above average.
It's really, it's the best you can do.
And so the guy is saying listen, this is our best computer.
Really you should buy it.
And obviously top of the line is like, that's a lot of money.
Yeah.
It's usually for for something that costs money right for things.
You wouldn't really use it for a person, right?
He's not with a lot of money.
No, no, no.
So top of the line, I think generally refers to electronics and cars or motorcycles.
And so you often hear top line stereo, top line TV, top line car.
But you wouldn't say this about food or people or art.
Yeah, you wouldn't say this painting is top of the line.
No, not about very unique things.
You can say this about kind of manufactured things.
Very good.
So we've taken a look at a lot of great phrases.
Why don't we listen to where I love for the last time and then we'll come back.
So can you fix it?
I'm sorry sir.
This computer is not broken or damaged.
It's simply just too old.
That's why your programs and applications are running slow.
There really isn't much I can do.
What do you mean?
I bought this computer just three years ago.
Yes, but technology is ever changing and technology is becoming obsolete.
Faster and faster.
Okay, I know where this is going.
How much will it cost me to get a new computer?
Well, this desktop over here is our latest model.
It has a four gigahertz processor with 16 gigabytes in RAM and a hard disk with one
terabyte.
Of course, it includes a mouse, keyboard, and desk speakers.
I have no idea what you were talking about.
I just want to know if it's good.
And if I'll be able to play solitaire without the computer crashing or freezing all the
time.
Easy as top of the line.
And I guarantee it will never freeze.
If it does, we'll give you your money back.
Alright, we're back.
So computers, a captain, I know you recently got a nice mac and tush.
Yeah, yeah, I did.
It's one of those big screen ones, right?
Yeah, it is.
It's a desktop, right?
So it's not a laptop.
And it's got a very fast processor because Max started using Intel processors a couple
of years ago and that made them much faster.
Wow, and it has this processor actually has two cores, right?
So basically it has two different brains almost within one processor.
Which gives it really bad headaches.
She complains to me often.
Are you a big Mac fan or PC fan?
I'm a Mac fan.
I've been converted.
My roommate in college, my sophomore year had a Mac and ever since then, I've really gotten
into them.
Really?
I went Mac and didn't turn back.
I still honestly cannot really use a Mac.
I get confused.
I'm looking for the start button and I'm looking for where my documents are.
It's really hard to change over, right?
But once you do, you don't want to change back because everything is so much easier on
a Mac.
But if you're really into PC gaming, then you should probably stick with it, stick with
the PCs because the games just don't really compare on Macs.
But I've heard that also, Max don't really suffer from viruses, right?
No, they don't, which is great because I always used to get these viruses that would
slow down my computer because you know, you open some email and also there's nasty in
this on your desktop.
Well, now I don't really have that problem and also there's really wonderful photo editing
software and video editing software.
So everything is just really easy to find and easy to use.
What about you, listeners, do you prefer the Mac, do you prefer the PC or maybe some
of our listeners don't really even like computers?
Well, let us know either way, we're very curious to hear what you have to say.
And of course, writing on our comment section is great practice for your English.
Right, so we'll see you guys there and until next time.
Bye, everyone.