Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco and my name is Catherine and today we're talking about one of my least favorite things Marco
mosquitoes
They're all over the place especially in summer or near water
Exactly
And for me the worst part is when you were trying to sleep and there's a mosquito that just keeps on biting you and won't let you sleep
Yeah
You can kind of hear it around your your head. Yeah, I hear you hear. Uh, I hate that or when you just get bitten and you're in bed and that just it's so much
And it burns sometimes. Yeah, so that has what we're talking about today fun stuff
Let's jump right into this dialogue and we're back in a minute to talk about what's going on
The mosquitoes are biting me too. I can't stop scratching
Everywhere sneaky little jerks. Do you have any bugs brain? No, I forgot to buy some
Then we'll have to put up with it. We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they bite us
Don't get drunk and fall asleep
That's without doubt the
Best idea you've ever had. Let's do it
Run there's different more
All right, we're back. So let's take a look at some of these words in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, so as we mentioned we're going to be talking about mosquitoes and well these are just little small insects that suck your blood
They do and they're very thin and
Not much to say about them. They were very important in the movie Jurassic Park if you remember that
Right now what's the difference between a mosquito and a fly?
Okay, a fly usually is just annoying. It doesn't suck your blood
But a mosquito does it sucks your blood and flies are fatter and and like
Shorter and they're big and black and they're green kind of some black and green and they
Yeah, they just buzz around so mosquitoes actually bite you. Okay, so am a mosquito and they fly
Now if a mosquito bites you you really really want to scratch that's right so
You feel like you need to scratch your body because you have this bite your you know, it's really an allergy
And you have a red bump on your arm a red mark and you scratch and it gets worse and worse
All right and moving on to our next word mosquitoes have a reputation of being sneaky
Okay, so you can say sneaky about a lot of things one, you know obviously we're saying mosquitoes are very sneaky
That means that they can kind of hide and get you when you're not expecting it
Yeah, because sometimes during the day you don't really see them in your room, right? They're hiding
Or they're in a place where you can't really see them and then a night all the sudden they come out
And they're very hard to see they fly around in in a way that's very difficult to catch them or kill them
Right we could say thieves are very sneaky like a thief is someone who steals something and they like to sneak
Around and hide in the dark and then when you're not expecting it they come out and they still your stuff
Hey exactly and now what are we what do we do or what are we use in order to prevent mosquitoes from biting us?
This is essential especially if you're going to the beach. We bring bugs spray bug spray
So a spray is something that
Shh
That you can usually have in a can that you push a button then it comes out
All right, it's like
It's like water, but it keeps the bugs away
So bugs spray keeps bugs away not only mosquitoes, but like flies too flies or any other type of bug
Now specifically for mosquitoes you would use maybe a
Mosquito repellent right so repellent is
It means something that pushes or keeps away things you don't want so something that keeps mosquitoes away is called a mosquito repellent
And usually it's a cream you put on your arms or legs
All right very good so interesting words that we've just taken a look at let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be right back
The mosquitoes are biting me me too. I can't stop scratching there everywhere sneaky little jerks
Do you have any bugs spray? No, I forgot to buy some then we'll have to put up with it
We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they bite us they'll get drunk and fall sleep
That's without doubt the
best idea you've ever had let's do it
Run there thirsty for more
All right, we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of different phrases on fluency builder
Fluency builder
All right, so the first phrase is very very common
The person in the dialogue says that they're going to have to put up with it put up with these mosquitoes because they didn't have any bugs sprays
So this phrase to put up with is really important all right, so if you put up with something and these that you tolerate it all right
That means even if you don't want to you'll still handle it. You'll still have to deal with it
You accept it. Mm-hmm. So maybe you have a little brother that's very annoying and you just have to put up with him
There's no other option
Yeah, or um someone says to you you're just gonna have to put up with it or you say I won't put up with it anymore
I won't handle it anymore. I'm done. All right
So I think this is a great phrase for us to take a look at a couple of different examples
Example one I
Can't put up with the noise any longer turn that music down
Example two
If you can put up with the smell then stinky tofu is actually very tasty
Example three
I've had to put up with him for too long. I want a new roommate
And
After this we've got another phrase we're talking about beer, okay, and so the person says oh I have an idea
Instead of bug spray we can we can cover ourselves with beer
So to cover yourself or cover ourselves
So it means that we put it all over us right so you could even cover yourself with bug spray
Okay, so every part of your body you put bugs spray on head to toe head to toe
You can cover yourself under a tree maybe or you can cover yourself with a blanket
Okay, so to cover yourself to completely hide under something and finally we have the response to this idea
The answer the person says oh without a doubt that means absolutely or definitely
Okay, so there is no doubt
It is true or it is certain right so a doubt is something that maybe you're not so sure about
You're not convinced but you can say this is without a doubt the best mosquito spray or this is without a doubt the best cake
I've ever eaten that means it's definitely the best cake of ever eaten all right so I think we've covered all the phrases now
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back
You
The mosquitoes are fighting me me too. I can't stop scratching here everywhere sneaky little jerks
Do you have any bugs spray? No, I forgot to buy some then we'll have to put up with it
We can cover ourselves with beer that way if they bite us they'll get drunk and fall asleep
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had let's do it
Run there's different more
The mosquitoes are very annoying but at times it can be very dangerous right they can
There are a couple of diseases that can be passed by mosquito bites one of them is malaria
And that's I think pretty common in Southeast Asia and Southeast Asia now there was another situation where people believe that if a
Mosquito bit a person infected with HIV or AIDS
Be could pass it on to another person
Aha, well, I don't know that that's even possible
Right, there's no AIDS carrying mosquitoes, but there's another disease called dengue fever
And this is another very dangerous one. It's also known as break bone fever and I think it's it's so painful
It feels like your bones are breaking and that's what it comes. It's very common in South America as well
And because we have such a tropical climate that in the rainforests of Brazil, Peru, Colombia
It's common to to see this but not so much anymore another eradicating it
All right, so an interesting topic mosquitoes are not only irritating but can be dangerous
So if you have any other questions or doubts, please come to our website English.com and we're there to answer any questions
So we'll see you on the website and until next time everyone bye bye