Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at English Pod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about a topic very close to my heart music.
That's right we're going to be talking about music and more specifically we are going to talk
about musical instruments that you would use in a band.
All right and so some people like to make their own music get together, hang out, play music
together so that's what we're talking about today.
I've got a new band that's going to start and before we get going we've got a word
to talk about and let's check this out in today's vocabulary preview.
Very cabbily preview.
All right so as I mentioned we are going to talk about instruments.
Instruments so you could say musical instruments but what is an instrument generally speaking?
Basically it's similar to a tool right?
So an instrument is something that you use to help you realize a task.
In this case musical instruments is more specific right?
Right so we're talking about things that you use to make music.
A piano for example.
Is a musical instrument or the drums.
All right so this is what we're going to be looking at today in the dialogue so let's
listen to it for the first time.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Yeah I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself who are the other members of the band.
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had to musical talent right?
Yes I'm a singer.
Perfect!
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Great!
Wait here?
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones or even your drums.
By the way where you keep them or practice?
Dude what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
All right we're back so apparently the band wasn't really a real band.
It wasn't but I have to say I'm very familiar with this because I have an Nintendo Wii
and I often play the game rock band so I can sympathize with the character.
So you also have your own band.
I do well.
Virtually speak virtual.
And I know you dudes too.
I do too.
That's right.
We are both fans of this game and this gaming console and that's why it's such a fun dialogue.
But let's take a look at some of the language that was used in this dialogue in language
takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Oh man.
So I've been in a lot of bands and I've been in a lot of musical groups so I can say
that the first instrument we want to talk about is maybe the most obnoxious.
The most obnoxious.
Wow.
Hard to listen to.
Probably and that instrument is the drums.
Right.
So the drums it's plural because you have many drums right?
Right you don't just have the dumb thong thong thong thong the bass drum.
You have many different drums together and so we could also call this a drum set.
A drum set.
All right.
So why don't we listen to an example of what a drum set sounds like?
We're back.
So I think that's clear moving on to our next instrument.
This one's maybe the most popular for young people to start because you can...
Play pretty much anything with it and it's also good for sing along.
Right and that instrument is the guitar.
Can you play the guitar?
No I can't.
I actually wish I would have learned but I never got around to it.
Well this is a really beautiful instrument and there are many different ways to play it but generally
it's either wooden with some strings or electric so it's plastic with some metal strings.
Right exactly.
So they have a different sound but why don't we listen to an example of what a guitar sounds
like?
All right.
So great example of a guitar pretty clear.
What's our next instrument?
The bass and this one it doesn't look like the word that's written BAS so we say bass
bass.
It's a very low instrument.
It's usually used to help keep the rhythm.
All right.
So it's similar to a guitar right?
Very.
It's the same form but as you say it's lower and it makes a lower sound.
Exactly.
All right so let's listen to an example of a bass now.
All right.
Pretty clear.
Moving on to our next word we have an amplifier.
Okay so amplifier is a thing.
It's usually a box that we plug in.
It's electric or it's electronic and it's a tool to make electrical instruments like
the electric guitar or the electric bass louder.
Right.
So any amplifier is any device that makes a sound become louder.
Exactly.
All right.
So this is really important for rock bands the world over.
Very good.
Our next instrument or actually more of a tool is very useful for the singer.
Yeah and it actually goes with the amplifier in many ways because the microphones
is our next word.
The microphone is something that you use to sing into to make your voice louder.
So right now Marco you and I are both using microphone.
Exactly.
So a microphone.
Very good.
And we have one last word and this is a verb to audition.
All right.
To audition.
So to audition means to show someone your talent.
All right.
So oftentimes when you start a play or an opera or a musical group you want to have auditions.
You want to audition people to see how much talent they have.
All right.
So it's basically an opportunity to demonstrate your skills and abilities.
Exactly.
So a job interview wouldn't really be in audition.
No.
Job interview has its own, it's own word.
But here we're talking about your singing ability, your acting ability, your reading
ability.
And sometimes we even have auditions here at English Pod to see how people come to a people
are on the microphone.
It's a way to have people show what they've got.
Very good.
All right.
So a lot of interesting words here.
Many instruments.
I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again.
We're going to slow it down a little bit and we'll be right back.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Yeah.
I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had some musical talent, right?
Yes.
I'm a singer.
Perfect.
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Great.
Wait here.
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones, or even your drums.
By the way, where you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
Alright, we're back.
So moving on with our lesson.
Why don't we take a look now at some phrases in fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
Alright, so on fluency builder, we have four phrases.
What's the first one?
Well, this first phrase is really important, Marko, because we're talking about bands and
starting bands.
And so there's often a phrase we use to describe this.
We say, two form a band.
Alright, so you form a band.
It's like forming something to form is to shape it, to make it look like something
that you want.
And so we can form artistic projects also.
But he were forming a band.
We're choosing people to bring together to make great music.
Alright, so we can say form a band or you can say as well, start a band.
Yeah.
Alright.
So we're forming a band and well, his friend was surprised that the the other guy knew had a plane instrument.
So he said, I've told you a thousand times.
Wait, wait, so he told him 1,000 times.
No, not literally.
I played an instrument.
Alright, this is a phrase and it's a little bit of an exaggeration to emphasize that I've told you many, many times already.
Great.
So this is something we say when we're trying to exaggerate like Marko said or to
really emphasize the point that like I've told you this before.
Right.
So mothers often use it.
I feel like we talk about mothers a lot.
Mother's often used this phrase when kids do something wrong.
I say, I've told you a thousand times not to wear your shoes in the house.
Exactly.
So it is a great phrase to really make your point that you've said something many many times.
Moving on, we have a kind of like a conjunction that you can use.
And it's by the way, to change the topic maybe by the way.
By the way, and so by the way, we keep these words together.
It's a fixed phrase.
By the way, something we add on.
So I say, you know, today went to school and I saw a lot of people.
Oh, by the way, John says hi.
Alright, so while I'm talking about this, I want to add that this thing happened or that this person said something.
Exactly.
So it is a conjunction, right, to put together two different ideas.
By the way, or you can start off your sentence with it. By the way, how is the new house?
No, because it's like it's like saying, oh, this thought just came into my head.
Exactly.
By the way, that's it.
Right, right.
And our last phrase on fluency builder is, we are set.
Alright, all we need is my Nintendo Wii and we are set.
Alright, so what are we set?
We are set.
Alright, we are set is another one of those phrases it's fixed.
And it literally, it means, and we are ready to start.
We are ready to go.
And everything is ready.
Yeah, we don't need anything else.
So Marco, I could say to you, just bring the salad to the table and we are set.
We are ready to eat.
Alright, and I think we are set to listen to our dialogue for the last time.
And we will be right back and talk a little bit more about this great topic.
I'm forming a music band.
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Uh, yeah, I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
Now that know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
You told me that you had to musical talent, right?
Yes, I'm a singer.
Perfect!
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
Great!
Wait here?
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones, or even your drums.
By the way, where if you keep them or practice?
Dude, what are you talking about?
It's right here.
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
Alright, we're back so rock band now.
I know that you play a real instrument, not only instruments on the Wii.
True!
What do you play?
I play the trumpet.
I was classically trained.
I started when I was 10.
Now is this the trumpet that has the three buttons on the top?
Yes.
Three pistons.
Because there's another one that doesn't, right?
There's one that has four pistons.
It's a pick-alot trumpet has four.
There's one that's a large and it slides in and out.
That's a trombone.
That's much lower.
Right, right.
But the trumpet is kind of a mid-range instrument.
It can go quite high in a little bit low.
And it's brass.
It's not wood.
It's made of a metal.
Right, it looks like gold.
Right.
Ta-da-da-da.
Alright, so you played the trumpet that you played in a band or in a...
Yeah.
I played in...
In high school, middle school and high school played in bands and orchestra.
And in college I played in orchestra.
And I've also played in rock bands because sometimes people want to...
Have a trumpet and go a little crazy.
Nice.
This is interesting because I'm sure a lot of our users out there actually play instruments.
And maybe a lot of them are also good at it.
So come to EnglishPod.com.
Leave your questions in comments and let us know if you play any instruments or maybe some
Strangestraments like the Zyla phone.
Or if you like to play, we rock band because we certainly do and we can support you on our live.
We can give you some tips.
Alright, so we'll see you guys there until next time.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.