Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we have a great elementary level lesson all about having fun.
That's right. Today we are going to have a lot of fun and well before we explain what exactly we're going to do.
Why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very vocabulary preview. Okay so the word we're previewing today is a noun. It's a thing.
It's a roller coaster. All right. A roller coaster. So that's what we're going to do today.
We're going to get on a roller coaster. But what is a roller coaster? Well a roller coaster is something that
we see often times in parks. I'm using parks and it's it's like a little train but it can go upside down
and it goes very fast and it turns and it's supposed to make you scared and happy. Okay so it goes very fast
Yeah many people have probably seen it. It goes very fast and it is a up and down and well you just get on it because it's fun.
You go fast and you get scared because you're going so fast and sometimes you're going upside down.
Exactly and for some reason I don't know why but in many romance languages the name is Russian mountains.
Exactly. Yeah it's also in Spanish. It's also a Russian mountain.
Yeah. So I think the reason is because back in the day back you know a hundred years ago when you were starting
the the first roller coaster came from Russia. Oh wow. Yeah. So that's why it's called it. Well that's a theory
I'm not sure but take a listen to today's dialogue we'll hear it one time and when we come back
we'll be talking about more interesting and exciting phrases and words about roller coaster.
I'm so excited! We're finally here! Six flags magic mountain. This is the best amusement park
in the world. All right settle down now you're going to give yourself a house attack. I can't
believe they charge us to thirty five dollars each. Seems like such a rip off don't you think?
It's not like I'm going to get on these things. Whoa. Bliper that's the world's highest
and fastest roller coaster. You go on more than one hundred miles per hour. I want to go on that one.
Can I mom please? Can I? Chris I'm not sure you should get on that. It seems a bit too much for you
and we just had breakfast 30 minutes ago. I don't think it's a good idea.
Come on mom. I can handle it. I promise I won't ask for anything else besides it's not like
I'm going to throw up or anything. Then I'm going to go. He'll be fine.
All right! Yeah this is amazing! See how I have to go?
Whoa!
All right we're back so interesting that I think this is very common. You get on one of these things.
You go so fast that you just throw up. I've never thrown up. I'm a roller coaster. No never.
Not many of them. All right well maybe it's not that common but let's take a look at some of the
words that we hear in this conversation between a boy and his parents. All right so as we mentioned
this word throw up two throw up. Why don't we take a look at that one first although it's
almost at the end of the dialogue. What is it to throw up? Okay well to throw is different than to
throw up. So remember that these two words go together to mean to vomit. That means that the
things in your stomach come out your mouth. So like we heard in the dialogue they came in like
yeah it's very it's a very disgusting sound. Yeah and so sometimes people throw up when they eat too
much sometimes they throw up when they're sick and sometimes they throw up after riding a roller coaster.
And so this is this is an important phrase to know. Or like when you're on a boat you get seasick
and you throw up or in the car sometimes you get car sick. All right so as we mentioned we're also
visiting an amusement park so why don't we explain this word a little bit amusement park?
Okay first of all everyone probably knows the word park you know it's a public place but in this
case an amusement park is a park of fun. A amusement means fun and so it's usually a place that you
go to and you pay a price and they give you a ticket and you can play all day long. So we have roller
coasters and food and shows. So probably the most famous or well known amusement park is Disneyland
so that's an amusement park. Exactly and there's lots of fun things to do for people of all ages.
All right and now the kid was so excited that the mom said all right you're going to give
yourself a heart attack. Okay well a heart attack is another serious health issue we talked about
throwing up before is when your heart stops beating. Right. Okay. So maybe something is stuck
or there's there's some problem with your your your heart and there's no more blood going through
your heart and so there's a very very serious issue but in this case she's saying you're so excited
you might hurt your heart. You might have a heart attack. You might hurt yourself because you're so
excited. Right. So she's exaggerating that's not really going to happen but she's trying to warn
him. All right and now the father mentioned that they paid $35 for each of their tickets and he
thought it was a rip off. Okay rip off is a great great phrase that we use in spoken English to
describe something that's uh unfair so a price that's unfair. Okay so you can maybe go to the market
right and you ask how much a sweater is and they'll tell you it's $100. You think that's a rip off.
What a rip off I can buy a sweater for $20 so 100 is definitely a rip off.
All right so that's a rip off. It was a rip off. He's not very happy with how much money he paid.
Not at all. All right and now the kid was talking about the roller coaster that is the highest
in fast as roller coaster and he said that the speed was at more than 100 miles per hour so what
about this miles per hour? Okay this is very important if you go to America you'll see that the
speeds on the road are all in miles per hour so mile is a distance and per hour means how many miles
you can travel every hour so in one hour you can go 100 miles. So we have the equivalent right we have
like kilometers per hour. Exactly and so miles per hour kilometers per hour these are both
called speeds. Okay and well this is called the imperial system right you use miles you use
inches and feet whereas the uh kilometers or or centimeters or meters you would use the
metric system right? Exactly because the counting um the counting is done by meters meters metric so
in this case we're in America we know that because the speed limit is 100 miles or the speed here
is 100 miles an hour. We know that we're in America because the speed the boy is talking about
is miles per hour. Very good and I think yeah use it in North America and that's pretty much it right.
I think they use miles in Britain really. Yeah I'm not positive I'd have to check with my British
friends. All right okay so that's all the words we have for language takeaway let's listen to
the dialogue again and we'll be back to explain some phrases. I'm so excited we're finally here
six flags magic mountain this is the best amusement park in the world. All right settle down now
you're gonna give yourself a horse attack. I can't believe they charge us 35 dollars each it seems
like such a rip off don't you think it's not like I'm gonna get on these things. Whoa
fiper that's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster you go out more than 100 miles per hour.
I want to go in that one can I mom please can I Chris I'm not sure you should get on that it seems
a bit too much for you and we've just had breakfast 30 minutes go. I think it's a good idea.
Well come on mom I can handle it I promise I won't ask for anything else besides it's not like
I'm gonna throw up or anything. Well then I'm going okay I'll help you find. All right
yeah this is amazing see how I have we're going whoa all right we're back so now what
we start with three phrases that we have prepared for you today in fluency builder fluency builder
okay this first phrase Marco is definitely a parent phrase okay so this is something that you
often hear parents sing to their children they say settle down now.
settle down now. Teacher say this too yeah all right everyone settle down. That means if I'm
really excited and I want to talk and I'm running around the room and my teacher says settle down now that
means quiet down go slowly sit down don't talk it means calm down calm down yeah so to calm down to relax
settle down. All right and now the next phrase is a very kids phrase I think right that you would use on
your parents so if they say no you can't go to your friend's house you oh come on please
oh mom come on. All right so what do you mean with that phrase what come on come on what?
So in this we have a child who's asking something he's saying can you please let me do something please
come on that means I'm encouraging you to change your mind or to let me do something so please let me
have my way. All right all right so come on and you don't only use it as a child or with your parents
right you can encourage your friends to like come on come with me to the bar come on let's go.
Please come on. All right you want to and our last phrase I can handle it.
Okay this is next to the phrase all come on so the boy is trying to explain that he's big enough
and old enough to go on a roller coaster but his mother doesn't know she says oh I don't know you know
you're you're too young and so he says I can handle it. That means I am big enough and old enough
to go on a roller coaster I won't have a problem. So you can do it right basically I am good enough
to do it. So for example if I give you a very hard project you can say I can handle it I can do it.
You could also say I'm very busy right now I can't handle it. Okay I can't I can't do it I'm sorry.
I can't do it. All right very good interesting phrases there they're very useful and very
very common in spoken English in North American well a lot of places so when we listen to the
dialogue for the third time and we'll be back.
I'm so excited we're finally here the next flag magic mountain this is the best amusement park in the
world. All right settle down now you're going to give yourself a house attack. I can't believe
they charge us 35 dollars each seems like such a rip off don't you think it's not like I'm
gonna get on these things. Wow bliper that's the world's highest and fastest roller coaster
you go out more than 100 miles per hour I'm gonna go on that one can I mom please can I Chris I'm not sure
you should get on that it seems a bit too much for you and we just had breakfast 30 minutes go.
I don't think it's a good idea. Come on mom I can handle it I promise I won't ask for anything else
besides it's not like I'm gonna throw up or anything. Then I'm going I'll be fine.
All right yeah this is amazing see how I ever got it.
All right so this amusement park magic mountain it actually exists in the United States right. It does and
six flags is really a brand so there are many different parks amusement parks called six flags and each one
has a different name. I'm not sure where magic mountain is but that one's in California.
Yeah and you have like six flags greater America. Yeah that's my Chicago. That's a little bit
sick. So they're basically amusement parks and their famous because they have a really great or
intense roller coasters right exactly so the one that we heard about in today's dialogue is called
Viper like the snake and that one is at the the amusement park in California you mentioned but
the famous ride in Chicago is Batman the ride. Oh really because you sit on a seat but there's no
place for your feet so your feet swing in the wind and it's very fast and you don't actually sit
on a train right the track is on top of your head exactly so you're hanging. So you see
everyone downstairs. Yeah well not downstairs down at the bottom and I hear they have a very serious
problem with people losing their shoes. I heard about this people wearing sandals and they just fly
off. Exactly so I want to warn everyone if you go to Chicago you go to these upside down these
flipped roller coasters you should bring real shoes not sandals. Well as we mentioned it's in many languages
in the romance languages they're called Russian mountain so I wonder for our Russian listeners do you
have any intense or great roller coasters in Russia I mean if they come from Russia they should have
amazing roller coasters there right. That's right or do you have any idea why we call them Russian
mountains in other languages? Please let us know our website is englishpod.com we also welcome your
questions and comments and other issues so until next time everyone bye bye.
you