Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you guys out there
that's right today we are going to talk about an interesting topic especially for women
we are going to the nails salon
okay so we're going to get our finger nails painted
alright so let's take a look at vocabulary preview to find out what nails salon means
very cablory preview
alright so if you go to a nail salon it's a specific place where they paint your nails right
exactly so it's a shop or a store where you can have your nails painted so they have special
people to help you if you want to go get your hair cut you would go to the hair salon
exactly so we have hair salon and nail salon in this case that the nail salon they can't cut your hair
okay very good so why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time
honey I'll be right back where are you going? I told you already I'm going to get my nails done again
you just went last week you spend more time at the nails salon than you do here at home honestly
why do you need a manicure every week? well first of all I like to pamper myself
my nails look great you should come with me why I don't want to have meal polisher anything like that
they don't only paint my nails the manicures will remove my cuticles find my nails and apply
at least four coats of nail polish yeah I don't like something I should definitely do
alright we're back so now we found some very interesting and specific words related to nails
so why don't we look at those now on language takeaway language takeaway
alright so this first word is an important word for every woman to know and I know a lot of men
who get this too it's called a manicure all right manicure and what exactly is a manicure
well a manicure is a service that you get at a nail salon and that means that the people at the nail
salon will cut your nails and shape your nails that means if you want them to be pointy or
boxy and then you get them painted and dried okay so they basically take care of your of your nails
of your fingernails a manicure exactly and so the important thing to remember here that a manicure
is for your hands right so you can also get your toenails or your feet taking care of right
exactly so that's different that's a pedicure because pedicure means foot so pedicure is for your feet
and a manicure is for your hands alright very good and well we talked about painting
your nails and the that paint has a specific name right exactly so you wouldn't use
wall paint on your fingers right right so you have to use a special paint and this is called nail
polish nail polish okay so a polish is something that makes a surface or a thing shiny
okay so nail polish is a paint that makes your nails very shiny alright very good and well
moving on we talked about a manicure and there's a specific word for the person that provides
this service that takes care of your nails okay so the job at a nail salon is manicureist that's the
person who paints your nails okay and so you could say I have a favorite manicureist her name is
Sally okay very good and well a manicure is they perform a manicure and well apart from painting
your nails they also push your cuticles or remove your cuticles like in the dialogue what are the
cuticles okay cuticle is a very hard word this word describes the skin around your fingernails
okay so you have skin all over your body but on your fingernail you have special kind of skin
and so a manicureist will sometimes push or cut the dead skin that's the the cuticle
from your finger okay very good so if you look at your fingernails now you will see a little
thin layer of skin on your fingernail that's the cuticle and well apart from removing your cuticles
and painting your nails they will also file your nails and this is a verb to file
to file okay so this is a word that's kind of like cut or trim but a file is a more delicate
process so it means that we kind of shave off very very very little at a time and so to file
your nails means to to make them shaped differently or to smooth them they're not cutting
clip clip it's not that it's a little bit less than that and now there's also a noun for this
a nail file and most women will usually have it it's a it's a long piece of cardboard that has
a paper that's kind of like sand on it kind of like sand paper it doesn't feel good when you rub
it with your hand with your hand but if you use it on your nails it will little by little just take
away little parts of your nail yeah like you usually see it the many secretaries you know
and TV shows they're always filing their nails exactly making them perfect okay so those are the
words we have for language takeaway why don't we take a look at our dialogue again and we'll be back
in a little bit honey I'll be right back where are you going I told you already I'm going to get my
nails done again you just went last week you spend more time at the nails along the new
do here at home honestly why do you need a manicure every week well first of all I like to
pamper myself and my nails look great you should come with me why I don't want to have nail
polish or anything like that they don't only paint my nails the manicurists will remove my
cuticles find my nails and apply at least four coats of nail polish yeah sounds like something I should
definitely do all right we're back so now why don't we start with some phrases some very good phrases
that we found in this dialogue in fluency builder fluency builder this first place is really important
when we talk about nails because it's the way that we describe going to the nail salon so I can say
I'm going to get my nails done today okay so to get your nails done that means that you're going to
get your nails cut filed painted etc I'm going to get a manicure but that's very I don't know I'm
serious so you could say I'm going to get my nails done it's more spoken language okay so I'm
going to get my nails and or you got your nails done very good and well the woman was talking
about why she likes to go get a manicure and she said that she likes to pamper herself
okay this is very common especially when women are trying to talk about why they spend money
on hair and nails and clothes is I like to pamper myself to pamper means to treat very very well
okay so if you go get a manicure it's kind of like pampering yourself or maybe going to a spa
exactly they're getting massage and so we could say also don't pamper the dog he's very naughty
so a sin and it would be to spoil to spoil oneself to pamper indulge okay so and well she was
talking about how they they perform a manicure and she talked about four coats of nail polish so
a coat we know that it's a kind of like a jacket right but in this case and this case it means a layer
so you paint your nails one time okay you have color maybe it doesn't look right okay it's very thin
so you say okay I'm gonna I'm going to paint two coats and then you paint one more time
and the color gets darker and you paint one more time and the color gets very dark and very thick
and so these are called coats that means layers of nail polish and that's a special where we use
more talking about painting our nails right so it's not only for nails but if you're painting your house
maybe you need two or three coats of paint exactly if we have a red wall and we want to paint
it white we would definitely need two three maybe four coats of paint otherwise we'll still see the red
haha okay very good very interesting phrases let's take a look at this dialogue for the very
last time and we'll be back shortly
honey I'll be right back where are you going I told you already I'm going to get my nails done again
you just went last week you spend more time at the nail salon than you do here at home honestly
why do you need to manic your every week well first of all I like to pamper myself and my nails look
great you should come with me why I don't want to have nail polish or anything like that
they don't only paint my nails the manicurists will remove my cuticles find my nails and
apply at least four coats of nail polish yeah I don't like something I should definitely do
all right we're back so a Katherine are you a big fan of manicures do you get it done often
I didn't use to but I really enjoy them now I think it's a nice way to relax on the weekends
so every couple of weeks I go to the the nail salon and I have my nails done all right and I think
one of the words that we didn't talk about here but it's very I don't know for men it's kind of
a strange smell is nail polish remover they pass its own right it's a it's a very strong chemical
it is really disgusting nail polish remover you know the the word to remove means to take away
and so when the nail polish we want to change the color we have to use this it's like water but
it smells really bad and so my boyfriend always gets angry when I use the nail polish remover because the
whole house starts to stink it's a very strong smell and you get kind of dizzy so yeah
it wasn't your head all right well if you guys have any questions any doubts or any suggestions
about this lesson or any other lesson please come to our website englishpod.com and we'll see you guys there
bye everyone