Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we have a cold lesson.
That's right. It's the winter season and of course it gets cold in a lot of different places around the world.
And so we're going to talk about heating.
Okay, this is very important but before we do get started we have a very important word to preview in the
vocabulary preview. Very cablory preview. All right, so we're going to preview the word freezing.
It is freezing today, by the way. So this is very appropriate.
Freesing means very very very cold. Okay, it is freezing. Okay, so it's very cold. It's freezing today.
It's so cold. In fact, you can't have water outside because the water will become ice.
It will freeze. Okay, great word. So let's listen to our dialogue for the very first time.
It's freezing in here. Can I turn up the heat?
Don't touch that thermostat. You don't pay the bills around here. Dad, are you serious?
What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it? Look, I can see my breath.
Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly.
Dad, I'm going to catch a cold. When I was your age, my parents didn't have central heating
like you do. We had a furnace in the center of the living room and that was it. We used it to cook,
heat the house and even dry our clothes. We never caught a cold. You should be grateful.
All right, we're back. This is actually what a lot of dads are like. I think we're on the
world. Yep, my dad definitely like to keep the heat low. Really? All right, so we'll talk about
that a little bit later. But let's take a look at some four words on language takeaway today.
Language takeaway. Well, this first word is important for anyone who has a home with heating,
is called a thermostat. All right, a thermostat. What is a thermostat? A thermostat is a dial or
like a device on the wall that tells you how hot or how cold the house is. It's like a thermometer
for your house. Okay, so you can move the thermostat, the temperature to make the house warmer or
colder, right? Right. So if it says it's 20 degrees and I think that's too cold, I can turn the thermostat
up to 23 degrees. All right, and well, very much related to a thermostat in what this device does
is our next word, central heating. Right, so if you have central heating, you have a thermostat.
That's the way to control the heat. And central heating means that you have one heater for the whole
house. And so the air comes into all the different rooms. So not many places in China have this,
but for example, in the United States and Canada, it is very common. Okay, so your house or your
apartment building will have central heating. And then you can control how cold or warm the house
is with thermostat. Exactly. Very good. And well, our next word is related to temperature.
And it's chilly. chilly, okay. So there's a big difference between chilly and freezing.
Freezing means very, very, very cold. Chili means a little cold. Right. So it's a little cold.
It's a bit chilly. Right. So it's a bit chilly today. I'm going to wear a hat. Okay. If it's freezing,
I'm going to wear a hat, a hat and mittens and a scarf and coat and boots. All right. So if it's a
bit chilly, it's not very cold. And while moving on, the dad mentioned about him having a furnace.
Right. That's right. The dad had a furnace in his house. And the furnace is a way to heat your
house. It's like a stove. So yeah, just consider it like a big oven. Right. Maybe you've seen it in
the old movies where you would have to throw firewood into the furnace to make it heat up the house.
Exactly. And so this is very common in older homes and not very common in apartments.
Right. And well, that's all the words we have for language takeaway today. Why don't we
listen to this chilly dialogue again?
It's freezing in here. Can I turn up the heat? Don't touch that thermostat. You don't
pay the bills around here. Dad, are you serious? What's the point of having central heating if we
can't use it? Look, I can see my breath. Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you
run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly. Dad, I'm going to catch a cold. When I was
your age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do. We had a furnace in the center of
the living room and that was it. We used it to cook, heat the house and even dry our clothes.
We never caught a cold. You should be grateful.
Alright, we're back. So now we have prepared for you three key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay, so this first phrase is related to thermostat, okay? So thermostat
like we said is like a thermometer but we can control the temperature. So if we want to make the
temperature hotter, we turn up thermostat. So this is a phrase over to turn up the heat.
You could say this about heat. You could say this about noise to can you turn up the radio.
Turn up the volume. So it's to increase. To increase to make bigger or warmer or louder.
Alright, and if we wanted to decrease the temperature in the thermostat, you would say.
Turn down, turn down the heat. Exactly. So it's too hot in here. Can you please turn down the heat?
Alright, very good. And our next phrase is, well, the dad was talking about the bills and how
expensive it is to use the thermostat. And he said, I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill.
Okay, so a bill is like you know something that you pay. It's money. And so in this case,
I don't want you to run up the bill. That means to increase the amount of money, I have to spend.
So maybe if you leave your television on all night, you're running up your electricity bill.
Exactly. Or if you talk on the phone 10 hours a day, you run up the phone bill and your mother kills you.
Alright, and well, the daughter was complaining about her catching a cold to catch a cold.
Alright, so remember this, a cold is when you have maybe a runny nose and the cough and the sore throat.
It usually happens when the weather changes, but we don't get a cold, you catch a cold.
Okay. And remember like in baseball, you throw and catch. It's something that's fast.
Alright, so you catch a cold. What about the flu? Do you get the flu or catch the flu?
So you can't catch a flu, but you can't catch a cold.
Just remember this phrase to catch a cold. I caught the cold.
No. To catch a cold or I caught a cold. It's almost like if I have it, I could throw it to you Marco.
I knew catch it.
Right, because it's in the air, the virus. Yeah, it passes very quickly.
Alright, very good. So an interesting dialogue. Let's listen to it one last time.
It's freezing in here. Can I turn up the heat?
Don't touch that thermostat. You don't pay the bills around here.
Dad, are you serious? What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it? Look.
I can see my breath. Put on a sweater. I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly.
Dad, I'm going to catch a cold.
When I was your age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do.
We had a furnace in the center of the living room and that was it. We used it to cook,
heat the house and even dry our clothes. We never caught a cold. You should be grateful.
Alright, we're back and well you mentioned about the thermostat and your dad actually controlling the heating at home.
Was it, was it the case like this in this scenario?
Um, it was sometimes would have to wear more clothes because we didn't want to run up the bill.
But we had a special situation in my house because I'm from Chicago and it's very cold in the
winter's in Chicago. But we had a fireplace. Okay. So even if it was very cold, we always had firewood
and we could put on the fire in the fireplace to keep warm. So everyone would stay in the living room
and read and listen to music and just, you know, relax. Now I heard that because, you know,
when you're burning wood, it causes some pollution. In some cities, it's banned, right? To actually
turn on or we'll have a fireplace. That's right. Yeah. So but in Chicago, you can still do it.
Absolutely. And in most of the states, you can. Although a lot of people in new houses,
they don't have real fireplace. They have electric fireplace. And so you can use a light switch to
turn on your fire. It's not a real fire. It's just a glowing light. Yeah. All right. Well, very good.
This is an interesting lesson, especially because the winter season is coming up and
well, everyone is cold. So we hope you enjoyed it. And if you have any questions and
any doubts, you can come to our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. Happy
studies and stay warm. All right. Everybody.