Hello English learners and welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine and it's the Christmas season Marco. So that means we have a very festive lesson today.
That's right. Christmas is coming up and well a tradition among many people around the world is to buy a Christmas tree.
That's right. I remember when we used to do this in my family, it was one of my favorite times of the year.
So we're going to explore this in today's lesson after we listen to the dialogue we'll be back to talk about some of these interesting words and phrases.
I'm home. Everyone come here. I bought a Christmas tree. Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow, it's huge. Are you sure it will fit in the living room?
Awesome. I'll go get the Christmas lights. Of course it will help me put it in the living room.
I found the lights. I got the Christmas ornaments. We could also place these stockings next to the chimney.
Great idea. While we decorate the tree, we can listen to some good old Christmas songs.
All right, we're back. As we mentioned, the entire dialogue is about a Christmas tree.
Why don't you explain what a Christmas tree is because many people maybe don't even
do or buy Christmas trees. Okay, well a Christmas tree is usually a green tree
that we cut down and we put in the house. So it's not a real tree with roots in the ground,
but sometimes it comes from a real tree outside. And the tree is very small on the top and it goes out
like a triangle. Okay, so it's a special shape. And we generally make it look very pretty with lights and
ornaments and decorations. And on Christmas on the 25th or the 24th it depends where you come from.
We put lots of presents underneath the Christmas tree. Wow, it sounds amazing. Well, yeah, and it looks
very nice. It does look really beautiful and it's just a really special part of Christmas.
And well, as you mentioned, sometimes the tree is just a fake plastic tree, but many times it's a
real tree and the type of tree that you use is a pine tree. Exactly. And so pine tree is a kind of
tree that doesn't have leaves. It has needles. That means that they're long, very thin, green pieces
that are all over the tree. And you can see these trees in most northern places like Scandinavia,
or in America, maybe Illinois and Minnesota, Michigan and Vermont. And they're very, as you say,
very unique trees, but they also have a very special smell, the smell of pine. They do. It's such a nice
smell that a lot of the things that we use in America to clean our houses have a pine smell because
it makes the house smell nice. Very good. So a pine tree, the dead brought a pine tree or a Christmas
tree home. And well, the wife was a little bit worried if it will fit. Okay, will it fit? This is
very important question because a lot of pine trees are very, very tall. Right. So if a pine tree
is three meters tall or four meters tall, will it fit? Is the question we ask? Is it too big?
Or is it going to be stuck on this thing in the house? And so we could ask this about anything.
I just bought a new TV. Will it fit in the living room? I don't know. I'm very nervous. I spend a lot of
money. All right. And well, you were talking about the Christmas tree and how you put a lot of nice
decorations on it. And so we say that we decorate the tree. That's right. So the verb here, this is an
action word, two decorate. So every holiday season in my family, we take one day and we decorate
the tree. That means that we take very small special ornaments and ribbons and lights. And we put
them on the tree to make the tree look pretty. Wow. You can also say decorate the house or to decorate
the house for a party. So this means to make something look special or pretty. Very good. We've taken
a look at very specific words related to Christmas trees and decorating it. So why don't we listen
to the dialogue again and we'll be back to continue with some more language takeaway.
I'm home. Everyone come here. I bought a Christmas tree. Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow. It's huge. Are you sure it will fit in the living room? Awesome. I'll go get the Christmas
lights. Of course it will. Help me put it in the living room. I found the lights. I got the Christmas
ornaments. We could also place these stockings next to the chimney. Great idea. While we decorate
the tree, we can listen to some good old Christmas songs.
Alright, we're back. So why don't we take a look at three more words on language takeaway part two?
Language takeaway. There's just so many words that are associated with Christmas and the
Christmas season that we have to look at them again here in Language takeaway part two. And
the first one we've already mentioned, it goes together with the phrase to decorate the tree.
Okay. So what do we decorate the tree with Marco? You mentioned ornaments. That's right. Christmas
ornaments. Christmas ornaments. And so an ornament is a thing. It's something that we use to make
something else look prettier. And so in this case, ornaments are sometimes round and red or green or
gold, we hang them on the tree. And well, in this case, it's a Christmas ornament for the tree,
but an ornament can be anything any nice piece of art or something they can use to decorate your house.
Right. Exactly. And in my family ornaments aren't just those round circles or balls for Christmas,
every family member has a special kind of ornament. So my dad has Santa Claus ornaments.
And my mom has funny rabbit ornaments. And I have in-law ornaments. So everybody has a special one.
No, that's really nice. And well, apart from ornaments, there is also this tradition of hanging
stockings. Okay. So a stocking you might have heard this word before in, in the sense of a clothing
item, a stocking is like a sock. A big sock. And it also means old, old stockings that women would wear.
But in this case, a stocking, a Christmas stocking is a very, very, very big sock that we hang.
And on Christmas, we get to fill it with very special things like candy and toys. Candy toys,
very good. So actually, you hang the stockings and the common place to do it in, or to put them on,
is it on the chimney, right? That's right. So there's a fireplace. And usually above the fireplace,
there's a shelf. We call it a mantle. And there's a place there to hang these. And the place where
all of the smoke from the fire comes out is the chimney. Okay. It's also the place where Santa Claus
comes down. Right. So you have the fireplace where you put the wood. You have the mantle that's
the space where you actually put the stockings on. And the tube that goes up and where the smoke
comes out of is called the chimney. Right. So you don't want to live there. And then actually,
the joke is that Santa Claus is definitely too fat to go down the chimney. But it's a special place
in the Christmas story because that's what Santa Claus does. Very good. Interesting words. Why don't
we listen to this dialogue a one last time?
I'm home. Everyone come here. I bought a Christmas tree. Look at this beautiful pine tree.
Wow. It's huge. Are you sure it will fit in the living room? Awesome. I'll go get the Christmas
lights. Of course it will. Help me put it in the living room. I found the lights. I got the Christmas
ornaments. We could also place these stockings next to the chimney. Great idea. While we decorate
the tree, we can listen to some good old Christmas songs.
Alright we're back. So as you say, the Christmas season is important in America and people not only
decorate Christmas trees, but also their house. And even outside they put Christmas lights all over
the house. They put little statues of Santa Claus in reindeer. And it's just it's a very,
I don't know. Sometimes I'll have a strange thing to do. It is. It's almost funny how much
people like to spend on not just time, but also money on decorating their houses. And so where I
come from, people decorate the outside. It's a lot. You have Christmas lights on all parts of the house.
And then maybe all of the reindeer in the front yard or whatever. Then they're 12 of them or nine
of them. I don't remember. But actually it was nice because when I live there,
with my parents, we would go out and tour around the neighborhood just to see other people's
Christmas lights and decorations because as we say, some of them can be very, very nice and they take
a lot of time and effort into decorating it. They do. It's really special. And at my house, we generally
just decorated the inside. But sometimes we did lights on the outside. And there's some very
funny movies to talk about this like National Lampoon's Christmas vacation. Right. And so there's
some really funny scenes about putting Christmas lights on the house. Alright well that's all the time
we have for today. But we'll definitely post a link of this movie that's actually very good.
It kind of depicts the traditional American in a funny way. It's a very funny movie. Alright. So
and if you have any questions, any other doubts or comments, you can come to EnglishPod.com and we'll see
you there. We will also enjoy the Christmas season until next time. Bye.