Hello everyone and welcome back to English,
Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and it's the holiday season.
That's right, it's almost Christmas and so we are bringing you one of the most typical
Christmas songs, with Christmas carols, I guess, in all over the world probably.
That's right and I've heard it in many different languages, even Chinese.
Yeah, you think Chinese?
Okay, I'll have to ask.
Yeah, I have to ask.
But yeah, we're talking about jingle bells today.
So the famous song, jingle bells, you'll hear it everywhere, especially during the Christmas season.
I only during the Christmas season.
And so let's listen to the song.
The song is pretty long.
It has like a couple of different verses.
But we've taken the main one, the first one and the chorus, which are like the most famous ones.
And so let's listen to the song.
Anyone who's so good
or no feels required.
Letting all the way, there's a bug theory making students proud.
What the hell is to write in English names on the night?
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way.
Oh, what the hell is to write in one voice of the name?
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way.
This is gonna be stuck in my head all day, Marko.
I know, it's kind of catchy though.
How can you not get into the spirit with this song?
Well, as you said, a carol, a Christmas carol is a song,
and they're meant to be catchy.
You know, you get them in your head and they stay there forever.
I think it's also because every mall or shopping center you go to,
they're playing these songs so they just kind of get stuck in your head.
In the background, all that I did, did do.
Yeah, exactly.
Makes you want to shop more.
Or kill someone.
Alright, so there were probably a couple of different words that you didn't understand here.
So we're gonna go through the whole song, a little by little, and we'll explain it.
So starting out with the first line, it says, dashing through the snow.
Well, okay, this is interesting because in sports, there's an event called a 100 meter dash.
Okay, so a dash is a very quick run.
Very fast, right?
That's right.
The dashing through the snow is kind of running or going through the snow very quickly.
Alright, we don't know who is running through the snow, but we know something or someone
is going very quickly through the snow.
And then the second line, it says, in a one horse opens slay.
Okay, so now we know who's dashing through the snow.
It's a horse in a, and you're in a slay.
Okay, so an open slay means that there's no roof.
So you're sitting under the stars and there's a horse pulling your slay through the snow.
Okay, so a slay is kind of like a vehicle for the snow, right?
There's no wheels, okay?
Because it's hard to drive and snow.
And so this is an old kind of vehicle that has maybe wood or metal underneath to make it slide.
To make it slide, very good.
Alright, and then we have this strange word here.
It's oh apostrophe er or the field we go.
Or the fields we go.
Well, this is very, very common in poetry.
Okay, so this is a way to make the word over shorter because over you can hear it two syllables.
Over, but sometimes we only want one.
So we say, or.
Okay, or the fields we go over.
Okay, interesting.
Laughing all the way.
Bells on Bob tells ring.
Now what are Bob tells?
What are these bells on Bob tells?
Okay, well Bob tails are the tails of certain animals.
So we can say we have a bunny rabbit with a bob tail.
That means the tail sticks up.
But it's also maybe reindeer have bob tails because their tails stick up.
You can see them.
Okay, so I guess in this case because it's Christmas.
These animals like reindeer and rabbits have little bells on them.
That and according to the next line, making spirits bright.
Right?
So you're making people happy.
That's right.
Spirit is your your attitude or your soul.
And in this case, you're making your being made happy.
You're happy because it's Christmas.
You're outside.
Very good.
And well, he says, what fun it is to laugh and sing a slaying song tonight.
Now slaying.
We know that slay is this vehicle to go through this.
No, but a slaying song, I guess is.
Is this song we sing when we're in a slay?
So this isn't the real word, but this is something that makes the song kind of.
Makes you think that these people are just singing a special song for being in a slay.
All right.
And now we go to the chorus.
Jingle bells jingle bells.
So this word jingle.
It's a verb, right?
Yeah, two jingle.
We can do it with your keys, too.
To jingle is to make noise when metal is touching metal.
So we have bells and they think they can each other.
I got some keys here.
I'll show you what jingleing is.
So we go like this.
Oh, it's jingle your keys, right?
Exactly.
So you can use it with keys with bells.
Can use it with anything else.
Anything that makes a sound like that?
Times jingle.
Okay.
All right.
Very good.
So jingle all the way.
Oh, what fun it is to ride again in a one horse open slay.
Jingle bells.
Oh, wait.
So all the way.
Maybe we're going someplace.
All the way wherever you're going.
Home or to dinner.
And what fun it is to ride in a one horse open slay.
So the chorus is not very hard.
And either is the first, the first.
You know, sometimes the song is pretty fast.
So sometimes you don't really understand what they're saying.
Personally, I did not know the lyrics of Jingle bells until we started doing this part.
Really?
Well, because when we sing it, we mumble.
You know, you can't hear all the words.
Oh, you don't know the words, but dashing through the snow.
Sometimes you have to think of it very clearly.
Very good.
So that's all the words we have for this podcast.
It's a very good Christmas Carol.
It's very catchy.
And I don't know how old it is.
I've heard it since I was small.
Well, probably old enough to come from a time when there weren't cars because they're
slay.
And when they used or because I don't see people use or anymore.
No, I think it's mostly just songs and poems.
You see it a lot in the 19th century.
Right.
And but it isn't interesting.
Also, I guess the relationship between like the slaves and snow.
When I don't Christmas is always related to this, even though, you know, in some places,
you don't have snow during Christmas.
That's right.
But it does.
I mean, we're here in Shanghai and we can hear people singing a song.
So, and there's no, so I think it's just a way to think about the season of Christmas and the attitude of people when it's Christmas time.
Right.
So I hope you enjoyed our lesson.
If you have any questions about this Christmas Carol, you can let us know on English.com.
And we'll also post the other verses, the less known verses of jingle bells because it's actually a pretty long song.
Very long.
And I don't know any of the other verses because I'm a special guest.
That's exactly how we chose the first one and the chorus because it's the most popular one.
So we'll see you guys there and Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
Bye.