Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right. We are going to talk about winter, but specifically about the clothes you wear during winter
when it's very very cold outside.
That's right and I hear you're not too familiar with some of these practices because where you come from,
you don't really have winter. We don't have winter. We have dry season and rainy season
but same temperature. Well Chicago definitely has a snowy season so I'm very familiar with these things.
So let's jump right into today's dialogue. We'll be hearing it one time and in a minute we'll be back to talk about it.
Bye mom. Wait Jimmy it's cold outside. Put a hat on.
Okay bye. No wait you'll be too cold without mittens.
All right see ya. Hold on with that wind you're going to catch a cold. Where this scarf?
Okay see ya after school and earmuffs put these on. Here we go.
What? Yes honey. I can't breathe.
Hey.
All right we're back so there were a couple of different items of clothing that we saw in this dialogue.
So let's look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay well first of all we have Mom and Jimmy. Jimmy is a boy's name. He's a little boy and
Mom is saying goodbye to him but first she wants him to put on clothes. So the first item the first thing
she asks him to put on is a hat. Now you've probably seen like a baseball cap or many different
types of hats but and sometimes in other languages they have specific names for a hat for winter right
but in English it's a hat. Anything that covers your head is a hat that's kind of like the category.
So maybe this one is a warm wool hat but it's in the end it's a hat.
The hat. Okay so he's put on the hat now what else is he going to put on? Well we need to keep our fingers
warm okay so there are two kinds of ways to keep your fingers warm and the way in this dialogue
that the boy keeps his fingers warm is with mittens. All right so mittens you put on your hands.
What's the difference between mittens and gloves? Okay gloves have special places for each finger
one two three four five on each hand. Right and mittens there's two spaces one for your thumb
and one for all your other fingers. Okay so that means you can't really hold things. So you kind of
look like a penguin or something like yeah you look like a yeah exactly like a penguin and it's
mostly for children adults don't wear mittens because adults need to hold things like keys and
bones and car, car steering wheels. So in this case mittens is usually for children. Okay so
mittens and while the mother is still a little bit worried so she tells him to wear a scarf.
Okay a scarf is all long usually made of wool a long piece of fabric that you put around your neck
to keep your neck warm. Okay so a scarf. A scarf. Okay and he's put on the mittens the scarf
the hat and he's missing some ear muffs. Okay this is a little funny because usually if you're
wearing a hat you don't need ear muffs but ear muffs are like headphones but they keep your ears warm.
Right and we wear these they don't cover your head they just cover your ears and usually they're
just two round circles over your ears. So as you say exactly they look like big ear phones
and they keep your ears warm now. As you say you usually don't wear this if you're wearing a hat
because well you would put your ears inside your hat. So it looks pretty silly. It is wearing all of
this together. All right and so those four key items, those four key pieces of clothing are for
our language takeaway today. When we listen to this dialogue again and we'll come back soon
to talk about fluency builder. Bye mom. Wait Jimmy it's cold outside but a hat on. Okay bye.
No wait you'll be too cold without mittens. All right see ya. Hold on with that wind you're
going to catch a cold where this scarf. Okay see you after school. Oh and ear muffs put these on here
we go. Oh yes honey. All right we're back so now let's take a look at four key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase as I said before has to do with the mum and the boy saying
goodbye to each other. So he says all right see ya. Yeah. Okay so see as into look to write you see
something and what about YA? Yeah. So this is a very spoken language way of saying you. So we could say
see you later but if you want to make it shorter you can say see ya. See ya. Bye. Bye. Goodbye. All right so see ya.
And then what's our next way of saying goodbye? Hold on. Oh wait that's not. We're not there yet no.
Hold on is our next phrase and this is a way to say wait. Wait hold on. So you just say hold on it means
wait it's not really rude right it's just a little bit more casual. Exactly it's very casual so you
cannot say hold that doesn't make sense you have to use these two words together hold on. So like I
said before with Marco who wants to go fast I could say hold on wait a second. All right okay so hold on
see ya and now you gotta be careful because you're going to catch a cold to catch a cold. Okay so
a cold is when you you know when you cough you have a sore throat it's starting to get cold outside
and you don't feel well okay so you're have a running nose it's it's illness and most people
get this every year it's very common but you don't get a cold you catch a cold okay okay so
catch is the same where we use for when we we talk about sports like throwing and catching okay
it's almost like it just hits you it's so fast you just catch a cold so that's a really important
one you just said because you don't use the verb get you don't get a cold you catch a cold or if you
say that you were sick last week because you had a cold you would say oh I caught a cold or I had a
cold exactly so remember present tense I catch a cold past tense I caught a cold last week okay
and our last phrase for fluency builder is here we go here we go okay so when do we hear this phrase
the mother says to the boy put these on here we go so she's doing something with him she's helping
him put his earmuffs on and here we go is a way to say okay I've finished okay I'm done okay
your earmuffs are on you so you're ready here you go here you go right so we say here we go like
everything is ready your earmuffs are on exactly so maybe I'm a computer and I have a problem
and I'm waiting waiting waiting waiting and you know when the bars loading and finally thing it's
ready here we go here we go now okay start it's ready or sometimes a waitress will come
and serve you food and say here we go here's your order exactly so this is a way to say
what you've been waiting for it's ready now okay great so I think it's time for us to listen to
this dialogue one last time before we come back here we go
bye mom wait Jimmy it's cold outside put a hat on okay bye no wait you'll be too cold without
mittens all right see yeah hold on with that wind you're going to catch a cold where this
scarf
okay see after school and earmuffs put these on here we go
well yes honey I can't breathe all right we're back so as you mentioned in Chicago it's
very very cold so I imagine you had all of these winter clothes right that's right and it's funny
because I remember being a small child and my mother doing this to me putting on snow pants and boots
and earmuffs and hats and gloves and scarves and all the sudden it's so hot inside because
you're wearing everything and so you can't even walk like you're saying a pink you look like a
penguin walking out the door and you get to school and you're sweating right and so in school
we had to take we had a special room and we had to take everything off because there's snow everywhere
and snow can be very dangerous because it melts and it turns into water okay so I have very strong
memories of all of this playing a mom taking them off and it's being warm all the time
well yeah when it's cold or you live in a place with cold weather you have to have these
items of clothing because otherwise you might catch a cold exactly so I hope that no one
out there catches a cold but if if you want some suggestions where scarf cover your neck that's the
most important you're head and your scarf that's important all right and if you guys have any
other questions or comments you can visit our website englishpod.com and we'll see everyone there
bye everyone bye