Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today
Marco and I have an elementary level lesson for you. That's right. It's a new year and so we have a lesson for you
where we are going to make new decisions and have a new opportunity in the new year. That's right. So the new year
is the time to change parts of your life, maybe. So that's what we're going to talk about today. Let's
listen to this dialogue three times and we'll make them back. We'll be talking about the words and phrases in the dialogue.
Now that it's the new year, I've decided to turn over a new leaf.
Yeah, you finally decided to wipe the slate clean. You got it. I have a new job. I'm living in a new city with new friends.
This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life.
So what are you going to do? Take up an art class or something? Well, first of all, I've decided to stop smoking.
It's not that I'm pinching pennies or anything. It's just that I've been smoking since I was 16.
And I think it's time to stop. I'm with you on that one. Anything else you're planning on doing?
One last thing. I've decided to come out of the closet. It's about time.
All right, we're back. And so if you noticed that dialogue has actually a lot of really, really rich phrases in there.
So today we're going to change the format a little bit and we're going to do fluency builder in two different sections.
So starting out with the first one on fluency builder part one fluency builder. So the new year, we think about new things,
changing things. We have a great phrase in English to describe starting fresh starting a new.
And we say turn over a new leaf. Okay, so you turn over a new leaf. So that means that you are going to
maybe make a radical change, right? Some completely new. That's right. So if you think about it,
it's a new chapter in your life for a new adventure or something like that. Maybe you're going to
quit your job. Turn over a new leaf. Start a new job. Okay. So you can say I'm going to turn over a new leaf or
Sarah, turn over a new leaf and quit smoking. Let's turn over a new leaf and forget the past.
There we go. All right, so to turn over a new leaf, so just imagine that you have a leaf on the ground and you turn it over and it's nice and clean.
All right, and talking about cleanliness. Our second phrase is to wipe the slate clean.
Okay, when I think about this phrase, I think about a chalkboard. Okay, so a slate is like a chalkboard.
And all of the things that you've done good and bad are on that chalkboard. And to wipe the slate clean means to
erase those words, erase those things. So perhaps Marco and I fight all the time and we're angry each other.
Finally, I say listen, Marco, let's wipe the slate clean. Let's forget the past. Let's forget the things we said and start again.
And start a new leaf. To wipe the slate clean is to just start over, you know, just to erase everything.
Let's forget about it and start over. Exactly. All right, and so we're starting over and his friend is asking you decided to wipe the slate clean.
And the friend said, you got it. You got what? What it? What is it? English and English, we love the word it.
Yeah. Well, in this case, you got it means you're right exactly. You understand what I'm talking about.
Okay, so if you agree with me or I understand what you're talking about, you would say you got it. You got it. You got it.
All right, so I'm trying to explain to you maybe Marco something very difficult. Like, you know, if you add four and ten, you get 14.
But what if you add ten more?
It's 24. You got it. All right. Okay, so he understands math.
Yes, okay. So that's the way you would use you got it. It's really popular phrase. I mean, you can use it and I'm pretty much anything.
Not only if you're right, but also if somebody agrees with it or you promise something, right?
So are you going to pick me up today? Yeah, you got it. Okay. So it's a way to agree or to show that you're saying yes.
Yes. Okay. So why don't we listen to our dialogue again? And we'll come back shortly to look at fluency builder part two.
Now that it's the new year, I've decided to turn over a new leaf. Yeah, you finally decided to white the slate clean.
You got it. I have a new job. I'm living in a new city with new friends. This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life.
So what are you going to do? Take up an art course or something?
Well, first of all, I've decided to stop smoking. It's not that I'm pinching pennies or anything. It's just that I've been smoking since I was 16.
And I think it's time to stop. I'm with you on that one. Anything else you're planning on doing? One last thing.
I've decided to come out of the closet. It's about time.
All right, we're back from now. Let's continue with our fluency builder. And well, they kept talking and
the guy mentioned that he's going to stop smoking. But it's not because he is pinching pennies.
Oh, pinching that sounds painful. Right. Okay, pinching is something you do, especially when you're a child.
You squeeze the skin pinch and it hurts. So it depends really as a whole, something with two fingers.
To pinch pennies means to try to spend very, very, very little money.
Right. So if we say, if I say, hey, Marco, you want to go to dinner night. There's this
really nice Italian place. It's a little expensive. But, oh, I can't. I'm sorry. I'm really pinching pennies
these days because I'm kind of broke. So maybe we'll go somewhere cheaper. Yeah. So actually pennies
are one cent. One cent coin. Right. They're called pennies in the United States. That's right.
And it's the smallest kind of money that we have in America. So if you're pinching pennies,
if you're saving pennies, it means you really don't have much money. Right. You're really, really
savings. Right. Okay. So pinching pennies. So he decided to quit smoking and his friend agreed with him
and said, you know what? I'm with you on that one. Okay. So you quit smoking, Marco, and I quit smoking.
I'm with you. And now I think it's a good idea. If I'm with you on that one, means I agree with you.
You're you're doing the right thing. So you can say, I'm with you on that one or you can just say,
you know what? I'm with you. Do it or I'm with you. I agree or I'm with you. I support your decision.
So you are going to go skydiving in a couple of weeks. That means you're going to jump out of an
airplane. I'm not with you on that one. I was a full by decision. I think it's okay for you, but I
would not want to do it. All right. Right. So you can do it in that way or just anything. You support
somebody's decision. I'm with you. I'm with you on that one. Exactly. All right. And our last phrase
to come out of the closet. So who's in the closet? Why is somebody hiding in the closet? Okay,
someone's not really hiding in the closet. This is a phrase we use to describe someone who is gay or
lesbian, who has a secret about being gay or lesbian. So when they come out of the closet,
they're telling their friends and family for the first time that this is how they feel.
So it's basically a phrase that's kind of a metaphor to say, you know what? I'm going to tell everyone
that I am gay or lesbian. Right. That's right. Well, it's because in English oftentimes a closet is a
place where we keep secrets. Okay. And so to come out of the closet means to share your secrets with
people. So sometimes in English you say, you have skeletons in the closet. That's right. This is a
little different. Maybe I killed someone. And it's a skeleton in my closet. It's a secret that I keep.
But skeleton in your closet can also be a very big secret. Like you were once married and
you never told anyone. Yeah. Right. Or I have I have two kids. And I never told you guys. Right. So
those were the skeletons in the closet. But in this case, it's to come out of the closet. And that's
always related to telling somebody for the first time that you are gay or lesbian. That's right.
And we don't say it about being straight, which is the opposite, which is man, men who love women
and women who love men. Right. You don't say it about coming out of the closet there. You say it
about being gay or lesbian. Okay. So very interesting. And so I think we should listen to this dialogue
for the last time. And we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Now that it's the new year, I've decided to turn over a new leaf. Yeah. You finally decided to
white the slate clean. You got it. I have a new job. I'm living in a new city with new friends.
This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life. So what are you going to
do? Take up an art closet or something? Well, first of all, I've decided to stop smoking. It's not
that I'm pinching pennies or anything. It's just that I've been smoking since I was 16. And I think
it's time to stop. And with you on that one, anything else you're planning on doing? One last thing.
I've decided to come out of the closet. It's about time.
All right, we're back. So this is very interesting. And these phrases are so common because
if you have a fight with somebody, you say, you know what, let's just wipe the slate clean and
start all over again. Or let's turn over a new leaf, let's stop fighting. And especially in New
years, right? Everyone makes a promise to start fresh. That's right. Well, the new year, you can
use a new calendar. You can take a fresh perspective on your life. It's refreshing. And I think
it's good that we do this. We evaluate the things that make us happy and we evaluate the things that
make us unhappy. And part of that means turning over a new leaf. Part of it also means apologizing
to people or trying to make the relationships in your life healthier. And I think it's very
healthy to the person in this dialogue says, listen, I'm finally going to come out of the closet.
I'm going to be honest with my friends and family. And that's really interesting because as
we said to come out of the closet is a phrase used in English and mostly related only in this context.
So you might see it in TV shows or in a movie. And but it's it's an interesting topic still
debatable all over the world about, you know, gay marriages and things like that. That's right.
So we're curious about your new years resolutions. Are you going to be wiping any slate's
clean? Are you going to be doing anything differently this year? Let us know on our website
EnglishPod.com. We look forward to hearing from you and until next time. Bye everyone. Bye.