Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about something that has always been very confusing for me.
For me as well, I don't understand very well what this is about.
We're going to be talking about time zones and a little bit about daylight savings time.
Before we get started though, let's take a look at this phrase and today's vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. All right. So the phrase is daylight savings time. Okay.
So we're trying to save daylight pretty much. That's right. So this is the time of year when we
change our clocks. What does that mean? That means in the fall, there's a special day and everyone
has it on their calendar and we change the clocks. We put them back one hour. So if it was eight
a clock now, it's seven a clock. Okay. So everything is earlier. Starts earlier. Yes. And that's basically
to take advantage of the daylight. Right. That's why it's called daylight savings time.
Exactly. And so that's for the winter. And then when the winter is passed, we change the clocks.
Again, we have the spring daylight savings where we change our clocks ahead. Okay. So it sounds kind of complicated.
Many countries don't have daylight savings time. They don't change their clocks at all.
But we're going to be talking about this in a little bit more. So why don't we listen to our dialogue
for the first time?
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time? What? Why do we have to do that?
Well, at the start of the spring, we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less in the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth. In any case,
to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
I see. That's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMP. I never know what
time zone we are in or wind it change my clock. That just stands for Grinnich meantime. Here in California,
we're in Pacific Standard Time. That is 8 times zones west of Grinnich. Remember when we were in Beijing?
Well, then we were in China Standard Time and that's 8 times zones east of Grinnich.
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the huge time difference.
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than 8 hours, we still arrived in LA the same
day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
Alright, we're back. So that was a pretty clear explanation of why we do these things.
But maybe there were a couple of words that you didn't understand. So let's take a look at those
now in language takeaway. Language takeaway. Well, Marko, what you were hinting at before this idea
that we have shorter days in the winter and longer days in the summer has to do with the
rotation of the earth. So the rotation of the earth is our first phrase. Okay, so the earth rotates.
What does that mean if it rotates? It means to spin around. But not just to spin around anywhere.
It means that if you draw a line through the middle of something, it never leaves that line.
It just kind of turns. Okay, so it's spinning like the wheels on a car. They rotate. That means they go around.
But they are fixed to the car. Right. So this is one of the reasons why we need to compensate
our clocks because of the rotation of the earth. And that's our next word to compensate. This is a
verb to compensate. And it's often used with money, but it can be used with time as well. Time or
sunlight. So with money, you'd say I paid him a hundred dollars, but I owed him a hundred fifty. So I'm
going to compensate him for the extra fifty. Okay. Means I'm going to fix it. Okay, so two
compensates would be the verb and compensation would be the noun. Now in this case, we're talking
about time. So how can we compensate time? Well, that means that if we have lost an hour because
we've changed the clocks, we have to compensate. We have to try and gain that hour back. And so that's
why in the spring after the day is start to get longer and longer, with the compensate for that by
changing the clocks again. Okay. So we're compensating time. Now related to daylight savings and this
whole time thing is time zones. We have time zones all over the earth and you've probably noticed this.
If you've traveled, you have to change your clocks or many times you've seen hotels, what time it
is in London and Hong Kong and Berlin, etc. And this makes a lot of sense because like we said,
the earth is rotating and so if it's daylight in Moscow and it's nighttime in New York,
obviously it's not the same time. Right. So to compensate for this difference, we have different
time zones and each time zone is pretty much an hour or so and you know half an hour different from
the next one. Right. So most countries actually have different time zones throughout the country unless
they're small that they don't really need to compensate any change or for example China, just to
unify everything. It's a big country but they have one time zones, China standard time.
Exactly, but in the United States we have four times. Right. All right. So that time zone and
out related to time zone is time difference. Okay. Well, think about math here, difference is a
where that we use in math and a time difference is the amount of time. That means how many hours
there are between one time zone and another time zone. So for example Beijing and New York
these are very, very far away from each other. If it's day in New York it's night in Beijing.
So that means if it's seven in the morning in Beijing, it's probably around seven at night in New
York. So the time difference would be more or less 12 hours. Exactly. But when it's daylight savings
time it's 13. So be careful. Right. Okay. I think that's pretty clear. I think we should go back
and listen to it. I like again and we'll be back soon with fluency filter.
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time? What? Why do we have to do that?
Well, at the start of the spring we usually have more daylight in the mornings and less in the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth. In any case,
to take better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
I see. That's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMT. I never know what
we are in or when to change my clock. That just stands for Grinnich meantime. Here in California
we're in Pacific Standard Time. That is eight times Zones West of Grinnich. Remember when we were
in Beijing? Well, then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight times Zones East of Grinnich.
That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the huge time difference.
Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than eight hours we still arrived in LA
the same day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at three key phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Oh, let's go back to the beginning of this dialogue. The person who's
explaining all of these interesting things is saying that well, in any case, to take
better advantage of the daylight available we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
So this is an important phrase you could say to take better advantage of or to take advantage of.
Let's talk about this. So take advantage of something. So to take advantage of something is to use it efficiently,
right? Or to take better advantage. So for example, if you drive to work every day and your neighbor drives
to work every day and you work at the same place you could take a better advantage of your car and the
cost by sharing the same car to work. Exactly. Or when people started to use computers,
you could say, well, they were taking better advantage of their time by speeding things up by
making things faster with the computers. Right. Or many mothers say take better advantage of your
time and read something instead of playing those video games. Exactly. So it means like you said,
to be more efficient to do useful or important things. That's right. And now when we talked about
what daylight savings, timings or GMT, what that stands for, this is an interesting phrase. It stands for.
Well, think about it as a picture. So if something stands for something else, that means the
original thing, it's not there anymore. And so in words and phrases like GMT, you GMT doesn't mean
anything by itself. But the G stands for something that M stands in. It's an acronym. Okay. So this is an
acronym that stands for that represents three big long words. Okay. Grinch mean time. Right. So we use
this a lot when we are defining words or when we are defining an acronym like GMT stands for Grinch
mean time or for example, USA stands for United States of America. Or you can even say someone's
name stands for something. So Marco, what is the M in your last name stand for? So your Marco
M, what is the M stand for? Right. And then I would say, well, it stands for Me here.
You're last name. Right. So you can use this when you see things that you don't understand,
maybe an acronym or an abbreviation like does Kathy stand for Katherine? Yes, Kathy stands for
Katherine. It's a short version of Katherine. Cool. All right. And well, now talking a little bit more
about time, you may be seeing the movie back to the future. And this is what it's all about to go
back in time. To go back in time. So we went back in time. This is what the person says about
the flight from Beijing to LA. What's interesting is that to go back in time is kind of a fixed
phrase. We always say like this. So we could say, if you went back in time, where would you go?
What time? What place? Right. So to go back in time, usually use it like this. Now, what if I wanted
to say to go into the future? Could you say go forward in time? You could go forward in time,
where you could go into the future? Right. Go into the future. So remember, if you want to talk
about going back in time, it's usually traveling to the past. Mm-hmm. Exactly. All right. So
that's all the phrases we have. Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the very last time?
Did you set your clock forward for daylight savings time? What? Why do we have to do that?
Well, at the start of the spring, we usually have more daylight in the mornings and lessen the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on the planet and the rotation of the earth. In any case,
to take better advantage of the daylight available, we compensate by moving our clocks forward one hour.
I see. Let's convenient. I never understood things like this such as GMT. I never know what
time zone we are in or a window change my clock. That just stands for a Greenwich Mean Time. Here in
California, we're in Pacific Standard Time. That is eight times zones west of Greenwich.
Remember when we were in Beijing? Well, then we were in China Standard Time and that's eight
times zones east of Greenwich. That's why it was so weird traveling from Beijing to LA because of the
huge time difference. Even though we left Beijing at noon and flew for more than eight hours,
we still arrived in LA the same day at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right, we're back. Now, this is actually something that really does happen right if you take
off in an airplane from Beijing. You fly for a certain amount of hours and you reach California
and it's still the same time. You reach it in the same day. It's very strange. The same thing
happens to me when I go home. So I leave Shanghai and I arrive in Chicago and I arrive at the exact
same time I left on the same day. So it's like a time never pass. It's the longest day of your entire life
because it's not 24 hours. The flight is 14 hours. It's really 24, 38 hours long, right? So it's
really intense and exhausting. And then what happens is when you do the opposite, you go from Chicago
to Shanghai, then you go into the future pretty much, right? Because you left on a Sunday, but you
arrive on a Tuesday. Or in my case, yeah, you leave on a Sunday and you arrive on a Monday and you
lose half a day of your life. Right. You're just sitting there and all of a sudden it goes past you.
Right. Yeah. So it all evens out in the end. Right. Right. So when you go back or when you come,
it all evens out. You recover. You get those hours of your life back pretty much. They're not gone forever.
All right. So if you guys have any questions, any doubts, you can send us an email at EnglishPod at
PraxisLanguage.com or come to our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there. Ask
away and until next time, everyone. Bye.