Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about office stuff. Things in your office.
That's right. We are talking about secrets in the office or maybe specific little things that people talk about behind other people's back.
Okay, bad things then. So this is an elementary level lesson. Before we get going though, let's take a look at a phrase in today's
vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview. All right. So the phrase for today is actually the same as the title for this lesson and that's office gossip.
Okay, y'all know what an office is. What is gossip? So to gossip means to talk about other people secretly or behind their backs or maybe talk about other people's problems or private things.
So oh my god, do you hear? John is totally going to break up with her.
People. Yeah, them knowing. Right. So you're talking about their private things, the relationships, maybe
you're even maybe criticizing them. That's right. So office gossip is talking about people in your office
without them knowing. So saying bad things about them. Right. So without any more delay, why don't we
listen to this dialogue for the first time?
Hey, Eric, have you heard? Hmm, no, go on. Tell me what's the latest office gossip?
Well, you didn't hear this from me, but the room is.
Paula is getting a promotion. No way, but she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her. She's so too
faced. You can't believe anything she says. Hey guys, what are you two whispering about? Oh, hi Paula, how are you?
I've got some good news. I'm getting a promotion. Congratulations. Eric and I were just saying that you
were the best person for the job. Yes, you're the best.
All right, we're back. So we have four key words that we want to look at from this gossip dialogue.
So when we take a look at those now in language takeaway. Language takeaway.
Okay, the first word is
rumor rumor. Now, this is an interesting word about gossip. Yeah, a rumor. So a rumor is a story that might or might not be true.
Right. Okay, so I heard a rumor that they broke up yesterday. Okay, so you're not sure if they broke up or no one has told you
for a fact. No, it means I probably heard it from someone else who heard it from someone else. Who heard it from someone else?
Who doesn't really know? Right. So rumors are maybe guesses about people and you don't know if they're true.
You see this a lot with famous people movie stars. They always talk about rumors that maybe they got married and secret or something.
Exactly. There's a rumor that Angelina Jolie and Brad Pitt are breaking up. Right. Okay, so we don't think that we don't know if it's true.
That's a rumor. So now the rumor that they heard was that this girl Paula is getting a promotion.
Promotion. This is an important office word. This means to be offered a better job in your company.
That means to move up. To move up. Right. All right. So this is a known. You get a promotion. Right?
Yes. I got a promotion last year, which also meant I got more money. Okay. Awesome. So that is a promotion.
Now when they were talking about the promotion, the girl said, I can't believe the guy said.
And Eric said, I can't believe she's getting a promotion. She's so too faced.
Too faced. So think about what this means to have two faces to be too faced means to have two different sides to your personality.
A good one and a bad one. Okay. So like I could be very nice to Marco Marco. Wow. You look so good today.
It's a nice guy. So how do I work her? And then oh my god. Marco's a good idiot. He's like never working and he's always on the phone.
Hi Marco. Hi. That is too faced. That's very good. All right. So two face means to have two different sides to your personality.
Now it's interesting the way that you use this word. You say two faced.
Right. So you have to add the idea thing. You can say he is too faced or he has two face. And now it's an adjective. So he's too faced.
Okay. She is too faced. Okay. Two face. I don't like people who are too faced. Okay. Very good. And we have one final word and
it's actually a verb when people talk like this. Okay. So what are you whispering about?
So usually when people are whispering they're talking about a rumor. Right. Or they're talking and see
you don't want somebody else to hear you. Right. So when you want to be very quiet like at the movie theater
you whisper. Okay. So those are our four words for language takeaway. Why don't we go back
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to take a look at a couple of phrases.
Hey Eric have you heard? Hmm. No. Go on tell me what's the latest office gossip?
Well you didn't hear this from me but the room is. Poola is getting a promotion.
No way. But she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her. She's so too faced. You can't believe
anything she says. Hey guys what are you two whispering about? Oh hi Poola. How are you?
I got some good news. I'm getting a promotion. Congratulations. How can I would just say that you
would the best person for the job? Yes. You're the best.
Alright we're back so now we have three key phrases from this great dialogue on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first one is the beginning to any great rumor. We say have you heard?
Right. So have you heard? Have you heard that she got a promotion? Right. It's kind you're not really
asking. Right. Although it is a question have you heard but you're not really expecting an answer.
What you're this means I'm going to tell you some gossip. Right. Have you heard?
Because maybe I did maybe I didn't but I'm still going to say it. She's still going to say it any
right. So usually you can say what right or in this case Eric goes, no go on tell me what's the latest
office gossip. So obviously he knows it's going to be gossip. Right. Have you heard?
Alright and so the next thing Pam says is well you didn't hear this from me.
Okay. What does this mean? This is typical. This is a way of saying okay don't tell anyone
that I told you. So you can tell people but just don't tell them that I said that this happened because
Pam doesn't want to get in trouble. Right. She doesn't want anyone to know that she was
giving out rumors. So that's why she's starting out with well you didn't hear this from me
but the rumor is okay. So you can so this is a way of saying alright don't tell anyone that I told you.
You didn't hear this from me. And also you can go you can say but the rumor is or you can say but
rumor has it. No rumor has it that Paul is getting a promotion. So you can go the both ways.
And now he exclaims something that's very strange if you just look at it from these two words. No way.
No way. What is no way? Well in this context no way means really? Wow. Right. I'm surprised.
So it's a way to express surprise. That's right but be careful because there's another meaning to this phrase.
For example um Mark, could you help me out get the get the groceries from the car? No way.
Okay that means you help me. No. Okay. Okay no way that means no but also if you say it like
no way. Right. You're saying wow that's so interesting. So it can be an expression of surprise or it can
be a way of saying no very firmly. No way. Exactly. All right so three great phrases there.
Very interesting dialogue about gossip. Very common in the office environment so why don't we
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit.
Hey Eric have you heard? Hmm no go on tell me what's the latest office gossip?
Well it didn't hit us from me but the room is.
Puller is getting a promotion. No way but she's a terrible worker and you can't trust her. She's so too
faced. You can't believe anything she says. Hey guys what are you two whispering about?
Oh hi Paula how are you? I've got some good news. I'm getting a promotion.
Congratulations Eric and I were just saying that you were the best person for the job.
Yes you're the best.
Okay we're back so office gossip is generally well it's common. It happens in every office but
I think that it's good to avoid too much gossip because sometimes people's feelings can get hurt.
Yeah it's it's actually very interesting because usually the bigger the company is I think more
gossip starts to spread because you know they're department so you got the marketing department
the finance department so you're like oh Kathy from finance she slept with the Tom from marketing
instead of like that then you have the gossip about the bosses. Right did you see he totally left
for the weekend but his wife was at home. Yeah so and also one of the situations where all
lot of rumors and office gossip some starts to come up is office parties or the office
Christmas parties where people maybe are drinking or something happens and a lot of rumors
start to spread and they're more relaxed and usual they do things they would normally do absolutely so
maybe we could open this up to you is there a common rumor or office gossip that you hear in your
office or is there that one secretary or guy that's always spreading rumors and gossiping and don't
use any real names you can just tell us general stories but that's about it for us here today at
EnglishPod hope you've enjoyed this check out our website EnglishPod.com let us know if you have
any questions or concerns but until next time bye bye