Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a sad lesson for you. This is an intermediate level lesson
about what happens when a friend or family member dies.
Exactly. So we have a lot of words that are related to all the preparations for when somebody dies
and also some phrases that you can say to someone that maybe had a family member who recently passed
away. So before we get into all of this we have a key word that we want to take a look at now
in vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview. All right so in vocabulary preview you have that one
word and it's the title of our lesson also funeral. Funeral. So funeral is an event that something
that we have. So basically a funeral is the time when we mourn someone who has died. It's a celebration
of their life. Right so it's kind of like a ceremony where you respect that person that passed away.
Right. Some people will talk about the person that passed away or maybe, you know it's time to
maybe honor that person too. As you say mourn and remember that person. Right so it's very common
for people in different religions to have different traditions. In some religions like I think in
Christianity you have a priest who will say some things that are very traditional and then say
some things about the person who died. And other religions have different ceremonies. Right. So
today we're going to take a look at what happens in preparing a funeral.
Hi Daniel how are you holding up? I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you. I'm doing much better.
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I imagine.
There are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time in date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket?
No. When he's being cremated. She was talked about how she didn't want to be buried.
I already chose a cremation earn and we planned to spread the ashes in the ocean.
I see. That sounds like something she would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be
tasteful. You're doing a great job. Thanks. It hasn't been easy but luckily we have life
insurance and when the left behind the detailed will that will sort out any other legal matters.
All right we're back so a pretty interesting dialogue and I'm sure you have a lot of
questions regarding some of those words and phrases that you heard. So why don't we take a look at
five key words on language takeaway? Language takeaway. So basically we have two
friends in this dialogue who are discussing arrangements for a funeral and one friend is asking
the other about his preparations and asks if he's bought a burial plot. Okay burial plot.
Now what is a burial plot and why would you buy one? Well a plot PLOT plot is a piece of land.
So you can think about this logically a burial plot burial to bury is a place space in the ground
where we bury a person. Usually you buy one of these at a cemetery right? That's right so
cemeteries have some usually a lot of land and you can pay for a piece of land. A small portion.
A small portion yeah and that's a burial plot. Okay good and well our next word is related to
what you put into this burial plot right? Somebody dies and what goes into this piece of land is a casket.
That's right and I don't know if any of you are fans of the TV show six feet under
but you'll know from this TV show that there are many different kinds of caskets. So a casket
is a box. You can have fancy caskets or you can have wooden caskets that are very simple like
pine and basically this is the box that the person's body will go into when they're buried.
Right very good so that is called a casket. Well moving on a new trend I would say in many
countries and many people around the world don't want to be buried. So what happens you get cremated.
cremated so this is the option for people who are not buried. In some countries China for example
I don't think you can be buried. You have to be cremated because there's an issue of space.
Right. And this is an option for most people where basically your friend or your loved one their body
is burned and you can collect the remains afterwards they're very small. They're ashes.
Right. So it's like a burning process. Okay interesting so the word is to be cremated to
get cremated. Yeah his body was cremated. It was cremated and well as you said you take the ashes
and you can put them in a cremation urn or just an urn. Okay urn this might sound like a
strange word to you but an urn is a special kind of pot. Okay or a vessel to hold things in.
So for example in this case we have a cremation urn that is a special pot usually very beautiful.
Sometimes there's a name on it with the deceased person's ashes or her remains.
Okay very good so as you said it's kind of like a vase or a pot. Something very nice and small
where you have the person's ashes. All right so now we know what happened during the funeral we know
what happens how you maybe cremate the person or you put them in a casket and well what happens
afterwards? Well afterwards you have a memorial service. Okay so many people want to know what's the
difference between a funeral and a memorial service? Right. In my mind a funeral is very quiet and
sad and you have some respectful words and you usually put the casket into the ground or have
some kind of ceremony but a memorial service is an opportunity to talk to friends and family,
to eat some food to have some drinks, to talk about the person who died. It's almost like the
party if that makes sense. Yeah exactly it's a it's a get together of people who obviously are
trying to give support to their friends or the family members who lost that person but also to
talk about that person in a good way and all the great memories they had I guess that's why it's
called a memorial service because you remember and you give out your memories about that person.
Okay great so a lot of interesting words there. Very specific to this topic but obviously
really important so why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again.
Hi Daniel how are you holding up? I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you I'm doing much better.
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I imagine
there are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time and date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket? No when
these being cremated she was talked about how she didn't want to be buried. I already chose a
cremation earn and we plan to spread the ashes in the ocean. I see that sounds like something she
would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful. You're doing a great job.
Thanks it hasn't been easy but luckily we have life insurance and when the left behind the
detailed will that will sort out any other legal matters.
All right we're back so we have a couple of phrases for to be exact that we want to take a look at
now in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase is a very useful one if you're
trying to ask someone about maybe how they're feeling or someone who's had some problems recently
you can ask them how things are going. One person says to the other, hi Daniel how are you holding
up? Right how are you holding up? Now you know that to hold up something means to have it in your
hands but in this case you're talking about how are things going? Right but I wouldn't say hey how
are you holding up? Right you wouldn't say that to somebody right if normal circumstance.
Not if Marco looks really happy I won't ask him but if someone has passed through a very
difficult period for example if someone dies and their family or perhaps if they've been very sick
or you know there's some negative or difficult things that happen that you can say how are you
holding up? So basically means how are you dealing with this difficult situation or how are you
dealing with your illness? Okay how are you holding up? Or how are you holding up with your
in-laws? Right exactly how are you dealing with a difficult situation and then the person
complimented this by saying and this is a very good phrase this whole sentence is very useful if you
want to say something nice to a person that has recently lost someone you say I am greatly sorry
for your loss. Okay so you might have heard the word loss before lose loss losses and now it's a
thing we normally say this about people who have died because you don't want to say I'm really sorry
for your dead brother. Right you know that's it's sad to do it. True to direct so in English we say I'm
greatly sorry for your loss for this part of your life that has been you know that has gone away.
Right you can also say I'm very sorry for your loss this is standard phrase for this is a standard
phrase for funerals and memorial service. Exactly so if somebody's brother died you go up to that
person and you can say I am greatly sorry for your loss I am very sorry for your loss that's
that's what you say and it's very respectful and it's very nice to say. Yes it's very nice.
All right so now moving on we've said that the person is sorry and everything but then they were
talking about the girl Wendy and that she had life insurance and that she also left behind a detailed
will. Does that mean she forgot it? She forgot it but then you can't mean that right? Right now yeah
this is a phrase that has a couple different meanings and so it's important to look at this one
we're talking about someone who has died who left behind something. It means that they have
completed it in this case or it survives them. Okay so they left that for you.
Okay because as you said it it has a couple of different meanings like to leave behind can be to
lose or to forget but in this case specifically it's to leave for you. Yeah you for example you
could say he died and he left behind three children okay so that means that he had three children
when he died and there's still there's still a lot. Right okay very interesting phrase to leave
something behind and so she left behind a detailed will and that's going to sort out any other
legal matters. To sort out this is a great verb this is a well as a verbal phrase that we hear a lot
with documents and wells and things like this. Basically to sort out means to solve problems
or to fix or to amend for example have you sort it out that problem you had with your
plane tickets? Okay yeah to sort out so have you fixed those problems or have you
solved those problems that you had with your plane tickets to sort out to fix to make arrangements
very useful phrase. Very useful phrase okay so for key phrases there really good ones why don't
we go back listen to the dialogue and boy back to talk a little bit more.
Hi Daniel how are you holding up? I'm greatly sorry for your loss. Thank you I'm doing much better.
I've been organizing everything for the funeral. How's that going? It's a lot harder than I
imagine. There are many things that you have to arrange. I booked a time in date with the funeral home
but I still have a lot of things to do. Have you bought a burial plot in a casket? No when
these being cremated she was talked about how she didn't want to be buried. I already chose a
cremation earn and we planned to spread the ashes in the ocean. I see that sounds like something she
would have really liked. I'm sure the memorial service will be tasteful. You're doing a great job.
Thanks it hasn't been easy but luckily we have life insurance and when the left behind a detailed
will that will sort out any other legal matters.
Alright we're back so now talking about funerals there's an interesting word. What is it called when a person
speaks at a funeral? Well normally at a funeral a loved one or a friend will give a ulyggy.
Ulyggy. Ulyggy. Okay that's ulyggy. It looks like a funny word but it's very important and it's
something that you hear a lot who will give the ulyggy or his son will give the ulyggy. So this is
maybe the keynote address in a funeral. This is the important speech where someone will discuss
the person who has died and his or her contributions and life. Right okay so that's called a ulyggy.
That's really really interesting because I don't know it. It's kind of a word that you don't really
use much and you wouldn't really know it. I have for example I didn't really really know about it
until I saw it in a movie when he made a mistake. He said google g or something like that.
Yeah yeah it was in a comedy. But it's a sad topic but it happens sometimes you have to deal
with these things and so if you have to do it in English well what better way than to learn all
of these things which could come in handy sometimes. That's right and you never know you're watching
a movie or something and this comes up. There are a lot of comedies like you said we call them
black comedies. It's a very dark and talk about this. They are like four weddings and a funeral
is a very famous English movie about this kind of thing and so this is useful vocabulary. It's
a musical phrases for those situations as well. Exactly even if you maybe meet somebody who I
remember I knew somebody who met a casket salesman. Really? Gold caskets. Interesting job.
Yeah so you never know. You never know. Well hope you've enjoyed this lesson not too dark for you
but please do remember to ask us any questions or practice some of your new words and phrases on
our website EnglishPod.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.