Hello everyone and welcome to the EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine. Today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you. If you're interested
in buying furniture for your house you should like this lesson.
Exactly. We are going to talk about a ton of different furniture items that you can get to decorate
your house to make it all nice. So we're going to talk about a lot of a vocabulary today. Pay attention
while you're listening to some of the pieces of furniture that we talk about. We'll be back
in a moment to talk more about them.
How about this floor lamp? Fine. Just get it. We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired. We still need to find an arm wire and a dresser. Fine. I'm going to go home and
drop off this nice stand coffee table and let's see while you look for the rest of the things.
Great. Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
Well, you're at it. Can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I can watch TV.
Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
Alright, we're back. So now what we're going to do is since we have so much of vocab, we're going to
take a look at this language in two parts. So now let's go to language takeaway part one.
Language takeaway. Okay. So everyone's heard of a lamp a light. This is something that
you use to read in the dark, for example, to see in the dark. But in this case, we have a floor lamp.
Floor lamp. So this is a lamp you put on the floor. Yes. Exactly. So usually this lamp would be
a lot taller. It'll maybe be like a meter taller, a meter and a half maybe. Okay. So, for example,
in your living room next to your sofa, you might have a very tall floor lamp. This allows you
to get more light in the room. Right. So sometimes, you know, the center light in your living room is
not enough. You want maybe more light in the corners. You get a little floor lamp. Mm hmm.
Okay. So that's the first item. Now that we go to the bedroom, we are getting an arm warm.
Okay. And arm war. This is kind of like a wardrobe. It's a it's a piece of furniture we use to
keep clothes in. But usually they're hanging clothes. Okay. So a closet is usually inside a wall,
right? Right. So closet is a part of your house. It's not furniture. Right. So an arm war is the same
as a closet, but it's not in the house. Like in the walls. It's outside it's a piece of furniture.
I could pick it up and move it. Okay. Yes. So an arm war is a tall place to keep clothing.
Usually you hang your clothes. You hang your shirts and your dressers and your coats. And moving on,
we have a dresser. Now this seems pretty straightforward to get dressed. You have a dresser.
Yeah. It makes a lot of sense. But there is a big difference here between an arm war and a dresser.
A dresser is usually drawers. So you keep your sweaters, your shirts, your socks, your underwear,
in a dresser. Okay. So at an arm war, as you said, usually you hang your shirts or your pants.
It's for hanging stuff only. A dresser is you have different drawers where you can put your socks,
your box or shorts, and any other things that you keep. Exactly. Okay. Very good. So two very
handy words and that's what makes the difference between a closet. So many people say,
oh, it's just a closet. A closet is different. Now a closet is actually part of your house.
It's a part of the wall. Maybe has a door. And yeah, there's a big difference there. Okay.
So moving on, we have a nightstand. That's also usually in the bedroom. That's right. So I always
wondered why is it called a nightstand and not a daystand? Well, a nightstand. It makes sense.
It usually has a lamp on it, a light on it. So when you're in bed and you want to read,
you have a nightstand next to you to put your lamps. You can turn the lamp on.
Usually, I also keep my books here. So when I'm reading, I put my books down, then I go to sleep.
Some people also keep their glasses and they're alarm clock on a nightstand. Okay. It's a small
table that stands next to your bed. Very good. And our last word for language takeaway part one,
we have a coffee table. Okay. So with the coffee table, Marco, we're moving back into the living room.
And in the living room, you have a sofa, you have some chairs. You need a table, but you don't
want a big table. You want a small table or a very short table. This is a coffee table.
It's called a coffee table. I'm not really sure why. I guess because if you're having coffee in
the living room, this is where you put the coffee. That's right. And we even have something called
coffee table books. These are big, beautiful books, hard-back books that have many pictures
that you put on your coffee table to look nice. It's not for you to actually read all the time.
I read them, but it's more important to use these books to look nice. Yes. This is interesting
though because in many other countries, they're not really called a coffee table. So the
direct translation wouldn't really help you in many cases. I think in Chinese, it's called a tea table.
Not a coffee table. It makes sense. I know in Spanish, it's just called a center table.
So this is basically the low table you have in your living room next to your sofa in front of
yourself, actually. So you can have tea or coffee and read books or put your feet up while
you're watching TV. Not in my house, not in my house. All right. So now why don't we go back,
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be returning a little bit with more vocab.
How about this floor lamp? Fine, just get it. We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired. We still need to find an arm wire and a dresser. Fine. I'm going to go home and drop
off this nice stand coffee table and love seat while you look for the rest of the things. Great.
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
While you're at it, can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I can watch TV.
Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway. Coming up, we have one of my favorite phrases in the English language.
I don't know why, I like it so much, but it is a great name for a piece of furniture.
A love seat. Love seat. Okay. Okay. So it sounds, it sounds very romantic. It does. Well, think about
it's sofa. A sofa can be very large. You can have four or five people on a sofa. Right.
But a love seat is a small sofa for two people. Okay. So that's what makes the difference. Right?
It's a sofa, but only two people can sit on this. That's right. So if it's a big sofa,
it's not a love seat. And what about if it's one? Because usually a sofa sets, you have a love
seat, a big one, and you have one sometimes an individual one. Do you just call that a chair?
Yep. A chair. A chair. Okay. Exactly. We'll come to it in a minute. There's a special kind of
chair that it might be, but we're not quite there yet. First we have another kind of chair, which is
very special. And it reminds me a lot of the 1970s. Right. We have a bean bag. And this is actually a
piece of furniture that's still very popular in many places. And it's called a bean bag because it's
a huge bag that is filled with beans. Right. Beans are something soft. And when you sit on it,
it looks like a ball, but when you sit on it, it can change shape. Right. It molds to how
what shape you are. And usually they're very light. And a lot of times I hate to say it, a lot of times
bachelor's apartments have these. That's right. It's actually very cheap piece of furniture.
And it's comfortable. Sometimes if you're watching TV, you can just sit on your bean bag.
And watch TV. Even I know some people may fall asleep on a bean bag as guests. I've never slept
that well, maybe once. But I don't remember sleeping on a bean bag. I imagine it's quite uncomfortable
about that. Yeah. But moving on after a bean bag, which is a good informal piece of furniture,
we have a dining set, which is a lot nicer. Okay, dining set. All right. So a dining set has many pieces.
You have a dining room table. Right. You have chairs. So a set is basically a collection of
a table and chairs together. Sometimes I think it will also include some type of piece of furniture
that's next to the dining table where you can keep your plates and you can keep your teacups and
all that. What's that called? That's called a buffet. And that's basically, it's like a dresser
for your dining room. Right. Exactly. It's got drawers and stuff for your plates, your cups,
like you said. And it's next to the dining room table. But the dining room set or the dining set
is for the dining room. It's the table where you eat dinner. Okay. Very good. And moving on to that special
chair that I am a big fan of. It's very comfortable sit on and it's called a recliner.
Recliner. So we have a word here recline. It means to lie back, put your head back to get comfortable.
So a recliner is a chair that you can change the shape of to make you lie down.
Fun. So you know, when you sit down, you're sitting. But what if you want to lie down and
a chair? This chair lets you do that. And it also from the bottom part where your feet are
a little thing pops up so you can rest your feet on top of this little extension of the chair.
Okay. So it has a built-in foot rest. What rest exactly? So it's very comfortable. It's very
popular if you ever watch the series Friends. Oh yeah. They have the recliners. It's very
comfortable to watch sports. For example, you have your bejoey has his recliner. And remember when
Joey and Chandler lived together, they have the two recliners in front of the TV. Those chairs are
recliners and they're very popular. Actually, I think in the United States, they're very
commonly known by the brand, lazy boy. That's right. There's a brand. It's not a kind of furniture,
but it's the name of the brand. It's lazy boy and they're very, very famous. You're right, Marko,
for their reclining chairs. Exactly. So a lazy boy is you may hear it, but the real word for it is
called a recliner. So a lot of interesting pieces of furniture there. I think our house is going to
look amazing. So why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time?
How about this floor lamp? Fine, just get it. We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
I'm so tired. We still need to find an arm wire and a dresser. Fine, I'm going to go home and drop
off this nice stand coffee table and let's see while you look for the recidder things. Great.
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
Well, you're at at it. Can you pick up a nicer cleaner? I really want one so I can watch TV.
Recliner? In my beautifully decorated living room? I don't think so.
All right, we're back. So talking about furniture, it's very interesting. How do you take it home?
What do you do? And in this case, they were transporting it themselves. And the guy said,
I'm going to go home and drop off this nightstand coffee table and love seed. So to drop off.
Okay, this is a great verb to drop off. It's a verbal phrase. So the preposition there is
off, not on. Right? So I could say, for example, Marco, I'm just going to drop off my bag at home and
then I'll meet you guys for dinner. That means I'm going to go to my house and put down my bag and then I'll leave.
So to drop off is basically to go somewhere so you can put something in that place.
But it doesn't mean that you're going to go to that place and stay there. Right. So if I say,
I'm going to drop off the kids at school. That means I'm going to take the kids and leave them at
school and then go away. It doesn't mean you're going to school yourself. Right, exactly.
So can you drop off the laundry at the dry cleaners, please? Very good. So I'm going to take the
laundry to the dry cleaners, leave it there and then go somewhere else. So what happens at three o'clock
when the kids are still at school? That's right. Now we use the opposite verbal phrase and that is to pick
up. Okay, drop off, pick up. So you go pick up the kids. You go pick up the laundry. So this isn't
just about some picking something up from a table or the ground. You can actually use your car
to pick something up. Right. You go and retrieve it. So I'm going to the post office to pick up my
package. Very good. So phrases that you're going to have to use if you're talking about furniture,
if you're talking about buying something. And what are on the topic? I know that one of the most
popular places to buy furniture is IKEA. Are you a big fan of IKEA? I like IKEA and I love what
they've done for people who don't want to spend too much money on furniture. furniture is expensive.
furniture is very expensive. You can spend $5,000 on a sofa. Yeah. And so IKEA is a wonderful brand
and I think a wonderful company because it makes good looking furniture affordable. And it's because
you put it together yourself, right? That's right. A lot of things you have to assemble or put
together by yourself. So you buy it in a box and then you make it. And it's a little bit frustrating
sometimes. But for people like me and I'm sure people like you, it's part of the fun is putting
stuff together. Yeah. Because it kind of feel like you kind of built it, but you really didn't.
So it kind of gives you that false sense of accomplishment. It's like I'm in the 19th century and I
could make my own furniture. So it's a very popular. I've actually and apart from having great furniture,
I understand that they have amazing meatballs. They do. Well, I'm a Swedish. I never get to eat
Swedish meatballs and here in China, they do have some of the better meatballs around.
So I would recommend if you haven't tried them. Try them. They're pretty good. Yeah, good
to like you. Good to like you. Have some dinner. Let me know. Our website is EnglishPod.com. Do
you like IKEA and do you love their meatballs? All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.