Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got an intermediate level lesson all about going to the beach.
That's right, you know, it's a very popular thing to do, especially during the summer.
It's hot. You want to go maybe to the beach to lay on the sand and maybe get some color.
And also swim in the ocean. Yeah.
Yeah, it's a nice way to cool off when it's really hot in the summer.
That's right. So we're going to talk about the beach and a lot of vocab that we find related to this activity.
But before we get into the dialogue, we have a word for you. Unvocabillary preview.
Very cabillary preview.
So the keyword today here is jellyfish jellyfish. So jellyfish is actually an animal, right?
That's right. It's a very dangerous animal. It's a small little animal.
So these things live in the water and they often live in shallow areas and they can sting you.
That's right. They look like a little plastic bags with little strings attached to it.
And they just float around and if you happen to touch one, it hurts a lot.
Yeah, it can be very painful. So jellyfish is our word today. Let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
And we'll be back in a minute to talk more about what's going on.
Oh, George, what a beautiful day it is. The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered here and there.
What a perfect day to be at the beach. The kids are going to have so much fun and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're playing.
It does seem like the perfect day. Glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather.
This looks like the perfect spot. Okay, kids, put on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp.
Your Mary, help me lay down these beach towels.
There we go. Can you help me with the umbrella? Perfect.
Okay, kids. Here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pale and a shovel.
I don't want to see an impressive sandcastle by the time we leave.
Don't stray too far. Wait, leave your sandals here, put on your wet shoes.
And stay in the shallow area. I don't want to see you go any further than that sandbar.
It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your flutes.
Your back already. The water is too cold, huh?
I'll tell you a secret. You see that small pool of water over there?
It'll be warmer in there. You'll see if you can find some seashells or catch some minos.
Ah, what is that? Jellyfish?
Jeremy, put that down right now. It could sting you.
Ah, let it be!
All right, great. We're back. So now I don't take a look at four key words that we have prepared for you today
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
First up, we have a very important thing to bring to the beach, especially if you're like me and you burn easily.
So this thing is called sunscreen. Okay, sunscreen. Now this is a liquid. Yep. And you put it on your
skin, right? And this protects you from the sun. So basically you put this cream all over your body
to prevent sunburns to prevent burning under the sun. It's very important. So it's called sunscreen
or also sometimes called sunblock. That's right. Okay, very good. Now we have our sunscreen and we
arrive to the beach and one of the parents say, all right, we're going to set up camp.
Okay, to set up camp. Well, this might be confusing because as many of you know, camp camping,
this is an activity, but we're not actually camping here. We're just going to be at the beach for one
day. So to set up camp means to organize or arrange ourselves in a place. So it's a colloquial way of
saying we're going to organize the area where we're going to spend the day. We're going to make
ourselves comfortable. So you set up camp. So not necessarily that you're going to camp there,
but that you're going to prepare the area. So this could be used in many other different areas,
right? That's right. So sometimes, you know, when tickets for really popular concerts go on sale,
people line up for days before they can buy the tickets. Well, if you're in line, you may be
want to set up camp. That means make yourself comfortable, sit down, bring a book,
open some food packages. Right, exactly. So it's a set up camp. And well, when we go to the beach,
we want to sit down or lay down on the sand. And in order to do this, we usually bring along
beach towels. That's right, Marco. So towels can be any kind of towel. You have the towel in
your bathroom or your kitchen. Basically a piece of cloth that you use to dry yourself. But
the special kind of towel we bring to the beach is called, of course, a beach towel. Right.
These are usually a much bigger than normal towels. Yeah, they're very, very big. And this is usually
because you want to lay down on the sand on top of this towel. Right. That's right. Okay. And
the last word that we have for language takeaway is a beach umbrella or just an umbrella. That's
right. So maybe you're lying down on this big, comfortable, soft beach towel and you're afraid
of being under the sun too much. So an umbrella is a way to protect yourself from the sun.
It provides shade. That's right. So it's called an umbrella or usually if you want to distinguish
between the umbrella you use for the rain, you can call it a beach umbrella. That's right.
Okay. And these are usually a lot bigger and you don't actually carry them around in your hand.
You have to put them into the sand. That's right. So it stands alone. Okay. So for key phrases there
for you on language takeaway when we go back, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
Oh, George. What a beautiful day it is. The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered
here and there. What a perfect day to be at the beach. The kids are going to have so much fun
and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're playing. It does seem like the perfect day.
Glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather. This looks like the perfect spot.
Okay, kids, but on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp,
your Mary helped me lay down these beach towels. There we go. Can you help me with the umbrella?
Perfect. Okay, kids. Here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pale and a shovel. I want to see an
impressive sand castle by the time we leave. Don't stray too far. Wait, leave your sandals here
or put on your wet shoes and stay in the shallow area. I don't want to see you go any further than
that sandbar. It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your floaties. You're back already.
The water was too cold, huh? I'll tell you a secret. Do you see that small pool of water over there?
It'll be warmer in there. You'll see if you can find some seashells or catch some minos.
Ah, what is that? Jellyfish? Jeremy put that down right now. It could sting you.
Ah, not on me. Ah!
All right, we're back. So now we have five more words that we're going to take a look at in
language takeaway part two. Language takeaway. Okay, so there are lots of fun things to do at the beach
and today we're not going to be talking about all of them because there are too many things,
but one fun activity is playing Frisbee. That's right, Frisbee. So this is a thing.
That's an object, a Frisbee or you also play Frisbee. That's right. So a Frisbee itself is
usually made of plastic and it's like a plate and it's very light and you throw it to your friends
and it sails through the air. Right, it kind of flies along the air and then somebody else has to catch it.
That's right. So you can play Frisbee or throw the Frisbee. It's very popular with people
playing Frisbee with their dogs, right? You throw the Frisbee and the dog chases it. Dogs, love Frisbee.
All right, another great activity that usually we do when we go to the beach is we build sand
castles. Okay, so I'm a master sand castle builder. I'm a really big fan of this activity.
Basically, you use water and sand to create castles. Right. And obviously you have to use tools like
shovels and buckets. Otherwise it might look kind of funny. And this is actually such a popular
activity that there are even competitions at times. People will not only build castles or houses or
structures but maybe a statue of some sort or an animal or a different thing. That's right, or people.
People. Yeah. So sand castle. Okay. And well, whenever we go to the beach, the ocean can be a
little bit dangerous. And that's why in the dialogue, one of the parents told their kids to stay
in the shallow area of the water. That's right. So shallow is it describes depth. So how deep
something is. Something is shallow. It's not very deep. Okay. So there's very little water. Okay.
But if there's a lot of water, maybe if you swim and you can't touch your feet on the ground,
we call that deep. So shallow is very low water and deep is lots and lots of water. Okay. Very good.
So you'll usually find this in the ocean if you go further further further in, it'll get deeper and
deeper and deeper and more more dangerous. Right. And this is why the mom also told the kid to
not pass that sand bar that was a head. Okay. Sand bar. This is a piece of sand that basically
rises very high in the water. So usually when you're on the beach and you go into the water and
it gets deeper and deeper and then all of a sudden it gets high again and there's more sand.
Right. And so that part that you can stand on that sand out in the water that's called a sand
bar. It's almost like a little island. Yeah, exactly. And as you say usually it gets deeper deeper
then you have the sand bar so it gets higher. But usually if you pass the sand bar it's going to
get really deep. That's right. So that's why the mother doesn't want her child to go past
the sand bar. Right. And well if you're ever swimming in a swimming pool in the ocean it's always a
good idea if you don't know how to swim well or if you have children to take along little floaties.
Okay. Floaties. I like this word. A floaties are plastic rings that you put around your arms
or maybe around your stomach and they're filled with air. Right. So when you go on the water
they help you float. Exactly. So this is very a very common thing to put on children because they
don't know how to swim well. You put them little floaties on their arms or around their stomach
and then they can just float and they won't drown. That's right. A lot of ways. Very good. So a lot
of keywords. There are related to the fun of going to the beach. Why don't we go back listen to
the dialogue for the very last time.
Oh George. What a beautiful day it is. The sun is hot and there are just a few clouds scattered
here and there. What a perfect day to be at the beach. The kids are going to have so much fun
and we'll be able to relax in the sun while they're playing. It does seem like the perfect day.
I'm glad we chose to get out of the city and enjoy the nice weather. This looks like the perfect
spot. Okay kids, put on your sunscreen while your mom and I set up camp. Your Mary
helped me lay down these beach towels. There we go. Can you help me with the umbrella? Perfect.
Okay kids. Here's a beach ball and a frisbee, a pale and a shovel. I want to see an impressive
sand castle by the time we leave. Don't stray too far. Wait. Leave your sandals here or put
on your wet shoes. And stay in the shallow area. I don't want to see you go any further than that sand
bar. It's too deep out there and we didn't bring your floaties. You back already. The water
was too cold, huh? I'll tell you a secret. Can you see that small pool of water over there?
It'll be warmer in there. You'll see if you can find some seashells or catch some minos.
Ah! What is that? Jellyfish? Jeremy put that down right now. It could sting you.
That. Let it be.
All right. So beach activities. You said you're a master sand castle builder. I love building
sandcassels. I won't say that I'm very good at it. Maybe not a professional. But I do a pretty
good sandcast. Do you like getting buried in the sand? I love it. Although it also scares me. Have you ever
had someone maybe cover you with sand and then you can't move? Yeah. So it's a little bit scary.
Obviously I'm not very comfortable with having my head covered. But some people even do that. They
cover their entire body head to toe. How do they breathe? And they have a straw out of their mouth
to breathe. Wow. Now I actually love going to the beach and it's relaxing. It's really fun.
But I don't really enjoy it going when there are a lot of people. Because I like to relax on
the beach. But when there are too many people, you know, they're running around. They're kids running around
and it's not very relaxing. Yeah, here you go. So but swimming in the ocean is also very dangerous, right?
It can be. It can be. So we recommend you go to some. So we recommend you go places where there are
lifeguards on duty or that you go with an expert swimmer. Lifeguards very good. Yeah. That's all we've
got though for today. We hope you've enjoyed this lesson. And we hope you're excited about the upcoming
summer months. If you have any questions or comments, please do visit our website EnglishPod.com.
Alright, we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.