Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we have
a very fun lesson for you today. That's right. We're going to talk about toys. So we're going
to actually take a look at a lot of different types of toys and we're going to be listening
to a couple of commercials. That's right. So we've got two children who are watching TV and
they're listening to a number of different commercials. So we're going to learn about some
of these very popular products in a moment. Let's first listen to our dialogue.
Switch Bob Square fans will be right back after these brief messages. Once that on the
horizon, the pirate ship, rape villages and fight very treasure with these new pirates
Lego set. Build the ship and decide who rules to see.
The new Play Doe sparkling bright precious gem press. Make large colorful gems for you and
your friends with five special molds. Comes with a new sparkling bright play Doe compound
in four new colors. Treasure chest salt separately. Wow, mommy. Can I get them for my birthday?
I'm Jean Gray. And Professor X. Collect all four of these special edition collectable
X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world. No way. I want
Professor X. The new collectors edition nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls. Little Bob
Abe comes with their own shape and staff. Her clothes are made with the finest fabrics
in real Italian lace. And her face has been hand painted by our finest artists. Only
$199. Oh, she's pretty. I've never had a porcelain doll before. I don't mom and dad will
get you that for your birthday. She costs a pretty penny. Plus, you'd most likely break her.
What is better than a board? What is better than one board game? Three board games in one. Enjoy
playing chess and checkers on this side of the board. What if you're looking for some more
fun fun? And play the classic game of sorry. That's ingenious. Why hasn't anyone thought
of that before? Now you can take a sponge Bob Squarepants wherever you go with a new sponge
Bob Squarepants glow in the dark and you'll go. And now, back to our show.
All right, we're back. So a lot of great toys. And actually, it's very popular that, well,
maybe you're watching cartoons. You get a lot of these commercials that are selling you
all types of toys. Absolutely, because normally children watch cartoons and children
like toys. So I think so. Exactly. So why don't we take a look at, so why don't we take
a look at six keywords that we have for you on language takeaway? Language takeaway. Okay,
Marco. So what's the first word we're looking at here today? All right. We have actually
a brand, a very famous type of toy. They're called Legos. Legos. So Legos. Legos are basically
little pieces that you put together to build things. Yeah, they're like little blocks. Okay. So
when you see them, they don't look like anything. But as a child, you get to create anything you
want. Mm-hmm. So Legos have become very famous. They have like special types that you can recreate
maybe a spaceship from Star Wars, a pirate ship, a lot of different types now. Okay. So the one
in today's commercial is pirate Legos. So they're building a pirate ship. Exactly. Legos.
All right. And the next toy that we have is also a proper noun. It's a brand and it's called Play Do.
Play Do. Okay. So Play, like playing with something playing basketball. But Play Do is, it's like
Play, right? It's like Play. But it's made out of flour, I think, and you can shape it into anything
you want. So when I was little, I used to make Play Do animals. You know, you could, you can make a ball
and you make another ball and then all of a sudden you have a cow. Right. So it's a very soft
texture type of a material that you can mold. You can give it different shapes. And that's what
we call Play Do. And obviously, as you say, it's it's safe for children. I think it's made out of
a head of some flour, salt and flour. And I think a lot of children sometimes eat this. So it's
pretty safe for kids. Right. So yeah, that's Play Do. It's a proper noun. And I guess everyone just
calls it Play Do. So this is the toy that we're talking about. Now moving on, we are talking about
the X-Men Wolverine Jean Grey, Rogue, Professor X. And all of these come in little statues that we call
action figures. All right. So what you're talking about here are obviously the X-Men Marko.
And X-Men, there are many different kinds of X-Men you have, like you said Wolverine,
who's maybe one of the most famous and Rogue. But when you collect these little statues,
these little dolls, they're called action figures. So figure is like a kind of doll. Right. So
the X-Men is just an example. You have action figures of all sorts of cartoons or movies,
Star Wars action figures are very popular. Right. Or GI Joe action figures are very popular as well.
That's right. So they're little toy statues that children play with. All right. Moving on,
now we have an adjective a way to describe the X-Men. That's right. So the X-Men, as you know,
are not normal people. They have special powers. Some X-Men can fly. Wolverine has
animal abilities. He can use his long claws. So these are mutants. That means that
they were humans, but something changed in them and it makes them have these special powers.
Okay. So a mutant is maybe a person that has special powers, like, like, as you say Wolverine
and all these types of X-Men. But I guess to, taken maybe a look at the verb mutate, that means
to change, to change, right? Okay. So to mutate is to change. So we could say, I found a frog that
had three legs. Okay. So it clearly mutated because normally frogs have, like, four legs.
Exactly. You see that sometimes with chickens that maybe have two heads or something like this.
These are mutants. Okay. They have mutated. Okay. Very good. And now moving on to our dolls,
they were talking about these beautiful, porcelain dolls. Okay. So let's talk about porcelain.
Because I think everyone knows what a doll is, but porcelain is a special kind of doll, right?
Right. It's a material. And usually you can find this material very commonly in your plates.
All right. So it's not clear. It's not glass. No. It's colored. It's normally whitish.
And very, very fine. Very pretty. So you call it porcelain. I guess it's a type of ceramic, right?
That's right. Okay. So yeah. You have porcelain dolls. Many people also have very fine china that
you call it like dinner plates or teacups and those are usually made of porcelain.
All right. And finally, they were talking about a game that has three games in one and one of the
kids said, wow. That's ingenious. ingenious. This is a great word. Makes you sound really fluent.
So ingenious basically means clever. Right. It's a really good idea. It's very clever. Good idea.
Yeah. So if something is ingenious, it's just, wow. It's very creative. For example,
I have a pair of gloves. But on the fingers, sometimes I can pull a cover over them and they turn
into mittens. Right. I think it's ingenious. Yeah. Because I have gloves and mittens all the time.
All right. So a lot of interesting words. There are a lot of specific toys and particularly
brands that you may or may not know. But why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue again and
we'll be back with fluency builder. Spungy pop square pans will be right back after these brief
messages. What's that on the horizon? A pirate ship. Raid villages and find buried treasure with
these new pirates Lego sent. Build the ship and decide who rules to see. Ah, cool. The new
Play Doe sparkling bright precious gem press. Make large colorful gems for you and your friends
with five special molds. Comes with the new sparkling rights Play Doe compound in four new colors.
Treasure chest sold separately. Wow, mommy. Can I get that for my birthday? Wolverine,
Jean Grey, Rogue and Professor X. Collect all four of these special edition collectable
X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world. No way. I want Professor X.
The new collector's edition nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls. Little Bobo peep comes with their
own sheep and staff. Her clothes are made with the finest fabrics and real Italian lace and her
face has been hand painted by our finest artists. Only $199. Oh, she's pretty. I've never had a porcelain
doll before. I doubt mom and dad will get you that for your birthday. She costs a pretty penny. Plus,
you'd most likely break her. What is better than a board? What is better than one board game?
Three board games in one. Enjoy playing chess and checkers on this side of the board. But if you're
looking for some more fun, flip it and play the classic game of sorry. Fetch ingenious. Why
has anyone thought of that before? Now you can take sponge Bobo square pants wherever you go with
a new sponge Bobo square pants glow in their dark yoyo. And now, back to our show.
Okay, so the first phrase here in fluency builders are really important one for anyone who's
buying anything because you often see this phrase on packages or you hear it in commercials.
Right, as you saw in the Play Do commercial, the guy said,
treasure chest sold separately. Okay, sold separately. That means the treasure chest is not
included. You have to buy it extra. Mm-hmm. As you say, you usually see it in packaging as well,
maybe you buy a toy car. And at the bottom it will say, battery sold separately. That means there
are no batteries in the box. You have to buy batteries extra. Exactly. So that's what the phrase
sold separately means. It indicates that you it's not included in the product that you are buying.
All right. Now moving on again to the action figures and the dolls. We saw this very
interesting way of describing them. For example, the action figures said, special addition,
collectible, X-Men action figures. Okay, special addition. This is really important. And it's very
common, I think, with special toys or action figures or even baseball cards. Special addition
means that they're produced, especially on one occasion at one time. They're not always produced.
Right. So for example, if you have, like you say baseball cards or maybe action figures,
they're produced normally, but then limited amounts, a special type of the same action figure will
be produced. So that's a special addition or also commonly known as a collector's addition. All right.
So some people collect stamps, stamps for letters that you send. And I know many countries like
America offer special addition or collectors addition stamps. These are produced once and usually they
mark a special occasion. Like the Olympics in 1996, we had special addition stamps. Right. So these
special addition objects are usually not used. They're for collectors. Like the name says,
right, collectors addition. Right. So you plan to sell them later on or you collect them for yourself.
They're not normal. Right. They usually go up in value because they're very limited. That's right.
Okay. So collectors addition, special addition. And now when they were talking about the
porcelain dolls as well, it's pretty expensive, right, almost $200. That's a really expensive doll.
And so one of the kids said, you know what? I think a mom and dad won't buy you that because
it costs a pretty penny. A pretty penny. This does not mean that the penny is beautiful.
Right. A penny is a one cent coin in the United States. That means it's very, very low in value.
The coin. But a pretty penny is actually the opposite. It means it's very expensive.
So why would, how would you use this in another, in another example?
I've always wanted to buy a Ferrari, but man, Ferrari's cost a pretty penny.
Okay. So you have to add the word cost before you say pretty penny, right?
That's right. You can't say it is a pretty penny. You have to say it costs a pretty penny.
It's worth a pretty penny. Exactly. It's worth a pretty penny. Okay. Very good. And for our last phrase.
I think this one is a very good phrase because it describes a lot of different toys
that glow in the dark. Glowing the dark toys. Okay. So something that glows in the dark.
The verb here is too glow. It means that it can be seen even when it's dark. Right. So for
example, when I turn the lights off and I can see this yo yo in my room, that means it's glow in the dark.
It has light even in the dark. Right. So there are a lot of different toys and things like this.
Usually glow in the dark toys, they have a green glow. Right. They look green in the dark.
I used to have stars. So they were stickers, stars, stickers, and I put them on my ceiling so that
when I was in bed, I could look at them and they were glow in the dark. So when the lights were off,
I still had stars. You can see them. Right. So yeah, glow in the dark. It's a way of describing
an item, an object that you are able to see in the dark. All right. So that's all we have for you on language.
All right. So that's all we have for you on Fluency Builder. When we go back, listen to the
dialogue one last time. Have a look back to talk some more.
What's that on the horizon? A pirate ship, rape villages, and fight very treasure with these
new pirates Lego sent. Build the ship, and decide who rules to see.
All right. Cool. The new Play Do, sparkling bright, precious gem press, make large colorful gems
for you and your friends with five special molds. Comes with the new sparkling bright,
played out compound in four new colors. Treasure chest holds up really. Wow, mommy.
Cigarette for my birthday. Hey, hi, gee, great. And Professor X. Collect all four of these special
edition collectible X-Men action figures and decide the future of the mutants in our world.
No way. I want Professor X. The new collector's edition nursery rhymes,
porcelain dolls. Little boatbap comes with their own shape and staff. Her clothes are made with the
finest fabrics in real Italian lace and her face has been hand painted by our finest artists.
Only $199 dollars. Oh, she's pretty. I've never had a porcelain doll before. I doubt mom and dad
will get you that for your birthday. She costs a pretty penny. Plus, you'd most likely break her.
One is better than a board. One is better than one board game. Three board games in one.
Enjoy playing chess and checkers on this side of the board. What if you're looking for some more
fun for this employee's classic game of sorry? That's ingenious. Why hasn't anyone thought of that
before? Now you can take a sponge Bob Square pants wherever you go with a new sponge Bob Square
pants glow in the dark yoyo and now back to our show.
Alright, so talking about toys, these are really interesting toys. Are there any specific toys
that you had when you were growing up or that you really, really liked? I had an amazing
bro train set. This is when I was young and a train set is basically like, like I was with trains.
So you build a track and you push the train around the track. I used to have a track that was as big
as the living room. My challenge, my goal was to use every single piece. She's very hard because
some pieces don't fit with other pieces. That was my favorite toy because I got to be very creative.
And then you would turn on the train and it would go away. It wasn't electric. I wasn't. I had to push it
by some. What was your favorite toy? Actually, when I was growing up, I used to collect little toy
cars. I had a lot of toys. I used to have a lot of little toy cars and I even had a little special,
like a box for them when you can, so I could see them. And then as time went on, I got to collect
the scale cars, you know, the ones that are one to ten, one to four. Did you build them or did
you buy them made? No, usually I bought them made. I actually tried the whole building model cars,
model airplanes, but it's so hard. Very hard. Even adults have a hard time. It's not very difficult.
So I don't know what type of kid actually does that when they're growing up. But yeah, so many toys
out there. So many people collect them, play with them. You have childhood toys that you're very fond of.
So that's what we want to know. What type of toy did you grow up with? What did you like to play with
when you were a kid? Or if you have kids, what toys do your kids like? Because we're not too familiar
with toys these days. We'd be curious to hear about those. That's right. So we want to hear from you
come to EnglishPod.com and we'll see everyone there. Bye.