Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about going to sleep or not being able to sleep
That's right. We are having some sleeping problems and we're actually going to check out a couple of words related to this topic right now on vocabulary preview
Very cablory preview
Okay, so the first word is actually the technical word that describes being unable to sleep
It's called insomnia
Right, so if you have insomnia, it means that you can't fall asleep. You can't sleep
Okay, so this is a pretty serious condition
For example, if you have insomnia and you don't sleep with three or four nights
You're not going to do very well at work, right?
Right, or if you're studying your tired at school, you can concentrate so it's a very big problem
What's that other word though? We haven't sammed the up, but we also have another interesting disorder
Right, if somebody is able to sleep, but walks while they're sleeping
That person is called a sleep walker
That's right, and you don't actually just have to walk to be a sleep walker
Right
You can do any number of strange things like
Basically acting like you're awake when you're not
Exactly, so some people get up and walk
Actually go outside, some people get dressed, some people have a go downstairs and cook
Yeah, that's right, and the worst is the people who eat because they gain weight and they don't know why
Exactly, so sleep walking is what you do
And if you do this, you're called a sleep walker
Okay, sleep walk is the verb sleep walker is the noun or the person
All right, so we've taken a look at two words that we're going to find in our dialogue today
Why don't we go now and listen to the dialogue for the first time
Alex, what's up with you? You look dreadful
Hey Jill, I don't know. I've been having trouble sleeping these past few weeks
I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get to sleep
I've tried stretching and different breathing techniques before going to bed
I've tried eating and not eating different foods
I've even tried counting sheep
And then when I finally get to sleep, I have these really disturbing nightmares
So I usually wake up in a panic and more tired than before I went to sleep
Wow, maybe you should get that checked out
Maybe you're stressed?
Just take some sedatives, words from me
Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when I have trouble sleeping
It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders
It's the stuff pilots used to regular their sleeping patterns
I heard of that, but does that apply to Alex's situation?
Yeah, sure, why not?
Sounds like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing
So taking melatonin should do the trick
But shouldn't he be looking into why?
It's been happening
Well aren't you the little psychologist
Our buddies having trouble sleeping, it's easy and curable
It's not something freakish like if he was a sleepwalker
Well, there's that too
Alright, we're back so obviously this person not only has insomnia
But also has nightmares, sleepwalks, a mess
That's right, and you can tell when someone hasn't been sleeping well
They have that look like there's bags under their eyes
Or they just look really tired
And so the friend here says Alex, you look dreadful
That's right dreadful
So this is an adjective and it's a way to describe someone that looks terrible
You look horrible, you look tired, you look sleepy
That's right, so this is not a compliment
This is something that you say when you're worried about someone
So for example, so for example if someone's really really tired
You say you look dreadful or if someone is wearing very dirty clothes
They don't look like they went home yesterday
You say, what's wrong? You look dreadful
Right, I think you can also use it to describe objects or maybe food
Right, this lasagna is dreadful
It's very bad, and you don't want to say that to the person who cooked it up first
Exactly, alright, so the person obviously because it's suffering from insomnia
It looks dreadful and he was explaining what he does to try to fall asleep
For example, counting sheep, stretching, and he also said that he tried different breathing techniques
Okay, so basically a technique is an approach to something, a kind of method
But in this case we're talking about breathing techniques
So for some people, one breathing technique is breathing in through your nose
And breathing out through your mouth
Like that, that's one kind of technique
So a technique as you say is a way of doing something
So breathing techniques are different ways of breathing
So maybe you will relax, so maybe you'll fall asleep, things like this
Exactly, it's one of those things that you might learn about in a yoga class
For example, there's different breathing techniques
Right, and you can combine techniques with other words
As well, adding the ING, for example, you have walking techniques
Maybe to put less stress on your knees
Or running techniques, swimming techniques, I think there's a technique for almost everything
Just about anything you can do, there's a technique for it
Right, yeah, yeah, for sure
Alright, and well, moving on, he was talking about his nightmares
And he described his nightmares as disturbing, he has disturbing nightmares
Okay, well, I think this is an important word to cover here, Marco, because we've heard the verb to disturb before
Like, I'm sorry to disturb you, because I'm sorry to bother you
But disturbing is an adjective, it describes something that makes me very uncomfortable
Right, so for example, a lot of times in the news, we see very disturbing images, car accidents or fires or bombs
And what's disturbing is when you see human beings who have been hurt, so images that make you really uncomfortable or sad, these are disturbing
Exactly, so disturbing nightmares are nightmares that are not very pleasant
They make him scared, maybe, or uncomfortable
Right, like a dream, for example, where your parents die, it's pretty disturbing
Exactly, alright, and well, one of his friends recommended you know what?
Stop with all of this, just take some sedatives
Okay, so sedatives are kind of medicine that help a person relax, or that help make a person tired
Right, so I think it comes from the verb to sedate
Yes, and basically that is to calm down to tranquilize
That's right, so in this case, we're talking about a person, but you can also give an animal sedatives
For example, if you want to take your dog on an airplane, the dog needs to relax, you give it some sedatives
Exactly, and I think when he mentioned a specific name of a sedative, it's melatonin
That's right, so melatonin, melatonin is a chemical that our body is naturally produced that help calm us down
And so a lot of pharmaceutical companies or drug companies sell melatonin in a pill form
It's basically, it's a chemical that helps you relax
Exactly, so obviously, if you take melatonin, you're going to feel sleepy, or you're going to be very relaxed
Then you're going to fall asleep a lot easier, hopefully, hopefully, that's right
So, and well, the whole thing that we've been talking about in some neonsleep walking
These are called sleeping disorders
Right, or you might also hear the term sleep disorders
They mean problems with sleeping, so people who either cannot fall asleep or people who have bad dreams or people who sleep walk
Exactly, so a disorder is something of an illness or a condition that is not normal
So, for example, as you said, a sleeping disorder or a sleep disorder
It means that you're not able to sleep properly or normally
But there are other kinds of disorders, right?
Right, I guess many people have heard of eating disorders
Okay, so that's basically people who do not eat like everyone else
Exactly, so that's what happens with a disorder
All right, so we've taken a look at a lot of vocab now, it's time for us to take a look at fluency builder
But before that, why don't we listen to the dialogue again
Alex, what's up with you? You look dreadful
Hey, Jill, I don't know
I've been having trouble sleeping these past few weeks
I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get to sleep
I've tried stretching and different breathing techniques before going to bed
I've tried eating and not eating different foods
I've even tried counting sheep
And then, when I finally get to sleep, I have these really disturbing nightmares
So I usually wake up in a panic and more tired than before I went to sleep
Wow, maybe you should get that checked out
Maybe you're stressed?
Just take some sedatives, works for me
Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when I have trouble sleeping
It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders
It's the stuff pilots use to regulate their sleeping patterns
I heard of that, but does that apply to Alex's situation?
Yeah, sure, why not?
Sounds like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing
So taking melatonin should do the trick
But shouldn't he be looking into why it's been happening?
Well, aren't you the little psychologist?
Our buddies having trouble sleeping, it's easy and curable
It's not something freakish like if he was a sleepwalker
Well, there's that too
Alright, we're back, so now we have three main phrases for fluency builder
Why don't we start with the first one?
Okay, so you heard in today's dialogue a...
An interesting phrase, I don't know if it exists in other languages
But in English we say when you're trying to fall asleep
There's a good technique to help you do so
You count sheep
Yeah, I think you see it in cartoons all the time
A person is sleeping and over that cartoons head is a little cloud
And you see sheep jump being over a fence
So yeah, basically there's a fence and you say one, two, three
And the process of counting helps relax a person
And then you fall asleep
Right, so counting sheep, I guess you're not literally out in a field counting sheep
You're just imagining sheep in your head and you're trying to fall asleep
That's right, counting sheep
Alright, and well one of his friends recommended that maybe he should go to a doctor
And Jill said that by saying maybe you should get that checked out
Okay, so to get something checked out, to get it checked out
This means to have a professional
Give you a suggestion or to have a professional look at something
Exactly, so maybe you should get examined
Maybe you should go to the doctor
This isn't just about disorders, right?
I mean, what if I have a sore tooth, I could say this
Right, so if you have a tooth ache
I would recommend, oh, maybe you should get that checked out by my dentist
Right, or maybe if you have a bad rash, you know your skin is very red
I say, Marco, I think you should get that checked out by a doctor
Exactly, so to get something checked to get something examined
By a doctor or a professional
Alright, and the last phrase that we have for you
So last phrase we have today comes from a suggestion at the end
The friend suggests taking mellotone and he says, listen, taking mellotone
Should do the trick right, so if you end the phrase by saying that should do the trick
Basically you're saying that should solve your problem, that should help you
Exactly, so the trick you don't have to think about what the trick is
It's just a way of saying it should fix your problem
So for example, when someone is fixing my car
And they have one more thing to do and it's finished
He says the mechanic might say that should do the trick
That means problem solved
Or maybe you're having you want to hang a picture on your wall
So somebody puts a nail in the wall and that should do the trick
And maybe that'll hold up the painting
Done, done, okay?
So that's a way of saying that should solve the problem
This should be the solution that should be all
Okay, okay, so why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time
Alex, what's up with you?
You look dreadful
Hey Jill, I don't know
I've been having trouble sleeping these past few weeks
I usually lie in bed for hours trying to get to sleep
I've tried stretching in different breathing techniques before going to bed
I've tried eating and night eating different foods
I've even tried counting sheep
And then when I finally get to sleep
I have these really disturbing nightmares
So I usually wake up in a panic and more tired than before I went to sleep
Wow, maybe you should get that checked out
Maybe you're stressed
Just take some sedatives, works for me
Every so often having some melatonin on hand helps me when I have trouble sleeping
It works on all kinds of sleeping disorders
It's the stuff pilots used to regular their sleeping patterns
I heard of that, but does that apply to Alex's situation?
Yeah, sure, why not
Sounds like he only has transient insomnia since it's a recent thing
So taking melatonin should do the trick
But shouldn't he be looking into why it's been happening?
Well aren't you the little psychologist
Our buddy's having trouble sleeping, it's easy and curable
Is not something freakish like if he was a sleepwalker
Well, there's that too
Alright, we're back
So talking about dreaming nightmares and sammni
All of this, what do you do if you can't fall asleep?
I don't really have this problem personally
Because I could fall asleep anywhere any time
I've heard some people take like warm milk before going to sleep
Yes, some people take milk
I've heard that dairy products before bedtime
Can make you have nightmares
I really do
I've heard that as well
I've heard that if you have seafood before bed
You'll have nightmares as well
But actually, have you ever had a dream
When you are doing something and you wake up in the middle of that?
Yes
I remember once I was dreaming, I was drinking a soda
And all of a sudden I woke up and I had my hand in the air
Like doing the action of me actually drinking the soda
Sometimes this happens to me when I'm falling asleep
I imagine I'm on a bike or something
I start to feel myself moving my leg
And I wake up and I'm like, wait, what am I doing?
The brain is very strange
I think especially in those times when you're kind of asleep
And you're kind of awake
Also when you wake up suddenly
I don't know if other people have experience this
You feel like you're falling or something
I'll wake up and wake up with a shake
Yeah, your body moves
Yeah, it's really scary
Your heart starts to beat
I don't know why that happens
It's unusual
But what we're curious to know what your sleep habits are
Do you have a hard time sleeping
Or are you like me?
It's very easy to sleep
Let us know on our website EnglishPod.com
Alright, we'll see you guys there
Bye
You