Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have a
new lesson in our series about interviewing for a new job. This is of course at the elementary level.
That's right. So this is part four of our interview series. Remember we are taking a look each week
at giving you tips and also the proper language for when you have an interview in English. And on this occasion
we're going to talk about our work experience. Okay you remember we talked a little bit about
educational experience and educational background. Well today is all about your last couple of jobs.
All right so I think we should just listen to the dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a bit
with language takeaway.
Right Rebecca. Now I see that after graduating from university your first job was for a local paper
in York called the York Harald. Actually I started with them as an intern. I was really keen on getting
some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good first step. Certainly. And after your
internship they seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter. I ended
up staying two years there actually. I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper.
I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills. Yes I see but you decided to leave
them in 2006 right? Yes that's right. My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find
a position with a national newspaper based in London. It's a London weekly right? Yes. In some ways
it was a step down from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects for the future.
All right we're back so now we've picked out a couple of keywords and we're going to take a look at
those now on language takeaway. Language takeaway. So Marco a lot of people don't start out
as a professional with a job. They have something else first. What is this? That's right a very
popular way to begin your work experience. You become an intern or you work as an intern.
Okay so the name of the job we could say is intern. I'm an intern or he's an intern at my company.
Exactly. So usually interns work at a company. Usually they're not paid and or if they are it's
a very very little pay and the purpose of an intern ship or to work as an intern is to gain experience.
That's right so it's basically like a study opportunity for a job that you know you want. I could
be an intern at a media company and I could learn all about media but it's not really a full job.
Exactly and usually it serves as an opportunity to maybe continue working at that company in the
full-time job. So you become an intern and the noun or what you are doing is called an internship.
So I'm an intern but what I have is an internship. Right. It's like saying I have a job. I have an
internship but I am an intern. Exactly. All right so we've covered those two words now. Let's move on
to when she's describing her work experience in the York Harald and she described it as a very good first step.
Okay so a first step you think about your foot, your step, your moving. It means the very first thing
you do when you're heading in some direction. Right and professionally I guess your first steps are
maybe becoming an intern. Right or you could say my first step was working in the male room at this big
movie studio but later I became you know famous movie producer. Exactly so that's kind of like
the way that you begin your professional life. And well then they started talking about the news
papers and actually Rebecca was offered a position as a junior local news reporter. Okay so junior
means usually lower ranking or not um not experienced. Someone who is just starting out and of course
after junior we have seniors. Right. So a senior news reporter is someone who's worked for many
many years as a reporter. Mm-hmm. Usually I guess a junior news reporter would like make less money
than a senior news reporter. Exactly you could also say junior executive or senior executive.
Junior manager. These are ways of describing length of experience. Mm-hmm. And in this case she's
junior but what kind of job does she have? Well she is a news reporter for local issues. Okay so
she's a local news reporter. Now what exactly does that mean if you're a local news reporter or
for local issues? Well if I live in Chicago and I'm a local news reporter I only write or report the
news about Chicago. It's it's a way of describing the things in my area. So it's the opposite of our next
phrase national news reporter. Okay so if you are a national news reporter or a national manager
of maybe a company then that means that you oversee things in the whole country. That's right so local
is my city or my county but in the case of national we're talking about the whole country nation
national. So national is an adjective but we could even go further than this. What if I am a reporter
and I talk about foreign countries? I talk about France and South Africa and even Iceland.
Mm-hmm. Then I guess you would be an international news reporter. Exactly. And I guess also
at the executive level you can have an international marketing manager right? That's right international
marketing manager, national marketing manager. These are very important ways to divide work to say
he is the international manager. Here's the national manager. This tells you the kind of the size
of this person's job. Exactly. Okay so now more or less you know how these jobs can be divided
junior, senior, national, local etc. So I think we should go back to the dialogue. Let's listen
to this dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit. Right Rebecca. Now I see that after graduating
from university your first job was for a local paper in York called the York Harald. Actually
I started with them as an intern. I was really keen on getting some experience in journalism
and this seemed like a good first step. Certainly. And after your internship? They seemed impressed
and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter. I ended up staying two years there actually.
I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper. I really enjoyed it there and it
really helped me build my skills. Yes I see but you decided to leave them in 2006 right? Yes that's
right. My husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a position with a national
newspaper based in London. It's a London weekly right? Yes. In some ways it was a step down from
my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects for the future.
Alright so now let's start with a couple of phrases and a phrasal verb on Fluency Builder.
Okay and today's dialogue we heard a lot of really wonderful phrases Marco. Some of them are ways
of making your experiences sound better. More professional even. For example this first one.
So I Rebecca's talking about her first job in York and she says I was in charge of the sports news
section in charge. So that phrase I was in charge of or to be in charge of what is this described?
This describes responsibility. Basically she's saying I was responsible for or I had to manage
the sports news section. She's taking credit for this job that was important. Okay so this is a
key phrase because this is the typical phrase that you used to describe your responsibilities or to
describe what you did in your previous job position or your previous job. So I could ask you when
you were in marketing what were you in charge of? Right and then you say well I was in charge of
and then you explain your responsibilities or what you did. I was in charge of our national accounts
or I was in charge of the local news. Exactly so this is a very simple phrase just remember it.
I was in charge of and then you can start explaining what were your responsibilities what you did in
your previous job. All right moving on now towards the end of that paragraph Rebecca says that
well being in charge of the sports news section was really fun and it really helped her build my skills.
It really helped me build my skills. So to build your skills or in this case I build my skills
means that I have some skills but maybe they're not really developed. Maybe you know I just finished
college I want more experience. Well in that time during my first job I build my skills.
I become better at writing or making having interviews things like that. Exactly so when you build
your skills you kind of improve your abilities or you gain more experience. All right and another
interesting phrase coming up here when Rebecca talked about moving to London with her husband she said
I managed to find a position with a national newspaper. Okay so I managed to or you could say
to manage to do something. This is a really interesting phrase because it's another way of saying
to be able to or to succeed at something. Okay so don't confuse it with a manager or to manage people.
That is also correct to obviously it exists but to manage to do something is as you said to
be able to do something. Right so for example I was running really late yesterday and I have a ticket
for a train at five o'clock. I thought I would miss the train but I managed to get to the train
on time. That means I was able to get on the train on time. Exactly okay so you managed to find a
job but I managed to get to the train on time I was able to. All right and towards the end Rebecca
talked about her job at the London weekly and she described it as a step down for my previous job.
Okay so good thing you're a bad thing Marco. To be a step down in something is a bad thing it's
to reduce in level or to decrease. Okay so basically she's saying listen I have this really great job
in New York and I took a new job in London and the new job it wasn't as good in many ways
because maybe she had less responsibility or maybe it paid less. So this is a way of saying it wasn't
as good as my last job. Okay so her new job was a step down from her previous job. You could say I
think his new girlfriend's a bit of a step down if you know what I mean. Exactly so usually you're
comparing right you're making a comparison between something from the past to now. Exactly.
Okay so a step down. Why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue for the very last time
and we're back to talk to you in a bit.
Right Rebecca now I see that after graduating from university your first job was for a local paper in
York called the York Harold. Actually I started with them as an intern. I was really keen on getting
some experience in journalism and this seemed like a good first step. Certainly and after your
internship they seemed impressed and offered me a position as a junior local news reporter. I ended
up staying two years there actually. I was in charge of the sports news section of the newspaper.
I really enjoyed it there and it really helped me build my skills. Yes I see but you decided to leave
them in 2006 right? Yes that's right my husband and I moved to London and so I managed to find a
position with a national newspaper based in London. To London weekly right? Yes in some ways it was
a step down from my previous job but it did offer me much better prospects for the future.
All right so talking about internships and in terms it seems that usually they get it's not
very exciting to become an intern because it ends up that the office people just make you
make coffee or or copies and stuff like that. You're not really gaining much work experience.
That is the reputation in the United States for internships so basically when you agree to
do an internship sometimes you have to apply to do an internship. It's a very long process.
You end up like you say making coffee for people or photocopying reports and this is really
boring work. Right I think yeah that is the reputation that many places have like you say in the
United States but also I don't know I guess it does seem in a way the only opportunity in order to
be able to get into an industry or a company maybe it's a really good company like I don't know like
like proctor and gamble and how else are you going to be able to get in there with no job experience.
Well that's right and a lot of people know that an internship doesn't really give you work experience
but they still give it they still think that it gives you some edge or some advantage when you're
looking for jobs later because if I write down on my my resume we were talking earlier about resumes.
If I write down on my resume that I was an intern at proctor and gamble wow that's really impressive.
Right it looks good. All right so this is an interesting topic let us know if you were ever an
intern maybe you started out as an internship or maybe you're doing one now. Was it better than we
said? Did you do anything else? Southern and making coffee we really hope so and that we look forward
to hearing about your experiences. All right we'll see everyone at EnglishPod.com and until next time bye bye.