Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today
we're going to continue in our series about job interviews. That's right. And on this occasion
we're taking a look at part five or an interview series where we explain why we left our previous job.
Okay and so in an interview this is a very popular question. Why did you leave your last job?
Learn some tools for answering this question in today's dialogue. We're going to take a listen to it
first and we'll be back in a moment.
Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job. I see you spent almost four years at the
London weekly. Is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest the first year was quite tough for me.
I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it
quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor
liked me so he promoted me to Features writer. Wow I real step up. Yes I was responsible for restaurant
and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position but to be honest it wasn't an
area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why did you decide to leave finally?
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities. I really needed a more
challenging role to be honest. All right we're back and as we saw Rebecca handled it quite well
explaining why you left your last job because obviously you don't want to say something like
I just really didn't like my company or you know the boss was a really bad guy.
Or I was fired for being lazy. Exactly so I don't we take a look at a couple of different words
on language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay so we've got some great descriptive words here.
These are some adjectives. The first one is tough. So Rebecca said to be honest the first year
was quite tough for me. All right so she's describing that her first year at that company where she was
working it was tough and that means hard. Difficult. That's right so you could say this is a really
tough situation. I mean it's it's a difficult situation. It's hard because there's no easy answer.
Exactly so if you describe something as tough it means that it's very difficult. Now there is
another meaning to this where it can be that you are a strong person. Right so that's different
because we're talking about a person not a situation but if you're talking about a job or an experience
or even homework like this homework is really tough it means that it's very hard. Exactly.
Well apart from her job of being a little bit tough she said that it was also a little bit frustrating.
Okay so usually these things go together. If something is tough like it's difficult it's usually
frustrating too. And so in this case something is frustrating when it makes you unhappy or for example
it makes you feel stressed. So something that's frustrating is not a good thing. Exactly so as you
gave the example with the homework assignment if you have maybe a math assignment that's very
difficult and you can't solve it you don't find the solution then you get frustrated you get maybe
angry at yourself or you get very angry for not being able to solve it so that's when you
when it's something is frustrating. I hate being frustrated exactly well it's not a nice feeling but
she said that well it was frustrating it was tough but you know after a while I proved myself.
Okay so that means that she was able to show someone that she can handle
difficult things difficult work difficult situations and so she said I proved myself and the new
editor liked me so basically she did a really good job. Exactly so if you prove yourself you're
showing someone that you have great ability or capabilities of solving a problem or being able
to handle a difficult job. That's right for example I could say you know last year Bob didn't do
very well at school but this year he really proved himself he studied hard and he got really good
grades. Exactly and well Rebecca what she got in exchange for proving herself she got promoted.
This is great so promotions are good things the verb here is to promote or to be promoted so in
this case she was promoted you could say last year I was promoted or he will be promoted next week
he doesn't know yet. Exactly now remember that to be promoted means to get a better position in
your job. Now as we mentioned the verb is to promote and you may be asking yourself why you're
using the verb to be in the past was promoted and this is because it's an ED adjective it's an
adjective that's ends in ED so you may think it's a verb but it's not it's actually an adjective.
The verb here is to be exactly so I was promoted was is obviously our verb here the verb to be
but promoted is an adjective that ends in ED. Okay and so if I'm the boss the action I do the
verb I do is I promote someone so this can be a little bit tricky but we recommend that you
check out the website for more details because we have lots of examples of how to use this.
Exactly well she got promoted and well she was really happy for a while but then she said you know
what I really needed a more challenging role a more challenging job. Okay challenging is a great
adjective it means something is difficult or it gives you a challenge so that means it's not easy.
Yeah so she found that her job was a little bit too easy so she wanted something a little bit more
challenging. Okay and so this is a really great word for job interviews in particular because
you're basically saying I want hard work. I want to prove myself that we go again prove.
I want to show you that I'm a good employee or hard worker and so I want a challenge something that's
hard. Exactly so uh is something that is hard is a challenge or you want something challenging.
So why don't we review these words that we've taken a look at now let's go back to the dialogue
and listen to it again.
Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job. I see you spent almost four years
at the London Weekly. Is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest the first year was quite tough
for me. I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have many responsibilities and I found
it quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new editor liked
me so he promoted me to features writer. Wow I real step up. Yes I was responsible for restaurant
and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position but to be honest it wasn't an
area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why do you decide to leave finally?
I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities. I really needed a more
challenging role to be honest. All right we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of
phrases we picked out for you on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. Okay this first phrase is unusual
because it actually happens at the end of sentences. This is very very common with people who are
making small talk or who are doing interviews. This is the phrase is that right.
So basically you saw that in the first line Mr. Parsons was talking to her and said well
I see you spent almost four years at the London Weekly. Is that right? So he's ending the sentence
with this phrase. So he's making the sentence a question. I see that you did this. Is that right?
So he's asking her to confirm the fact that he knows about her because maybe they've never really
talked before. So this is a good way for him to ask her to give more details.
Exactly. So for example Marco I hear that you're from Ecuador is that right?
That's right. So apart from ending the sentence like this if maybe somebody asks you is that right?
You have to confirm you have to say yes that's right or yes.
It's also good to elaborate to give more details. Yes I'm from Ecuador. I was born there but I've lived
in the United States. This is a way to give more information because that's basically what the
person's asking. Yeah I think it wouldn't be very good if you're at a job interview and the person
says is that right and you say yes that's right and then you don't say anything else.
So yeah the basically the point is you have to confirm or deny it to say yes that's right or
no that's not right and then you have to give some information about the question. Exactly.
All right now moving on when Rebecca again was talking about her job. She was saying it's tough
and I didn't have many responsibilities and I found it quite frustrating. Okay so this is like
lost and found like I lost my hat and I found it later. No no this is what's interesting about
this verb find that we are not actually looking for something or we didn't actually find
something we were looking for. This is kind of a realization right? That's right it's like a feeling.
So I find this movie boring. That means I think this movie is boring. It's the way that you're
thinking about something. That's right or you can say I found Paris to be quite an expensive city.
Yeah pretty expensive. So this is your impression. This is the way that you feel about something.
Exactly. So this is another way that you can use this word to find. Now again when Rebecca
talked about proving herself she used a very interesting I would say phrase very popular well known
phrase slowly but surely. Okay so slowly but surely is the opposite of right away.
So something that happens right away is immediate like I got promoted right away.
But slowly but surely means after lots of time and even hard work this good thing happened or
it's usually a good thing actually. Yeah yeah it's you're basically saying that you didn't do anything
very quickly but you did it very well. So slowly but surely I finished building my home.
Right so it didn't happen overnight but it did happen over time. You can also say it's about studying
language. It at the beginning learning English was really hard but slowly but surely I became fluent.
Exactly okay so slowly but surely. And the last phrase that we have for you today you may have
seen that Rebecca used this phrase to be honest a couple of times before explaining something.
So why does she say to be honest? To be honest is sometimes something we say in English to fill
some space or some time we call it filler but it's also a way to introduce something that's negative.
So for example in this dialogue she's talking about her negative experiences.
You know my job was tough my experience was bad. So she says to be honest it wasn't the best
experience but I learned from it. She's saying this to introduce some things that are maybe not
positive not happy things. That's right so it's another way of saying look I'm going to tell you the truth
and it may not be something positive but you know this is what happened. So to be honest I didn't
really like my last employer or something like that. Right we can even talk about this with your friends.
So hey Marco did you like that movie, shutter island? To be honest I didn't really see it.
Oh fell asleep. Or you could say to be honest I didn't love it. I didn't really like it.
Exactly so it's a very it's a very good phrase but don't overuse it I think sometimes
you get into the habit of using it all the time and just like like you know sometimes.
Well you know like I went to the movies like yesterday like and like to be honest like so try to keep
these fillers as you describe them to a minimum so don't really use them too much. Yes save thoughts
and ideas nice action verbs not too much fillers because sometimes especially in an interview
it makes people think that you don't really know much to say. Yeah exactly okay so let's listen to the
dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to chat a little bit more.
Okay now I'd like to find out more about your last job. I see you spent almost four
years at the London Weekly is that right? Yes that's right. To be honest the first year was
quite tough for me. I was really just treated more like an intern. I didn't have many responsibilities
and I found it quite frustrating. So what changed? Well slowly but surely I proved myself and the new
editor liked me so he promoted me to features writer. Wow I real step up. Yes I was responsible
for restaurant and food reviews mostly. I spent three years in that position but to be honest it wasn't
an area of journalism I wanted to stay in long term. I see so why did you decide to leave
finally? I just felt that the paper couldn't offer me any new opportunities. I really needed a more
challenging role to be honest. All right so talking about your last employer this is a pretty
ideal thing. Now do you have any advice that you can give our listeners about describing your
last job? Why did you leave your previous employer? Well I do have a little bit of basic job advice.
I would say don't complain about your last employer. Don't say my boss was mean, my co-workers
were lazy, my company was terrible because usually as a as a person doing an interview that makes
you think that this person if they work for you will complain about you. And so I think it's important
like what Rebecca does in this dialogue to keep it positive. Every negative situation can become a
positive experience. So the job was tough but it was a good challenge right? Or but she learned how to
do many new things. Exactly. I think this is important for anybody in any language but an
English especially to use some of these phrases and to say you know I really like a challenge or
I didn't feel this was challenging enough. Things like this as opposed to my old boss is so mean he
may be working on the weekend that company is so terrible. I mean that kind of stuff no one wants to
exactly and I think it's not really useful because even if the company is the competitor so you
don't really get any extra points for forgetting them like the dirty secrets of what was going
on the company may be saying oh my co-workers they were just so mean to me and stuff like this.
Yeah no it makes you seem like a complainer and no one wants to hire a complainer. Exactly.
All right so this is an interesting topic we would like to hear from you so come to English.com
and tell us why did you leave your previous employer or just let us know about some of your
interview experiences or some of your interview questions. We're happy to help you out. We'll
hope to see you at the website. All right we'll see you there. Bye.