Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we've
got another lesson all about food and eating. So today we're going to talk about all the tools that we use
when we're at the table. So what we use when we're eating. That's right. So let's take a listen to today's
dialogue and when we come back we'll talk about some of these words and some of the great phrases you're
learning today.
Honey can you set the table? I'm sure. What are we having for dinner? Do I need to put anything out in
particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers. I don't know if your brother
is coming tonight. So set an extra-place match just in case. Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead. Forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy bone serving dishes. Just be careful because
the wine glasses are also there. Oh.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of words in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So our first word is a very important one. You might have heard it before.
The word is silverware. Okay silverware now this means that it's usually made something that's
made out of silver right? It could be. Maybe traditionally it's made out of silver but it doesn't
have to be. You could have wooden silverware or other metals. It's basically the things that you
use to eat food with. Okay so we're going to take this as a category. Silverware are all the tools
that we use to eat food with and in this so for example a fork is some a part of a silverware.
It's a kind of silverware fork. A fork is the one that you usually put in your mouth with a piece of
lettuce or meat or something. Okay so it's pointy it has a like four little points. Now the one
that we use to have dessert or to have soup with we call that a spoon. A spoon that's right so to
eat yogurt or ice cream you use a spoon and finally to cut things you use a knife. Okay so in
the dialogue we saw the plural form knives but singular it would be knife. That's right and sometimes
there are foods that are very very hard to cut. For example steak is very hard to cut because it's
a tough meat and so in that case we use a steak knife to cut it. Okay so we have a knife or a
steak knife. Steak knife more specifically is used to cut meat. All right so these are three kinds
or actually four kinds of silverware. Of course there are other kinds but those are the most
important. After that that we have something that's important for making your food taste better.
So what if I want to add salt or pepper? What are those things called? Those are called salt and
pepper shakers. We saw them in the dialogue that we need to put out the pepper and salt
shakers. So the little thing where you keep the salt is called a shaker. That's right because the
action the verb is to shake. That means moving your hand up and down so some salt will fall out
onto your food. Exactly so usually it's only salt and pepper that we keep in these things and
these little shakers. But apart from salt and pepper shakers when all the silverware were putting out
we're also putting out some saucers because we're going to have coffee later on.
Oh say okay so there's not only goes together with cups cups and saucers but everyone knows what
a cup is what is a saucer. So a saucer is this little plate that you put under the cup when you're
having coffee. So usually that's where you keep your spoon or maybe the little bag of tea.
Okay so a saucer is important because it also helps in case you spill some coffee or tea so
the coffee or tea doesn't go on the ground it goes on the plate. Exactly so that little
plate is called a saucer. Now where do we keep all the plates all the silverware? We usually
keep them in a cupboard. Okay so you might want to say cup board because it's cup CUPCO
ARD that's not right. The word is pronounced covered. Okay so even though it may seem like you should
pronounce cup board the correct pronunciation is covered. Covered. Covered and a covered like you
said is usually in the dining room or the kitchen because it houses it keeps all of our plates
and bowls and sometimes our silverware. That's right okay so actually in the cupboard we also have
some other things dishes. Specifically we have a gravy boat in there. Okay so I'm not even sure
why they call it a boat but a gravy boat is basically a special dish. It's like us it's a
catalble with a spout so you can pour it that keeps gravy so gravy is like a liquid or a sauce
that goes on top of meat or potatoes. I guess it kind of looks like a boat just imagine a boat
but inside it's empty so then that's where you put the gravy in. You can pour it. You can pour it.
All right and so we can find that we can also find serving dishes which are basically big
plates or bowls that we use when we're having dinner at the dinner table to keep for example a turkey
or a roast. And specifically we were also looking for wine glasses. Well maybe we weren't
looking for them but they found us because the person getting stuff out of the cupboard dropped
some wine glasses. These are very very easy to break. Wine glasses are basically just glasses
that maybe are tall and you drink wine out of them. That's right so there's specific type of glass
usually used to drink wine. So wine glasses I guess normal glass that you used to drink maybe
juicer water is just called a glass. Right you wouldn't say wine glass only when you're drinking wine.
Okay so we've taken a look at a lot of vocab here. A lot of tools that we use at the dinner table
when we're having dinner. So let's listen to the dialogue again and review.
Honey can you set the table? I'm sure what are we having for dinner. Do I need to put anything
out in particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers. I don't know if your
brother is coming tonight so set an extra place mat just in case. Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead. Forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
I'll also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy bone serving dishes. Just be careful because
the wine glasses are also that oops.
All right we're back so now we have four key phrases that we've prepared for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay so this first phrase is very important especially as a
child your mother or father might ask you to do this the phrase is to set the table. Okay so that's
a phrasal verb to set the table and what does it mean if you're asked to set the table. It means you
will put down the plates and the silverware and the bowl so that everything is prepared for dinner.
Okay so this is actually what we were doing and a complimentary phrasal verb to this.
When you're setting the table as you said you are putting down or putting out
the different spoons knives dishes all that stuff. Right so the verb to the verbal phrase to put
out means to place down or to make sure that you get something out on the table. In this case my
mother would usually ask me to put out extra glasses for water okay or don't forget to put out the
wine glasses in case we're drinking wine it just means to place down. Exactly so just remember that
it's we use it because all these things that are inside the cupboard so you have to take them out so
you have to put them out on the table. All right and sometimes we may have a guest or we may need an extra
chair or an extra seat because we're having company and the person in dialogue said to set an
extra placement just in case. Okay so a placement is basically a piece of plastic or maybe fabric
that you put in front of a person when they're at the table so it's on the table and it's
something that protects the table so it's small everyone has one and the bowl and the silver
will go on top of that placement but it also indicates that that is where someone will sit. Okay so
to put out or to set out an extra placement means to prepare an extra place for someone else who will
be coming. So if you have a guest for example you'll set out an extra placement for him or for her.
Okay so we can say set an extra placement because this is by this we are referring that somebody is
going to sit down at the table or you can just simply say set an extra place for someone. That's
right set an extra place your older brothers coming home from college tonight. Okay so we can set
an extra place for him at the table and well in this case we didn't know if the brother was
really coming or not so she said just in case. This is a great phrase one that you'll hear all the time.
It means I'm not sure what the result will be or what the outcome will be but in case something happens
or just in case we should do this. So for example Marco I think it's going to rain today you should
bring an umbrella just in case. Okay so this is a way of saying you're preventing something you're
prepared maybe if it does rain you'll have an umbrella just in case bring your umbrella.
Okay so a lot of great phrases there, a lot of vocab so why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time.
Honey can you set the table? I'm sure what are we having for dinner. Do I need to put anything out
in particular? Well make sure to put out the pepper and salt shakers. I don't know if your brother
is coming tonight so set an extra place mat just in case. Okay should I use the fancy silverware?
Yeah go ahead forks spoons and knives. I roasted some meat so be sure to put out some steak knives as well.
I also set some cups and sauces for some coffee after dinner. Honey have you seen our soup bowls?
They're in the cupboard where you keep the gravy bone serving dishes just be careful because
the wine glasses are also there. Oh.
All right we're back so talking about dinner and silverware. There are also a couple of other
names that we didn't mention. For example many people refer to ceramic plates as China.
Yeah these are usually the the fancy kinds of plates and dishes that you have in your house.
Obviously if you have just kind of the cheap ceramics that you can throw away or even paper
paper plates, those aren't very important but at a wedding or in a special occasion a person or
family might receive Chinaware. China and that is very nice, very pretty porcelain plates or
just lacquerware. Okay so you can call it Chinaware which is basically plates that are either
very fine ceramic or porcelain as you said. That's right. Or what was the other word that you said before?
Lacquerware. Lacquerware is a certain kind of plate or ceramic that has a kind of sheen
to it. It's very special kind of basically pink job. Oh okay yeah because it's always been kind
of a strange the fact that a name like China would also now be related to plates but apparently
I guess because Chinese porcelain is renowned as being such high quality I guess this is why
we just have a word for it called China or Chinaware. I think it actually has to do with the fact
that the Chinese and the old days sent sold what most of the British bought their porcelain from
China and so it was very very invoked it's very popular and it was basically the only thing that
the British wanted they just wanted all of this China and it became a part of the vocabulary then.
Yeah it's really strange though that you would they would call something China. It's like
I don't know any other country that you call something you know like French. This is a French
or a Frenchware. I can't think of any. Li Moj is a name of a city in France and it's a
certain kind of ceramics. Oh there you go. All right so an interesting topic there are many other
tools that we didn't mention would like salad fork and ice cream spoon. I don't know there's so
many as sometimes if you go to a fancy dinner you will have maybe three spoons, three knives,
three forks and you don't know what to do with it. Start on the outside and go in that's my
one recommendation. Exactly so we're really curious to know what you have to say come to our website
English.com if you have any questions you can leave them there or if you also want to suggest a topic
for a lesson or anything you want just let us know. All right we'll see you then. All right bye.