Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we've got one more episode in our series about interview skills
This is an elementary level series and we're here today to talk about things that you might not be very good at
That's right today. We're going to talk about weaknesses and that is our word for vocabulary preview. So let's take a look at it now
Very vocabulary preview
Okay, so what is a weakness a weakness is a thing or an activity or something that you're just not very good at or something that you think you can improve
Okay, so obviously no one is perfect and
Like we saw in the previous lesson we had a lot of good things about ourselves key strengths
And now we're going to talk about our weaknesses maybe
You're a little bit lazy that might be a weakness. That's right. So weakness is the opposite of strength and that is the topic today
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue
Okay Rebecca well I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities
But let's talk a little bit about your weaknesses
Okay, well, it's always more difficult to describe that. Listen to it
Definitely but if you had to pinpoint one weakness what would it be?
Well as I mentioned before I do tend to get frustrated if I don't see progress in my work or career
I suppose I'm quite a restless character my father always taught me to be a higher cheever
So would you say if things don't go your way at work it could easily get you down?
Well in a way yes, but I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work I always give 110%
I would never shock my responsibilities. I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon
Well, you know journalism is a highly competitive world
So you do need to keep pushing yourself. It's true
Okay, well, let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we? Yes, please
All right, we're back so obviously Rebecca did a very good job at talking about her weaknesses in a very positive way
So before we get into analyzing that why don't we take a look at a couple of words you used on language take away
Language take away
One of the first words that Mr. Parsons used was a clear impression so impression
All right, so I think this is a very common word when people talk about first impressions
Or I get the impression so what is an impression well an impression is like an idea or a feeling
So I can have an impression about something it means that I don't necessarily understand it really well
Or don't have experience with it, but it's it's an idea that I have about something that's right
So for example
Uh, maybe you meet somebody new and you said I get the impression that he is liar
But maybe then you get to know him and he's not so this is your this is your idea about something or the way you feel about something
So in this case a Mr. Parsons has a clear impression of her positive qualities
That means that he has an idea or an understanding of the things that Rebecca is good at
But he wants to know more about her weaknesses that's right and Mr. Parsons asked her to try and pinpoint
One of her weaknesses so this word to pinpoint this is a great word and not really sure where it comes from an English
But I think it's very visual you can see what the word means
Pinpoint means to to locate or identify or
Really be specific about something that's right, so maybe if you go to the doctor and you say that your
Back hurts the doctor might ask you to try and pinpoint where on your back you have the pain
That's right, so it's a way to be specific or very exact about something okay
So if she had to pinpoint something she said well
I do get a little bit frustrated. Okay, so frustrated is a way you feel I feel frustrated
He is frustrated. It's uh it's basically a feeling that you get when you have to do something
But you don't think you can do it or maybe something annoys you and you get frustrated
For example when people tap like this
And I'm working I get frustrated because it's a distraction. Okay, so everyone has different things that frustrate them
Now if we take a look at this word
It is actually an adjective and we usually use it you get frustrated or as you said you feel frustrated
So remember it may look like a verb
But it's actually an adjective that ends an ED frustrated to get frustrated. He got frustrated or we feel very frustrated
Okay, and well apart from being frustrated. She also said that she is a restless character
Okay, so someone is restless if they don't like to stay in one place all the time
That means someone who wants to move around or to go places or to travel or to see new things is restless
That's right, so
She has a restless character that means she likes to move around. She doesn't like to stand still in one place
Maybe she gets bored very easily
Okay, so that's somebody that would be restless
But moving on she also said that she doesn't like to shrink her responsibilities
Okay, you often hear these words go together. So what's responsibilities are things that we need to do
Right things that other people expect us to do
to shrink a responsibility
Means to to not do something that you're supposed to do. It means to avoid responsibility or to
To push it away. Okay, so it's a verb to shrink your responsibilities. You shouldn't shrink your responsibilities. That's right
All right, so a lot of interesting key words there. Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with fluency builder
Okay Rebecca. Well, I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities
But let's talk a little bit about your weaknesses. Okay, well, it's always more difficult to describe that
Definitely, but if you had to pinpoint one weakness what would it be? Well, as I mentioned before, I do tend to get
frustrated if I don't see progress in my work or career
I suppose I'm quite a restless character my father always taught me to be a higher cheever. So
So would you say if things don't go your way at work it could easily get you down? Well in a way yes
But I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work I always give 110%
I would never shock my responsibilities. I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon
Well, you know journalism is a highly competitive world
So you do need to keep pushing yourself. It's true
Okay, well, let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we? Yes, please
So we've picked out three key phrases for you on fluency builder. Let's take a look at those now
Starting with Mr. Parsons saying so would you say if things don't go your way at work
It could easily get you down two great phrases there. That's right. So the first phrase if things don't go your way
So this is kind of a funny phrase when you think about it because they go your way like to me or
Right, what is my way? This basically means if things do not happen in a way that makes you happy or in a way that
You expect
Mm-hmm. Okay, so we could say he lost his job
He couldn't pay his bills things just didn't go his way. That's right. So things are not
Happening as he planned the or is he expected you can also say the opposite so he won the lottery and
He also met a really beautiful girl who wanted to be his girlfriend things were going his way. Okay, very good
So if things are going your way it's good if things aren't going your way then it's bad. That's right
Okay, and so if things aren't going Rebecca's way
Does that mean that it could easily get her down?
Okay, so to get you down or to get someone down means to make you sad upset or frustrated like that where we just turn
So
You could ask someone like Marco what gets you down?
Rainy days. That's a good one. Yeah, rainy days get me down too
So it's kind of a way of saying what makes you sad or depressed or what makes you unhappy or in this case
If something doesn't happen as you planned it if it doesn't go your way does that make you sad does that get you down?
Okay, very good. So a very good question there and
She responded it kind of yeah that does happen, but she always tries to give 110
Okay, so this is a really funny phrase because you think I can give everything I have
I can work really hard and that's 100% but we say 110% means you do more than you can
It's like pushing yourself more than is possible. That's right. So
This is a very common phrase in sports in business people are saying for example
I always remember my coach saying I want you guys to give me 110% out there
That means like I really want you to try very hard to do as much as possible
Even more than your best more than you think you can do exactly so again it refers to the effort that you put into
Something it can be in business sports anything and she's basically saying I always do more than my best
I do as much as humanly possible. That's right. Okay, so a lot of great stuff there from Rebecca
Why don't we listen to her one last time and will we back in a bit?
Okay Rebecca, well I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities
But let's talk a little bit about your weaknesses
Okay, well it's always more difficult to describe that, isn't it?
Definitely, but if you had to pinpoint one weakness what would it be?
Well as I mentioned before, I do tend to get frustrated if I don't see progress in my work or career
I suppose I'm quite a restless character my father always taught me to be a higher cheever
So would you say if things don't go your way at work it could easily get you down?
Well in a way yes, but I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work I always give 110%
I would never shirk my responsibilities. I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon
Well, you know journalism is a highly competitive world so you do need to keep pushing yourself it's true
Okay, well let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we?
Yes, please
All right, so talking about weaknesses
I think one of the common mistakes when people talk about weaknesses is they say they work too much
and everyone says you should never say that in an interview
Yeah, I think it's a it's a bad way to
talk about yourself because a boss or an employer really wants to hear a real weakness
and I worked too hard as a way of saying I have no weaknesses. I'm actually really really perfect
I just think it's a lazy answer so maybe you should avoid saying I worked too hard and really focus on things that you
You do have to to work on and then I think the key is to say that I know this is something that I have a hard time with I know this is a weakness
And I'm trying to improve it. Yeah, I remember in some of the interviews I've had I think my common answer was
I'm sometimes I'm very late on that very punctual
So but you know it's it's a it's a it's a real weakness and oh, I may seem
Like difficult, but then you give it a little spin by saying yeah, I'm sometimes not very punctual
But then I try to make up for it. Maybe it's staying more time at the office or sometimes I try to
Wake up a little bit earlier and make it on time. I don't know something like that right?
So the key there is just to show that you know it's a problem that you're trying to work on it. Yeah, so
This is actually the hardest part for me of an interview talking about yourself in a negative way because obviously
You want to get the job so you want to make sure that the employer has a good idea of yourself, but
It's hard. I think it's the hardest part for everyone. Yeah, I don't think it's just you. Yeah, it's hard
So this is an interesting topic. Why don't you practice and come to our website English puttuk
And on our comments section why don't you tell us what your weaknesses are that's right
We hope to hear from you of course you can also share with us your strengths on our lesson about strengths
But in this one I recommend everyone practice this because it will come up at some point and it's good to get the practice in so English pod.com
We hope to see you there. All right guys. Bye