Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got an elementary level lesson for you all about getting up in the morning.
That's right today we're making breakfast and well of course many people have different things when they're making breakfast and very big.
Others are small. So but this is what we're going to talk about today. So why don't we listen to the dial?
I'll go and see what they're having for breakfast today.
Smells good. What's for breakfast? Well since we're getting up so late I decided to make a big breakfast.
Nice brunch. Kind of. So I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs some French toast and buttermilk pancakes.
Wow you really went all out. Did you make any coffee?
Yeah just the way you like it. I also put out some cereal and mostly if you feel like having something more light.
Looks good. I'll squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
Get the jam and butter while you're in there. Oh and don't forget to serve. All righty.
All right we're back. So a lot of interesting things are huge breakfast.
Way too big for me. I don't like to eat a big breakfast because I feel like it's
makes me tired and then I don't have any energy. Especially if you just get up right.
Exactly. You need to shower and maybe have some fruit and then go to work.
But we can talk about it that at the end. There were a lot of interesting words and phrases
that we heard that we would benefit from taking a closer look at.
Language takeaway. All right so on language takeaway today we're going to take a look at our first
word and it's an interesting word. It's kind of a mix of two things brunch. That's right. So
this word comes from two different words. Breakfast, bro, breakfast and lunch. That's right.
So brunch. So if you have brunch what is exactly a brunch? Well there's two ways to look at
brunch. One is the time element. Usually brunch is later than breakfast but maybe a little earlier
than lunch so 11 o'clock or maybe even noon. But the other thing is size because you're putting
two meals together usually brunch is very big. You eat a lot of food. Okay so it's a perfect
combination of breakfast and lunch. I'm the type of person that likes having scrambled eggs
at noon. So this is a perfect solution. brunch. Right. You don't have to only eat eggs at breakfast.
You can eat them at lunch as well. Exactly. This is actually something we do a lot in America
from other's day. So mom wakes up late. We take her to brunch. It's a very big special meal. Very
good. And talking about eggs and the types of eggs that we can have. I mentioned scrambled eggs
and in the dialogue we also heard soft boiled eggs. Okay these are two very important kinds of eggs.
Usually if you're in a restaurant they will ask you how do you want your eggs cooked or done.
And my answer is always scrambled scrambled. This means someone mixes the eggs before they are cooked
and then when they cook they are hard. They're yellow. Okay there's no white it's just yellow and
it's a little hard mixture. But soft boiled eggs are very very different. That's right soft boiled
eggs you actually don't break the egg or open the egg to cook it like scrambled eggs. You actually
put the entire egg and boiling water. I think it's for two minutes and then you take it out and then
you open the shell and the eggs are kind of cooked. It's kind of hard in some parts but it's also
kind of liquidy in other parts. That's right. So the outside the white part is hard but the yellow
part the yolk is liquid. It's not hard. That's right and actually if you want the whole egg
to be hard you can ask for hard boiled eggs. That's right those are cooked for much longer.
That's right. Okay so we have scrambled eggs soft boiled eggs we have French toast and we have
buttermilk pancakes. Okay so you can ask for just pancakes. But if you want to be specific you
want to give instructions about what kind of pancakes you can ask for buttermilk pancakes.
And what exactly is buttermilk? buttermilk is a very very creamy eggy milk that's very very high
in fat that makes everything taste better. I think this is used a lot in baking not really in
other kinds of foods. So you can have buttermilk muffins or buttermilk biscuits but usually you have
buttermilk pancakes and so these are very rich, very fatty pancakes. Awesome yeah they taste delicious.
All right so now if we want to eat a little bit more healthy we do have some cereal and some
musely. musely is a funny word it's not a sound we make very often in English musely. Yeah I think
it actually comes from German. It does look German because actually the spelling is MUE so you would
kind of want to say MUEZLY musely or something. Yeah no we say musely and it's basically a mixture
of granola or different kinds of fiber grains. Yeah so just think of having like raisins and maybe
some almonds granola all mixed up and you have this nice thing that is goes well with yogurt musely.
It's very very tasty and also very good for you. Okay and now well actually going back to pancakes
no pancake is possible to eat unless you put syrup on it right. Well some people might disagree I
know a lot of people who eat pancakes with honey or butter. True. But the best I think is with syrup
and syrup is basically liquid sugar and you put it on your pancakes to make them sweeter. Okay actually
it's the same thing as honey basically except that it doesn't come from bees. Right so real syrup
we say maple syrup comes from maple trees and you tap the tree and it comes out it's very very sweet.
But we also have syrup you can buy at the store which is hard to manmade. Yeah it's basically just sugar.
Okay very good so that's what we have with pancakes usually but why don't we go back listen to our
dialogue again let's review all of these yummy breakfast treats and we'll come back in a bit with flinty builder.
Smells good what's for breakfast? Well since we're getting up so late I decided to make a big breakfast.
Nice brunch. Kind of so I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs some French toast and buttermilk
Wow you really went all out did you make any coffee? Yeah just the way you like it. I also put
out some cereal and musely if you feel like having something more light. Looks good I'll squeeze
that some fresh orange juice. Get the jam and butter while you're in there oh and don't forget the
syrup. Alrighty. Alright so now on fluing seabilder why don't we take a look at a couple of phrases.
Fluing seabilder when the guy was kind of surprised he said wow you really went all out.
Okay so this comes from the phrase to go all out so he went all out or I'm going to go all out
and this means to give something your best to do more than is expected. That's right so
if you go all out when you're making breakfast it means you just you cooked a lot or really good
and you spend a lot of time doing it. For example if it's someone's birthday and I know it's
their birthday I go all out by buying gifts and a cake and lots of decorations and calling all
their friends and having a party so this is doing everything for them. That's right okay and he was
really surprised and he really seemed to enjoy breakfast and he said looks good. Okay this is uh
this is a way to say good job or nicely done. It's almost a way to say I'm happy about this.
Alright yeah and obviously you can also say that the food looks delicious so it looks good. It
looks good so it's a way to say you know well done looks good or in this case looks very tasty.
That's right okay and now this is an interesting part he says our squeezes some fresh orange stew so
let's take a look at this verb squeeze. To squeeze uh this is something you usually do with your hand
when you tighten something. So for example your toothpaste. Yes you squeeze your toothpaste so the
toothpaste will come out. So in this case we are squeezing the orange just to extract the juice.
That's right so you you hold the orange right tight you make the juice come out and then you have fresh
squeezed orange juice and this is different from orange juice you buy in a store. Okay so you can say
our squeezes of fresh orange juice that means you're going to make fresh orange juice and this
fresh orange juice that you make is called fresh squeezed orange juice. Fresh squeezed. You probably
seeing this in the store like some bottles they say 100% fresh squeezed orange juice. Yeah it's good for
advertising. All right so very good a lot of great interesting phrases there won't we listen to
our dialogue one last time. Smells good what's for breakfast? Well since we're getting up so late I
decided to make a big breakfast. Nice brunch. Kind of so I made scrambled and soft boiled eggs
some French toast and buttermilk pancakes. Wow you really went all out did you make any coffee?
Yeah just the way you like it. I also put out some cereal and mostly if you feel like having something
more light. Looks good I'll squeeze that some fresh orange juice. Get the jam and butter while you're
in there. Oh and don't forget to serve. Alrighty. All right so talking about brunch and breakfast what
is your typical or ideal breakfast? Oh that's a hard question breakfast is my favorite meal of the
day so I could eat breakfast all kinds of breakfast anytime but one of my favorite kinds of breakfast
is a Greek diner breakfast. Greek diner what does this have? Okay well we have a lot of diners or
small restaurants that are very very cheap and fast in America and this usually involves some
scrambled eggs that are made with cheese and toast and potatoes and bacon and sausage and a coffee.
Wow big breakfast. Very big. But delicious. Nice. What's your favorite? I also in really,
really like breakfast and I actually like having places that you can have 24 hour a day breakfast.
All day breakfast is called so I can have breakfast for dinner. Right that's usually in America you
go to a diner because they have breakfast at 4 o'clock in the morning or at 7 o'clock at night.
I'm not really a coffee person I actually enjoy either juice, orange juice or hot chocolate. I really like
my chocolate and definitely pancakes three buttermilk pancakes stacked and as you sit before syrup but I
actually also put butter on it so. Gross I know a lot of people do that they put butter on first.
Yeah and then they pour the syrup. Yeah of course. So it's like complete very very fatty and
hash browns. I'm definitely a fat enough hash browns. Those are potatoes that are chopped very very finely
and you fry them together so it almost becomes like a potato pancake. Okay yeah exactly. So a lot
of great stuff and obviously breakfasts around the world are different. I know for example in some
countries they have the Fisherman's breakfast so in the morning you have black coffee rice and fish.
That's right because you're going to work all day. So we're really curious about how
breakfast is in your country. What a typical breakfast is like. Yeah what are traditional
breakfasts and what is your favorite breakfasts? Let us know on our website. Englishpod.com we hope to see you
there. All right bye bye.