Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have a lesson for you all about life at home and life with
your parents. That's right. We've all lived with our parents when we were younger or maybe we still
do and of course they have certain rules in the house and well when you break those rules something
happens. There are consequences and that's what's happening in today's dialogue.
So let's take a listen to this dialogue and when we come back we'll be talking more about
what's going on and what some of these words and phrases mean.
Do you know what time it is?
Um... 10.
Get in this door young man. It's midnight. You are two hours past curfew.
I know but it wasn't my fault. I told Jennifer she had to drop me up before 10 but she wouldn't leave
the party.
I don't care. You are grounded for life, Mr.
Mom, that is so unfair.
You know the rules and you broke them. No allowance and no TV for a week. I usually never
ground you but this time I have to put my foot down.
What? For being a couple of hours late you have to be kidding.
I don't want to hear it. Now go to your room.
All right we're back. So a very typical case somebody or the kid returns home it's too late
and now they're in trouble.
Yes, his parents are not very happy and this case it's his mom who is telling him
what the consequences will be. So let's take a look at language takeaway and find out what some of
these keywords are.
All right so the first word that we're going to take a look is actually something that his
mom said and he said that you are two hours past curfew.
Curfew. So curfew has to do specifically with the time when your parents expect you at home.
That's right. So if your curfew is 10 o'clock you have to be home before or by 10 o'clock.
Right. So in this case if the boy's curfew is 10 o'clock and he arrives home at midnight 12 o'clock
he's two hours past curfew. That's right and even sometimes cities or governments will implement
certain curfews at certain times. That's right and I don't think adults really have curfews at home.
No, I don't think so.
What you want but a kids definitely have curfews. What happens though, Marco when you break
curfew? So this is a very serious offense and you're going to get punished and the way that we say
this usually parents to their children you are grounded or you ground that kid.
Okay. So you might have heard this word when talking about airplanes or flights at an airport.
The plane was grounded. It basically means it can't go anywhere. And so when you're talking
about a kid or person you basically mean okay you're grounded you can't go out with your friends.
You can't go anywhere. Usually you can go to school. Right. Right. But you can't have fun.
Is the meaning? That's right. So it's usually a fixed phrase. You're grounded. That means that you are
punished. You can't go out. But in this case the mom specifies saying you're grounded. So that means
that he can't go out. But on top of that she said no allowance and no TV for a week.
Man. So allowance is the money that your parents give you to go out like to go to the
and your parents might give this to you on a weekly basis. So every Saturday you get $5
or on a monthly basis every month you get $20. And when his mother says you're not going to have
any allowance for a week that means we're not going to give you any money this week. That's right.
So that is in allowance. How much money you get per month or per week? The key thing about
allowance though is that it's not something you do for work. You don't work and receive allowance.
If you work you have a salary. Allowance is something that you get for free from someone.
Yeah. So you can get an allowance from your your boss to eat. But you can also have an allowance
from your parents to do fun things. That's right. So usually kids obviously they can't work. So
they get an allowance from their parents. Usually for fun things like going to the movies and stuff.
Exactly. All right. Now going back a little bit. Let's take a look at two ways that the mom
addressed or called her son. Because obviously it's her son. But when he got home, she said
it in this story young man. Okay. These are angry mom phrases. When you're in trouble,
your parents tend to use different words to talk to you. So this is a very popular one.
Young man. Right. So it's like saying you should be mature. But you made a mistake.
Yeah. All right. So come inside right now young man. Yeah. It's a it's a way to kind of emphasize
that you are also very angry. And also when he was trying to explain what happened.
She said, I don't care. You're grounded for life, Mr. You're grounded for life, Mr. So these are
both ways of talking to young boys. Mr. is the opposite of Miss. But in the case of a young girl,
you'd say, get in this door young lady. Right. And then you're grounded for life, Missy. Missy.
Yeah. I think they say Missy. Missy. So Missy, Mr. Young man, young lady. These are always
referring to people in kind of it's weird. It's kind of like they're adults, but they're not.
Yeah. That's right. That's like saying you're in trouble. Yeah. So a very interesting
thing's going on here with this young man who got grounded. Why don't we go back? Let's take a
look at our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Do you know what time it is? 10. Get in this door young man. It's midnight. You are two hours
past curfew. I know, but it wasn't my fault. I told Jennifer. She had to drop me up before 10.
But you wouldn't leave the party. I don't care. You are grounded for life, Mr.
Mom, that is so unfair. You know the rules and you broke them. No allowance and no TV for a week.
I usually never ground you, but this time I have to put my foot down. What? For being a couple
of hours late, you have to be kidding. I don't want to hear it. Now go to your room.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at four key phrases that we've picked out for you
on fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right. So this first phrase is something that actually we
hear when the young boy or the young man is giving his excuse for being late. He said,
listen, I told Jennifer. She had to drop me off before 10. That's right. So the phrase will
verb there is to drop off. This means to leave someone somewhere. That's right. But usually it
means to drive someone to a certain place. So for example, Jennifer probably has a car.
And Jennifer was supposed to take this boy home. So he said, she was going to drop me off
before 10 o'clock. That means kind of leave her leave him at his house. That's right. So the
verb is to drop off, but we usually insert the subject in between. So to drop me off, she is going
to drop me off. I dropped him off at the bank. That's right. All right. So now that Jennifer was supposed
to drop him off at 10, that didn't happen. So he got grounded. And his mom was saying that
she usually doesn't really ground him. But this time, I have to put my foot down. She's angry.
Yeah. He's upset. And she's angry. And she said, listen, I have to put my foot down. What does
this mean? You put your foot on the ground. It's strange to hear this phrase. It means that she's
going to be strict. That she's not going to let him just get away with it or not ground him. She
really has to be strict. And she has to punish him. Okay. So to put your foot down or I put my
foot down, this means to be strict with someone to not maybe bend the rules or be flexible. So for
my mother was always very, very loose with my brother. He could do what he wanted or whatever.
But one day, he did something really horrible and she finally put her foot down. And she grounded him.
She grounded him for three months. All right. So that's what happens when somebody puts their
foot down. And now, obviously, he was very surprised that he's going to be grounded for so long.
And only for being a couple of hours late. So he said, you have to be kidding. You have got to be
kidding. So this is a rhetorical. So he's not talking about joking here. He's saying,
no way. I can't believe it. This is not happening to me. Yeah. You're not serious. You're not serious.
So he's upset. And I would be too. No one likes to be grounded. But he's saying, okay, come on.
No way. That's too serious. That's right. So this is what this is a phrase that you can use with
someone if you're not really believing what they're saying or your surprise. You have to be kidding
you have it. Usually there's also a degree of anger. So you're upset at the decision.
For example, I'm watching the world cup right now. And there was a foul. And I was very upset because
I didn't think it was a foul. And I said, you have got to be kidding me. That's right. Okay. So that's
exactly the way that we would use that phrase. And well, obviously, the mother had made up her mind.
She's very decided. And she said, I don't want to hear it. So this is the end of the conversation.
Okay. This is one of those phrases that will just stop anything you're talking about. So
they're arguing and she says, nope, I don't want to hear it. That means no more excuses. No more
talking. This is the end. That's right. I don't want to hear it. And it's using many scenarios,
right? Not only for somebody being angry or grounded, but also in a meeting. I don't want to hear it.
That's it. We're doing my idea. We're going forward with it. I'll be careful because that's usually
with the boss. We'll say. That's right. It's not the most gentle phrase. And so you have to be careful
with how you use it. But if you have authority like your apparent or your boss, you can say, nope,
I don't want to hear it. I have made my decision. That's right. Okay. So we've taken a look at a lot of
great things. Why don't we go back, listen to our dialogue one last time and we're back in a bit.
Do you know what time it is? 10. Get in this door, young man. It's midnight. You are two hours
past curfew. I know, but it wasn't my fault. I told Jennifer. She had to drop me up before 10.
But you wouldn't leave the party. I don't care. You are grounded for life, Mr.
Mom, that is so unfair. You know the rules and you broke them. No allowance and no TV for a week.
I usually never ground you, but this time I have to put my foot down. What? For being a couple of hours
late, you have to be kidding. I don't want to hear it. Now go to your room.
All right, we're back. So obviously we've all been grounded. What is the longest you've been grounded for?
Do you remember? I was at a girl so maybe a week. Really. Maybe not even. I never really
gotten trouble as a kid. But I think once I was grounded the entire summer. Yeah, I don't remember exactly
what I did. But my dad was pretty upset with me and he was really strict. So I got grounded quite a bit.
I tend to think that girls get in trouble less. I don't know if it's because they're good.
I think probably it's because they're better at hiding things from their parents.
Maybe. Because whenever I would come home my mother would always wake up. But she's very
she doesn't really understand what time it is. And so I'd say, oh Mom, it's 11 o'clock. Good night.
Yeah. And it'd be like four o'clock in the morning. And she had no idea. So who was the person or the
parent that put their foot down? Was it your mom or your dad? My dad was the series one.
Oh, really. Yeah, it's it's interesting because sometimes it's the the dad that's very
kind of helps you out and tries to kind of not get you grounded or something. But sometimes it's the
other way around. The mom is really strict and firm and it has like, come on, don't ground them.
They're just having fun. Well, I think in some families that the children understand who is strict
and who is maybe not so strict. And so they say, oh, well, Mom said that it's okay. So I think maybe
you should let me go out in the dab. It'll be very angry because the mother said that it's okay. That's right.
All right. So that's all the time we have for today. We're really curious to get your
stories. Maybe tell us why were you grounded or how long were you grounded for?
Or what was your curfew when you were a child or growing up? Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there. All right. See you guys there. Bye.