Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we're talking about where people come from or nationalities
That's right. Many people come from many different countries just like our listeners and there's specific words or adjectives are and nouns to describe people like for example somebody who is from China
A Chinese person. Mm-hmm. That's right. So in your case Marco you are an Ecuadorian
That's right. So that means I come from the country Ecuador. I am the other hand. I'm an American. I come from America
That's right. So we have a lot of these examples. Why don't we jump into the dialogue? Let's see where all of the people from this
International class are from and we'll be back to talk about it
Hey how's your first day of class? I'm a level two and I'm loving my class this semester. It's great being in a class of international students
Man was okay. Except that no one in my class speaks English
I guess it will force me to converse in Chinese more in class so at least I should improve a lot this semester
That's both fortunate and unfortunate. It's the United Nations in my class. We have people from all over the world
There are three Germans a poll a Scott two French
In American a Brazilian a Chilean a New Zealander though he prefers to call himself a Kiwi
Who else do we have? Oh we have a Moroccan a Tagalese a Pakistani and two Indonesia's
That's quite the array of nationalities everyone in my classes from Asia except me there were a few South Koreans
Several Japanese Malaysian ties in Napoleon
Filipino Kazakhstan and
One Russian well, I think you're pretty lucky actually you have the opportunity to learn so much about Asian culture
I guess so but I think it's going to be hard to relate to my classmates
Especially with the language barrier. I think I might change classes
Don't stay the course your spoken Chinese will be eternally grateful
I bet you it'll even surpass mine with all that practice. I highly doubt it your girlfriend is Chinese.
Well, there is that yes
So the student jokes that their class is kind of like the United Nations
So it does sound like it we have so many different nationalities that we're going to look at them in two groups today
But the United Nations as you know is a political group that has people from all over the world who make decisions about
Politics and the environment things like that. That's right. So why don't we take a look at these nationalities now on language takeaway
Language takeaway
The first few are from Europe so these are some European
nationalities we've got German. Where's a German from? A German is from Germany. Okay, so next to Germany
We have another country Poland what do we call a person from Poland you call that person a poll
So is this for a woman and a man or is this just one gender? Yeah, it's for both. Okay, so poll
Yeah a girl that's from Poland would be also a poll now someone that comes from Scotland on the other hand
That would be a Scott or if it's a man a Scott's man
Scott's men. Okay, now this is interesting because we are mentioning the nouns of
These nationalities like for example German now when we took a look at poll from Poland
What would be the adjective do I say I am poll? I am Polish okay or if you want to use the noun
I am a poll but the adjective can be used for things as well. I love to eat Polish sausages
Okay, or for example some or something from Scotland you can say I love Scottish whiskey or I love Scottish
Kiltz those skirts all right, so that's the adjective but in the case of France the country
France we have to say as a noun he is a Frenchman. Okay, and if it's a woman a French woman
That's right or in the case of an adjective I love to eat French bread. Okay, now we're being on to South
America we took a look at a Brazilian and a Chilean okay, so Brazil Brazilian in this country there are many
Brazilians and Chile or Chile as many Americans say has people called Chileans
Some people say Chilean so I don't know I guess something the accent varies a little bit now what
We move back to the other side of the world. We have a new Z-lander
All right, so many of you have heard of Australia maybe New Zealand is not as famous it's a small country near Australia
And the people who come from there are called New Zealanders it's very hard to to say those sometimes
Especially when we have to use the adjective New Zealand that's right so the student said he prefers to call himself a kiwi
All right, so kiwi is a special kind of bird that could only be found in New Zealand and so this became a very popular
symbol for for New Zealand and now people from New Zealand call themselves kiwis so I could say I have many kiwi friends
That's right, okay kiwis so now if we go to the African continent we have Moroccan and
Toe-leads so Morocco is in North Africa and a person who comes from there is Moroccan
You can also say I like to eat Moroccan food which is very popular
But when we talk about the country to go
What do we call a person from that country to go leaves?
Okay, so it's to go that's the way you pronounce it because if you look at it, I would say to go
But it's not to go it's to go or as my French speaking friend would say to go
That's right. All right, so that's that's our first set of nationalities
Lessons into today's dialogue one more time and we'll be back in a moment to discuss the other nationalities
Hey, how's your first day of class? I'm a level two and I'm loving my class this semester
It's great being in a class of international students
Mine was okay, except that no one in my class speaks English
I guess it will force me to converse in Chinese more in class so at least I should improve a lot this semester
That's both fortunate and unfortunate. It's the United Nations in my class. We have people from all over the world
There are three Germans a poll a Scott two French
In the American a Brazilian a Chilean a New Zealander
Though he prefers to call himself a Kiwi
Who else do we have? Oh, we have a Moroccan a Tagalese a Pakistani
And two and don't eatans
That's quite the array of nationalities everyone in my classes from Asia except me
There were a few South Koreans several Japanese Malaysian ties in Napoleon
Filipino Kazakhstan and
One Russian well, I think you're pretty lucky actually you have the opportunity to learn so much about Asian culture
I guess so but I think it's going to be hard to relate to my classmates
Especially with the language barrier. I think I might change classes don't stay the course your spoken Chinese will be
Turnily grateful. I bet you it'll even surpass mine with all that practice. I highly doubt it
Your girlfriend is Chinese. Well, there is that. Yes
All right, we're back so now we have more nationalities prepared for you
So let's take a look at those now on language takeaway part two
Language takeaway
We're in Asia for this part of today's lesson so we're going to start with a country called Pakistan
What do we call the people from Pakistan we say they are Pakistani okay? So in Chicago for example
There are many Pakistanis mmm, okay, and moving on to Southeast Asia we have
Indonesians all right Indonesia is the country and people who come from there are Indonesian
Okay very good now if we go back to the north part of Asia we have South Koreans
So we have north and South Korea on our maps a person from North Korea is North Korean and a person from South Korea is South Korean
It's kind of like that same structure American Brazilian Korean very good and moving to the island of Japan
We have Japanese so this is an adjective we're talking about a Japanese person
He is Japanese or we can also talk about the food like sushi is Japanese food that's right
Okay moving back to Southeast Asia again we have Malaysia
So people from Malaysia are called Malaysian okay again with this pattern mmm Malaysian Korean
That's right and I think you say Malaysian food or you say Malay I heard some people say Malay
I've said Malaysian food generally, but melee I think is one of the languages and I think it's
Nethnic group as well so you can have melee people in Singapore for example
Okay, and actually we have Thai people and Singaporean so we have two countries
They're Thailand and Singapore so Thai is the adjective to describe things that come from Thailand
It's kind of unusual it doesn't fit that pattern that I mentioned
But it's a very important one to remember if you like to eat food from this country Thai food
Yeah excellent food and Singaporean food is also pretty good and people from Singapore are also called Singaporean
Here we've got a very tricky one. I've got the country the Philippines
What do you call a person from the Philippines? So the Philippines is actually spelled PHI like the Philippines, right?
But if somebody is from the Philippines we say Filipino with an F
All right, Filipino this is interesting especially for people who are native Spanish speakers because
The Philippines was a Spanish colony for a very long time and so you might hear someone refer to himself as a Filipino
He's a man or if she is a woman a Filipino
So this is very similar to the Spanish structure of having a gender on the end of the word that's right
And well now we move we're moving on to Kazakhstan and Russia
We have people that are from Kazakhstan and Russia and we say they are Kazakhstan
So this is very common in that part of the world
To end the adjective in an eye like Afghanistan afghani Pakistan, Pakistani
Kazakhstan Kazakhstan
Kazakhstan and so these are the stands the former USSR that's right
So this is a very important structure to remember but Russia is pretty easy. Yeah people from Russia
You say they are Russian or you have Russian food
Really Russian
So we have a lot of different nationalities there and obviously we didn't cover all of them like I think
I don't know maybe 200 nationalities
So why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit more about this really interesting topic
Hey how's your first day of class? I'm a level two and I'm loving my class this semester
It's great being in a class of international students
Mine was okay except that no one in my class speaks English
I guess it will force me to converse in Chinese more in class so at least I should improve a lot this semester
That's both fortunate and unfortunate
It's the United Nations in my class we have people from all over the world
There are three Germans a pole a Scott two French
In American a Brazilian a Chilean a New Zealander though he prefers to call himself a Kiwi
Who else do we have oh we have a Moroccan a Tagalese a Pakistani and two Indonesia's
That's quite the array of nationalities everyone in my classes from Asia except me
There are a few South Koreans several Japanese Malaysian ties in Paporian
Filipino Kazakhstan and one Russian well I think you're pretty lucky actually you have the opportunity to learn so much about Asian culture
I guess so but I think it's going to be hard to relate to my classmates
Especially with the language barrier. I think I might change classes don't stay the course your spoken Chinese will be eternally grateful
I bet you it'll even surpass mine with all that practice. I highly doubt it your girlfriend is Chinese
Well, there is that yes
All right we're back so I'm talking about nationalities. I think there's one that we didn't mention that's very very popular people from Ireland
Okay, so people from Ireland are called Irish Irish the Irish or Irishman
This is a similar structure to a lot of those countries in northern Europe like Sweden and Finland
That's right so somebody from Sweden would be called Swedish
Yes, or a Swedish is the noun so I love to eat Swedish food like salmon
But the similar the similar structure applies to Finland in Finland. They're very famous for their Finnish
Bread finish so that's the way that you say finish with double n right that's right. It's not like I finished my homework
It's like F i n n I s h finish finish and now what about people from Denmark?
They are Danish Danish and what about people from Norway?
They are Norwegian so that's one that does not fit the pattern and this is a very interesting one that also does
In fit the pattern at all people from Holland
Okay, so Holland as a country has two names we sometimes say Holland we sometimes say the Netherlands
But a person who comes from Holland is called Dutch
Is Dutch that's right so it doesn't have to do with neither
Holland you don't say a Holland or Netherlands you don't say Netherlands. It's Dutch
Dutch are you also you also read this on like cookie tins
You know boxes for cookies Dutch style cookies. That's right. All right, so that's a very important one when it comes to food
But we're very curious to hear about where you come from you should try some of the new vocabulary words that we have introduced here
Talk about your friends or your family, but also tell us if we didn't include your nationality
That's right all right, so we'll see you guys there English. Bye