Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have the beginning of a very long series on giving a presentation.
So this series is at the intermediate level right Marco.
That's right. It's part of our business series. We previously took a look at how to go upon an interview.
Now we're going to talk about presentations. So everything about a presentation, how to give a presentation,
language you can use in a presentation and a lot of other things like this.
That's right. So today we're going to talk about the very beginning of a presentation.
Let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Hi everyone. Can everyone hear me? Can you guys sit back here?
Everything?
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon. As most of you are aware,
2010 marks an important moment for alpha computers. We have bounced back from the recession
and now we are set to launch our new line of laptop and desktop computers.
I'm really pleased to welcome Michael Ford, the global marketing manager for alpha computers,
who has flown in from California to give all of you an overview of the marketing campaign,
and to answer any questions you may have. So please give a warm welcome to Mr Ford.
Thank you Jonathan. It really is a pleasure to be here today. It has been three years since
I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that operations here are obviously going from strength
the alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds in China and that is certainly down to the
hard work of all of you here. So congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation this afternoon and giving you an
idea of the topics that will be discussed. The presentation today is divided into five main parts.
First of all I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X4-20 line.
How the whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our existing
brand line. Secondly I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X4-20.
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals in this sector. Then I'd like to go on to outline
the campaign concept for the X4-20. Finally I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions
or points you may have for me.
All right we're back so as you can see it's the very beginning of a presentation we're kind of
starting to give people an idea of what we're going to talk about. So let's take a look at some
of the language Mr. Ford used on language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So the reason Mr. Ford is giving a presentation is because he wants to talk about their
company's new line of computers right and so he says that they're going to launch a new
line of desktop and laptop computers. That's right so they want to launch a new line of
laptop so this verb to launch means to bring out to the market. That's right so instead of the
word to start which you could use in many different ways like to start eating or to start swimming
in this case to launch means you're going to introduce a new product to the market like you said
Marco. That's right we are going to start selling to the market a new product. We're going to launch
a new line of laptop and desktop computers. For example this spring Steve Jobs launched the
iPad which is a new product. That's right so he launched the iPad and the iPhone 4.
They're always launching new things at Apple. That's right. All right so since they're launching
this new line of laptop and desktop computers Mr. Ford first wanted to give a brief overview of
the marketing campaign. Okay so first of all we're going to talk about how this product is being
marketed so you want to give a general picture or very simple picture of what's going to happen.
So at the beginning this will happen then this will happen at the end this will happen and that's
what we call an overview. That's right so it's a brief or general idea of what we're talking
about in an overview. Nothing too specific we just want to give you a general idea. That's right.
After that Mr. Ford starts talking and he he's talking about the presentation which has many
parts and he wants to talk about what each part will contain. So he says I'd like to briefly touch on
the background of the new X429 so this verb to touch on. That's what it means. Okay so when he says
he wants to touch on the background of this new computer he's basically saying I want to talk about.
All right so this is potentially very confusing because we know the word to touch means to put your hand
on something but to touch on this is a phrasal verb this means to talk about or to address.
That's right so for example a teacher at a university will touch on many topics during his lecture.
That's right or I'd like to touch on where we're going to dinner tonight because I'm very hungry.
Okay so basically it's a nice way of saying I want to talk about this. That's right.
That's right. Okay and then apart from touching on the background of the new computer he said he
also wants to talk about projected sales for this new computer. Okay so projected sales this phrase
includes two words sales means how much of something you sell obviously but projected means what you
expect to sell so the projected sales have not happened yet they will happen in the future and
so they're basically my guess about sales. That's right so basically we are giving an estimate of
what we think we will sell those are projected sales we think we will sell a thousand computers those are
our projected sales. Right and after that we have one more key word this word comes to the very
end of the speech Mr. Ford says we will then go on to discuss our key rivals now who is a rival
Marco? Okay so a rival is basically your competitor or maybe kind of your enemy.
All right so computers who is Apple's rival? Maybe HP or IBM or Dell. Very good so a rival is
someone you compete with. That's right so he's going to talk about his key rivals so basically
the word key is your most important rivals. All right so for example who is one of Batman's key
rivals because we have rivals not just in business but also in life. That's right so for example I think
maybe Batman's key rival might be the Joker or the Penguin. All right so let's take another listen to
today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment with some very important phrases.
Hi everyone can everyone hear me? Can you guys sit back here everything?
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon. As most of you are aware
2010 marks an important moment for alpha computers. We have bounced back from the recession and now
we are set to launch our new line of laptop and desktop computers. I'm really pleased to welcome
Michael Ford the global marketing manager for alpha computers who has flown in from California to give
all of you an overview of the marketing campaign and to answer any questions you may have. So please give
a warm welcome to Mr Ford. Thank you Jonathan. It really is a pleasure to be here today.
It has been three years since I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that operations here are
obviously going from strength to strength. The alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds
in China and that is certainly down to the hard work of all of you here so congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation this afternoon and giving
you an idea of the topics that will be discussed. The presentation today is divided into five main parts.
First of all I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X4-20 line.
How the whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our existing brand line.
Secondly I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X4-20. We will then go on to discuss
our key rivals in this sector. Then I'd like to go on to outline the campaign concept for the X4-20.
Finally I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions or points you may have for me.
All right so we prepared three phrases for you. Let's take a look at those now on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first phrase is really important because it's about the part of the
speech that happens before the speech begins. Usually you have a person who's going to talk about
something but you also have someone who introduces that person. That's right. This is John.
He's going to talk about computers. He's very smart. Listen to everything he says. So we usually hear
the phrase, let's give a warm welcome to. Yes this is a very nice way of presenting someone.
So obviously this person is talking to a group of people and he's introducing Mr. Ford. So he says,
let's give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford. So that's saying let's clap. Let's let's say hello to him.
That's right. So like you said this is an invitation to clap. You have to clap when you hear this.
Warm welcome means. Let's be nice to him. Let's all smile and encourage him. You know,
you think about it. Someone who's going to give a speech is probably nervous. So this helps them
feel comfortable. That's right. So it's a very nice way if you're maybe presenting someone who's
going to talk. You can say let's give a warm welcome to whoever you're presenting. Okay.
Now when Mr. Ford was talking he mentioned this very interesting phrase about operations. He said,
it's clear to me that operations here are obviously going from strength to strength.
Okay. So that means things are going well. You do one thing. You do it well. You move on to another thing.
You do that well as well. Okay. So that's what it means from strength to strength. So we're saying
that things are going from good to better. That's right. And getting better. Okay. And what about our
last phrase? Our last phrase is kind of similar to the last one. The alpha brand continues to grow
in leaps and bounds. All right. So you can you can have a company that grows. It grows a little.
You can have a company that grows quite a bit. Then you have a company that grows in leaps and
bounds. That means a lot. Okay. So to leap is to jump, right? That's right. And so this is what
we're saying. We're just jumping higher and higher. We're getting bigger and bigger or better and better.
That's right. So this is an exaggeration. It's like saying that it's not going quickly. It's going
to be the speed of light. It's just so fast. All of a sudden, just really growing. Okay. A lot of
interesting phrases there. A lot of key vocab. I think we can listen to this dialogue again. And what we
back in a bit. Hi everyone. Can everyone hear me? Can you guys sit back here? Everything?
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon. As most of you are aware,
2010 marks an important moment for alpha computers. We have bounced back from the recession
and now we are set to launch our new line of laptop and desktop computers. I'm really pleased
to welcome Michael Ford, the global marketing manager for alpha computers, who has flown in from
California to give all of you an overview of the marketing campaign and to answer any questions you
may have. So please give a warm welcome to Mr Ford. Thank you Jonathan. It really is a pleasure
to be here today. It has been three years since I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that
operations here are obviously going from strength to strength. The alpha brand continues to grow
in leaps and bounds in China and that is certainly down to the hard work of all of you here.
So congratulations to all of you. I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation
this afternoon and giving you an idea of the topics that we'll be discussed. The presentation
today is divided into five main parts. First of all I'd like to briefly touch on the background
of the new X4-20 line. How the whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our
existing brand line. Secondly I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X4-20.
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals in this sector. Then I'd like to go on to outline
the campaign concept for the X4-20. Finally I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions or
points you may have for me. All right so as we mentioned this is the first part of a
10-part series all about public speaking, giving a presentation. We're going to talk about
many aspects of a presentation like charts and graphs and using power points all these really
modern ways of giving a presentation. That's right and we're going to try and talk to you about
some of the places and presentations that English learners tend to struggle with. You know it sits
sometimes very hard to know what to say especially like in today's lesson. How do you introduce
someone in a presentation? It's not very common to learn how to say that. So we hope that through
these podcasts you'll be able to learn some really important phrases and become more comfortable
while you're giving presentations in English. That's right and of course if you have any questions
about these lessons or any other lessons you can always find us at EnglishPod.com or you can
send us also your suggestions about any lesson topics you may have. That's right so we hope to hear
from you please let us know what you're thinking and until next time everyone. Bye!