Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson about things that you buy for your kitchen.
That's right today. We are going to buy a lot of machines and devices for our kitchen.
So let's jump into the dialogue. Let's see what we are buying and we'll be back in a bit.
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished getting all the kitchen appliances that we need.
What are you getting?
Well, the first thing on my list is a new blender. I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker.
Don't forget to also get a new mixer. I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it.
Yeah, I know. I also decided to throw away the old toaster and get a new one.
I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to make some nice steamed fish or veggies.
I'm actually thinking of completely refurneishing the kitchen and getting a new stove of in dishwasher and trash compactor.
That's a good idea. The kitchen will look amazing.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at some of those strange machines on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay. So the kinds of machines you buy for your kitchen are called kitchen appliances.
Okay. So the word appliance in appliance is basically a machine or device that is used for the home.
That's right. So there are many different kinds of appliances.
You can usually plug these in. They usually need electricity to work.
But the ones we're talking about today are special. Therefore the kitchen.
So that's why we call them kitchen appliances.
That's right. Okay. Very good.
So the kitchen appliances that we are looking at or we're trying to buy is, well, the first one we have is a blender.
A blender. So a blender is a kitchen appliance that you use normally to make drinks.
So this is a glass jar that is that's usually on on the top of a little machine.
And when you put in, for example, some ice and some tea and some lemonade and you can mix it up.
And you have this special mixed drink. So it's called a blender.
That's right. So as you mentioned, it's usually made.
It's usually used to make some sort of juice or drink.
But we also are getting a juicer, which is specifically to make juices.
Now what is the difference between the blender and a juicer?
Well, a blender is as a machine that turns the things inside it around.
So it mixes them together.
But a juicer is different because a juicer will actually take the juice from the fruit.
So for example, if I have an orange and I cut the orange and half, I put that half on the juicer and it turns around so that the juice will come down.
That's right.
Because otherwise I have to use my hands to squeeze it and that takes time.
So this is an electronic appliance that helps me get the juice from my fruits.
That's right.
Okay. So we have a juicer to make juice.
A blender to make different drinks.
And now to make coffee, we have a very simple machine, a coffee maker.
Okay. So coffee maker is just a simple machine that you put water and coffee into and it will make the coffee for you.
Usually it's called a drip coffee maker because the coffee drip drip drip drip down.
But there are many different kinds of coffee makers.
Okay.
Now this next appliance can be a little bit confusing because now this one is called a mixer.
So what is the difference between a blender, a juicer and now we have a mixer?
Well, there are different kinds of mixers actually.
But usually the kind of mixer that we're referring to that we're talking about is one that is electronic.
And it looks like it has these two funny spoons on the end.
And when you turn the mixer on, you put it into a bowl and you mix the things in the bowl.
So for example, if I want to make pancakes, I put some flour and some water and some eggs into a bowl.
And I can start with my hand with my spoon but it's very tiring.
So it's a mixer that's electronic to turn those ingredients around on its own.
That's right. So it's quicker and obviously you don't get as tired.
Very good. So I think we should take a break. Let's go back to our dialogue.
Let's check out some more appliances and we'll be back to talk about the rest of them.
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished
getting all the kitchen appliances that we need.
What are you getting?
Well, the first thing on my list is a new blender.
I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker.
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it.
Yeah, I know. I also decided to throw away the old toaster and get a new one.
I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to make some nice steamed fish or veggies.
I'm actually thinking of completely refurneishing the kitchen and getting a new stove of
an dishwasher and trash compactor.
That's a good idea. The kitchen will look amazing.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at more kitchen appliances on language
takeaway part two.
Language takeaway.
Well, this first item, this first appliance is something that I know a lot of people all
over the world are familiar with. It's called a rice cooker.
Mm-hmm. Now a rice cooker as the name says, it is used to cook rice, but it doesn't
in a very simple and automatic way.
That's right. So you put the rice in the water and the rice cooker and you turn it on to
what 20 minutes and then later 20 minutes later it's already cooked.
It's done. Done. Easy.
Right. It's actually very convenient and very simple to make.
And now along with a rice cooker, sometimes we also get a steamer.
Okay. So a steamer is something that we normally use with vegetables or in Asia a lot of times we use
it with dumplings, little foods that are stuffed.
And so a steamer is something that you use to cook a food, but with the steam from hot water.
That's right. You don't put the food in the water. You don't fry the food, but you use the steam
that hot air to cook the food inside. That's right. So it's actually considered to be
some of the one of the healthiest ways of cooking food because it's not as oily.
Okay. So now an interesting appliance that is actually not very popular in any other place except
anything North America is a trash compactor.
Okay. So trash means garbage. It's the things that you want to throw away that you won't use anymore.
And the compactor is something that actually takes the trash and it makes it very small.
Okay. Compact means small. And so a trash compactor is like a special garbage bin.
You put your garbage in it and you close it and you say compact and then it makes loud noise.
Boom. That's right. And then when you pull it out you open it up.
The trash is very very small. Very small. So it's very easy to throw away.
Uh-huh. So as we said, I've never actually seen this appliance in any other country except the United
States in Canada. I don't think I have either, but it's pretty popular in American homes because it
helps save space and it's very easy to throw things away that way.
Yeah, that's right. I guess you can make a little bundle of trash and it's much easier than throwing
a big bag of trash away. Exactly. Okay. And well, we're doing all this because we are kind of
refurnishing the kitchen. We are giving it new furniture. That's right. So we want to change the
appearance and to do this we will refurnish. So to furnish something means to put furniture in it
to make it look nice. To refurnish means to change the furniture because we already have some,
we don't like it. That's right. And so you can do this with your whole house. That's right. So maybe you
throw away the old couch and the table and the kitchen cabinet and you put a new one so you are refurnishing
your home, refurnishing the kitchen. That's right. Two refurnish. Okay. So a lot of great
vocab here. I think this is very useful for the kitchen, especially if sometimes you don't really know
what appliance you need to buy or or what the instructions of a recipe say. So why don't we
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
I have been looking at this online catalog for over an hour and I still haven't finished
getting all the kitchen appliances that we need. What are you getting? Well, the first thing on my
list is a new blender. I decided to also get a juicer and a new coffee maker. Don't forget to
also get a new mixer. I lent the old one to my brother and he broke it. Yeah, I know. I also decided
to throw away the old toaster and get a new one. I am also getting a rice cooker and a steamer to
make some nice steamed fish or veggies. I'm actually thinking of completely refurnishing the kitchen
and getting a new stove oven dishwasher and trash compactor. That's a good idea. The kitchen will look
amazing. All right, we're back now. Another appliance that I think is also not very popular in
other countries apart from the trash compactor we saw in the dialogue a dishwasher. A dishwasher,
that's right. So this is something that you find in many American homes. So why do you think
trash compactors and dishwashers are not so popular in other places? I'm not sure. It's possible
it's because they're not very energy efficient. I'm not really sure. I never had a trash compactor
in my home in America, but we always had a dishwasher and this was very, very nice to have,
because you don't have to wash the dishes by yourself. You put them in the machine and the machine
washes. So but you have to do some work before you put the dishes in dishwasher. You have to
put them in the sink and in water for a while and then you take them out and then you put in the
dishwasher, right? Now what what we usually did is if there was food on a plate we take the food and
we put it in the trash and if it's you know sometimes you leave the plate for like a day or two
and it's very hard. Then you have to put some water on it because otherwise it will be hard and
you'll never it will never come off. But if it's recently used you put all the plates all of the
cups all of the knives and forks into the dishwasher and it uses hot water and some soap and it will
wash those dishes in about 30 minutes. So how well does it wash? It washes very very well. Some
work better than others but of course if you if you have food that's two days old on a plate then
it won't wash your head. Right. I think it also has to do with the type of instruments that people
use around the world to cook. For example big pots. I don't think you can put pots in the dishwasher,
right? No you can't. You could not put a wok in the dishwasher. Uh-huh. But I think it also has to
do with the fact that dishwashers are very big and if you have a small apartment or like me a very
small kitchen it's impossible to make room for a dishwasher. Yeah but it seems like a very convenient
thing and of course there's so many other kitchen appliances that uh well if we started to mention
all of them we would run out of time. But if you have any questions or any comments about this lesson
or you have maybe some other kitchen appliances you can come to our website EnglishPod.com
and leave those there. We hope to see you at EnglishPod and until next time. All right. Bye.