Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right today we're going to take a look at our mobile phones but not the physical phone.
Now we're going to talk about services that you can get for your mobile phone.
All right so in America and many other places you don't buy that little card with money on it.
You actually have to pay every month for a service.
So we're going to learn about this today. Let's check out our dialogue.
Tell ComoBio how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
Certainly sir. We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
call waiting and also three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great. Are there any other fees?
Not at all. No hidden fees are surcharges. It is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect.
I also wanted to know if there's any call forwarding service.
I am usually out of town and would like my call to be forwarded to a local number.
Yes of course. We can activate all of these services in about an hour.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some of these services on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So Marko the first word that I want to talk about today is this verb to activate.
That's right we have a verb here to activate.
And this means to make something start to work to make something begin.
That's right so to turn on but you don't say hey can you activate the light?
Right right. You wouldn't say that you say can you turn on the light?
But to activate means to start a service.
That's right. So this is what we want today.
We want to activate some services and the first one that we asked for is voicemail service.
Now let's think about the words that make up this one word voicemail.
Voicemail so it's like a mailbox for your phone.
That's right where you leave messages obviously not text messages but you leave voice messages.
That's right so you know I'm sorry I cannot answer the phone right now.
Please leave a message after the beep.
That's my voicemail message.
That's right so it's actually a very useful thing.
We'll talk about that a little bit later.
But let's take a look at our next service.
We also want to get call waiting.
All right so this is a very interesting service.
I don't know if they have this in other parts of the world but in America if I'm talking
on the phone to you Marco, we're having a nice conversation but then my mom calls.
When I'm talking I hear beep beep beep.
I hear some sounds and that means someone else is trying to call you.
That's right.
All right so you can't hear this but I can hear this and that means if I want to
talk to my mom I'll say hey Marco listen someone else is calling can I call you tomorrow.
That's right so actually call waiting is a very useful service because the person that's calling
you will never get a busy signal right you'll always seem available but the good thing is that you can
switch between calls.
So I could say hey Marco listen I think that's my mom can you hold can you wait?
I will be right back and then I push a button and then I can talk to my mom and then my mom says
okay I'll talk to you later I push a button and then Mark will be there.
That's right that's right.
Very useful service as well.
Now let's take a look at our next service that we are also getting as part of this package.
We are getting three way calling.
So from the name of this we can think of three people talking.
All right so maybe Marco you want to talk to my mom too.
That's right.
So we can talk and then we add another person so you can call a third phone number one two three
me you and someone else and the three of us can talk at the same time.
That's right so it's kind of a way of having a small conference between three people.
That's right.
And so this is this is what you can do with three way calling.
You can call two people simultaneously and talk to them at the same time.
So a lot of great services here I think we've learned a couple of different things.
Why don't we review it and listen to the dialogue again.
Tell Como Bial how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
Certainly sir.
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
call waiting and also three way calling.
Sure that sounds great.
Are there any other fees?
Not at all.
No hidden fees are surcharges.
It is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect.
I also wanted to note there's any call forwarding service.
I am usually out of town and would like my call to be forwarded to a local number.
Yes of course we can activate all these services in about an hour.
All right we're back so now let's keep on going here towards the last half of our dialogue.
Let's take a look at some more words on language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway.
So this first phrase in language takeaway part two is hidden fees.
Hidden fees.
What are the?
The operator guarantees that there are no hidden fees.
So this is usually what we call the fine print.
The small fees that we don't really know about.
So they say oh it costs $3 a month.
But you have small little hidden fees like if you're late on a payment they'll charge you an extra
dollar or if you use the service too much they'll charge you another extra dollar.
Right so a fee is something that you pay.
And something that is hidden means you cannot see it.
And so like you're saying with this example there are many many conditions, many many different
things rules that we have to follow and if we don't follow those rules exactly then maybe this
company that provides the phone service will ask us for more and more money.
That's right and actually it has to do a lot with our next word where she said that there are also
no surcharges.
Okay so a surcharge is an extra amounts of money that you have to pay.
So we say that this service has no hidden fees or surcharge.
So that means that we don't have to pay anything additional to what we are paying.
For example some companies will say okay pay us $10 and you get your new cell phone
phone plan.
Mm-hmm.
But to activate your service is another $5.
So the total price is $15 and that's a surcharge that's an extra fee that you have
to pay.
That's right.
Okay and continuing on the topic of money she says it is a flat monthly rate, a flat monthly rate.
Well monthly is an adverb that tells us how often we pay.
We pay one time every month but this term flat rate is very very important and it happened.
We use this term a lot when we're talking about paying fees.
Mm-hmm.
So a flat rate means it does not change when you for example talk more on the phone.
That's right.
So you pay the same amount every month.
A clear example is probably your internet service provider.
You pay $20 a month and that's a flat rate.
If you use the internet 24 hours a day nothing happens.
You don't pay more.
If you use it less you still pay the same amount of money.
So what if I pay $10 normally?
But this month I use the internet a lot and now I have to pay $15.
Is that a flat rate?
No, no that's not a flat rate.
Okay that's a chain that that changes with my use.
That's right.
Okay.
And now let's take a look at one last service that this man was also
interested in getting and he says that he wants to get a call forwarding service.
He wants to forward his calls to a local number.
Okay so to forward something means to pass it along.
So call forwarding means that if I'm not available for example
I'm not at home and someone calls my home.
There's no one there to talk to the person that's calling.
Then maybe I could have a call forwarding service that will make the call go to my
cellular phone.
All right so the call forwarding means that the call will travel to another phone.
That's right that's right.
So as you said this is what call forwarding is and the word to forward as you said to pass
along maybe many of you have done it in your emails when you get maybe a nice message.
You forward it to more of your friends and this is the the exact same definition.
Exactly.
So you have one message and you pass it on to someone else.
And so in call forwarding you normally have this service if you're often on business trips or
traveling your out of town.
That's right.
It's very very helpful for people who are not in one place all the time.
That's right so why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
Tell Como why how can I help you?
Yes I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
Certainly sir.
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services,
call waiting and also three-way calling.
Sure that sounds great.
Are there any other fees?
Not at all.
No hidden fees are surcharges.
It is a flat monthly rate.
Perfect.
I also wanted to note there's any call forwarding service.
I am usually out of town and would like my call to be forwarded to a local number.
Yes of course.
We can activate all these services in about an hour.
So talking about all these services it's very interesting because many of these services
are not really available everywhere in the world.
Like for example voicemail.
That's right so in China no one really has voicemail.
It's very strange for an American because you think well if I'm not home I want to know why this
person called.
But oftentimes you just have to call back and find out.
That's right and actually I really think that
voicemail service is a very good thing especially if you need to leave a message for someone.
You know hey we're at the restaurant called me back when you have a chance.
But also a call waiting I really really hate to call someone and have the busy you know the busy
tone.
Yeah.
And then you know that they're on the telephone but you don't know when they will stop talking
on this really annoys me too especially when I call for delivery food from a restaurant.
It's like please answer your phone.
Maybe someone's ordering a lot of food.
That's right.
So actually these services are very common in the United States and I'm sure
they're even more services now I know that you can have a telephone number for example in
another country but it'll ring in the United States.
Yeah that's right or you can connect your computer and your messaging service and all these
things to your phone so it's pretty pretty technologically advanced but I'm very curious to know
you guys are listeners what kind of services for your cell phone or for your landline do you have
do you have call forwarding or voicemail.
Let us know our website is englishpod.com.
Alright we'll see everyone there. Bye.