Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Katherine and we've got a very sad dialogue today actually Marco.
That's right today. We have a very sad but interesting dialogue of something that happens all the time.
Maybe you have a girlfriend, maybe you had a boyfriend and you break up.
That means you are no longer boyfriend and girlfriend.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Hello. Hey do you want to go out tonight? No, I think I'll pass.
Mark broke up with me. I feel awful. What? What happened? Just last week you were talking about going on vacation together.
I don't know what I did wrong. He said he needed some space to figure things out.
He said I didn't do anything wrong but I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche. Mark's not worth your time Lydia. You deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch but I had hoped we could work it out next weekend when we both had some time off.
I think he found someone else. I had been getting suspicious because he had been spending a lot of time with a coworker.
Whatever. He's a jerk. Forget about him. There are many more fish in the sea.
Talk about being cliche Maggie. But you're right. There's no use for me to soak around.
Let's go out tonight.
All right we're back. So obviously this girl Lydia is very torn. She's very sad because her boyfriend broke up with her.
That's right. She's crying the whole time. That's going on. That's right. So but she did mention
her and her friend mentioned some interesting things. Why don't we take a look at some of the words they
used on language takeaway? Language takeaway.
So first of all her friends says hey do you want to go out tonight and what is Lydia say?
She says no I think I'll pass. All right I think I'll pass. I will pass. So what is this
verb mean to pass? So that means she is politely rejecting the offer or the invitation.
So no thanks. No thanks. That's basically what it means. I won't go. So hey Marco you want to go see
a movie in a couple hours? I think I'll pass. I got homework to do. All right so Marco will not
come. That means to decline an invitation. That's right. So that's what it means to pass.
Now as they continue to talk they mentioned some of the problems with their boyfriend but
Maggie said that's so cliche. So the boyfriend said something and Maggie thinks that what he said
was very very cliche. So what is something that is cliche? cliche means something that is said or
done very often. It's almost like we would expect it. So like for example what's a cliche
phrase or a cliche action? Well in the dialogue they were talking about ways of breaking up with people
so for example it's not you it's me. Let's break up. So that's a cliche because it's a sentence
it's a phrase everyone always says. It's not very maybe not very honest or like a movie cliche
would be you know a couple they're getting married but their parents the parents of the bride
they're divorced the hate each other but then at the wedding they get back together they're
going to get married again that's a cliche story. That's right because you've heard it before.
Right all the time it's very common. So something's very common something that you would expect to
that's almost that's a cliche and a cliche calling something a cliche is not a good thing it's usually
a bad thing. That's right. Okay so Maggie goes on to say that you know this guy Mark her
ex boyfriend he's not really worth it she says you deserve so much better. Okay so to deserve
is a verb and it means that you should receive something or you should expect something so
almost like you know in this case you deserve better you have earned something better your good
person you should receive you know you should have a good boyfriend. That's right so when when she
says you deserve so much better she's talking about deserving a better guy a better man.
Or for example so Marko you work so hard at school you're always doing your homework you
really deserve good grades. You should receive good grades. Very good. Now when Lydia said yeah you know
what I just thought we were having some problems and we had hit a rough patch so she's talking about
a rough patch what is that? A rough patch is actually something we talk about a lot in spoken English
it's a way to describe a period of time so maybe a week or a month when things are difficult you
know when maybe you argue with your boyfriend or girlfriend or when you're sad a lot or when
you're confused and so a period of time when you're angry or sad with your boyfriend or girlfriend that's
a rough patch. So maybe we can apply a rough patch to another situation like at work maybe you're
going through a rough patch at work. That means I'm always busy I'm always tired I don't feel
happy with my job I'm going through a rough patch. So it's usually a temporary period of time where
things are going bad. It could be a week it could be a month it could be a year but it's a it's a
fixed amount of time it's not forever it's just a period. Okay very good and Lydia went on to say that
you know she thought that maybe he was going out with someone else and she was suspicious because
he was spending a lot of time with some other girl. Okay so to be suspicious is to think that
something is happening but you don't know so for example Marco I think you've been taking the milk
from the kitchen you are always drinking coffee and you always take milk in your coffee and there's
no more milk so I think it was you. I'm being suspicious I'm thinking that maybe you did something
bad or wrong. I'm guilty. So maybe you're suspicious that someone is stealing the milk or maybe
you suspect or you're suspicious that your next door neighbor is maybe a car thief. Right so
you're very suspicious that means you're always thinking that this person or someone else
is doing something bad. That's right okay so a lot of words they're talking about relationships
talking about cliches why don't we go back let's listen to the dialogue again and we're back
in a bit with the fluency builder.
Hello hey do you want to go out tonight? No I think I'll pass. Mark broke up with me. I feel awful.
What what happened? Just last week you were talking about going on vacation together.
I don't know what I did wrong. He said he needed some space to figure things out. He said
I didn't do anything wrong that I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche. Mark's not worth your time Lydia you deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch but I had hoped we could work it out next weekend when we both
had some time off. I think he found someone else. I had been getting suspicious because he had been
spending a lot of time with a coworker. Whatever he's a jerk forget about him there are many more
fish in the sea. Talk about being cliche Maggie but you're right there's no use for me to
soak around. Let's go out tonight.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some of those phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right so Marco these are cliche phrases that we hear in English. When people
are breaking up okay so there's some breaking up phrases but there's also phrases that you might
hear from your friend after you have a breakup okay the first phrase we're gonna look at I think
is to need space so he said he needed some space. Right and that's a cliche phrase as we said but
it means that maybe her her ex boyfriend or Mark needs more space needs more time to be on his own
or needs more time to do his own things. That's right so when you're in a relationship you have a
boyfriend or girlfriend you're always together. I need some space means I want to be alone.
I don't want to be with my boyfriend or girlfriend. Sometimes this is just a small period,
sometimes it's forever. It depends. That's right so when somebody says that they need space it means
they need a little bit of more time to be on their own or to be alone as you said and also he
had also given her another cliche phrase. Mark said that she is not the one for him.
Okay so the emphasis here is the one. The one. She's not the one for him so in English we often talk
about the one and this means the person that you will marry. The love of your life. Your
significant other you're other half. That's right and so you hope that you will marry the one.
But her boyfriend realized he said listen I like you but you're not the one. You're not the person
that I will marry so this is a phrase you often hear and break up. So if you're single maybe you
don't have a boyfriend or you're not married you might say that you haven't found the one.
Or yeah you have a lot of different boyfriends but you still haven't found the one. That means the
one you will marry. That's right. Okay very good and now towards the end of the dialogue Maggie
also gives her some advice and said you know what? Forget about him there are many more fish in the
sea. Okay so this is a phrase that we often say when we're trying to make somebody feel better.
So the person is sad and we want to make them happy and so there are many more fish in the sea
means that there are other men in the world. Okay you're sad you broke up I understand but there
are so many other men you could date. So she's trying to say hey listen look at this world. There's
so many different options. That's right so it's the it's the similarity of how in the sea you
have so many fish in the world you have so many men so don't worry about it. And you can say this
about women too. So for example if I'm talking to my male friend or my brother and my brother just
broke up with his girlfriend I can say hey listen there are many more fish in the sea.
Many other women. So don't worry about it. Don't worry about it you'll be okay.
And Lydia says you know what I think you're right and there's really no use for me to
soak around so what is she mean to soak around? To soak now this is something that is very
visual for me I see somebody soaking their head is low they're sad someone who is soaking
often wears their sweatpants or their pajamas they don't they don't make themselves look good
to soak around means to be in your house to be sad to watch TV and eat ice cream so stop
soaking don't look sad be happy. So to soak is to act sad and to you know be very down.
So it's kind of like you're very it's kind of a combination of being lazy but and also sad at the
same time because something bad happened to you. Exactly and so we often say that in English
teenagers like to soak you know oh I'm so angry at my parents and your parents will say hey stop
soaking go study that's right very good okay so a lot of great phrases here I think we can go back
let's listen to this dialogue one last time
hello hey do you want to go out tonight? No I think go past
Mark broke up with me I feel awful. What what happened just last week you were talking about
going on vacation together. I don't know what I did wrong he said he needed some space to figure
things out he said I didn't do anything wrong that I'm a great person just not the one for him.
That's so cliche Mark's not worth your time Lydia you deserve so much better.
I know we had hit a rough patch but I had hoped we could work it out next weekend when we both had some time off
I think he found someone else I had been getting suspicious because he had been spending a lot of time with a
coworker whatever he's a jerk forget about him there are many more fish in the sea
talk about being cliche Maggie but you're right there's no use for me to soak around
let's go out tonight. All right so talking about breakups these cliche lines and
and we'll Maggie's obviously upset what other cliche lines or breakup phrases have you heard
apart from it's not you it's me you're just not the one I need some space I need some space
I think give you more like a friend you know because there's like a boyfriend or girlfriend but
then there's a friend and so listen I like you but I think give you more like a friend.
Yeah I think that's a typical one especially if you're asking someone out on a date they might say that you know
oh I really like you but I see you more as a friend than anything else. So there's another one that's very
popular sometimes you hear people say I'm just not ready for a relationship and that's also a cliche
line or I'm not ready to commit. I'm not ready to commit yeah and it's interesting because I think
breaking up is one of the hardest things that people can do and I think maybe this is why
you just use one of these phrases that are so popular in common because I guess it's kind of a
a good way to explain and very soft terms what you want to say and to break up with someone.
That's right and I think that sometimes people are afraid to make the other person sad and so they say
these things that are very you know general like it's not you it's me. Right but sometimes this
makes the other person even more sad because they don't understand why that they're breaking up so
what about breaking up over the telephone or breaking up with the letter? Oh, generally at least in
America we say that breaking up over email or letter or phone is not a good way to end a relationship.
It's very cold. It's very cold so the other person would be very angry if if that happened.
That's right you just want to see the person and say listen let's have a conversation let's talk
about this face to face. Okay so this is actually very interesting because as we say maybe
in other countries or in other cultures is not really a negative thing to break up over the phone
or maybe send an email saying you know what I don't want to see you anymore. Right so I'd be very
curious to hear about you guys and your cultures and what happens when people break up where you live.
So let us know our website is englishpod.com we hope to see you there and of course we hope that you
haven't had any very bad big up experiences but if you're comfortable sharing we'd like to hear
about your culture and your background. All right so we'll see you guys there. Bye.