Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you. This is about fixing things.
That's right. So sometimes in our office or in our house,
some small things may break like maybe the door or the air conditioning. So in this case,
we need to call a special guy to come and fix it. So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be
back at a moment to talk about who this guy is.
The air conditioning is not working. We need to call a heavy man before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that. I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom toilet
that keeps clogging up. That would be convenient. They might as well ask him to fix the electrical
wiring. The circuit breakers keep going out all the time. It's really annoying.
Yeah, you're right. This office is falling apart. Frank told me the other day that the
gutters outside were clogged and that's why the parking lot was flooded. I know. I was in
ankle deep water trying to get to my car that day. The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those keywords and phrases on language
takeaway. Language takeaway. Our first word today is the name of this job. The person is called
a handyman. Okay, so that's a profession. You are a handyman. Now what exactly does a handyman do?
Well, a handyman fixes things. He is usually a generalist. You know, he fixes things all over the
house, not just the bathroom or the kitchen. So he can he can just fix things that are a little
bit broken. But if for example, your car is, it needs a new radiator or it needs a new
important part. You maybe would take the car to someone who is more
experienced with cars. But in the case of a handyman, if anything's broken, he can generally fix it.
Okay, so as Katherine explained basically a handyman just does any type or many types of general work
of things that may be broken around the house or the office. And a couple of examples of these
in today's dialogue didn't really what was that first one kind of gross. Yeah, well he had to fix the
air conditioning, but then he also had to fix the bathroom toilet because it kept clogging up.
Okay, so a toilet gets clogged up to clog up. What does this mean? So it means that something is
blocking the way of, you know, the water being able to to go out. So the water doesn't go down.
Right. And sometimes if the toilet is really clogged, then someone tries to flush the toilet
again, the water comes onto the floor and it's very dirty and very gross. That's right. So
actually maybe sometimes in the kitchen pieces of food may fall into the sink and it may clog up
the sink. Okay, so to clog up means to block or to to get in the way of. That's right.
And apart from the toilets being clogged up, he also may have to take a look at the circuit
breakers. All right, so this is not about water or about plumbing. Circuit breakers have to do with
electricity and in this case that box in your apartment or near your apartment that controls the
different circuits. So sometimes if the lights go out, you know that you have to check the circuit
breaker and make sure that the circuits are all working properly. That's right. So the circuit
breakers are kind of like a protection from too much electricity and that's why they go out.
And now for our final word on language takeaway, something that also got to clogged up at their
office, we're talking about the gutters. All right, so many people's houses have gutters or
sometimes an office building will have gutters. These are trays on the roof of a house or a building
that will catch the water when it rains because you know, sometimes rainwater can be very,
very heavy and it's dangerous on your house on the roof of your house because it can hurt the roof.
But if it comes into this gutter into this little tray, then it will come down and fall in the ground.
So these are a way to protect your roof. But these often get clogged up with leaves and with
garbage. That's right. So they're like small little ways or little roads if you want to call them.
Where the water can go and escape and go into the specific place. We have them on the sides of roads as
well many times. So gutters that you find on the ground, sometimes you find them on the roof of a
house, but those are a little bit different. The gutters on the ground are basically pathways for water
to come down because if there's no gutter, then all of the water is on the road and it can flood
very quickly. That's right. And so this is a way for the water and even the garbage to go on the
side of the road and not be not being the way of the cars. That's right, you see them on highways and
roads very often because you don't want the road filled with water. So these gutters are a small path
where all the water will fall into it and escape safely from the highway. That's right. All right.
So that's all the time we have for language takeaway. Why don't we go back have another listen to
the dialogue and we'll be back soon with fluency builder.
The air conditioning is not working. We need to call a head-in-man before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that. I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom
toilet that keeps clogging up. That would be convenient. They made as well as come to fix the electrical
wiring. The circuit breakers keep going out all the time. It's really annoying. Yeah, you're right.
This office is falling apart. Frank told me the other day that the gutters outside were clogged
and that's why the parking lot was flooded. I know. I was in ankle deep water trying to get to my
car that day. The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
Now let's take a look at three key phrases on fluency builder. Fluency builder.
Well, this first phrase is a phrase that I like to use and I do use it very often.
We heard that Dan is on top of that. All right. So we need to call a handyman in here and he says,
no, Dan is on top of that. So to be on top of something, what does it mean?
Well, when she says, Dan is on top of that, she's basically saying, Dan is taking care of this
or Dan is already calling the handyman to come and fix it. So you are aware of the problem
and you're trying to solve it. Okay, so don't worry. You don't have to call the handyman.
Dan is on top of that. Dan will call him. Right. So to be on top of something is to make sure
that something is done. So you could say, you know, Marco, I really, I hope you stay on top of that
project because it's very important. Right. Or don't worry. The report will be finished on time.
I am on top of that. Great. All right. Now moving on to our next phrase, they were talking
about all the problems that this office has and the person said, well, they might as well
ask the handyman to also fix the electrical wiring. Okay. So this phrase might as well
is kind of hard to understand. I think sometimes, basically what the speaker is saying is that
while he is doing this, he can also do something else. Okay. So he's here. He can fix many things.
He might as well also fix electrical wiring. Right. So taking advantage of the fact that you are
already doing something or you are already here, you can start doing something else as well.
Or maybe we could say this in a different context to like, you know, we're going to order a
pizza for lunch. You know, what, Marco, might as well order two because there are so many people here.
Right. So taking advantage of the fact that we are ordering pizza, we might as well get more
for everyone. Okay. And for our last phrase, when they mentioned all the work that has to be done,
they said the handyman definitely has his work cut out for him. Okay. So if someone has his work
cut out for him, it means that he has a lot of work to do. That's right. You can also say this
to someone that you're talking to. So Marco, Marco is writing a book. I say, hey, Marco,
that's a really long book you're writing. It looks like you really have your work cut out for you.
That's right. Or maybe this project is really difficult. I really have my work cut out.
Okay. So you're basically saying I have a very hard time ahead of me. Okay. So that's all the phrases
we have for you. I don't really have a listen to our dialogue one last time.
The air conditioning is not working. We need to call a handyman before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that. I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom toilet
that keeps clogging up. That would be convenient. They might as well ask him to fix the electrical
wiring. The circuit breakers keep going out all the time. It's really annoying. Yeah, you're right.
This office is falling apart. Frank told me the other day that the gutters outside were clogged
and that's why the parking lot was flooded. I know. I was in ankle deep water trying to get to my
car that day. The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him. So a handyman is also
commonly referred to as a jack of all trades. That's right. So these are both kind of funny words.
First of all, handy as an adjective means useful. We're helpful. So maybe a hammer is a handy tool.
It's very handy tool or you know, I find my iPhone has some very handy applications. I can use the
dictionary. So handyman is someone who's helpful. He can do many things. But a jack of all trades
is very special because it means he is a person that can do basically any job. Right. So sometimes
in offices, people may have someone that they may refer to as a jack of all trades. So he may
fix the computers. He also knows a little bit about marketing and does many odd and random things
around the office. That's why he could say my friend Paul. He is a jack of all trades. He can fix
a car. He can cook. He can, you know, fix a door or a window, but he can also so. So he's a jack
of all trades. He has many, many skills. That's right. And talking about these skills,
being a handyman is not a profession per se. It's actually a trade. That's right. And so we say this
because it's something that you normally do with your hands. And you don't have to go to university
to study at you. Maybe have an apprenticeship where you study by working. And it's one of a few
very, very important trades like being a plumber or an electrician. But a handyman is more general
likely said. You can do many different things. That's right. So very interesting. There are many
trades out there. Maybe you can come on the site and mention some of these that you may know. Like
for example, a very well-known trade is a cobbler, a person that makes shoes, makes shoes or
very weird word though because shoes and cobbler don't seem to have a strategy to that. Yeah.
Well, many, many, many trades like this. I know before they used to be blacksmiths.
All right. So many types of trades. And of course, if you have any other questions or doubts,
you can visit our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there. Bye.