Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about eating food and certain foods that people don't eat.
That's right so today we have special diets. We're going to talk all about being a vegetarian or a vegan.
And we're going to explain all these words when we come back. So now let's just listen to the dialogue.
Hey Julie. Do you want to go grab some of the eat?
Sure. What do you feel like having?
I really feel like having a big juicy steak.
Oh. Okay. I don't eat meat but that's fine. I'm sure wherever we're going they will have other options.
I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
I'm not. I'm a vegan.
Oh, what? A vegan. I don't eat or use any animal-based products. I don't wear leather.
E eggs drink milk or anything that comes from an animal. I used to be a pescatarian before which
basically means you don't eat meat but still have fish and seafood. Wow that's interesting.
It must be tough. It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian friendly restaurants sometimes but
since more and more people are vegetarians or vegans nowadays it's getting a bit less difficult.
That's a lot of fun.
All right. We're back. So now probably a lot of you have an idea of what it means to be a vegetarian
but let's take a look at that word and many more on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So a vegetarian is a noun. I'm a vegetarian. Yeah.
Vegetarian is a noun to person. You say I am a vegetarian. He is a vegetarian.
And in this case a vegetarian person does not eat meat. So chicken, beef, none of that stuff.
That's right. So as you can see it has the prefix vegetable.
So that's what they just eat vegetables.
And it's a little bit hard to say what vegans don't eat. It's a little bit hard to say what all
vegetarians do or don't eat because some people have different rules.
That's right. Some people eat eggs. Some people don't.
But there is something that is a little bit different from a vegetarian. It's called a vegan.
And this person has many, many rules about what he can or cannot eat.
Right. So a vegetarian basically does not eat meat.
A vegan as we saw in our dialogue doesn't wear leather. For example, doesn't wear leather shoes or a jacket
or use or eat anything that comes from an animal. That's right. So no eggs. Right.
No food that might have any animal products in them. So vegans often try to find foods at the grocery
store that that come from natural products that are not animal based. And so there has to be a symbol
on the back of the box or the jar that says it's vegan. That's right. So in that case they don't drink milk.
They don't eat eggs. Nothing that you can think of that comes from an animal.
But on the other hand, this person used to be a pescatarian. So this is another type of
of person that has a special diet. Very much like a vegetarian. A pescatarian is a person who
is a vegetarian but who also eats fish. And so maybe I'm a pescatarian because I don't
consider fish to be animals. Okay. So I don't eat lamb. I don't eat chicken but I do
eat fish. I'm a pescatarian. All right. So a vegetarian does not eat fish or any type of meat
the same as a vegan but a pescatarian does eat maybe shrimp and fish and any type of animal from
the sea. Okay. And well, that brings us up to our next word. A pescatarian will eat seafood.
Seafood is a word we use to describe animals that come from the sea. So not just fish.
Also like you said, shrimp and lobster. You could even think of really delicious food like a
seafood pasta or seafood salad. Okay. So you've got clams, you have oysters. Anything that
comes from the sea is considered seafood. Right. That's right. And our last word in language
takeaway is an adjective. We heard at the end of the dialogue. Our character said,
it must be tough. Right. Okay. Now tough is an interesting word because in English it has a
few different meanings but what was the meaning of the word tough in today's dialogue?
In today's dialogue when the person said it must be tough. It's basically saying
it must be difficult. It must be difficult to be a vegetarian. Right. So it's a hard situation.
You could also say, oh man, this homework is really tough. That means it's hard. It's difficult.
All right. Great. So we've taken a look at a lot of keywords there. What? When you take a break,
listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Hey, Julie. Do you want to go grab something to eat? Sure. What do you feel like having?
I really feel like having a big juicy steak. Oh. Okay. I don't eat meat but that's fine. I'm sure
wherever we're going they will have other options. Right? I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
I'm not. I'm a vegan. A what? A vegan. I don't eat or use any animal-based products. I don't
wear leather. E eggs, drink milk or anything that comes from an animal. I used to be a pescatarian
before which basically means you don't eat meat but still have fish and seafood. Wow. That's
be tough. It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian friendly restaurants sometimes but
since more and more people are vegetarian or vegan nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
All right. Now we've prepared three phrases for you. Let's take a look at those now on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So it's a very interesting and very very common phrase at the beginning of today's
dialogue that we use all the time in English. This is to grab something to eat. The character says,
hey Julie, you want to go grab something to eat. So taking that as a phrase, we are inviting someone
to go eat something. That's right. So I could say, hey do you want to go eat something?
Or I could say, hey do you want to go grab something to eat? Okay. And the verb grab is to take
or to to hold in your hand. So you want to go grab something to eat is basically that.
Right. But don't be confused because grabbing normally means holding with your hand. But to
grab something to eat, generally just means, hey, would you like to go eat something with me?
Okay. And of course, we want to go grab something to eat. And the guy says, I really feel
like having a big juicy steak. So we feel like having a steak. This is very spoken English. So
remember when you're talking to your friends, this is okay. But maybe if you're writing something,
it's not as good. But I feel like a steak means I want to eat a steak. Right. It doesn't mean you
are a steak. No, I don't feel like a steak like a piece of meat. But I do want to eat a piece of
like I do want to eat a steak. And so I feel like having or I feel like a steak. These are both
acceptable in spoken English. So you basically feel like doing something or you feel like eating something.
For example, if we're going to have dinner, you can say, I feel like having Italian food.
Yeah, I don't feel like having Italian food tonight. I feel like having Mexican food.
And I also feel like watching a movie. Exactly. So great ways of using a feel like and then
a verb like having or watching a movie. Now, now getting back to the vegetarian, the vegan aspect
of our dialogue, we saw that the girl explained how she does in eat or use any animal-based
products. So these three words, animal-based products. So product is basically anything that will be
sold or bought. Animal-based is a way to describe a product. So some products have animal products in
them. Right. So for example, my shoes are an animal-based product because they are leather and
leather comes from cows, which are animals. So you're basically saying that they have
something from an animal. They are made up of that something that comes from an animal, like leather shoes.
Exactly. And it's not just shoes. It's also shampoo or some of the foods that you eat like in
jars and cans. And so it's important if you're vegan to look on the side of the can or the side of
the box and see, is this an animal-based product? Are there animal products in this? Right.
Right. Okay. A lot of interesting things in this dialogue today. What we listen to it one last
time and way back. Hey, Julie. Do you want to go grab some of the eat? Sure. What do you feel like
having? I really feel like having a big juicy steak. Oh. Okay. I don't eat meat, but that's fine. I'm
sure wherever we're going, they will have other options, right? I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
I'm not. I'm a vegan. Oh, what? A vegan. I don't eat or use any animal-based products. I don't wear
leather. E eggs, drink milk or anything that comes from an animal. I used to be a pest-gaterian before
which basically means you don't eat meat, but still have fish and seafood. Wow, that's interesting.
It must be tough. It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian friendly restaurants sometimes,
but since more and more people are vegetarian, or vegans nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
All right. So talking about vegan vegetarians, pest-gaterians. It seems like these diets,
or these lifestyles are more and more popular, but as we saw in the dialogue, it can be a little
bit difficult, especially in maybe in countries where it's not so popular to have these diets.
Definitely. I think that in places where you can find vegan and vegetarian products very easily,
being a vegetarian becomes much more easy because you have more options. Right. But if you're
living in a country where it's very hard to eat a meal without having meat, then you might just eat
potatoes every day. Right. We'll get very, very difficult and very boring. Well, that's one of the
main arguments or the main concerns with people is that even though you can argue that you can get
all the vitamins or many of the vitamins and minerals from nuts and from vegetables,
it's still not healthy to completely exclude from your diet, maybe sources like of proteins,
like meat, or eggs, or dairy products. That's right. And so in America, for example, it's very
easy to find supplements. You can take vitamins like calcium and you can have pills that will
give you some protein and you can find all sorts of exotic vegetables that will help you supplement
your diet. But in a place like trying to for example, I think it can be a lot harder to find those
products and to find those supplements. And so being a vegan, especially or a vegetarian, poses a lot
more challenge. Especially I think with what you mentioned that products are usually labelled,
where they tell you if they have any animal-based products in there. Whereas in other countries,
it's probably not labelled and it's a little even things like getting fat free things, or a little bit
more difficult in other countries like for example China. That's right. So we would like to know
are there many vegans or vegetarians in your country? And if there are, do you think it's hard for them
to buy food? Why are we not? Let us know our website is englishpod.com. All right, we'll see you guys there.