Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we have a delicious Italian food lesson for you today.
That's right. We are at an Italian restaurant and we are ordering food. So this is going to be
very helpful. Next time you are at an Italian restaurant with your friends and you're ordering up some dishes.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your servant tonight. May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations?
Well, I personally like the chicken panner with cream mushroom sauce but the prawn fit the
china is also very nice. No, no, no. I'd like to have the grilled chicken but can I have
spaghetti instead of spinach? Of course, man and for you. I, uh, I'll have the horse strike.
All right, we're back and now let's take a look at all those delicious Italian dishes on
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So first of all, we have two different kinds of sauce really. The first is cream mushroom.
So what's a cream sauce, Marco? A cream mushroom sauce. So basically this is cream from like milk
and you have mushrooms in it and it's, I don't know, I think everyone has seen it's a very thick white
sauce. It has little slices of mushrooms in it. It's kind of a sweet. That's right. And so
oftentimes you see there's cream sauces which are white and tomato sauces which are red.
Right. And this here is a cream sauce so it's white and it's got chunks of mushroom in it, right?
Tasty. And the waiter also offered prawn with the pasta. So what is a prawn?
prawn for the chini. So prawn is like a big, it's like a word for shrimp. I always think of
jumbo prawns, which are these big, big shrimp shrimp shrimps. So they're basically the same thing
shrimp and prawn are basically the same. That's right. And they're they're a seafood that
when they get cooked they curl. Yeah. So they look like a circle but they're pinkish or red. That's right.
They're they're very tasty. Okay. So now let's take a look at the different types of pasta. So we
have three different types of pasta that the waiter suggested. So the first one is, okay,
we're going to say all three in the American way. But I'm going to tell you the Italian way is
quite different. So I'll say that afterwards. The first is penny. Okay. So this is a type of pasta.
What does it look like? It is like a small tube. So maybe maybe three centimeters long.
And it is round and it has a hole in the middle. And so it's a kind of pasta. And what about the
fetucini? So fetucini is a long noodle but it's flat. It's flat. It's flat. Okay. So it kind of looks like
a shoelace. Yeah. It's long and flat. Okay. And then we have spaghetti which I think many people know.
And this is probably the most popular one. That's right. Spaghetti is very long. Just like
fetucini but it's very very thin and round. So it kind of looks like maybe a pencil, a very long
pencil. But very thin. We're like hair actually. Yeah. And there are thin kinds. So they have a special
name. But this is, this is just a normal pasta that you will see everywhere. It's very long. And
you can twirl it. You can spin it around your fore around your fore. Okay. So that's what we have.
We have penne, fetucini and spaghetti. Now the other woman ended up ordering horse tripe. Now this
is also another Italian dish. What is this exactly? Well horse is the animal. So this is a,
this is tripe that comes from a horse. But tripe is a certain part of the animal that we,
we, it's a food name actually. So when we eat the stomach lining, the part of the stomach that
goes around the stomach, it's kind of squishy. Okay. Soft. That is called tripe. And you can have
tripe from many different animals like cows or pigs. But in this case it's horse tripe. So it's
basically that thick piece of like spongy material around the animal's stomach. Okay. And when
you cook it, it looks very funny. So this is, and this is actually a famous Italian dish as well, right?
I think so. I think they eat it in the South more. But you can definitely get tripe in a lot of
different places in Italy. Okay. Very good. So there you have it. A lot of different dishes,
Italian dishes. We've taken a look at a couple of pasta dishes. What we take a break,
listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your servant tonight. May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations? Well, I personally like the chicken pan with cream mushroom sauce,
but the prawn fit the tuna is also very nice. No, no. I'd like to have the grilled chicken,
but can I have spaghetti instead of pine? Of course, man. And for you? I, uh, I'll have the horse tripe.
All right. We're back. So now we're going to give you three key phrases. Fun fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So the phrases we have selected for you today are phrases that you are sure to
hear anytime you go to a restaurant in America or any other English speaking country. But basically,
you have a waiter who comes to you if you sit down and this is what they'll say. The first thing
they'll say is I'll be your server. I'll be your server tonight. So he introduces himself. He says,
good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight. So when he's saying I'll be your
server, it's another way of saying I'll be your waiter. They're waiter. That's right. But server can be a
man or a woman. Uh-huh. And a waiter can only be a man. If it's a woman, it's a waitress. Okay. So
waitress for a woman, wait her for a guy, but if we use server, it's for men and women. Yes,
I'll be your server. And I just like to remind you that this is more common in America because
in America, waiters and waitresses or servers, they have to earn tips and so they're very nice.
Uh-huh. Okay. So this is why they introduce themselves. They are very nice to you. And then they ask,
may I take your order? May I take your order? So the verb to take here doesn't mean to take it
from you. It means to ask you and then they'll write it down. Okay. So the server will ask you what
you want to order and then we'll write it down. And the order is what you have decided to eat. So that's
the food that you order. Now this next phrase is very, very handy, especially if you're in a country
that maybe you don't know the dishes well or if you're in a restaurant that you want to see what
they recommend it. You can just say, do you have any recommendations? Do you have any
recommendations? Okay. So this is a way to ask the server, what's good? So what he thinks is
good or what the restaurant serves very well? Okay. So you could say, I've never been to this restaurant
before. Do you have any recommendations? Or maybe even, you know, Marco, we're having dinner.
And I know that you really like Italian food and I don't know much about Italian food. So I can
ask you, do you have any recommendations? Okay. So this is a way of asking what is good here? What is
what is what is delicious in this restaurant? What's good to eat? Okay. All right. So three phrases
there for you and we take another short break and let's listen to the dialogue for the last time.
Good evening ladies. My name is Josh and I'll be your server tonight. May I take your order?
Do you have any recommendations? Well, I personally like the chicken pen with cream mushroom sauce,
but the prawn fit the tuna is also very nice. No, no, I'd like to have the grilled chicken,
but can I have spaghetti instead of spinach? Of course, man. And for you? I, uh, I'll have the horse strike.
All right. So talking about pasta. Now, one thing before you mentioned that all these different
types of pasta, they're basically the same thing that just different shapes, right? That's how you
distinguish them. Well, yeah, they're basically made from the same ingredients. And so you have most
of them are kind of a yellow color. Sometimes you have pasta that are a dark like a brown or a green
that depends on what kind of things you put into the dough. Right. But generally they're the same
ingredients, but they are different shapes. Like they have curly ones and they're long ones and short ones.
All right. So how do you pronounce, uh, we said pen in an English and American English, but in
proper Italian, it would be pen nae. Pen nae. So you, you double pronounce the consonant. What about
Fetuccine? Fetuccine. Oh, it's Fetuccine. Fetuccine. In American, we say, uh, Fetuccine.
Fetuccine. Yeah. Fetuccine Alfredo is a very common American Italian dish, right. In Italian,
it would be Fetuccine. So you might hear it differently. And what about spaghetti? Spaghetti.
Spaghetti. Oh, you pronounce the double t as well. That's right. Okay. So, uh, you said that,
obviously there are a lot of other types of pasta. What about this pasta that's, uh, I think it's made
of spinach. It's green. Yeah, that's, uh, that's just a spinach pasta. Oh, okay. It's just
good. So they put the spinach in the dough. Um, but you can also find very many shapes, like the
angel hair pasta, right? Very thin. It's very thin. It's very thin. That's the one I was saying.
It's almost like a hair. It's so thin. It's very, it's long as well. What about those little
curly tubes? Um, you, they look like pen nae, but they're kind of curved. Look, they look like little
ends or you. Oh, you have macaroni macaroni. Elbow macaroni. We call them in America. And they
look like your elbow on your arms. We call them elbow macaroni. What about the ones that are, um,
they have like a spiral. They kind of look like springs. Those are called fusilli. Fusilli. Uh huh.
Yeah, and you also have one that's very special. This is my favorite pasta, by the way. It's called
or a kitte or a kitte. And they look like your ear. And that's what that means in a time. It
means your little ear. Oh, really. Yeah, so earpastas. Wow. And what about ravioli? This is probably
one of the most famous dishes. Ravioli. What is this? A ravioli is like a
square. It's like a square pasta. Mm-hmm. But it's more like a pocket or a pillow. And inside,
you have ingredients like meat or cheese usually is very popular. Right. So you have this cheese inside
this little, this little packet. This little, yeah. It's a little dough. It's very soft and very warm.
And then on top, sometimes people like to put butter or tomato sauce. Okay. Really delicious.
So that's the main diff. Like this was obviously all the passes that we mentioned. They're just, uh,
they don't have anything inside them. No, they're just dough. But a ravioli is a special kind of pasta.
That's like a, it's almost like a dumpling in a way. It's tough. There has to be a season-side.
All right. Really interesting. I think Italian cuisine is among one of the most famous foods in the
world. And well, you should let us know if what is your favorite Italian dish. Please let us know
our website is EnglishPod.com. And when you're there, you could find out what our favorite dishes are.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.