Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we're going shopping
today in EnglishPod. That's right today we are going to the store because we want to return a product.
So maybe the product that we bought had some problem and we wanted our money back. That's right.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about what's going on.
Hi, I would like to return this TV. Sure. Do you have a receipt?
Yeah, here you go. Actually I also want to return this keyboard.
Okay. May I ask what the reason for returning these products is?
The TV flickers a lot when I am watching a movie and at times the image is not very clear.
I see. And what about the keyboard? I spilled some coffee on it and now it won't work.
I'm sorry, man, but we can only exchange a refund defective products. We cannot take
responsibility for misuse or damages. Fine. I don't know why they make these things so delicate anyways.
All right we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those keywords on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So we've got a great bunch of words for you here today. The first three are
nouns and then afterwards we've got a couple of adjectives to describe those nouns. But first up,
we have the word receipt. That's right. So we want to return the television and the worker
there asks us if we have the receipt. Okay. A receipt is a small piece of paper that you receive
from a clerk or a server after you buy something. So if I buy a TV, I will have this small piece of paper
that says that I paid $500 for the TV. That's right. So usually they will ask you for the receipt
to see when you bought the product and if you bought the product at that store. That's right. So the
receipt has all sorts of information, date, time, method of payments cost, all those things. Right.
It's very important if you ever want to return something. Now later on the dialogue,
the character explains why he wants to return the TV. Now Markle, why does he want to do that?
Well he has a problem with the TV when he's watching a movie. Basically the image is not very
clear. So this is the keyword image. So image can mean a couple of different things. You might
hear the word image to mean a photograph or a picture like on a computer. But in this case the
image is how well you can see the images on TV, the things on TV. That's right. So on TV,
it's like you're seeing many, many images all at once or very rapidly together. So maybe if you
can't see clearly, you say that the image is not clear on the TV. All right. So if it's fuzzy,
like there's gray and black, the image is not clear. You can also say that, you know, I really like
my new TV. The image is very clear. That's right. Okay. And not only are we returning a TV,
but we're also returning a keyboard. All right. A keyboard, a key is something that you can push.
But a keyboard is this thing that you use with your computer to type words. That's right. So many
of you who are using the website as we speak are using a keyboard and a mouse. So these are probably
one of the two most well-known objects when you're using a computer. That's right. And keyboards
come in many different shapes and sizes. You can buy French keyboards and Russian keyboards. So
keyboard is the general word for this tool. Okay. So we're returning the keyboard and the clerk
explains that we can only return it if it is defective. If the product is defective. All right. So
this is one of those adjectives I talked about a minute ago. And adjectives describe things.
So my keyboard is defective or this TV is defective. That means it doesn't work. That's right.
So we have a defective product. It's not working properly. It has some problem. And well, the guy
was complaining that he didn't understand why these things like the keyboard are so delicate.
All right. Delicate is something you might see written on the side of a box. When you receive a
package, something that is delicate breaks very easily. That's right. So you have to handle with
care. So for example, glass is very delicate. It can break easily. All right. Glass is delicate, but
stones are big rock. That's not delicate. That's right. All right. So that's all we have for language
takeaway. Let's review everything and listen to our dialogue. Hi. I would like to return this TV.
Sure. Do you have a receipt? Yeah. Here you go. Actually, I also want to return this keyboard.
Okay. May I ask what the reason for returning these products is? The TV flickers a lot when I'm
watching a movie. And at times the image is not very clear. I see. And what about the keyboard?
I spilled some coffee on it and now it won't work. I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only exchange a
refund defective products. We cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages. Fine. I don't know
why they make these things so delicate anyways. All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at a
couple of phrases we've picked out for to be exact on fluency builder. Fluency builder.
The first verb we have today here in fluency builder is the main verb in today's dialogue
to return. So I would like to return this TV. Okay. So when you want to give back a product,
you don't say I want to give back or anything like this. You say I want to return this product.
Well, it's not just giving back. It's giving back and getting your money back. That's right.
So to return means that you bring back the product and the store will give you back your money.
That's right. And he wanted to return the TV as we mentioned because the image was not very clear.
But he also mentioned that the TV flickers a lot. So what is this to flicker to flickers another
verb and flicker is something that the things with light do. The light flickers. The TV flickers. It
means the light comes on and off on and off. So dark light, dark light. It's not very steady. It's not like
there's light. Right. Dark. And so this is very annoying when you're watching TV because it
goes light, dark light, dark and it's hard to see what's happening. Exactly. So it's basically
just imagine someone is turning on and off the light all the time. That's the same thing that's
happening with the TV. It flickers. Exactly. We're like when a light bulb in your lamp,
when a light bulb is dying, it flickers. That's right. All right. So we wanted to actually
return these goods and the clerk explained that we can exchange or we can refund defective products.
Okay. These are two important verbs. Exchange means to trade one thing for another. Right. So
when I go to a foreign country, I exchange money. Right. I can exchange Japanese yen for American
dollars. Right. But at a store like an electronic store, I can exchange my TV that I don't like
for maybe a really good MP3 player or something like that. So that's what happens usually if
maybe your TV is broken or it had some problem. You exchange it for a new one. Right. So
but maybe you don't want the TV anymore. Maybe you change your mind. So you want to get a refund.
So refund, you hear this word fund. It has to do with money. A refund means that the store will
give you all your money back. So if I refund my TV, I give my TV to the store. The store gives me $500
or whatever the money for the TV was and I can buy anything else anywhere else. That's right.
So this is what happens when you get a refund. Very different from exchanging the goods.
And finally the clerk explained that they cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages.
So remember this as a phrase. This is really important to take responsibility.
It means that if something goes wrong, you will take responsibility for you will handle it.
All right. So for example, the store says that it can't take responsibility if something is broken.
That means that they won't pay you back money. That's right. So if you buy a TV and you accidentally
get it wet or you get water inside and this is why it gets damaged, then the store cannot take
responsibility for this damage. Or you could say the other way around. You could say if you're at the
office and you make a mistake on a report, you say, listen boss, I'm really sorry. I take full
responsibility for this mistake. You can you know, punish me or you can make me do it again.
But I take responsibility means that I say it's my fault. Right. Your guilty. All right. So
that's all we have for fluency builder. Let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we can review
everything we've just learned. Hi, I would like to return this TV. Sure. Do you have a
receipt? Yeah. Here you go. Actually, I also want to return this keyboard. Okay. May I ask
what the reason for returning these products is? The TV flickers a lot when I'm watching a movie
and at times the image is not very clear. I see. And what about the keyboard? I spilled some
coffee on it and now it won't work. I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only exchange a refund
defective products. We cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages. Fine. I don't know why
they make these things so delicate anyways. So returning goods is a very useful thing if you
maybe bought a TV at a department store or an electronic store, then you would want to return it
if you had some problems. Now, how easy or difficult is it to do? Because in theory, in the dialogue
it seems like it's really easy. It depends on the store. Of course, so some stores make it easier to do
this. Some stores make it harder. I can tell you in most stores if you don't have a receipt,
it's probably very difficult. Really? Yes. But a lot of stores have something else that they sell
you or give you when you buy something. It's called a warranty. And this is something that will
help protect you if you take the TV home and you have a problem. Right. I mean, that they will come
fix it or they will give you a new one without any questions about what happened. Now, not only can
you return goods such as TVs, electronics, or maybe clothes, but in some cases, also things that
you buy at the supermarket like maybe chicken. I've heard that maybe sometimes you buy chicken and
you open it up that same day and it's gone bad. Really? I've never had that experience, but
I think it makes sense. It depends where you buy it of course. Right. Obviously, I had a supermarket
and you show the receipt or maybe milk. Maybe that's gone bad sometimes or yogurt. Well,
because they probably shouldn't sell it if it's bad. Exactly. If you tell them that they still
do bad milk, okay? Exactly. So that's called an exchange. You would exchange the bad one for
the good one. Right. You wouldn't get your money back. No, maybe, maybe not. Maybe. All right. So
that's all the time we have for today, but this is actually a very interesting topic because it
has to do a lot with customer service. So let us know what your experience is with customer service,
with returning something. Is it very easy, very difficult? Maybe some stores don't even accept
returns. They say, once you buy it, you cannot return it. All sales final. Yeah, exactly. So let us know
our refunds or exchanges common where you come from and have you ever had a bad experience where
you bought something and it didn't work when you got home. Let us know where our website is English.pl.
All right. We'll see you guys soon. Bye.