Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a very popular kind of movie.
That's right today we're talking about twilight and all the creatures that you can find in this
new movie. Okay so the name of the movie is twilight. Let's take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll be
back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure. What's playing? The new twilight movie!
Twilight? As in the vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand what
everyone is so excited about these films about vampires. It doesn't make sense. Of course it does.
It's like a modern tale of Romeo and Juliet. You have a couple that is in love but can't
be together because they're so different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength
is really sexy and there you have it. Plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie
even more enticing. I don't buy into that. I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and
everyone will be into where wolves are zombies.
All right we're back so now let's just jump into some vocab but let's take a look at what we've chosen
for you on language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay so language takeaway today Marko we have
three different kinds of creature or monster. That's right so if anyone knows about the movie
Twilight it's mostly about vampires. That's right so vampires are a kind of imaginary creature
that like to suck people's blood. Right. They have long teeth. That's right so they look like
people and they go out at night and they drink people's blood and they can't stand in the sunlight
because they will die if they're in the sunlight. That's right. All right so we have vampires and also
another type of imaginary creature that we find here is uh, where wolves we can find where wolves.
Okay so you know the word wolf, a wolf is an animal but a where wolf is a man or a woman who turns
into an animal when the moon is full. Right so you're a man or a woman by a day but then at night
when there is a full moon you transform into a wolf so you are a where wolf. And we have one other
kind of monster here this is a very disgusting kind of monster called a zombie. All right also
very popular in the movies you have zombie so they're people who are dead but they're still alive.
That's right so they can't think all they want to do is each other people and they're usually
very very stupid and you have to cut their heads off to kill them. That's right so zombies are also
a very popular type of creature in this movie so we have three creatures vampires, where wolves and
zombies but now let's move on to some of the other vocab that we found. When the friend was
explaining about the movie and how it's very cool she said that the cast is hip. Okay so something
that is hip is also very cool so a hip person is someone who's really interesting or cool or maybe
up to date current. Right very popular. So for example you can also talk about a place a restaurant
or a club as being very hip. That's right so you can say these days bell bottom pants are not hip
anymore they were hip in the 1970. That's right so they're not cool they're not popular they're not up to
date. Now moving on to the end of that paragraph we see that the explanation continued and saying that
the movie makes it even more enticing having a hip cast and a sexy theme. So something that is
enticing makes you want it. Okay so an enticing movie attracts people. So I find a warm apple pie
very enticing it makes me want to eat it. Okay so something that is enticing basically makes you
want to have it or it makes you desire it. Exactly. All right and our last word for language take away
when the friend was kind of skeptical and said you know what I think it's just a fad. Okay something
is a fad if it is a passing trend. So it's not always popular it's only popular for a short time.
So the word is fad if a d it sounds very similar to fad but it's not it's a fad fad. So we can say that
twilight is a fad it's something that's popular now but that might not be popular in two years.
Exactly so it's something that's very popular now but maybe later it won't be like maybe for example
Harry Potter was a fad. Exactly so that's language takeaway for today but don't go anywhere we still
have some great phrases for you coming up in fluency builder.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure what's playing? The new twilight movie. Twilight
as in the vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand what everyone is so
excited about these films about vampires. It doesn't make sense. Of course it does. It's like a modern
tale of Romeo and Juliet. You have a couple that is in love but can't be together because they're
so different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength is really sexy and there you
plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie even more enticing. I don't buy into that.
I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and everyone will be into where wolves are zombies.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of phrases we've picked out for you on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. The first phrase that we have today is related to this idea of going
to the movies and so one of the characters today said, sure I want to go to the movies. What's playing?
That's right now this question is a key question and you can use this whenever you want to know
what movie is currently being shown at the theater or at the cinema. Okay so you put what movie is playing?
There are many movies playing or there are no good movies playing tonight. That's right.
So movie plays at a theater. Exactly so you want to know what movie is playing? You say
what movie is playing tonight. All right so now for our next phrase this is actually going back to the
qualities of vampires. One of the people in the dialogue described vampires is having superhuman strength.
Okay so in this case super means more than. So superhuman strength is more than what's normal
for a human being. So maybe a human can pick up a table but superhuman strength means that if I
have it maybe I can pick up a car or something that's very unusual. They're very heavy. That's right so
superhuman strength we're talking about how strong you are and then you can also mix it up with
other qualities of a person. So for example you can have superhuman speed. You're very, very fast.
Superman is someone who had both superhuman strength and superhuman speed. That's right. So it's
a way to describe a person having a quality that's more than normal. And for our next phrase after
superhuman strength and something that's really sexy that person says and there you have it.
And there you have it. So how do you why do you end that sentence where and there you have it?
And there you have it means and that's the explanation why. Okay so let's think of the question
the question is why do people like these vampire movies? And the other person said well vampires are
sexy and they're immortal and they have superhuman strength and there you have it. So that means
and that's why. Okay so it's usually of this phrase and there you have it. You have to explain
something or give a couple of ideas before you say it before you use it. All right and exactly
and the key here is that and there you have it comes at the end of that statement. So always.
Well you know why is Jim popular? You could say well he's funny he's smart he's good looking
and there you have it. Right perfect. So you're basically saying and that's the reason why.
All right and for our last phrase when we were talking about a fad the person said pretty soon
this will pass and everyone will be into where will or zombie. So this might seem a little bit confusing.
What does it mean by everyone will be into where will be zombies? Okay so let's take a look at
this as a phrase to be into. I am into something you are into something. This means I am interested in.
So I could say I am into books and movies. Marco what are you into? So if I say I am into surfing
and bungee jumping I would say it sounds like you're interested in or it sounds like you like
sports and extreme sports. So you can be not only into activities but you can be
into a specific type of movies for example. I'm really into horror movies. And I could say I'm not
into horror movies. I am into romantic comedies. Okay so it's another way of saying that you
enjoy it or you like it or you realize some type of activity. Exactly. All right that's it for
fluency builder let's take another listen to today's dialogue and we'll be right back.
You want to go to the movies tonight? Sure. What's playing? The new Twilight movie. Twilight
as in the Vampire movies? No way am I watching that. I don't understand why everyone is so
excited about these films about vampires. It doesn't make sense. Of course it does. It's like a modern
tale of Romeo and Juliet. You have a couple that is in love but can't be together because they're
so different. Add in the fact that immortality and superhuman strength is really sexy and there you
plus the cast is hip. Young people that make the movie even more enticing. I don't buy into that.
I think it's just a fad. Pretty soon this will pass and everyone will be into where wolves are zombies.
All right we're back so obviously the dialogue revolves around Twilight and vampires but
mostly it's all about as we said something that's hip that's current that's popular now
but many times is also a fad. That's right so let's think what was a fad from the 1980s?
I think the 80s the fad was maybe you can talk about the hairstyles. Men and women had those
big kind of hairstyles long in the back and very very tall in the front. That's right so in the
80s as far as fashion fads things that were only popular for a short time. We had big hair
and we had bright colors like electric pink and green and blue and also those t-shirts
that would change color when it was hot or cold. Oh that was really cool. That should come back.
Those were super hip. Well now it's hip to wear 80s clothes. Yeah. So it's another fad.
Right exactly because then that's called that you're being like what is it like retro? Retro. Yeah.
Retro means you like to use styles from a long time ago so yeah. 70s and the movies now before was magic
and sorcerers you had Harry Potter. Now it's turned to vampires. That's right I wonder what the
fad will be in a couple of years. I don't agree with the person in today's dialogue. I don't think
zombies will be a fad. There was a short period a couple of years ago when there were many many
zombie movies. Yeah. For example Resident Evil or Sean of the Dead. Yeah. But I wonder in the
future if we're going to be seeing movies about other things. Yeah I imagine maybe not in these
these creatures. I don't know. I guess vampires have always been kind of sexy if we're
as you know they're immortal and they're good looking. They're usually very good looking and
charming and that's how they get their victims. That's right. But it's interesting to see let
us know we really care if there are any local fads in your country because sometimes fads can be
regional. That's right so let us know what you're into. Say I'm into this. Our website is Englishpod.com.
All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.