Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're going to be talking about a very fun game.
That's right today we're going bowling, a very popular sport among many people.
And so we're going to take a look at how you play this sport and all the vocab related to this great game.
Alright so let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be right back.
Alright so the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross that line where the lane begins.
Why not?
Because they polish an oil it to make the ball slide down. If you step there you'll slip and fall.
Okay so I got my bowling shoes, my ball, our names on the scorecard, so now how the heck do I play this?
You throw the ball down the lane and try to knock down all the pins.
If you do that is called a strike. If you don't knock them all down on the first try then you get a chance to get the
After 10 frames we add up the points and see who has the most.
300 is a perfect score but very hard to get.
Got it. Okay I'm going to give it a go.
Oh no my ball went in the gutter.
I told you it's harder than you think. Now let a pro show you how it's done.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some of that vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word we have today in language takeaway is lane.
That's right a bowling lane. So a lane that is where you actually play this this game.
That's right a lane is also a word for like a road, a small narrow road.
So in bowling this is the flat surface, the floor that's long, that you roll the ball down.
That's right. Okay so that's your lane.
So as you said you roll the ball down the lane and you try to knock down the pins that are at the end of the
lane. That's right so pins are they're a little bit heavy. They're usually white and they have
they're wide at the bottom and narrow at the top. They almost look like wine bottles. Exactly.
And the goal of the game is to knock these down to make them fall on the ground.
That's right. Okay so that's why you are using that's why you're throwing the ball down the lane to
knock down these pins. Now if you knock all of them down on your first try that's called a strike.
A strike that's right. So that means all 10 pins fall down on your first try.
But sometimes you don't get a strike. You may be knocked down eight pins and then later on your
second try because every person gets two tries. On your second try you knock down the last two pins.
Now what's that called Marco? So if you knock all of them down on your second try that's called a
spare. Okay strike usually you write it with an X. That's on the scorecard and a spare which is
two two tries to get all 10 pins. That's a slash. That's right. spare. And if you don't get all of the
pins in two tries you still get points. So if you knock down eight pins you get eight.
Or if you knock down four pins you get four. That's right. And you put your score on your scorecard.
And now each player usually gets 10 frames or 10 different opportunities to knock down all the pins.
All right. So usually these are boxes on the scorecard and you can play 10 frame bowling. We're
also five frame. But it's important to remember that each frame gives you the opportunity to
to bowl two times. Right. All right. So you get those two tries. So really it's 20 total
tries to knock down these pins. That's right. And now if you did really well and on every opportunity
of each frame you got to strike that means that you would get a perfect score. That's right. A perfect
score. That means that you made no mistakes. You knocked down all the pins on the first try.
And now obviously down the lane. It's not as easy as it looks because on to the sides of your
bowling lane you have this kind of a path that's to the bottom. So if your ball goes in there you
can't get it out. That's right. So remember like I said earlier a lane is also the name of a
place where we can walk or drive. It's like a road. Well we have gutters which are on the sides of
these roads and also in bowling gutters. They're lower and normally on the streets they're for water.
But in bowling they're they're the places on the right or the left side where your ball will fall.
And if your ball falls into the gutter or it rolls into the gutter you will hit no pins. Right.
That's I think that's the main thing. If your ball goes in the gutter you don't hit any pins at
all it just goes straight down and you don't hit anything. That's right. So it's really sad when you
when you've you bull badly and you get a gutter ball we call it. That's right. All right. So let's take a
look at all this vocab again. Let's listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder.
All right. So the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross
that line where the lane begins. Why not? Because they polish an oil it to make the ball slide down.
If you step there you'll slip and fall. Okay so I got my bowling shoes my ball.
Our names on the scorecard. So now how to heck do I play this? You throw the ball down the lane
and try to knock down all the pins. If you do that is called a strike. If you don't knock them all
down on the first try then you get a chance to get the spare. After 10 frames we add up the points
and see who has the most. 300 is a perfect score but very hard to get. Got it. Okay I'm going to give
it a go. Oh no my ball went in the gutter. I told you it's harder than you think. Now let a
pro show you how it's done. All right so we've picked out three different phrases for you. Let's
take a look at those now in Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. All right so the first phrase that we
have today is something that you're going to hear a lot although I want to remind everyone this is
very informal so we heard someone say in the dialogue. So now how the heck do I play this?
Okay so how the heck do I turn this computer on? Okay so how do I turn this computer on means
I don't know please help me but how the heck means I really don't know I really need your help.
That's right I really don't understand what's going on I need someone's help. Like how the heck did
this happen means I absolutely did not expect this to happen. I'm very surprised. That's right it's
actually a not very polite phrase to use but at the same time it's not terribly in polite.
It's in the middle. Uh-huh but it's very informal. All right so now the person understands how
the game works and he says okay got it I'm going I'm gonna give it a go. Okay I'm gonna means
I'm going to and this is very informal. Gunna is a way to say going to I will but the phrase here is
give it a go. What does that mean mark? Oh give it a go. So if you're gonna give it a go it means
that you're going to try. Okay so I'm gonna try so we can say this um now that we know how to play the
game let's give it a go. Let's try to play because we've been talking about it but we haven't been doing it.
That's right. So to give it a go means to try to do something. Mm-hmm exactly and that's basically
it if maybe you're watching a game on the street and you want to try maybe a card game you say okay
I want to give it a go. I want to give it a go. All right and what about our last phrase?
Now the very last phrase is the last phrase of our dialogue the character says now let a pro
show you how it's done. All right so how it's done this um let me show you how it's done
because this person is saying I'm a pro. Let me show you how it's done. It's a very interesting way
of saying saying something in English but what is the real meaning of this phrase? He's basically
saying now let me show you how to do it. Okay the correct way. Right so basically he's saying
you didn't do it very well. You didn't bowl very well. You're new. Let me show you how
professional people bowl. Right. Let me give you an example. Exactly. Maybe you and your friend
are making a cake and you don't really know what you're doing so your friends says move over.
Let me show you how it's done. That means the proper way to do it the correct way.
Mm-hmm. So Markle you're not doing it right. Let me show you how it's done. Exactly. A very
useful phrase and actually it can seem a little bit confusing because you're using the the
verb they're done. So it may seem a little bit weird do done but don't worry about it. Just take it
as a phrase. Let me show you how to do it. Let me show you how it's done. That's right. So that's
all we've got for fluency builder. Today let's take another listen to our dialogue and we'll be back
in a second.
All right. So the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross
that line where the lane begins. Why not? Because they polish an oil it to make the ball slide down.
If you step there you'll slip and fall. Okay. So I got my bowling shoes, my ball,
our names on the scorecard. So now how the heck do I play this? You throw the ball down the lane
and try to knock down all the pins. If you do that is called a strike. If you don't knock them all
down in the first try then you get a chance to get the spare. After 10 frames we add up the points
and see who has the most. 300 is a perfect score but very hard to get. Got it. Okay. I'm going to give it
a go. Oh no my ball went in the gutter. I told you it's harder than you think. Now let a pro show
you how it's done. All right. We're back. So bowling is actually a very kind of like a past time
in the United States. You get together with friends and you just go bowling. That's right. I do believe
it's also considered a sport. So many people play professionally or semi-professionally. But for
me it's always been a very social game. Something you do with a group of friends. You go out. It's
really fun. Yeah. Especially because when you go bowling many people can play. Not obviously at the
same time but you take turns and so while you're waiting people are talking and eating so it is a
very social activity. That's right. So maybe a group of people will rent a lane. Remember we were
talking earlier about a lane being that one kind of strip of wood where you roll the bowl the ball.
A group of friends can rent a lane or two lanes and the four or the eight of you can play together.
Each person playing one frame at a time. That's right. And now actually the other thing about
is it's very funny to see people trying to bowl or maybe with the heavy ball or maybe they
pass the line that we said they shouldn't pass and they slip and fall. So I guess that's what also
makes it a little bit fun to play. Yes it can be a little bit embarrassing if you're not. I'm not
very good so I'm a very embarrassing bowler but it's also really fun because if you go and you just
you know have a nice time and it's it's a very social game. Well it is and and actually we are
really curious to know if you've ever been bowling and many people have never been bowling and they find
it very very fun. So why don't you come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and
comments there as well. Yeah we hope to see you there until next time guys bye.