Hello everyone and welcome to English Mod. My name is Marco.
Hi guys, my name is Catherine and today we're talking about something that is a little bit
private. That's right, but very necessary to learning English because it's very, very useful.
That's right. So we're talking about clothing more specifically underwear. So the clothes you wear
under your clothes. That's right. Okay, so let's just jump into the dialogue. Let's see what happens today
and we're back in a bit.
Lily, I found a pair of men's boxes in the laundry machine this morning.
What? That's weird. That's your boyfriend's. Now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is extra small.
What do they look like? They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh, and there's a snoopy on it, which is hilarious.
There's a my undies. All right, so a lot of great vocab there. Let's take a look at that now on
language takeaway. Language takeaway. So the first thing we have here in language takeaway is actually
very interesting Marco because we don't say one underwear or one boxers. We say a pair of just like
pants, a pair of pants, or a pair of underwear. A pair of pants, a pair of shorts, of socks. The
same thing goes for underwear. So I really don't know why because it's one piece. So our pants,
but basically you have two holes, two places for your legs. So anything with your legs, your socks,
your shoes, your pants, your underwear. You need a pair. They have pair because you've got the
both sides left and right. Okay. All right. So you got a pair of a pair of men's boxers. Now
before we describe the underwear part, let's take a look at this other machine, a laundry machine.
Okay. So you know what a machine is? It's usually something that uses electricity to help us
with a with a task or a job. But a laundry machine is special because it helps us clean our laundry.
What kind of things are laundry? So anything that's your clothes. So basically it's also called a
washing machine. Right. So laundry machine or washing machine. Same thing. It uses water and soap to
wash your clothes. That's right. Okay. So now let's get into the type of underwear here specifically for
men. Usually we have boxers, boxers shorts. That's right. So shorts means that they're they're not
long. They're short, but boxers or boxers shorts, as you say, are usually pretty loose. They're not very
tight and they're longer than the other kinds of underwear we have. Okay. So boxers are a type of
underwear that men wear under their their their clothes. And as you say they're pretty much shorts.
Right. But they're called boxers or you can call them boxer shorts. Now the I guess the classic or the
common the common form of men's underwear are called briefs. Briefs. Now these are smaller than
boxers and they're tighter. Okay. And they are usually made out of some kind of material that
stretches. You can pull them a little bit. And this is this is again a smaller version. Well,
a smaller kind of underwear. That's right. So boxers are more like shorts briefs are kind of
and briefs are not really short. They're more like a I guess kind of like a swimming suit they look
well. Yeah, like a bathing suit bottom for men. Okay. Now that's it. Okay. And these. Okay. So
both these things we could actually describe as undies. That's right. So undies is a common
spoken language way of saying underwear. Okay. So it's very casual. And it's usually something that we
say with our family or friends. Especially moms like to say this with their kids. And these.
All right, honey. I'm going to buy you some new undies this. Okay. As a child you feel very embarrassed.
Undies is a way to say underwear. All right. Okay. So that's all the folk have that we have for you
on language takeaway. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we're back in a bit with fluency
builder.
Lily, I found a pair of men's boxes in the laundry machine this morning. What? That's weird.
That your boyfriend's now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is extra small. What do they look like?
They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh and there's Snoopy on it which is hilarious.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at some descriptive words in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right. So as you said Marco, we have a lot of great phrases today and some words for
describing underwear. And you can describe other things with these words as well. The first one we
have is phrase extra small. Okay. So when you buy underwear the sizes you sometimes get small,
extra small, large, medium, but it's just the way of describing how big it is.
All right. So you know the S, the M and the L are small, medium and large. But if you see the X, S,
that's extra small, it means it's very small. All right. We also have XL which is extra large.
That's right. Okay. So now that we've described the size, now we're going to describe a little bit
of how they look like the colors and maybe any characteristics. So the first thing that we see is
the color is light blue. Okay. So we've got blue which is normal blue. We have light blue which is maybe
the color of the sky on a beautiful summer day. There's also we didn't hear it in today's
dialogue but there's another color. It's dark blue which is almost more like purple or black.
That's right. So this is the way of describing a color. Now it can be for any color except
white. You don't really say light white or dark white. Yeah, you don't. So you could say
light green, dark green, light orange, dark dark orange. Okay. And now some characteristics. They had
thin pink stripes. So we have the word here thin. So not fat thin. Uh-huh. Pink. We have the color.
But what are stripes? Okay. Stripes are a very common design for clothes and you often see stripes.
They're like lines. Okay. And so that means that you have different lines that are pink.
You often see stripes on flags. So for example, the American flag has red and white stripes.
Okay. Very good. So as you said, they're lines. And yeah, usually in clothing you can find maybe shirts
they have vertical stripes or sometimes even horizontal stripes. Yes. But these, theseundies are
quite unique. They're very special because they have pink stripes. That's right. Okay. So that's all
the language we have for you. We want to we listen to our dialogue one last time and we're back in a little
bit.
Lily, I found a pair of men's boxes in the laundry machine this morning. What? That's weird.
That your boyfriend's now Kevin only wears briefs. Plus this pair is extra small. What do they look like?
They're light blue with thin pink stripes. Oh, and there's snoopy on it, which is hilarious.
There's a myundies.
All right. So in this case, we're talking about men's uh box of shorts because there was a
confusion about the boyfriend. But women also wear boxer shorts. It's very popular now among women.
Yeah, it is. It's usually something that women wear over their underwear. Uh huh. Women don't
really wear boxer shorts as underwear. Uh huh. Women's underwear is smaller. It's like men's briefs.
Mm-hmm. Okay. So if you if a girl wears boxers and it's usually for maybe if they're just
around the house and you don't want to wear pants and you don't want to wear shorts, you can just
wear a pair of comfortable boxer shorts. Exactly. Like they were pajamas. Uh huh. Okay.
And actually, I think a lot of girls also use boxer shorts as pajamas, right? That's right.
Mm-hmm. Okay. They're comfortable and they're light and you know, they're they're
they're usually made from cotton, which is a nice material to sleep in. Mm-hmm. Now when we're talking
about briefs, there is also another way that I've heard that they're called sometimes
a more uh maybe funny way of calling them. Some people say they're called tidy whites.
That's right. This is usually something we say to joke because in America at least many men
like to wear young men like to wear boxers. Right. So they call briefs tidy whites. Because usually
their briefs are just white. They're plain. They don't have any design or any other color.
Now they're plain and they're white usually or gray and uh they're tight not like boxers.
So the the casual name, this is not something you want to say to your English teacher.
Right. The casual name or the funny name is tidy whites. Tidy whites. And actually this is a
very interesting because with newer generations I think uh men are wearing boxers instead of briefs.
Before I think the only option was briefs. Exactly. But now boxers have grown more
more popular and I think when you're a little kid your mom always buys you little briefs and
everything but then when you're a teenager I think you just switch over to boxers. It's not as cool anymore
to wear briefs. Yeah. I think it's it's the whole uh fact of how kids sometimes dress with a
saggy or baggy pants and so they like to show their their boxers. That's right.
I don't know for some reason. I don't really understand that but if you do let us know our website
isenglishpod.com. We're gonna have all the vocabulary and stuff on the website so check it out.
All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.