Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and it's
the holiday season Marco. People are eating large meals with their families and I think often
times when you cook a lot of food you have something extra at the end. What do we call that?
That's right. Today we're going to talk about left overs, left overs. That's the extra food after
your meal that you eat later, maybe the next day. Exactly. So you know during Christmas or during some
holidays we cook so much food that obviously we can't eat it all. So we put it back in the refrigerator
and then we eat it later. So those are called leftovers. All right. So let's listen to this dialogue
about left overs and we'll be back in a moment to discuss what's happening in the dialogue.
What's for dinner? Left overs? What? Left overs have whiten from when? From last night.
I'll talk to left over Turkey. Mix it with some dice, peppers, onions, just add a little bit of
mayonnaise and make some sandwiches. It's not dangerous though. I mean bacteria and germs we producing on
food that was left out or reheated. Well I didn't leave the turkey out of room temperature for
more than an hour and I refrigerated soon after we finished eating. Also when reheating I put it in
the oven for 15 minutes at 100 degrees Celsius. Well okay. I'm just afraid of getting food poisoning.
Don't worry about it. Making a new meal out of leftovers is almost an art. Not only do you save
money but you always get to be creative and have something different to eat.
All right so a lot of vocab there. Let's take a look at it in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right so Marko there's one cooking term really in this dialogue that is
it's a little bit different from the others. So let's start with that. It's diced. That's right
we were talking about taking some peppers or diced peppers. So when you dice a vegetable or anything
that you're cooking basically you're making little little pieces little squares almost. That's
right so you can cut something many different ways. You can cut big pieces in small pieces but
diced peppers diced is a specific way to cut something in small like you say small squares.
And so in recipes you will often see this instruction dice the peppers or in this case
the peppers are diced. That's right. All right so we took some turkey mix it with dice peppers and
a lot of things and the roommate was a little bit concerned about bacteria and germs. All right so
bacteria and germs these sound like very scientific words. Um bacteria is something that grows on
well everything really but if you leave food out for example it gets bacteria or germs are things
that can make you sick. That's right and so we need to avoid these things in the kitchen because they
make us unhealthy and that's why we wash our hands and things like that but when you have food that
slaps out the risk is what Marko is that you get bacteria or germs on it. Yeah so it's dangerous
like especially with meat. Yeah leave it out it's very very dangerous because you can get some
bacteria that will make you sick and the reason why we're a little bit concerned is especially with meat
is if you leave it out after cooking it at room temperature. All right so room temperature is the
temperature of a normal room maybe it's um 65 degrees or in what's 25 degrees Celsius. Yeah um it's the
temperature of the the inside of a room and so um it's not cold it's not hot it's just normal and when we
leave food out especially meat like you're saying we have to be careful you can't leave it out for
very long if it's something like eggs or milk or um what we call perishables. That's right so
actually here comes the other two words that are a little bit of a contrast we're going to talk
about uh food that is reheated or refrigerated. All right so the room is explaining don't worry
we have done these things to this food so it's safe. So one thing you can do to food to make it
safe to kill germs is to reheat it. That means um well you know the word heated right it's
to make something hot but how is that different reheated? Well because you cooked it already so it was
warm now it went a little bit cold because it's at room temperature so in order to make sure
that it's safe to eat and you kill that bacteria you reheat it so you kind of cook it again a little
bit. Yeah you cook it again so with leftovers we often have to reheat things because they were hot
then they were cold and now we want them hot again. That's right. So we reheat them. The opposite of that
would be refrigerate. Right and this is what you should do if you take something and put it in the
refrigerator what you are doing the verb the action is to refrigerate it. That's right so to refrigerate
something means to make it cold. You know there are important things that we refrigerate. We
refrigerate eggs. We refrigerate milk. We refrigerate butter. These are things that can make us sick if we
don't make them cold. Exactly so those are the two words now obviously we it's a little bit different
because the prefix to reheat means to do it again while to refrigerate means you're just making it cold.
Yeah well they're important terms and again we also have the adjectives this is reheated or
refrigerated but there are another couple of phrases that are really important so let's take a
listen to those in fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right so the first phrase we're going to take a
look at is when one of the roommates says hey what's for dinner? What's for dinner? All right this is a
very very standard phrase this is something you'll hear at home you'll hear with your friends.
It's usually something we say that when someone is cooking food for dinner. That's right we're asking
what are we going to eat for dinner? Mom what's for dinner? Mm-hmm exactly. I used to say that
every single day when I came home from school. Well obviously you don't want to say the long phrase
what are we going to have for dinner tonight so you just say what's for dinner? What's for dinner?
What's for dinner? And then the answer would be Lazagna or Turkey sandwiches. All right exactly.
Now when they started talking about the leftover turkey he was a little bit concerned as we said
about bacteria and germs because it usually happens that you get this on food that was left out.
All right so the verb here is to leave out to leave something out. It means to leave something or put
something at room temperature. Right. So Marco you and I are eating turkey it's Thanksgiving and we
start to have coffee and dessert and the turkey is still in the room at room temperature we did not
refrigerate it. That means it was left out. How long was it left out? Well maybe two hours. Right.
Okay that means so it's not in a refrigerator. That's right and that's exactly what it means so
maybe you go to sleep and you left the turkey out. It's still on the table maybe at room temperature.
Oh no we can't eat it if we left it out for like 12 hours. Exactly. All right so it's not good to
leave food out. And now what happens is if you do eat food that was left out for too long,
you could get food poisoning. Now this is very serious and it's something that you should be very
careful about when you're cooking food poisoning is getting sick from your food. Right. They're
different kinds of food poisoning but usually it makes you throw up but makes your stomach hurt. It's
quite painful. That's right. And so this is why we say you know you should wash your hands before you
cook you should make sure that you refrigerate meat because you want to avoid food poisoning.
That's right and it comes from the noun poison, a poison which is something that is harmful
for your body. That's right there are many different kinds of poison but food poisoning means
becoming sick your body getting sick after you eat something bad. That's right. All right so a lot of
great stuff here we can review everything one last time. What's for dinner? Leftovers? What?
Leftovers of what and from when? From last night. I took the left over turkey. Mixed with some
diced peppers and onions just add a little bit of mayonnaise and made some sandwiches. It's not dangerous
though I mean bacteria and germs reproducing on food that was left out or reheated. Well I didn't
leave the turkey out of room temperature for more than an hour now refrigerated soon after we finished eating.
Also when reheating I put it in the oven for 15 minutes at 100 degrees Celsius. Well okay.
I'm just afraid of getting food poisoning. Don't worry about it. Making a new meal out of
leftovers is almost an art. Not only do you save money but you also get to be creative and have
something different to eat. All right so this is actually a good advice about leftovers about
having something to eat but at the same time I don't know how many people actually are very careful
with these things. For example pizza sometimes you leave pizza out on the table all night and the next
morning you have some pizza. I always refrigerate my pizza. Really? I know people who leave their pizza
out and then eat it but there's cheese and sausage and you know you want to refrigerate that stuff.
So I always wrap it in plastic and put it on a plate in the fridge. Okay you wrap it in plastic.
Well because in the refrigerator there's also germs so you need to make sure you cover your food.
Right right right and what about have you ever had a bad case of food poisoning because of
having leftovers? No. I've had food poisoning but not because of leftovers because as I said before
you know I wrap things I put them in their refrigerator. I'm very careful because I don't want to get sick
or I don't want to get other people sick because you know Thanksgiving or Christmas you have to give
food to many other people and you know I don't want to make anyone sick. And actually you can't get
food poisoning not only from leftovers but from maybe food that maybe was expired like sometimes
the cheese maybe can be expired and realize it and you know you get food poisoning. Or from
people who are cooking with things that are not clean. So you have something that's not clean
or food that's not fresh and it makes you very sick that's food poisoning. That's right. So it's an
interesting thing especially with like I said so many holidays where you cook so much food that
people have a lot of leftovers and not only that but even at restaurants maybe you order too much
so you have leftovers you want to take home to your dog or to have later. I love leftovers.
Let us know do you have leftovers in your country? Are there things that you should and shouldn't
do with when cooking? Let us know or our website is english.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.