Hello English learners welcome back to EnglishPod my name is Marco and I'm
Erica and we're bringing you the final lesson of our job interview series.
That's right and in this lesson we're going to be focusing on two very very common but
sometimes difficult questions.
Okay so we've talked about preparing for the job interview in part one part two we talked about
educational background and work experience and in part three what are we going to be looking
at two questions why we should hire you and your greatest weakness.
Okay so these are the classic common questions that you'll get at a job interview right?
That's right so why don't we just get started and we'll take a listen to the dialogue and see how
our interview E handles these questions.
Very good.
I have a couple of final questions.
I hope they're not too hard.
Oil, why should we hire you?
I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
I have a unique combination of strong technical acumen without standing soft skills you know
I excel at building strong long-term consumer relationships.
For example when I headed the customer support department in my previous company our team
resolved about 70% of our customer's problems.
I decided that we needed better information and technical preparation on our products.
So after I implemented a series of training sessions in coordination with our technical
department we were able to solve 90% of our customer's issues.
Given the opportunity I could bring this kind of success to this company.
Woo!
Impressive!
So what would you consider to be your greatest weakness?
It's a be honest.
I struggle with organization and time management.
punctuality has never been a strength in mind.
I find it hard to organize my time effectively.
I've actually addressed this weakness recently by attending a workshop on efficient time management.
It helped me a lot by providing me with great insights on how to get organized and use my
time efficiently. So I think I'm getting better now.
Great. Well let me tell you that I'm very pleased with this interview.
We are short-listing our candidates this week and next week we will inform our short-listed
candidates of the day and time for a second interview with our CEO.
Great thanks a lot. I hope to hear from you. Goodbye.
Well our interview is doing very well but I think he had a little bit too many
beans or chill. Oh my god! This is probably the most embarrassing thing I can think of.
But he doesn't say anything so I don't know. Maybe he should have said oh part in me
excuse me. I don't know. I don't know. It's a controversy.
Yeah. Okay but what isn't a controversy is the language because there's some great stuff in here.
So let's take a look at the language in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright we've got some great phrases and words for you to use when you're talking about
what sort of benefits and skills and experience and expertise you can bring to a company.
Okay the first thing that he said and it's a very interesting word he said
technical acumen.
Technical acumen.
acumen.
This is a really hard word. What is acumen?
It's basically insight and understanding and the ability to
make good and difficult decisions.
Okay so he has a very strong technical acumen.
So a strong insight or understanding of technical issues.
Okay or I can change it and may say I have a very strong business acumen.
Exactly. These are the two most common ways that this word is used.
Technical acumen business acumen.
Okay great. Now let's take a look at another word which is very interesting because
everybody knows it. Yes Excel Excel Excel Excel.
Excel now Excel is of course the software that you use right?
Yeah but here it's a verb meaning to be really really good at something.
Right to be the best maybe. Yeah to Excel at something.
Yes so I excel at cooking.
All right so Excel you are the best.
I mean that's not really going to help me in a job interview but
but the next word might.
Head. Heads.
Well in the dialogue we heard it as headed in the past right?
Yeah that's right he headed the customer's support department.
So I think this is very a great I think this is a great word to use when you were saying
I was the leader. I was the main person in charge.
Yeah the manager. So this is a nice verb to use to show that you are leading something.
Okay okay now for the next word struggle to struggle.
Struggle struggle.
So what does struggle mean?
It means that you have difficulty doing something.
So it's hard for you.
Yeah yeah for example when I was in school I struggled with math.
Okay and now I struggle with Chinese.
Exactly so to have a hard time.
Yeah why don't we hear a couple of examples of how this word is used.
Example one.
We're really struggling to reach our sales target.
Example two.
Yeah to be honest I do struggle with time management.
Example three.
The teacher farted in class and I really had to struggle not to last.
Okay so great examples. Let's move on to our next word punctuality punctuality punctuality
Okay so to be punctual it means to be on time always.
So punctuality would be the noun form.
Right so the condition or the state of always being on time.
Right so punctuality to be punctual.
Yeah and our interview east struggles with punctuality.
Right like me.
I guess you guys have something in common.
We do.
Now he has a problem with punctuality but he said he has
a dress this weakness.
Yes to address a dress.
Address.
Now if you notice it's spelled the same way as address.
That's right but you pronounce it differently.
So the verb address has the stress on the second syllable.
Okay address.
Yes and that means to deal with.
To deal with the problem.
Yeah to acknowledge the problem.
And to try and solve it and to try and solve it.
So different from your home address where you live.
Yeah and there the stress is on the first syllable.
Address.
Right perfect.
Very good.
Okay so let's listen to this dialogue one more time and then we'll come back
and talk about these two questions.
Greatest weakness and why should we hire you.
Very good.
Oh I have a couple of final questions.
I hope they're not too hard.
Oil.
Why should we hire you?
I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
I have a unique combination of strong technical acumen
without standing soft skills you know.
I excel at building strong long-term consumer relationships.
For example when I headed the customer support department
in my previous company our team resolved about 70% of our customer's problems.
I decided that we needed better information and technical preparation on our products.
So after I implemented a series of training sessions in coordination with our technical department
we were able to solve 90% of our customer's issues.
Given the opportunity I could bring this kind of success to this company.
Impressive.
So what would you consider to be your greatest weakness?
To be honest I struggle with organization and time management
punctuality has never been a strength in mind.
I find it hard to organize my time effectively.
I've actually addressed this weakness recently
by attending a workshop on efficient time management.
It helped me a lot by providing me with great insights
on how to get organized and use my time efficiently.
So I think I'm getting better now.
Great.
Well let me tell you that I'm very pleased with this interview.
We are short listing our candidates this week.
And next week we will inform our short listed candidates of the day and time
for a second interview with our CEO.
Great. Thanks a lot.
I hope to hear from you. Goodbye.
Alright Marco. Well this classic question why should we hire you?
I think you'll hear it in many, many different interviews.
And how did he deal with it here?
Well the first thing that he said is very, very important because
they are asking you why so your immediate reaction would
be to answer with because or I think that.
But there's a different way of approaching it which is a little bit more professional.
He said I think that I would be a perfect fit in this company.
I think I would be a perfect fit in this company.
That's how he started his answer and then he explained why.
So this sounds really strong doesn't it?
Yeah basically it just makes you seem to be very confident and puts you like
you are already part of the company.
Hmm. So this is a great way to start off this question.
But you got to follow this up with some information.
So what kind of information should you be giving?
Well like we talked about in your work experience the same thing goes here.
What do you have to offer to this company?
What special skills or insights or experience can you bring that would help us?
Yeah that nobody else can bring.
Exactly. So again you have to start talking about your strengths and your previous
experience but with examples right?
Very very specific examples and whenever you can throw in some numbers or some specific
successes that you have had.
Exactly. And once you've talked about these things you can close off this answer.
By saying given the opportunity I could bring this kind of success to this company.
Given the opportunity I could bring this kind of success to this company.
So that is just like a magical sentence saying like if you give me the chance I will demonstrate
how good I am and how I can help this company.
Yes. I really really strong closing arguments.
Yes. So that's the way you should more or less approach that question right?
All right but let's turn now to the classic classic question your greatest weakness.
What is your greatest weakness? When you get this question be sure to not say
my greatest weakness is I work too much. My greatest weakness is I'm a workaholic.
Right or what was it or I am perfectionist.
Yeah these we can see right through these. I mean that they're two obvious and they're two
silly. I mean everyone has a weakness so don't try and turn it around into a strength.
I just don't think that's a good idea. Okay so yeah be sure to stay away from these answers.
But you can say anything like in this case he has a problem with being on time.
Yeah so be honest say what one of your greatest weaknesses are but
the key to making this weakness look good is saying what you are doing to solve this weakness.
Exactly so so really be truthful tell tell the interviewer what you're not good at because
because you're there's obviously something that you're not good at. Exactly so you can say
I am usually late but I am getting more organized I am doing the seminar. I you know yeah
let the interviewer know that you are trying to improve this weakness. Exactly and be sure to
also think about your strength right? Yeah be prepared to answer the question what is your
greatest strength? So and again when you're talking about your strengths be sure it's something
more specific than saying oh I'm very responsible. Yeah you want to be a specific as you can and again
give those examples give those successes give those numbers. Right exactly so think about your
weaknesses think about your strengths. If you don't know them ask people to ask your colleagues or
ask your friends what do you think is my greatest strength? Maybe you're a funny person that's a
strength. Yes okay well remember there's there are three parts to this interviewing series and you
can find them on our website at EnglishPod.com. Right come to our website EnglishPod.com you can
look at all of these three lessons and I hope they are really helpful and of course if you have any
questions or comments or maybe you'd like a little bit more of this interview series let us know.
All right guys well thanks for listening good luck in your interviews and until next time goodbye.