Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you an advanced lesson for all of our advanced learners out there
That's right and in this lesson we're visiting a history class
Yes, we're going to be talking about a very interesting topic that's known around the world
which is international workers day
That's right and we're going to learn a little bit about the history of the workers movement
in the United States, right but we're also going to be taking a look at some great words
and of course a little bit more advanced or complicated structures
That's right so I guess without further ado we can get started with the dialogue
All right everyone settled down, let's get started
As you know an important aspect of becoming a good citizen is understanding the genesis of our legal system
It's not enough to simply memorize our laws
It's necessary that we comprehend why and how they were formed
This brings me to our topic for today
Does anyone know what we celebrate on May 1st?
Syncodemio
No, that's May 5th in Spanish James, no wonder you're failing my Spanish class
May 1st is international workers day
Do we get a day off from school then?
No, it is not considered to be a national holiday here in the US
But another country is it is
Oh man
In the 19th century working conditions were appalling
With workers being forced to work 10, 12 and 14 hours a day
Support for the 8 hour work day movement was growing rapidly
Despite the indifference and hostility of many union leaders and by April 1886
250,000 workers were involved in the May Day movement
previous legislative attempts to improve working conditions had failed
So labor organizers took drastic measures
They passed the resolutions stating that 8 hours would constitute a legal day's work
And on May 1st 1886 the resolution took effect
Cool, is that why we only work eight hours now?
Yes
But the happy ending came at a high price
On May 3rd 1886 police fired into a crowd of strikers at the McCormick Reber Works factory
Killing four and wounding many on mass meeting was called for the next day to protest the brutality
And then what happened?
Well, as we say the rest is history
All right, so we were in a history class and we learned something new something interesting, right?
Yeah, international workers stay
It's not celebrated in the US but in many other countries it is
Right, on May 1st a lot of people have a day off so that's always good
Yes
All right, so why don't we take a look at some of the words that we saw in this dialogue
Which were maybe a little bit different or difficult in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, we're just gonna look at five words here and the first one
We talked about the genesis of the movement right Genesis Genesis
Okay, so many of you may know that Genesis is a book in the Bible, right?
That's right, that's where this word comes from it's the first book in the Bible
So it's the beginning or the origin origin so that's a Genesis so the Genesis of our legal system you would say
Right or the genesis of this problem
So it's the origin yeah, it's a little bit of a formal word. It's not yeah, I guess maybe you can say the origin or the beginning
Yeah, but maybe in an academic setting you can talk about the genesis. Yes very good all right. What do we have next?
Well, one of the reasons why the the workers movement got started was because of the
Appalling working conditions
Appalling a Pauling if something is a Pauling it's
Shockingly bad very very bad. Yeah, so now if something is a Pauling like the working conditions were a Pauling
That's right you would feel a Pauled exactly. I'm a Paul that you're behavior. Okay, so it's almost like you are disgusted
Yeah, that's right. Yeah, very very strong word. Yeah, very strong. Okay, okay, so the working conditions were a Pauling and people were setting up this movement
Right, but what happened? They met some hostility
Hostility hostility hostility from the police, right? That's right. So what is hostility?
Hostility is the state of receiving an unfriendly reaction. Okay, they acted in a very unfriendly way and it also suggests
You know, I hint of violence even if somebody is hostile
They can maybe be aggressive and maybe to a point violent
That's right. Okay, so a hostile person. Yeah, or a hostile environment to dangerous environment
Okay hostility hostile very good. Yeah, now because of these
Pauling working conditions the labor movement decided to take
Drastic measures. Drastic measures. Yeah, Drastic measures. This is a really wonderful phrase and I think it would help us to listen to a few examples of this phrase in use
Example one
The president was faced with some difficult decisions. I was forced to take drastic measures to solve the crisis
Example two
The police took very drastic measures to control the protesters outside the government palace
So we understand drastic measures as extreme actions or decisions, right? Yeah, exactly. I think there's a saying that says
Desperate times call for drastic measures. No desperate times call for desperate measures. I have thing
Well, okay, but it goes around there somewhere, right? So like that if you really have an emergency you need to do something
Drastic you have to take drastic measures or you can even say take drastic action. Okay
Very good and what about our last word after the protest and did
Violence people started to get angry because of the brutality the police showed okay brutality brutality
brutality so again, maybe brutality and hostility or maybe similar, right?
A little bit similar so brutality is the state of being harsh or very forceful. Okay, so brutality now
We also use the word brutal right so that means harsh or very forceful now
Sometimes we can use that word, but not in a harsh or forceful way, right? Yeah, and it's it's quite yeah
I might say something like oh my god that test was brutal
It was brutal or so it was really hard or really difficult right so that's what you're saying with this word that it's very hard or it was very intense
Yeah, maybe one more one more example. Okay, so for example I can say oh I went for a run today
And it was brutal so so tired so it was really difficult yeah and
Marco is this something that's used by everyone that phrase brutal using and in that context would be for younger people
Maybe not really you wouldn't really hear older people using it so it's a little bit slang. Yeah, yeah, okay
All right great great so those are five interesting vocabulary words as Marco mentioned
We want to look at some more difficult structures now in fluency builder
Fluency builder
Okay, so we have some phrases that we saw in this dialogue and
Well, let's start with the first one well the teacher opens his discussion by talking about how an
Understanding of the legal system is an important aspect of being a good citizen
Okay, an important aspect and an important aspect so well, maybe we know the word important right so what's he's aspect?
A part of something an important part of something okay, so the teacher started with an important aspect of and then
Specify the idea or what part it belongs to right so it usually follows this form now
Is an important aspect of now? Okay, so for example
Quality control is an important aspect of keeping customers happy. Okay, perfect a part of very good
So aspect sounds a little bit more formal or just a lot more intelligent, right? Yeah, professional and
Actually this it's a wonderful way of setting up your idea
So the teacher said that it's an important aspect of understanding the legal system was understanding its origins or its
Genesis yep, and then she moved on and said that it's not enough to simply memorize laws
That's right. It's not enough to simply do something. Okay, so the beginning of this sentence
It's not enough to simply something
By starting a sentence like this you are indicating that more is required right?
So here it's not enough to simply memorize the laws
We're saying that most people just memorize the laws, but they need to go further and understand them
Exactly another example would be it's not enough to simply pass your exams
You must get good grades as well
Right or maybe in a business context
It's not enough to simply satisfy your customers you must impress them. Okay, very good
So that's a very good way of starting out this idea of more is required. That's right more is required. All right
All right, well, I want to move on to one final point here. I found this sentence to be really really interesting
They passed a resolution stating that eight hours would constitute a legal days work
Okay, so why is this interesting? Well, I found that you know there's two verbs going on here
They passed a resolution
That eight hours would constitute a legal days work. So we've got two verb times going on here at the same time
And I'm wondering about this this one would okay, so what's happened here?
Obviously this happened in the past is like about a hundred years ago, right? So the resolution was passed
Hundred years ago, huh, right? So it this is going on in the past right, but there was a future action that was going to happen in consequence of this
Right, so the resolution stated that eight hours would constitute
So that it's like the primary action was the passing of the resolution and the result is this sort of
This event that happens in the past, but is a future event to the first time or event
Does that make any sense at all? So this is called the future in the past, right?
That's right, okay, so it's a it's a grammar structure
Manio you may be know the simple present or the or the or the future
Tenses, but this is a little strange one and as we said so it may be it's a little bit difficult to understand the grammar in general
So why don't we take a look at some more examples of how we would use this future in the past?
Example one
The president said that he would cut taxes by five percent
Example two
I made a promise that I would not smoke anymore
Example three
Call told me he would buy a new car
Okay, so now I think it's clear this whole idea of the future in the past and well
We'll also be answering any questions on the site if you have any problems, right?
That's right, okay, so why don't we listen to the dialogue one more time and then we'll come back and talk about this holiday
Which is the international workers day
All right, everyone settled down. Let's get started
As you know an important aspect of becoming a good citizen is understanding the Genesis of our legal system
It's not enough to simply memorize our laws. It's necessary that we comprehend why and how they were formed
This brings me to our topic for today. Does anyone know what we celebrate on May 1st?
That's May 5th in Spanish James no wonder you're failing my Spanish class
No May 1st is international workers day. Do we get a day off from school it? No
It is not considered to be a national holiday here in the US but another country is it is oh man
In the 19th century working conditions were appalling with workers being forced to work 10
12 and 14 hours a day
Support for the eight hour work day movement was growing rapidly despite the indifference and hostility of many union leaders
And by April 1886
250,000 workers were involved in the May Day movement previous legislative attempts to improve working conditions had failed
So labor organizers took drastic measures they passed the resolutions stating that eight hours would
Constitute a legal day's work and on May 1st 1886 the resolution took effect cool is that why we only work eight hours now?
Yes, but the happy ending came at a high price
On May 3rd 1886 police fired into a crowd of strikers at the McCormick Reaper works factory
Killing four and wounding many a mass meeting was called for the next day to protest the brutality and then what happened?
Well as we say the rest is history
All right, so Roe Erica in Canada do you celebrate this we do but not on May 1st?
Really when is it the first weekend in September?
Oh really and why I am not 100% sure
I think it's because we already have a long weekend in in May because we sell it because on the 24th of May is the Queen
Queen Victoria's birthday so we have to celebrate that really yeah, it can have two vacations on the same month
Wow, well, yeah, I mean it's not productive right exactly what about an Ecuador?
Yeah, we do on May 1st. It's a it's a holiday and we actually have two holidays in May as well
Because on the 24th we actually celebrate the battle of Pekingcha which is one of the decisive battles for the independence of Ecuador
So we don't mind having two holidays in the same month. Well it sounds like Ecuador is a better holiday
I don't really can it that's so yeah, so yeah on May 1st people take vacations and or companies usually on May 1st
We'll do something special for their employees. Oh, that's kind of a nice gestures. Yeah, so it's like it's workers days
So they'll set up maybe a barbecue or a trip or something like that. So that's what usually happens on May 1st
Great well what about in your countries? Listeners. Do you celebrate? May day. May day. Yeah, yeah
May 1st, right? And if you do well, let us know come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments there as well
That's right. Well, thanks for downloading this lesson and until next time bye
you