I'm Oak English, learner. Welcome back to another podcast here with us at EnglishPod
and my name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we have an advanced lesson for all of you
and a very good one because we're going to be talking about the very serious topic global warming.
That's right. And even though most people agree that global warming is a big problem,
there's still this sort of fringe element of people who believe that actually a global warming
doesn't exist. Exactly. So that's what we're going to be looking at today. But before we tell
you more or less what the dialogue is about, let's take a look at some words in vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview. We're going to look at two words here and you'll hear both of these in the
dialogue. So the first one is polar ice caps. polar ice caps.
Polar ice caps. So when we talk about polar ice caps, polar is like the poles, the
north and south poles of the earth. Okay. So the extreme the top and bottom, the top and bottom of
the planet. Yep. Okay. And what about ice caps? So the polar ice caps are masses of ice that
that live or that exist on the top and the bottom of the world. We have these big chunks of ice
that are on the top at the bottom of the planet. Yes. So they're all year round. Okay. So these are
the polar ice caps. What about our next word? Well, next word is endangered species.
And endangered species. And endangered species. Okay. So endangered species. It's a type of animal
that is at risk of completely dying out. Okay. So it's not completely extinct. Right. So it's
endangered. Okay. In danger of. Yeah. So an example of endangered species would be the Bengal tigers.
Okay. The tigers or the pandas. Mm-hmm. Right. Or maybe gorillas. Right. So all of these animals,
they're very few of them left in the world. So they are endangered species. Okay. So with that,
I think we're just about ready to turn to our dialogue. Now here we're going to learn a lot of
language that you can use when you want to make an argument or express to your point of view in a
very sort of academic way. But Markle, what are we arguing about here? So we're going to listen
as a college professor is lecturing about global warming and well, one of the students doesn't really
agree with what he's saying. And therefore global warming is the greatest deception of the early 21st
century. Questions? Uh, yeah. And the lecture you said, there's more evidence in the scientific
record supporting global cooling? Well, yes. Essentially, the historical record supports a theory
of climate cycles, warming and cooling are cooperating processes in the planetary ecosystem.
If that's true and the planet is getting cooler, what explains the rapid melting of the polar
ice caps and the dramatic rise in the global average temperatures? But are global temperatures rising?
If you look at the data from 1975, you'll be misled. If you were serious, you would look at the
record starting in the 1880s. Then you would see how dramatically the Earth's temperature has changed.
Young lady, I'd beg to differ. Look, the point of the lecture was to emphasize that there's
evidence for both sides. And I'm putting forth the argument that there's greater evidence in
support of the global cooling hypothesis. Look, it's an indisputable fact that the public is
being manipulated and scared into believing that there's some kind of climate crisis. This
scare mongering is done quite simply for political reasons. But even without the uncomfortable
reality that greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide contribute to global warming, isn't the
topic appropriate for politicians to discuss? Not if they want to use your tax dollars and mine
to fund completely unnecessary initiatives. Yeah, like conservation, protecting endangered species,
and investing in renewable energy. At the very least, you have to concede that this debate
has the potential to end our dependence on foreign oil. Buying oil supports autocratic countries
that use these revenues to devastating ends. I've never been so disrespected in all of my days.
I'm a professor, a scientist, and a researcher of high regard. Yeah, and the deplicitists want
it that. Everyone knows you're in the pocket of the oil lobby. Why should we trust your so-called
findings more than tobacco institute studies, which says smoking doesn't harm health. You're full of
it. Some people just cannot handle civil debate.
All right, so apparently this college professor is a not very truthful in what he's saying, right?
Well, yeah, maybe he believes it, but I certainly have very strong and differing opinions.
So that's the interesting part is that we heard a lot of language that she used to argue
her point of view. So this is interesting, and we can start now looking at some of this language in
language takeaway. Language takeaway. So the college professor was arguing against this idea of
global warming, and she said, look, it's an indisputable fact. Okay, and indisputable fact.
And indisputable fact. Okay, so let's break it down, and let's take a look at this word indisputable.
You can't argue against it. Okay, so something indisputable is you can't argue with it, and
will affect something that's true. Okay, so you can't argue with this.
This piece of information. Yeah. All right, indisputable fact. So what do we give a few examples?
It's an indisputable fact that China is the most popular nation on earth. Okay, exactly.
Or it's an indisputable fact that English pod is the best podcast out there. Indeed, it is indisputable.
All right, so indisputable fact. And what about our next word? Well, the student
accused the professor of scare mongering scare mongering. Okay, now this is kind of a strange word
scare mongering. Yeah, and I think some examples will help us to understand the meaning a little bit better.
Example one.
Software flaws are not the same as virus attacks, and saying otherwise is just scare mongering.
Example two.
There's been a lot of scare mongering caused by the rumor that mobile phones caused cancer.
Okay, so basically we understand that it's kind of putting fear in people's minds.
Yeah, it's sort of like selling fear for your own benefit.
Okay, so making people afraid for some objective or some purpose. Yeah, and you know, this word
reminds me of the word a fishmonger. Okay, a fishmonger. What's that? Which is basically a seller of fish.
So a scare monger is a seller of fear. Okay, interesting. So now we have a way of remembering. Yes.
scare mongering. All right, and moving on to our next word, we have auto-cratic.
Auto-cratic.
An autocratic country. So an auto-cratic country is ruled by someone who holds total power.
Okay, so we have an autocratic country. So basically we have a leader that rules everything, right?
But we can apply it not only to a country, we can say a person is autocratic.
Yeah, you could say, oh, I can't stand my boss's autocratic leadership style.
Or maybe a company. This company is a very autocratic organization.
Okay, very good. And what about our last word?
The student accused the professor of being duplicitous. Okay, so she said he is duplicitous.
Yes, duplicitous. All right, what does that mean?
When you are duplicitous, you have behavior that is dishonest and is designed to trick people.
Okay, so you're not a very honest person if you're duplicitous. Yeah, you're telling lies as a means
of making people do something or tricking them. Okay, very good. So a duplicitous person or a
duplicitous idea, maybe? Mm-hmm. Okay, all right, so these are all the words that we have on
language takeaway today. But now let's move on to some very interesting phrases that we can use
to put forward some arguments in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay, Mark, are you actually
just mentioned our first phrase, which is I'm putting forth the argument that. Okay, so putting
forth the argument that. Mm-hmm. So if you put forth an argument, you present it.
You present it or you push it towards some of your. Yeah, give it. Uh-huh. So can we just put
forth an argument? Well, actually, you can put forth a lot of things like put forth a suggestion.
Okay, I'm putting forth a suggestion that we should get a new computer. Or an idea.
Tim put forth the idea that we should go on vacation to Hawaii. Mm, good idea. All right,
so you can put forth many different things. So the professor obviously is putting forth the argument
that global warming is a myth and the student obviously totally disagree. And she said,
you have to concede that. Okay, you have to concede that. You have to concede that.
All right, so this word concede or you have to concede, why don't we listen to some
examples before we listen to the meaning? Example one. I'm sorry, but I can't concede with you
on this point. Example two. Julie conceded that she might have forgotten her sister's birthday.
Example three. Both philosophers conceded that there for
philosophies have some errors. Okay, so you have to concede that. Basically, you have to agree
that this one point in my argument is true. Maybe you're arguing many different points with somebody,
but you tell them, well, you have to concede that the earth is round. Okay, so that that part,
I can't argue with. It's really true. Okay, very good. So concede. Mm-hmm. Now, at the end of the
dialogue, the student accused the professor of being in the pocket of the oil lobby. Okay, so he's in the
pocket of to be in the pocket of. All right, so if I have somebody in my pocket, what does that mean?
It means basically you're bribing them. Okay, so maybe I have the senator in my pocket. Okay, so obviously
you're paying the senator to do what you want. Okay, very good, so it's another way, it's a very informal
way of saying I'm bribing somebody or that person is being bribed. That's right. So why don't we
move to our final phrase? And the students was talking about the professor's so called findings.
Okay, so you're so called finding. So called. So this word so called. You use this word when you
want to take away from the importance of an idea. All right, so I use it before and now, right?
Right, so for example, my so called friends. Okay, so these friends are not really your friends,
maybe. So yeah, their friends and name, but they don't act like friends. Okay, so you can say my so called
job. Okay, so maybe you kind of go to work, but do nothing all day. Right, or maybe you don't even
really like what you do. Right, so my so called job, my so called friends, or maybe my so called
teacher. Okay, so this is a bad teacher. I exactly, so we use it a lot with many different nouns,
right? That's right, so that's our last phrase for Fluency Builder. Now, I think it will help us
understand these words and phrases a little bit better to hear them again in context.
And therefore global warming is the greatest deception of the early 21st century. Questions?
Yeah, and the lecture you said there's more evidence in the scientific record supporting global
Well, yes, essentially the historical record supports a theory of climate cycles warming and cooling are
cooperating processes in the planetary ecosystem. If that's true and the planet is getting cooler,
what explains the rapid melting of the polar ice caps and the dramatic rise in the global
average temperatures? But are global temperatures rising? If you look at the data from 1975,
you'll be misled. If you were serious, you would look at the record starting in the 1880s.
Then you would see how dramatically the Earth's temperature has changed.
Young lady, I'd beg to differ. Look, the point of the lecture was to emphasize that there's
evidence for both sides. And I'm putting forth the argument that there's greater evidence in
support of the global cooling hypothesis. Look, it's an indisputable fact that the public is
being manipulated and scared into believing that there's some kind of climate crisis. This
scare mongering is done quite simply for political reasons. But even without the uncomfortable
reality that greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide contribute to global warming,
isn't the topic appropriate for politicians to discuss? Not if they want to use your tax
dollars and mine to fund completely unnecessary initiatives. Yeah, like conservation,
protecting endangered species, and investing in renewable energy. At the very least,
you have to concede that this debate has the potential to end our dependence on foreign oil.
Buying oil supports autocratic countries that use these revenues to devastating ends.
I've never been so disrespected in all of my days. I'm a professor, a scientist,
and a researcher of high regard. Yeah, and the deplicitists want it that.
Everyone knows you're in the pocket of the oil lobby. Why should we trust your so-called
findings more than tobacco institute studies, which say smoking doesn't harm health? You're full of it.
Some people just cannot handle civil debate.
All right, very good. So interesting ways of putting forth arguments and
well, it's an interesting topic and very controversial, right? That's right. But what I
noticed in this dialogue is that the student was pretty assertive in putting forth her argument
and standing up to the teacher. Right, she argued with a teacher a lot, and this is interesting
because it's a very cultural aspect, I think, right? Yeah, in North American universities,
there is this idea that it's really important to think critically and to argue against different
ideas and to really speak up when you don't agree with something. Right, so basically there's
this culture of questioning, not only what you're being taught, but you can also question the teacher.
You don't actually have to believe everything that the teacher is saying. Exactly. And actually,
I think this situation is really interesting. You always go to these lectures, and there's always
a question and answer period at the end of the lectures. And I think that there's this group of
sort of academically minded people who feel like it's really cool to ask these really difficult
questions and engage in arguments with the props. Yeah, that's really true. But actually, she
used a lot of polite language and a lot of polite ways of actually arguing with the professor.
Yeah, until the last point when she said you're full of it. Yeah, you're full of it. Right,
you're full of it. So what she's saying here, all right, she's basically saying that you're full of shit.
Where go? So yeah, you wouldn't really say that. So to be a little bit less rude, you would just say
you're full of it. Yeah, but that is one step too far. I think I think this would be considered a
little bit rude. Yeah, for a professor, yeah. But I guess if you're don't believe what your
friend is telling you or maybe he's exaggerating, you can say all you're full of it. Yeah, okay. So
some great argumentative language here in this dialogue, but we want to give you an opportunity to
try out some of this language. So come to our website at EnglishPod.com. Right, we are there to
answer any questions or doubts and we'll see you guys there. All right, guys, until next time, goodbye.