Hello English learners. Welcome back to another advanced lesson here at English Pod,
my name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we're going to be back in the office. That's right.
We are listening in as somebody gets a little bit of trouble from their boss for being a bit
late on a project. All right. So we're going to be at the office. Somebody misses a deadline. And so
well, how do you handle the situation? What can you do to explain yourself? And what language
can you actually use to talk about mis-dead lines and late work? All right. So let's see why this
person missed the deadline and let's find out what happens.
And so I just wanted to check in with you and find out where we are with this project. As you
know, you missed a fairly significant deadline last week and this will negatively impact the
team's ability to move forward with the next stages of this project. They know. I'm really sorry that
I missed a deadline. But really, it wasn't my fault. You see, we had all of these unexpected
technical problems at the last minute. And I couldn't get into the database and extract the kind
of information that I needed for the data analysis. You know, if the tech guys would have done
their job and kept to CRM stable, then I wouldn't have missed my deadline. Oh, come on. And
excuse like that is tantamount to lying. You're essentially blaming the tech team for your time
management issues rather than accepting responsibility for the fact that you were procrastinating
for the past two weeks. No, I'm not trying to pass the buck here. I know it was me who was
ultimately responsible for getting this done. But the thing is, I could have finished on time
if the system hadn't gone down. And you know, with everything I've got going on now, I can't afford
to waste time dealing with technical problems. I've got a lot of my plate and there are only 24 hours
in a day. I'm not going to accept this excuse. You're using these small technical glitches as a
crutch and trying to rationalize the fact that you've missed your deadline. Look, we have standards
and I expect you to live up to those standards. No more phony excuses. If you're in over your head,
you tell me no more missed deadlines. Now, I want that data on my desk by 9 a.m.
Well, it sounds like this guy isn't really accepting a lot of the responsibility for his
misdead line. Exactly. Well, apparently he's explaining that it wasn't only his fault, right?
Yep. So some technical problems. But, you know, he used a lot of pretty, pretty interesting
language. And I think it'll help us to look at that now in language takeaway. Language takeaway.
All right. So on language takeaway today, we have five words and let's start with the first one.
All right. Well, the boss is not really happy with the excuse that the employee was giving. And he said,
an excuse like that is tantamount to lying. Tantamount. Tantamount to something.
Okay. So if an excuse like that is tantamount to lying, what is what is he trying to say here?
Basically, it's the same as or it's almost the same as. So similar to. So if I say tantamount to
something else, how would I use it? You know, Marco taking my computer without asking is tantamount to
stealing. Okay. So even though I'm not actually stealing and are taking it home with me,
it is almost like stealing. Yeah. And the interesting grammatical thing here is that we almost
always use a jar and dried after. So tantamount to verbaeangi. Okay. Tantamount to stealing,
to lying, tantamount to killing. Okay. Well, on that happy note, let's go on to our next word.
Now the boss was really unhappy with the employee for procrastinating. Procrastinating.
Procrastinating. So the verbaeang is to procrastinate. And when you procrastinate, you say,
oh, do it later. I'll do it tomorrow. Okay. So you kind of delay things or you leave it for another day.
All right. Very good. So two procrastinates. A favorite verb amongst college students. I actually
thought for a little while that procrastinate was to have babies. Oh, oh. Okay. It's kind of similar.
What's that? Let's go. Procreate. Procreate. Yeah. So for a while, I always thought that procrastinate
was like having babies like, why are you procrastinating? And I'm like, I'm not. Well, glad you got that
straight. So yes, our listeners procrastinate is not to say as procreate. Okay. I learned that the
hard way. Yes. Well, it sounds like you had a little bit of a glitch in your understanding of language.
And that's our next phrase. So in the dialogue, they were talking about some glitches with the
system. A glitch in the system. Okay. So a glitch. Now this is a common among computers. Right.
A glitch is an error. Right. So when you're talking about a glitch and you're talking about
computers, it's an error and mistake. But we also use it to talk about any unexpected problem,
a small and expected problem. Okay. So a small glitch. Yeah. There was a glitch in our plan and we
arrived 10 minutes late. Or I can say this movie has a glitch in the story. So there's a small
problem in the story that doesn't make sense. Exactly. All right. So the employee was blaming
his lateness on these small technical glitches. But the boss didn't believe this, right?
The boss said you're trying to rationalize the fact that you missed the deadline. Okay. To
rationalize. To rationalize. So the boss is saying that he's trying to rationalize. So that means
he's trying to make sense of it. Well, this is an interesting psychological word. And when you
rationalize something, you think about it or describe it, like especially some bad behavior
in a way that makes it seem better or proper or more sensible. So you're trying to convince yourself.
Yeah. You're telling other people, but you're also telling yourself that it's better.
Okay. Or that you're right when you're actually wrong. Yes. Yeah. Okay. So he was trying to
rationalize the fact that he missed the deadline. So he was trying to explain to the boss and also
kind of make himself believe that it wasn't really his fault when it was. Now because this
is a little bit of a difficult concept to understand, I think we should hear some examples.
Example one, you can't rationalize your sense behavior by saying he's going through a hard time.
Example two. As much as I tried, I couldn't rationalize buying such an expensive pair of shoes.
Example three. You know it was the wrong thing to do. Stop trying to rationalize it.
Okay. So clear as daylight now, this word rationalize. All right. And our final word. So the boss
really wasn't happy with these excuses. And he said no more phony excuses. Okay. phony phony.
PH-O-N-Y phony. So phony is basically false or fake. Right. So a phony statement.
A phony watch. Okay. A fake watch. Yeah. Not a phony watch, but phony watch. A phony. So a lot of great
words in this dialogue, but as you mentioned, we also saw some very interesting phrases that we can
use in situations like this. So why don't we start now with fluency builder? Fluency builder.
Well, you know, one of the interesting things about English is that we have a lot of ways to
make things sound more direct, less direct harder or softer. And in this dialogue, there are
few examples of how we use softening words to do the opposite to actually make it a little strong.
Okay. So why don't we start with the first paragraph. In the first part of the dialogue,
he said you missed a fairly significant deadline. A fairly significant deadline.
Now, this word fairly kind of sort of. So it's not very significant. It's kind of significant.
But in this context, when the person is saying it, it just sounds a little bit softer, but your
understanding is it's a very important deadline. Okay. A very important deadline. So another
similar example of this is the boss was saying you're essentially blaming the tech team. Okay.
You're essentially blaming. So essentially is like basically or pretty much. So it sounds a little
softer. But what he's actually really saying is you're doing this. Right. So instead of saying
you're blaming the tech team, he adds this word essentially to kind of say, well, basically you're
saying it's their fault. Yeah. But the context or you understand that it's actually very direct
and he's saying it's your fault. Yeah. So he's saying you're almost blaming the tech team. But what
he means is you're blaming the tech team. Now our third phrase is very interesting because it's kind
of like a saying. That's right. So the employee says, I'm not trying to pass the buck here.
I'm not trying to pass the buck here. I'm not trying to pass the buck. Now what's the buck?
A dollar bill. A dollar bill. So he's what I understand that he's saying. I'm not trying to
blame somebody else or or pass the blame onto someone else. Mm-hmm. But you can think about it
like this. Like imagine he had some fake or phony money, right? And he wants to pass that on to the
next person. So he doesn't get in trouble. Okay. So I'm not trying to pass the buck. I'm not trying to
pass the blame. Put the responsibility on someone else. Very good. But you know what? You know what?
You know what he really means here? What? I am trying to do this because he knew. Yeah. He knew that
it was a fake dollar bill. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Now the fourth one is interesting as well because
it's kind of like a metaphor. Mm-hmm. He said the boss said you're using the small technical glitches
as a crutch. So using something as a crutch. Now the crutch is a, you know when you when you break
your leg, you use those wood in or metal sticks to walk with. Okay. To help you walk. Yeah.
So the boss is basically saying you're using these technical glitches as an excuse or as an aid
to why you missed a deadline. Yeah. So if you think about it like this, some people might say,
okay, if you walk with a crutch, then you, you won't succeed, right? Because whatever. So he,
this guy, the employee is basically saying, yes, I know that I should meet deadlines, but these
these problems these glitches are like my crutch that make me not succeed. Okay. So he's trying
to just make excuses. Mm-hmm. So, um, God, Mark, that was a little bit difficult to understand.
Do you think we should give a couple more examples? Yeah. I think I think some more examples
would be very useful. So let's listen to a couple of them now. Example one. I realized that I was
using Aga-Haz a crutch to get through the day. Example two. I think Bill's very capable of being successful,
but he uses his disability as a crutch. Example three. Stop using your weight as a crutch.
Just because you're a bit fat doesn't mean you can't get a great job. All right. So a lot of
great phrases, great words, and well, I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue for the
last time. And then we'll come back and talk about this aspect of meeting deadlines.
And so I just wanted to check in with you and find out where we are with this project. As you know,
you missed a fairly significant deadline last week and this will negatively impact the team's
ability to move forward with the next stages of this project. I know. I'm really sorry that I missed
a deadline, but really, it wasn't my fault. You see, we had all of these unexpected technical
problems at the last minute and I couldn't get into the database and extract the kind of
information that I needed for the data analysis. You know, if the tech guys would have done their job
and kept to see our M-stable, then I wouldn't have missed my deadline. Oh, come on, and excuse
like that is tantamount to lying. You're essentially blaming the tech team for your time management
issues rather than accepting responsibility for the fact that you were procrastinating for the past two
weeks. No, I'm not trying to pass the buck here. I know it was me who was ultimately responsible
for getting this done, but the thing is, I could have finished on time if the system hadn't gone
down. And you know, with everything I've got going on now, I can't afford to waste time dealing with
technical problems. I've got a lot of my plate and there are only 24 hours in a day. I'm not going
to accept this excuse. You're using these small technical glitches as a crutch and trying to rationalize
the fact that you've missed your deadline. Look, we have standards and I expect you to live up
to those standards. No more phony excuses. If you're in over your head, you tell me no more
missed deadlines. Now, I want that data on my desk by 9 a.m.
This employee got in a lot of trouble from missing his deadline. Exactly. I think it's a very
important aspect of not only Western culture, but also in general, assuming guilt when it's your fault.
In this case, we saw that the employee didn't really want to accept the fact that he, it was his fault.
Yeah, he didn't say, yeah, I know it was me. I'm sorry. And this is my plan to fix it.
Now, this is very important among cultures because in some cultures, the aspect of
losing face is so important, right? Right. So somebody may not really want to assume guilt or
they have to because it's part of the culture. But what's the standard in North American business
practice? I would say that you would have to assume the responsibility and take
responsibility for your actions. Right? And say, yes, it's my fault. I did it, but I'm going to get
it fixed or I'll do it or I'll make up for it. So some good, some good business tips here today
in this lesson. Now, remember, if you have any questions about the language, or want to tell us a
little bit about how you assume responsibility in your culture, visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
Right. We're always there to help you out and until next time. Thanks for listening and goodbye.