Hello English learners, welcome back to another advanced lesson with us here at English
Pod. My name is Marco. And my name is Erica. So today we're bringing you another advanced lesson
and this time it's kind of historical. Like the name suggests, we are listening in as a
president says goodbye to the nation before he steps down from his role as president. Now actually
this dialogue is very much based on president Eisenhower's farewell speech.
Okay, so pretty pretty famous. Now we have to tell you that we did change the speech a little
bit, right? Just a little bit to make it a little bit more understandable, but it's basically
what he said to the nation back in 1969. All right. Now I will as well tell you that this is a
pretty hard dialogue. It is very hard because the structures are a little bit complicated and even
to a certain point a little bit poetic, right? So why are we taking this speech as our dialogue?
What are we going to learn from this? Well, we're going to learn some structures and some
words that you can use maybe on a resignation letter or maybe in a celebration you want to
think people are coming. Okay, so we're going to learn some pretty difficult vocabulary, but also
you learn some really useful structures like you said you could use in a resignation letter or even
in a formal speech of your own. Exactly. Now this presidential farewell speech is divided into two
parts. So today we're going to do part one and then next time we'll finish the speech with part two.
So let's listen to President Eisenhower as he says goodbye to the nation and we'll come back just in a
little bit.
Good evening my fellow Americans. Three days from now after a century of service to our country
I should lay down the responsibilities of office as in a traditional and solemn ceremony
the authority of the presidency is vested in my successor. This evening I come to you with a
message of leave taking and farewell and to share a few final thoughts with you, my countrymen.
Like every other citizen I wish the new president and all who will leave her with him,
Godspeed. I pray that the coming years will be blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
Our people expect their president and the congress to find essential agreement on questions of
great importance. The wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our great nation.
My older relations with congress begin on a remote and continuous basis when
long ago a member of the Senate appointed me to West Point. I then had the pleasure of building
more intimate relationships with Congress during the war and the immediate postwar period.
Finally we have progressed to the mutually interdependent relationship we've had during these past eight years.
Wow so Eisenhower is a pretty good speaker isn't he?
A good speaker and well he said a lot of really nice things when he was saying goodbye.
Yeah pretty inspiring I thought. Really inspiring and as we said there were a couple of
different and difficult words and phrases so why don't we start right now with language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Well Eisenhower said that in three days he shall lay down the responsibilities.
To lay down the responsibilities. All right lay down something. Basically we understand the
verb to lay down. Yeah to put it down. To put it on the ground. Right. Now he's using it with
responsibilities which is a little bit strange but it's kind of like a metaphor by saying
lay down arms to lay down your weapons. Right and you know what this is a really common phrase
that we would hear especially when we're talking about you know the end of a war or something like that.
To lay down your arms down your weapons. Yeah so here I think Eisenhower is kind of referencing this
and giving us a little bit of poetry in his speech. Right so it's not that he's quitting it's not
that he's being fired. Yeah he's just like finishing what he started. Yes so he's laying down
his responsibilities. Now I think this would be quite an interesting phrase to use for example
in a resignation letter. Right so I would say a month from now I will lay down my responsibilities as
manager. Yep. All right so that sounds pretty good. Now he said he's going to be laying down the
responsibilities in a traditional and solemn ceremony. All right solemn. Now solemn what does
that mean? What does a solemn ceremony? Well a solemn ceremony would be a serious, respectful and a
little bit sad ceremony. Okay so it's a serious matter it's and it's very respectful. Yeah so you might
say for example on the 11th of November when you're remembering the war you might say something like
this is a very solemn day. Very good. Okay and the authority of the presidency is vested in my
successor. Okay so interesting verb. No so interesting word vested vested. The authority vested in
my successor. Very good. So this word basically means power that I have by law. Right so this
power this important power you have is given to you by the law by the president by the country.
This is a very common word you will hear in a wedding. When the priest or the person that's
leading the wedding will say by the power vested in me by the state of California. Yep I now
pronounce you has been in life. I now pronounce you as an annoyance. So you're saying the power that I
have given to me by the state of California I can now make you be married. So here Eisenhower is saying
the authority of the presidency is vested in my successor. So the power of the presidency will be given to
his given to the next next president by law. Exactly and he also wished the new president and
everyone with him he said God speed. All right God speed. God speed. I wish you God speed.
Now God speed what does that mean? Well it's kind of a blessing you know um it basically means
good luck and good fortune. All right and especially in the journey. Yeah I think you'd almost
only use this when someone's going off on a big trip or a journey so um here they're going on
the journey of the presidency. Right. So wish you God speed. God speed. Very good and now let's take a look at
our last set of words. Uh when he was talking about Congress he said that his relation with Congress
began on a remote and tenuous basis. All right so two interesting words here remote and tenuous.
Now remote we understand as being far away or distant. Yeah what about tenuous though?
But tenuous is kind of unimportant or not really relevant. All right so actually this is a pretty
high quality um useful and smart sounding word so I think we should hear a few more examples of how it's
used. Example one. How can you say the earth is actually getting cooler that is a pretty tenuous argument.
Example two. John believes that Elvis Presley is still alive. He's got a tenuous hold on
reality. Example three. We're making us have seen more important in you all. Connection between our
community success and your performance is tenuous at best. All right so as we said these are some pretty
pretty difficult words that we found in the dialogue but now I want to go and look at some really
interesting um formal structures that I didn't how I used here so let's look at those now in fluency
builder. Fluency builder. All right I'm fluency builder today we have three phrases and we'll
starting with the first one I think it's one of the most interesting ones. He said three days from now
after a half a century of service of our country I shall lay down the responsibilities of office.
All right so what's interesting about this? If you take a look at the structure he's saying three days
from now which is future future and then he makes a reference to the past after a half century of service.
Okay so we got future past and then again future I shall lay down the responsibilities.
All right so this is actually quite a good structure if you're giving a farewell speech or even
even I could imagine using this at a wedding. How would you use it in a wedding?
Why might say um 12 hours for now after a long and beautiful relationship this couple shall marry?
Very good so you're making reference to the future and then a past event or something that's been
going on for a while and then future again. Why don't we do one more example? So for example in
resignation letter I can say I can say one month from now after 30 years of hard work and dedication
to this company I shall lay down my responsibilities as product manager. All right interesting.
So we can use it and it sounds good it sounds very professional and and very poetic. Very poetic.
Yeah, that's nice. Yeah. All right so that's one interesting structure. Now what
are we going to this next kind of very formal and helpful in a very formal speech?
Well President Eisenhower said this evening I come to you with a message of leave taking
and farewell. So this evening I come to you with a message of leave taking and farewell.
So it's a very nice way of saying I'm talking to you today because I am saying goodbye. Yes.
So what I really like about this phrase is the beginning part. This evening I come to you with a message
of. So again let's suppose we're at a wedding. I'm offering a toast or I'm the best man I could say.
This evening I come to you with a message of love and trust and respect. All right or maybe
if you're the leader of a company you might say something like this afternoon I come to you
with a message of hope for the future. Very good. And now the part when he says leave taking
and farewell it's basically saying taking leave or taking like a vacation right? Yeah. Yeah. Fair
well. Goodbye. Goodbye. And what about our last phrase? This is actually a bit of a long one.
So I'm going to read it now. Our people expect their president and the congress to find essential
agreement on questions of great importance. The wise resolution of which will better shape the
future of our great nation. Okay great. Now let's take a look at the first part. Basically he's saying
the people expect the president and the congress to give them answers right? Well yeah it's
to agree on an important issues. But in the part when he says the wise resolution of which will
better shape the future of our great nation. Yeah and this is the part I want to focus on the wise
resolution of which. Now this is a really wonderful sort of a formal structure. So we can see what he's
doing here. He's talking about the first idea right? So the president and the congress need to find
agreement on important issues right? Now the wise resolution of which. So he's referring back to
that idea. Uh huh. So the wise resolution of what? Of the essential agreement on questions of
great importance. Right. So really useful structure. Why don't we hear a few more examples of this?
Example one. We now face a great challenge. The overcoming of which lead us all to untold
riches and success. Example two. We as a company now face our most difficult months to date.
Yeah come of which will determine our company's future. Example three.
The ambitious plan to reduce poverty. The start of which was launched last Tuesday in New York
will require huge investment of taxpayers dollars.
All right so as you can hear from the examples we have the main idea and then he passes on
but then kind of refers back to it again. Yeah and this sounds quite formal but also quite literary
and intelligent. Yeah it makes it makes you sound well spoken. Mm hmm very good. This was quite a
difficult dialogue with some really interesting and tricky structures and words. So why don't we
hear it one more time altogether? Good evening my fellow Americans. Three days from now after a
century of service to our country. I should lay down the responsibilities of office as in a
traditional and solemn ceremony. The authority of the presidency is vested in my successor.
This evening I come to you with a message of leave taking and farewell and to share a few final thoughts
with you, my countrymen. Like every other citizen I wish the new president and all who will
leave her with him, Godspeed. I pray that the coming years will be blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
Our people expect their president and the Congress to find essential agreement on questions of
great importance. The wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our great nation.
My own relations with Congress begin on a remote and continuous basis when Lona Go, a member of the
Senate, appointed me to West Point. I then had the pleasure of building more intimate relationships
with Congress during the war and the immediate postwar period. Finally we have progressed to the
mutually interdependent relationship we've had during these past eight years.
All right we're back and here with us in this studio we have Pete, the actor in the dialogue
of President Eisenhower's presidential farewell speech. He's a pretty convincing actor at that.
Not quite. So Pete is going to give us a little bit of insight about President Eisenhower.
All right so what can you tell us about President Eisenhower? Well he started off as a general.
He was an accomplished officer all through the early 20th century and then he was the
Supreme Commander of the Allied Expeditionary Force in World War II.
So now he's most famous for D-Day. He was leading it.
Or he was on the battlefield. No he was he was the organizer. He was he was kind of like the
brains behind the operation. Yeah I don't know if you want to leave this in but there's a really
cool document that he wrote right before the invasion and it said he basically knew this we're going
to go one of two ways and he wrote down a script to read in case it failed and he basically
said you know I'm sorry to inform you that the invasion did not go as planned and this is set back
our war effort and when the invasion went well he threw that in the trash and then one of his
aids found down and was like wow this is a historical document and they kept the
really. So they had the they have the copy. Alternate history. All right so he was an accomplished
general an amazing warrior but what about his presidency? Well at the beginning probably the biggest
thing he did was to wrap up the Korean War which was a vow he made during his campaign and then he
visited Korea obviously the war is still technically on but they did a range of ceasefire.
Eisenhower built up the interstate highway system which is one of the big reasons that America was
able to become economically successful in the 20th century. He did it basically so that in case of a war
we'd have an easy way of shipping our soldiers and nukes across the country but but it worked well anyway.
Yeah it is one of these things that pays aside benefit at least he had to sell it to the to the
to the country that way. It's very likely that he didn't intend ever to use it that way but you know
you have to have like it's like the war on Terry you got to sell these things. Well and I guess it's
had a huge impact not only on the economy of the states but also like the culture and in the way
that people view the car and it's a fact on society. Definitely. So pretty influential guy this Eisenhower.
Yeah and a very historical lesson is just a little bit of a culture and maybe some insight on
American history it's not like we're politically active or anything but but yeah it was some
interesting information there and also well he was considered to be a pretty good president.
Yeah he's really I wouldn't say among the top five or so but quite accomplished. Well maybe not the
greatest president we've ever seen but he wrote a pretty good farewell speech so I think we have
that to thank him for. All right guys so if you have any other questions or comments you can come to the
website at englishpod.com and you can leave them there for Erica or I. Okay so thanks for downloading
you guys and until next time goodbye. Bye.