Hello everyone, and that will come back to another great lesson here at English Pod,
my name is Marco.
My name is Kathen, hello everyone.
And today we've got a great lesson for you at the upper intermediate level.
We're going to be talking about an interesting topic which is gambling.
Yeah, I don't know if you like to do this, Marco go, you know, I'm actually going to play some cards,
play some poker, blackjack, throw the dice.
I'm actually a bit of a fan of the roulette.
You have to throw the ball under the wheel that's spinning and lands into like a little compartment
in a number.
Right.
So you can win like a based on the number and the color.
But it's interesting because if you get the number right, it pays you 35 times your bet.
Wow, that's a lot of money to win.
A lot of potential there, but there's a lot of numbers on that wheel.
But that's the thing, some people like gambling, some people don't like it.
And in some countries, in some states, it's illegal, right?
Exactly.
So today we're talking about a city that's looking to legalize this sport.
So we're going to take a listen here at one time.
We come back.
We're talking all about what's going on today's lesson.
Did you hear the state is thinking of legalizing gambling in our city?
Soon you're going to have amazing hotels and casino's here, which would be good for
business.
Are you serious?
Gambling is a vice industry built on deception and fed by the intentional exploitation
of human weakness for the sole purpose of monetary game.
It discussed this.
What are you talking about?
How does it exploit people?
Wow.
To begin with, gambling is addictive.
It ruins marriages, destroys families, and bankrupt communities.
Once you're addicted, it's very difficult to stop.
People have lost their houses, cars, and have been left out on the street after becoming
addicted.
Secondly, it exploits because men become addicted to gambling most often because of the
action and risk.
Women gamble to escape, and senior citizens will start gambling for social interaction.
Underage gamblers often start gambling on sports with friends and then illegal bookies.
Geez.
Now that I think about it, maybe legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
Although I have been to lost vagas, and I didn't become addicted or anything like
that, you cannot predict who will be committed to gambling.
Now, excuse me, I have a protest value to organize.
All right, so a very strong opinion against gambling, right?
Absolutely.
So we've got someone who hasn't really thought it through, and another person who has thought
way too much about what's going on.
And well, he did point out some very interesting arguments against gambling.
And so we're going to take a look at some of the language that person used today in language
takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, this first thing we've got here is a word that has to do with the topic of today's
lesson.
So legalizing gambling.
What does it mean to legalize?
Right.
So to legalize, to make it legal.
So legal is the word that refers to law.
And so that means to make something okay, it means to allow something in a state or
country.
Exactly.
So in many countries, it's illegal to gamble.
So in this case, this city is looking to legalize it to make it legal.
All right, so many young people in America would like to see this law changed.
You're not allowed to drink until you're 21 years old.
Drink alcohol that is.
So they would like to see the legalization of underage drinking.
Now is it 21 in all states or in the majority?
Real states.
I thought it was only in some of them.
Now it changed in the late 70s, I think.
But you absolutely cannot drink until you're 21.
Wow.
What do you think?
Is that okay?
Or is that?
I think that it encourages young people to drink irresponsibly.
And so I believe we should legalize drinking at the age of 18 because it would make
people learn how to be more responsible.
Right.
Interesting.
We want to legalize underage drinking in English.
All right, now let's not mention it.
But this next word is very, very important.
He's saying that gambling or the gambling industry exploits people.
Okay, exploit.
You might have heard this in the news before.
We talked about often in the news.
The exploitation of people.
But in this case, we're talking about, yeah, exploiting people through money and gambling.
Right.
We exploit basically is to take advantage of them.
We have to use them for something, not to treat them as people, but to use them as a way
to get something.
All right, so we often hear about it as you're saying news about factories or companies
exploiting their employees or something of the sort.
We can also exploit the earth for its resources by taking oil and taking diamonds and
taking gold.
Okay, so to take advantage of, interesting.
So to exploit is the verb, but exploitation is the now.
All right, that's the thing.
So we talk about the exploitation of people in this country or the exploitation of
the earth.
And they're talking about how gambling exploits people and how it's a vice.
Ooh, vice is.
So for those of you, a Christians out there, you might be very familiar with the sins, right?
The seven deadly sins.
Well, these are all vices.
Things that you do that are bad.
So drinking too much is a vice.
Right.
Or eating too much, right?
Or spending money without having money may be a vice for you.
So addictions are also a type of vice, right?
Like drinking, smoking, or drug abuse.
Exactly, because they're all vices.
So vice is a bad thing.
Now we often, now we may remember this show, Poppy, the American show called Miami
Vice.
So what is that?
Well, Miami Vice, it's in the city of Miami.
I mean, it's about police officers.
So in the police, there's sometimes a group called the vice squad.
These are people who go out and try and stop people who are doing things that are vices.
Oh, like drugs and gambling.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Vise squad.
Interesting.
All right.
And now for the last word on language, take away this interesting word, a bookie.
So if any of you like to go to the horse races, you might be familiar with this one.
A bookie is someone who helps you make a bet.
It's his job to help you make a bet.
So we often see it in movies, maybe you are betting on a sports competition, right?
And you are betting on $10 against this team.
So you would go to a bookie to place your bet because they're not really any legal place
where you can do it.
Exactly.
Or if I want to say, okay, tonight, the Chicago Bulls are playing the sons and you want
to put $100 on the Chicago Bulls.
That means they're going to win.
So you use a bookie and he helps you put the money down.
Now, this is a legal, right?
Generally, it's a legal.
Yeah.
It depends on, I guess you can go to a bookie at the horse races and a legal bet.
But generally, it's a legal, I think.
Okay.
So a sports bookie, we would say a sports bookie, right?
Yeah.
Interesting words.
A lot of words related to, as we said, addictions and vices.
But that's, I guess, kind of what the whole gambling industry involves, right?
Absolutely.
All right.
So now that we've seen those great words on language, take away.
Let's move on now to fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay.
Fluency builders, where we get into some of this really exciting stuff, stuff where
we hear some opinions from a person who is not very happy with the gambling industry.
So this first one, gambling is an industry built on deception.
Okay.
So it's built on deception.
So it's an industry.
So it's not really tangible.
Right.
So this is a metaphor.
It's like saying that this industry is dependent on something.
What does it depend on?
Disception.
So it's deception.
So to deceive, right?
They come from the verb deceive, which basically says, like a false appearance, right?
Not really being completely truthful.
Okay.
It's really good.
So a lot of movies that we like to watch or theater is based on deception on a good
way because you get the idea that something is a certain way, but it really isn't in
real life.
So deception is in a theater maybe a good thing.
But in general, deception is a bad thing.
I could say, Marco, I'm sorry.
I deceived you.
You lied to me.
I lied to you.
Yeah.
So deception usually involves lies or trying to make something seem like something
that it's not.
Right.
Okay.
So this industry is built on deception and he said that the sole purpose of this industry
is to make money.
Exactly.
So this free sole purpose is very, very common.
You hear this a lot?
So like your human soul.
Like your human soul is spelled differently.
So you're talking about the one.
One only.
Yeah.
So my soul love.
Okay.
I only have one love.
My soul pair of shoes.
I only have one pair of shoes.
So it's one thing.
But the sole purpose.
So the only reason that this industry exists is what?
For monetary gain.
So monetary.
Monetary.
I've heard of the International Monetary Fund.
Exactly.
The IMF.
So monetary refers to money.
Money.
As the door said, it's a gas.
And the gain, which means basically means making it to get more money.
Yeah.
So that's the point that this person is making that the sole purpose of the gambling industry
is to make money.
Ouch.
So he's saying there's no other reason to gamble.
People are in this industry just to make money.
It's greedy.
Well, I mean, basically, you could probably say that almost about almost all the companies,
right?
But about education companies.
That's different.
Education is very different.
Absolutely.
So let's another industry that has a sole purpose.
For example, non-profit organizations.
Their sole purpose is to help people.
All right.
Okay.
I can get into that.
Yeah.
Cool.
So sole purpose and monetary gain.
Very useful phrases.
But let's take another listen to today's dialogue.
That put to you some of these great, great new words.
Did you hear the state is thinking of legalizing gambling in our city?
Soon you're going to have amazing hotels and casino's here, which would be good for business.
Are you serious?
Gambling is a vice industry built on deception and fed by the intentional exploitation
of human weakness for the sole purpose of monetary gain.
It discussed me.
What are you talking about?
How does it exploit people?
Well, to begin with, gambling is addictive.
It ruins marriages, destroys families, and bankrupts communities.
Once you're addicted, it's very difficult to stop.
People have lost their houses, cars, and have been let them on the street after becoming
addicted.
Secondly, it exploits because men become addicted to gambling most often because of the action
and risk.
Women gamble to escape and senior citizens will start gambling for social interaction.
Your age gamblers often start gambling on sports with friends and then illegal
books.
Geez.
Now that I think about it, maybe legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
Although I have been to Las Vegas and I didn't become addicted or anything like that.
You cannot predict who will be committed to gambling.
Now, excuse me, I have a protest value to organize.
All right, so gambling, what are your opinions about it?
Pro, gambling, or anti-gambling?
Okay, well, here's the thing.
Gambling is a sport.
And some it involves money, obviously, but people also don't, I don't think should have
other people telling them how to spend their money unless they have some kind of problem.
Right?
So the lot isn't getting involved if you have a drinking problem until you're harmful
to people around you.
So I don't think that it's right for the government to be able to say less than you
can't gamble because it's your own money.
If it makes you happy, it makes you happy.
Interesting.
Now, we've seen very specific cities or places where you can actually gamble in this way.
You have a monoco or Las Vegas or a cow more recently, right?
So very interesting cities or countries that have been built on the gambling industry, which
apparently is a multi-billion dollar industry.
I'm so, I don't know.
What do you think?
Do you, are you against gambling?
Are you for gambling?
I mean, is it one of those things that you can really, or do you maybe even like it?
Maybe some people don't even really care for it.
They don't find it fun to play Blackjack or go to the, play a round of poker or something
like that.
Yeah, well, that's their problem.
I enjoy it.
I think it's fun.
I mean, as long as with anything, you do it in moderation.
Right?
I mean, so you don't do it too much.
I think it's okay.
All right.
Listeners come to our website, EnglishPod.com to the comments section where you can
tell us, well, what are your opinions?
If you do, like gambling, tell us what game you like.
And also, if you have any questions or comments, we're always there to answer them, right?
It can be a big issue to talk about because some people are really against it and some
people are, right?
So curious to hear your opinions.
Yeah, we look forward to your opinions and we'll see you guys later.
Bye, everybody.