Hello English learners. Welcome back to English.
Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about something very serious.
Very serious. Today we're talking about capital punishment.
So if you've never heard that phrase before, you might have heard another name for this topic.
It's called the death penalty.
Right. So if you commit a crime and basically the judge says that you will have to be put to death for that crime.
All right. So many countries no longer have this.
This law, the United States, you can see it in some places, some states, but not in others.
So we're talking about today is the debate between to have the death penalty and to not have it.
All right. So we're going to actually have a little debate in the end of if we agree that we should have the death penalty or not.
But before that, why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time?
That's all for today's class.
We'll continue our lecture on crime and punishment tomorrow.
Do you think we should be tougher on crime?
Well, it depends on what you mean.
For example, we could bring back the death penalty for murder, give longer prison sentences for lesser offenses and lock up juvenile offenders.
Those sound like really draconian measures.
Firstly, what do you do about miscarriages of justice if you've already put innocent people to death?
You don't use capital punishment if you're absolutely sure that you'd convicted the right person.
But there have been many cases of wrongful conviction where people have been imprisoned for many years.
The authorities were sure at the time, but later it was shown that the evidence was unreliable.
In some cases, it had been fabricated by the police.
Well, no system of justice can be perfect, but surely there's a good case for longer prison sentences to deter serious crime.
I doubt whether they could act as an effective deterrent all the detection rate is so low.
The best way to prevent crime is to convince people who committed that they're going to be caught.
It doesn't make sense to divert all your resources into the prison system.
But if you detect more crime, you still need prisons.
In my reckoning, if we could lock up more juvenile criminals, they'd learn that they can't get away with it.
Soft sentences will merely encourage them to do it again.
Yes, but remember that prisons are often schools for criminals.
To remove crime from society, you really have to tackle its causes.
Well, if I were president, I would impose tougher laws and punishment.
I would have a peaceful society based on fear of punishment, not consciousness of doing the right thing.
You sound like a dick to here.
Well, if it works, why not?
Alright, so Markle, there's a lot of really great legal terms here, legal and crime terms.
And so let's look at a few of these in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so let's take a look at the first one.
They mentioned juvenile fenders.
Alright, so let's look at these two words because, um, well, a fender can be pretty general.
It's someone who commits a crime.
So an offender.
But we're talking about a special kind of a fender.
Here we're talking about juvenile offenders.
So they're young offenders.
Right, and in America, legally you're a juvenile offender if you're under the age of 18.
Okay, so if you commit a crime while you're a juvenile, you get judged differently.
Right? You don't get the same treatment as an adult.
Right, the usually the punishments are not as harsh because people like to think that younger people,
younger children or teenagers, they don't really understand the law.
They don't really understand crime or good and bad.
So it should be easier on them.
Hmm.
Alright, very good. So we have juvenile offenders and we also have a wrongful conviction.
Alright, this is an, oh, moment for a, for a judge because a wrongful conviction.
Well, conviction first of all is a decision.
So this is a court's decision on whether or not a person is guilty.
So you convicted the person.
Right.
Marco was convicted guilty of stealing my computer.
I was too, that happened.
Okay.
Right.
But it's a wrongful conviction if Marco didn't really still a computer, but we decided that he did.
Okay. So it was, it was a wrong decision.
Right, it was a bad decision in the sense that it's actually not what happened in reality.
Hmm.
A wrongful conviction, very good.
And actually related to a wrongful conviction many times it happens because evidence is fabricated by the police.
Alright, so this is a big no-no.
This is something that really shouldn't happen and it's against the law in many countries.
So fabrication or to fabricate is to fake to make something up.
Hmm.
And so evidence that's fabricated is, is evidence that the police or other people create
to try and make someone look guilty, but it's not actually evidence.
It's not really, it's not true.
It's not true.
Right.
And now moving on, they were talking about a deterrent for crime.
Okay, so to deter is a verb, to deter means to try and get someone to not do something.
Alright, so I'm going to try and deter my staff from taking early lunch breaks.
So I'm going to punish someone as a deterrent.
As a deterrent, okay.
So you have the verb deter and you have the noun a deterrent.
Right.
Yeah, and so oftentimes, very strict laws are meant to be deterrence.
They're meant to keep people from doing bad things from breaking the law.
Alright, so for example, capital punishment is one of those deterrence.
If you kill somebody, then if you get caught, you are also going to be killed.
So I mean, I'm never going to kill anyone because I don't want the law to decide that I'm going
to get killed.
Exactly.
And our last word for today, they were talking about imposing tougher laws.
I would impose tougher laws.
Okay, so to impose is a verb that means to put in place or to set up or enact.
And so by force, right, you don't really agree to do it.
Like the dictator imposes his will.
Alright, so he makes everyone do what he wants.
But we can impose measures that do something.
It's, yeah, it's kind of like forcibly making people follow some kind of rule or follow a person.
Now sometimes you would see that you have a company or you have people at your house and they're like,
well, you know, stay over for dinner and they're like, oh, I wouldn't want to impose.
Alright, so I wouldn't want to bother you or I wouldn't want to create more work for you.
Because, you know, when you're making food, you have all these people.
They don't want to impose on you.
Alright, so that's another way of using this impose on somebody.
Alright, so after all of these words that we've taken a look at,
why don't we start now with fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
Okay, so as you know fluency builders are placed where you get to talk about some phrases and words that allow you to
be more fluent in English. So these are sometimes idioms or sometimes phrases words that go together
commonly and the first one is no exception. It's a miscarriage.
So miscarriage of justice.
Alright, a miscarriage of justice. Now we have different words here.
The first one miscarriage is usually related to a medical term.
Right, it's a pregnancy that has a sad result.
It's a pregnancy where the woman's baby dies or the woman loses the baby.
And a miscarriage of justice is a metaphor.
It's a way to say that justice was not carried out.
It means that, for example, with those wrongful conditions,
the law failed to accomplish its objective.
Yeah, to accomplish its objective and to be fair.
Okay, so a miscarriage of justice.
Interesting. And moving on to our next phrase, they were talking and discussing this whole death penalty
situation and she mentioned in my reckoning.
Alright, so this is a great way to share your opinion or your idea with someone.
You're saying pretty much in my opinion, in my according to me or, you know, the way I'm thinking is this.
So I can also say I reckon, right?
Exactly. I reckon it's going to rain later.
I think it's going to rain. So in my reckoning, in my opinion.
Alright, I reckon. And to finish off fluency builder, they said that the person or the criminal
couldn't get away with it.
Alright, so this is another one of those phrases that each word maybe means something different.
You can get somewhere, but put together to get away with something means to do something bad.
Or illegal or that's not okay without getting caught.
Or being punished.
Or being punished. So you can say get away with murder.
You know, he got away with murder. You know, he did something that was really, really bad, but no
and caught him.
And also it means the criminal got away. So they couldn't catch him.
Right, or I could always say to my brother, he would always lie to my parents and get away with it.
So he never got caught. He never got punished.
Okay, so he got away with his lie or got away with it. Got his way.
Right. Alright, so I think this is an interesting phrase. Why don't we listen to a couple of more
examples.
Example one.
Do you think they could get away with using the cheaper product?
Example two.
Thieves got away with two Picasso's, which were never found.
Example three.
He almost got away with murder.
Unfortunately for him, the police discovered his secret.
So we've taken a look at a lot of great phrases. Why don't we listen to where
dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back.
That's all for today's class. We'll continue our lecture on crime and punishment tomorrow.
Do you think we should be tougher on crime? Well, it depends on what you mean.
For example, we could bring back the death penalty for murder, give longer prison sentences for
lesser offenses and lock up juvenile offenders.
Who sound like really draconian measures? Firstly, what do you do about miscarriages of
justice if you've already put innocent people to death?
You don't use capital punishment if you're absolutely sure that you convicted the right person.
But there have been many cases of wrongful conviction where people have been imprisoned for many
years. The authorities were sure at the time, but later it was shown that the evidence was unreliable.
In some cases, it had been fabricated by the police.
Well, no system of justice can be perfect, but surely there's a good case for longer prison sentences
to deter serious crime. I doubt whether they could act as an effective deterrent all the
detection rate is so low. The best way to prevent crime is to convince people who committed
that they're going to be caught. It doesn't make sense to divert all your resources into the
prison system. But if you detect more crime, you still need prisons. In my reckoning,
if we could lock up more juvenile criminals, they'd learn that they can't get away with it.
Soft sentences will merely encourage them to do it again.
Yes, but remember that prisons are often schools for criminals. To remove crime from society,
you really have to tackle its causes. Well, if I were president, I would impose tougher laws
and punishment. I would have a peaceful society based on fear of punishment, not consciousness
of doing the right thing. You sound like a dictator. Well, if it works, why not?
All right, so now the big question, Katherine. Do you agree with the death penalty?
Oh, this is a big one, and I don't think we have enough time to go into it in much detail here,
but I definitely think that is extreme, right? And so we have this phrase, a draconian measure.
Right, I think. I think that in the dialogue. Yeah, so draconian, something as draconian,
is excessive or severe, you know? And I think that there are a lot of reasons not to have the
death penalty. Because the death penalty, well, you're pretty much saying, we as a society think that
murder is wrong, but we're going to show you that you've done a wrong thing, like a bad thing,
that's against the law by killing you. All right, and so I have to disagree with that on a philosophical
level. But what about practical? Practically speaking, I think that there are a lot of problems with
the prison system and the legal system in the United States, for example, because prisons are really
crowded. One percent of the American population is imprisoned, and so I think that so long as the
prison system still has problems, there's a really good argument for having the death penalty,
but still, I think that it's excessive and it's unnecessary and that there are other ways to
punish prisoners. It is an interesting topic because you have many different angles that are in favor
or against the death penalty. For example, you have religious views where you say that you should not
take a life of another person no matter what, or you have other views that say that the death penalty
is simply wrong and that you can't write a wrong with another wrong. Right, exactly. So it kind of
doesn't make sense. But at the same time, you do, like you say, the prisons are full of people,
and it costs around, I think it's $12,000 a year per person to keep them in prison. So what do you
do with all of these people that have life sentences that are going to spend the rest of their lives in jail?
So it is interesting. And many countries are very, very strict with their legal system in
comparison with the United States, right? Definitely, but there is a statistic that's pretty stunning
that I think among the top 20 developed nations in the world, I think only the United States is
the one with the death penalty. Exactly. And actually, the ratio of the people compared to the
population that are in jail is much higher in the United States than in other countries. That's true.
So it is a very questionable topic, but we want to know what you think. Do you think that the death penalty
is just a viable way to do justice? Or do you think maybe it's just wrong and we shouldn't have it anymore?
Yeah, we're hoping that this will get the conversation going on our website. If you have any opinions
please let us know about them. Englishpod.com is the website and of course you can always email us
or send us a PM if you're a little bit shy. All right, so we'll see you guys there. Bye, everyone. Bye.