Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod.
We have an advanced lesson for you today.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine and I'm very excited about this lesson Marco.
It's very interesting.
It's about a very controversial topic and a very popular person in history, Charles Darwin.
That's right.
So he's most famous perhaps for his book The Origin of the Species and we're going to be talking
a lot about science today.
So put your thinking caps on.
How are I?
So without further ado why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time?
Man, it's been forever.
What have you been up to lately?
I've been busy preparing for my exams.
Not to mention all the term papers I've had or right.
Same here.
I'm up to my neck and work but at least you've got some of our holidays after finals.
Where you headed now?
I'm going to my anthro class.
We've been focusing on Darwin all term since it's a 200th anniversary of his birth or whatever.
I'm sick and tired of Darwin Darwin Darwin.
What?
Why?
How can you not like Darwin?
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
This theory of evolution revolutionized the field of biology and anthropology.
I don't like him.
His theory of human evolution and natural selection is full of holes.
It's not as solid as you make it out to be.
To save that again and you'll make enemies with half of the academy, not to mention
your professors.
Furthermore, the explanation proposed by Darwin about the origin of the species and the
process of natural selection constitutes a grand step towards a coherent understanding of
the world and its very beginnings.
I'm not minimizing his huge contributions to science.
It's just that his theory reminds me of the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
What are you talking about?
Which came first?
The chicken or the egg?
This is a classic logical problem and I think it applies to Darwin's theory.
How did the very first living organism come to be?
Interesting.
I think that question is better suited for my philosophy class.
In the meantime, how about we settle this?
With a duel!
All right, interesting.
They have very different views on Charles Darwin, right?
They do.
They're both pretty nerdy people.
This is a very nerdy university conversation that's happening between classes.
I think maybe they're like PhD candidates or something.
Before we get to talking about some of the ideas in today's dialogue, let's talk about
some of the words and phrases that we hear to understand better what's going on.
The first part we're going to talk about in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, on language takeaway today, let's take a look at the first word and well, one
of the things that many people say is that Darwin revolutionized the fields of biology.
So he revolutionized these because he pushed them forward.
He made many changes.
He forced changes.
So people had to change the way that they thought about these things.
If you revolutionize something a topic or an idea you are creating new knowledge almost,
right?
Exactly.
You can think of the word revolution, which is a thing.
So you think of the Russian revolution or the American revolution.
These are times of change.
So two revolutionized is to bring about change.
Very good.
So moving forward, they were talking about human evolution.
Human evolution.
What is that exactly?
Good question.
So you're not a monkey.
I'm not a monkey, but we come from monkeys, right?
So we evolved.
Right.
So the process is called human evolution.
That means the process by which humans changed forms to become what we are today.
Okay.
So you evolve.
Now is it evolution usually think of something positive, right?
Something evolves into something better?
Is it always that way?
No, we have another word for the negative.
So the positive is to evolve to become better, to get worse is to devolve.
Okay.
Yeah, to devolve, to go back and to kind of lose things that you had.
Okay, interesting.
And then they were also talking about Darwin's theory of natural selection, natural selection.
Okay, this is maybe one of the things that Darwin was most famous for, and that's why we've
included in this language takeaway because it's a key phrase.
It's something you hear people talk about along.
Okay, so natural selection is a process again, and it's the process by which stronger
animals survive over time and weaker animals don't.
So if there's a weak species, it can't really survive because it keeps dying and dying.
And then finally there's no more.
And so this is called natural selection because no one's actually choosing what animals
will survive, but it's kind of a natural process.
Right.
Mother nature is choosing it.
Very good.
This is one of the things that Darwin is most famous for.
And well, as Catherine mentioned, Darwin wrote the book Origin of the Species.
Right.
So origin means beginning.
So the origin of mankind.
Right.
So there are many different kinds of animals.
You can even see there are many different kinds of mammals.
But there are many different species within that.
So human beings, black bears, coalesce, chimpanzees.
These are all species.
So species is a classification.
So the origin of the species is kind of a way of telling the story of how all these things
came about.
Right.
The origin of the species.
And the last one, this word is kind of strange.
He talked about the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
Okay, conundrum.
I love this word.
It's very funny sounding.
Yeah, conundrum.
It means like a problem or a little or something that's hard to understand.
Right.
So in this case, it's the conundrum of the chicken and the egg, right?
Which came first.
How else can you use conundrum?
You could say that maybe there's a situation that's very strange and hard to understand.
This is quite a conundrum.
This is quite a conundrum we have.
Yes.
So it sounds very fancy, very well educated.
It does.
All right.
So interesting words on language takeaway.
Why don't we move on now to four phrases on fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right.
I'm fluency builder today.
We have four phrases as we said.
So what's the first one?
The first one is great.
It's very visual.
You say I'm up to my neck in work.
I'm up to my neck in papers to write.
Mm-hmm.
So this means I have so much stuff to do that you could pile it up and it would come up
to my neck.
So I have as many papers that are almost as tall as I am.
Exactly.
And so I could say I'm up to my neck in work.
I have no more time to do anything.
Sometimes people also say I'm up to here and then those like the point at their forehead
or somewhere around their head.
I'm up to here with your nonsense.
Exactly.
So this is a way of saying that I'm really busy.
Really busy.
I'm really tired of it.
All right.
And our next phrase is one that most mothers use.
I'm sick and tired.
Ah, I'm sick and tired of all of your whining.
Go do the dishes and don't complain.
Right.
So it always goes together.
You are sick and tired.
Right.
And sick comes first.
So I'm sick and tired of this.
I'm sick and tired of your bad attitude.
Okay.
And that means that you are, I'm just tired of it.
I don't want you to have a bad attitude anymore.
I'm just, yeah, I'm really annoyed by it.
I'm annoyed.
Okay.
Sick and tired.
And then we saw a phrase that was a little bit separated.
He said the sentence went like this.
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
So to turn something on its head.
Like you said, Markowitz, it's split into two parts.
So he turned the field of computer science on its head.
So to turn on its head means to completely reverse something, to turn it around.
You think 180 degrees.
Okay.
And so if biology used to be one way, then Darwin made it completely different.
So we can say that Isaac Newton completely turned physics on its head with his theory
or his findings on gravity.
And then years and years later, we had Albert Einstein who turned those theories, or
who turned that theory on its head with his own ideas about physics.
Very good.
So to turn something on its head to completely change the course of or prove something
to be maybe wrong.
And the last phrase that we have is the person argued that Darwin's theories were full
of holes.
Okay.
So to say a theory is full of holes is a little bit different than saying that his
pants are full of holes because when you say something is full of holes, maybe they actually
have holes.
But at theory is an idea.
So it can't have holes.
So you're saying is that it's not completely sound.
It's not without some problems.
And so maybe you're saying that, well, the cookies are gone out of the kitchen Marco.
And I saw you in the kitchen.
So clearly you ate the cookies.
Right.
So I can say that's full of holes because it was me and it was three other people who
were in the kitchen.
So you can't blame me.
But it went to a together two people.
Right.
So if something is full of holes is that it has maybe mistakes or it's still missing
complete evidence to prove it.
Or it has bad logic.
Bad logic.
All right.
Interesting.
So we've taken a look at a lot of words and different phrases here.
Let's listen to this argument one last time.
Man, it's been forever.
What have you been up to lately?
I've been busy preparing for my exams.
Not to mention all the term papers I've had or right.
Same here.
I've got to my neck and work, but at least you've got some of our holidays after
finals.
Where you headed now?
I'm going to my anthro class.
We've been focusing on Darwin all term since it's a 200th anniversary of his birth or
whatever.
I'm sick and tired of Darwin Darwin Darwin.
What?
Why?
How can you not like Darwin?
His work turned thousands of years of ideas about creation on their head.
His theory of evolution revolutionized the field of biology and anthropology.
I don't like him.
His theory of human evolution and natural selection is full of holes.
It's not as solid as you make it out to be.
Save that again and you'll make enemies with half of the academy.
Not to mention your professors.
Furthermore, the explanation proposed by Darwin about the origin of the species and the process
of natural selection constitutes a grand step towards a coherent understanding of the world
and its very beginnings.
I'm not minimizing his huge contributions to science.
It's just that his theory reminds me of the conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
What are you talking about?
Which came first?
The chicken or the egg?
This is a classic logical problem and I think it applies to Darwin's theory.
How did the very first living organism come to be?
Interesting.
I think that question has better suited for my velocity class.
In the meantime, how about we settle this?
With a duel!
We're back.
So, interesting this Darwin's theory and his explanations for the origin of species and life
as we know it.
But there is the opposite to this.
There is a certain thing called creationism.
There is.
This is a big source of controversy, especially in the United States because in some places,
people want to teach creationism as well as evolution in schools.
So this is the big question.
Are they still equal as theories or is one theory more proven than the other?
Right.
It is kind of hard to determine which one is better because one is based on faith.
The other one is based more on scientific evidence.
They're not really even the same on the same scale as we learned before.
That's like apples and oranges.
It is and there are some people who would say that we have lots of ways of quote unquote
proving what happened in the past.
But as long as we weren't there, we never really do no.
And there's always changes in science.
So how can we be sure that what we know now isn't false.
It isn't misunderstanding.
Right.
I think for now, this is the best explanation.
But that doesn't mean that it's the correct one.
It would be in a hundred years from now we'll have another explanation that's much better
or maybe complimentary to this one.
Well we want to know what you guys think come to our website EnglishPod.com.
We really want to hear your opinions.
What do you think about this topic?
It is a little bit controversial.
So we really look forward to your comments and any other questions you may have.
Yep.
And just a reference.
Creationism is the idea that God created the world or a superior being created the world
and that everything came from that.
And so let us know what you think I am very curious to.
And that's about it for today.
All right.
One more time.
Bye.