Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod at my name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we have a very scary story
we're actually bringing you the first of our advanced media lessons and what better way to start it with
than a scary story for Halloween than with.
So what better way to start this advanced media lesson than with a scary story?
Right so Halloween is coming up and advanced media usually features a new story or some kind of story that we can then kind of break down and talk about
just have a conversation about because your advanced level learners and you want to have fun with English.
So where is today's spooky story set Marco?
Well it starts out with a guy who remembers something very scary that happened to him when he was a kid.
Okay and so one of the main characters in today's story is his great aunt.
That's right his great aunt and so basically this is a family member but it's your father's aunt.
Right your grandmother or your grandfather's sister.
Right so your aunt is your parent sibling.
But in this case we're talking about one generation older than that so you could say great aunt, great uncle, great grandfather, great grandmother.
It's like one step back.
Right so this is usually a very old person and the great aunt is definitely an important character in today's story.
Exactly so let's not keep you in suspense any longer why don't we listen to this scary story and we'll be right back to talk about it.
I don't know the lights went out honey can you light a candle?
Sure what do we do now?
Well we can just talk you know like we used to.
I know I'll tell you a scary story it happened to me in my dad when I was a teenager.
I was living with my father at the time when he received a phone call.
Hello yes this is him.
I see sorry to hear that.
Okay no problem.
I'll be there shortly.
Packs and clothes, Connie, my great aunt is very ill and known in the family wants to take care of her.
We're going to stay at her house for a few days.
And what aunt I never knew you had a great aunt.
Well the family doesn't talk about her or get near her for that matter.
Why is that?
Come on we have to go.
So we arrived at this old house on the outskirts of our town.
There was almost no one around and the house had an eerie look to it.
Once inside the house we walked to her room and I was surprised to find my dad's great aunt in a wheelchair.
Yelling at someone but we were alone in the room.
Hi Ann Ursula this is my son Tony.
Why have you come?
Why are you here?
Don't you know it is in safe.
My time is near.
He's coming for me.
Who is coming for you?
The pranks of darkness.
The Lord of the underworld.
The temeter.
The skull.
Serpent.
Come on Ann Ursula let's lay you down.
You need to get some rest.
Tony help me lay her down.
That night we slept in one of the 12 rooms of that big old mansion.
The trees outside seem to come alive and their shadows formed a ghoulish shape on my bed.
All of a sudden we heard screaming.
Why are you standing?
I'm only saving you.
Dad, dad, dad something is attacking Ann Ursula.
The door is jammed.
Stand back.
Ann Ursula where are you?
Over here.
And as we approached her, she was lying on the floor with her hands and feet open like the
Vitruvian men.
Breathing heavily with bloody marks and scratches on her arms, legs and face.
Remember how I mentioned that she was in a wheelchair?
My aunts had been paralyzed from the neck down for just over a year.
After this incident, strange things would happen in the house, and my aunt would yell and scream.
According to her, warding off the evil that had come to get her.
As the days passed, she became very weak and eventually was unable to talk.
My dad had to ward during the day, so I was left to care for her.
When she lost her voice and laid on her deathbed, I would hear her breathe in and out.
It's a finally one day she breathed in and never excelled.
That night, I felt relieved that it was finally over, but it wasn't.
I was so terrified of what I was hearing that I didn't sleep all night.
The following morning, I went to the bathroom, expecting to find a mess and everything torn up.
But I found everything exactly as it was before.
The movers came that same day, and as we were cleaning out her drawers and personal items,
we found strange notebooks with names and amounts of money written next to them.
We found pictures with people's faces sewn with black or red string.
And you want to know what the strangest thing was?
There was a small doll filled with dead ants.
It was a strand of hair tied around its waist.
And on the doll's face, there was a picture of me with the numbers 31, 10, 0, 9.
You know what date it is today?
October 31, 2009.
Alright, we're back, so what do you think? Pretty scary.
Yeah, it's a little scary.
Now, what's interesting about this story, it's based on a true story, so that makes it even scary.
No.
There I has, there's happened to you.
No, no, I'm not old enough, but this actually happened to a family member of mine,
and that's why I know this story, so it was kind of told to me when I was a bit younger and I remembered it.
And well, Halloween is a great time to remember these things.
And the first time you heard it, it scared the crap out of you, right?
I have for sure.
Actually, the first time I heard it, we were on airplane, like, on October 31st.
Oh wow.
So it was pretty scary.
Well, we've got a lot of really interesting stuff here.
We're not going to dwell too long on the grammar or the vocabulary because we seem that most of you have understood this,
but there are a couple of things that can be really difficult even for English speakers.
So the first one is this phrase, my time is near.
My time is near.
So what does that mean exactly?
Well, my time is near.
My end is coming.
It means I'm very old and I'm probably going to die soon.
So my time is time.
That's when you die.
Okay, so it's always used in reference to death, right?
In this case, yeah.
So it's used in our friends to death, and in this case, we have the aunt who's talking about herself.
You could also say his time is coming.
We should visit him in the hospital.
So it's a kind of softer way of saying that someone is going to die soon.
Right.
Okay, so my time is near or his time is near.
All right.
And then something really interesting in this story as well.
She had many different names that she called the devil.
So she didn't directly say the devil.
She said the Prince of Darkness.
Prince of Darkness.
Lot of the underworld.
The Tempter.
The Tempter and the Old Serpent.
So these are actually different ways that historically have been used to describe the devil.
That's right.
And a lot of them are biblical, like the old serpent back in the first.
The first pages of the Bible when the serpent Temps.
That's that's exactly.
And so we hear a lot of these, especially on Halloween.
These are great words to use to kind of diversify and not say devil devil devil.
Right.
Okay.
So apart from those synonyms for the devil, she also used it interesting phrase towards the end when she said,
I shall be judged before you can take me.
Hmm.
So judge to judge.
This is to see if something is right or wrong.
But in this case, we talk about judgment at the end of a person's life.
So that means when you go to the gates of heaven and they're Saint Peter and he has a list of the good and the bad.
And he says yes or no.
Right.
And then if you're if you're if you're a know you get sent down to hell.
If you're yes you go to heaven.
So she says I shall be judged.
This means I want my day in court.
I want to to have my actions analyzed by Saint Peter.
Not by you.
Right.
Exactly.
So actually this makes reference to a lot of beliefs in Christianity, right?
So it's just another another aspect of the story, but of course.
But other religious probably don't have the same things such as the gates of heaven and Saint Peter.
The system of the system of judgment.
All right.
So what do you think of the story did you like it?
I really liked it.
I thought it was really spooky and I thought that it built up well.
But I really I also like the imagery.
We talked about or we haven't talked about this yet, but he describes.
He describes his great on the character describes great on his being spread out like the vitrovy in man.
So you have this image of her arms spread out in her legs spread out.
You know that picture that Da Vinci did of a human being and it's like an anatomy and it's in a circle and you can see the legs and the arms.
That's just so really like a powerful visual image.
Yeah, you can imagine her laying on the bed in this position, right?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, it is pretty scary.
What about you have you ever had any close encounters with the supernatural or ghost sort of goblins or something like this?
No, personally I've never had any experiences like that.
And I tend to not believe those stories, but maybe if this is happening to someone I knew I'd be a little bit more skeptical or less skeptical.
But what about like when they have those documentaries or those recordings of strange voices or appearances like these old castles and inkland or stuff like that, what do you think?
I love those shows.
I just watched one and it was about a haunted house.
There was a woman who used a wijie board that let a demon out and the demon possessed the girl and they called in a priest and the priest had to like exercise the demon from the little girl and the house was haunted and it was hurting people and it was like possessing people.
Wow, sounds like a movie.
Yeah, that is, but it was like a TV show on Discovery Channel and it was a really really really fun.
But like I don't actually believe that like a spirit could push someone down the stairs.
I think that you trip in the new attribute it to a spirit.
What about the wijie board? That's an interesting tool that many people say opens up you know like portal portals and dimensions towards hell or spirits can come out and stuff like that.
Right, well for those of you who don't know the wijie board is a board like a piece of cardboard that has letters on it letters and numbers and so you have this glass that you hold.
And once the spirit comes it guides the glass to point out to names or places and you spell them.
And they're really popular. We're like 13 year old girls who have these summer parties and they use it and we have to say you know who's she can a date and then go.
And it moved.
But yeah, I believe in the power of the human mind.
So I think a lot of times even if we're not aware of it were the ones manipulating this.
Or believing what we want to believe.
Yeah. But what about you or you superstitious or you believe in ghosts?
I'm not superstitious. I don't know what to think about ghosts because I've actually had a couple of very strange encounters with the supernatural but I really wouldn't say oh yeah.
I believe in ghosts or I believe there's spirits that haven't been put to rest or they haven't finished business you know like in Casper or something like that.
Yeah.
But once we were having dinner with my family and in the house where we used to live and it was a very old house and we had a glass of water on the table and all of a sudden it started to move and rotate across the table to center of the table and we all sighed and no one was touching it.
So we all were pretty confused and nervous and then just kind of burst out and nervous laughter and we didn't really know what to make of it.
But it was very strange because it moved a good amount towards like half of the table and it was spinning at the same time so it was very strange.
So so things like this and you know in general his Hispanic or Latin American culture are they're very superstitious.
They have a lot of beliefs and like magic or some people still say are reluctant to give out a picture for example because of something like this in the story.
So you shouldn't give out pictures to boyfriends or girlfriends or anyone because if you break up or something is to happen then they could do something with that picture and maybe hurt you.
Really so this idea that you have a like likeness like a picture or a doll or something.
What can you say about that because I don't I didn't really know anything about it having that means that you're able to like do something to that very person.
Yeah, yeah, like not necessarily like a voodoo doll right where you see that you can put pins in it and then you can put it in.
It would hurt someone but people believe that pictures for example they capture your image and so if somebody has it and wants to do harm or black magic then they can use that as a as an instrument to get into you.
The same as pieces of clothing or the serness hair and things like this so that's why there are the shaman's or the you know the Indian.
The Indian witch doctors who do cleansing like this and people still actually go to them people in the city still believe in these things and they'll go to a shaman and get themselves cleans because they believe that they're luck.
They have really bad luck or they've been very, very sick for a long time and doctors can't figure out what it is they think it's because someone has cast a spell on them or is doing some black magic to them and they need to get it cleansed.
Wow, so yeah, it's really really common but it's all part of the folklore and the heritage of of the countries and you know it's actually very, very interesting and some things are just really out there really weird.
Yeah, well a lot of it I think comes from indigenous beliefs mixing with catholicis and too right because a lot of South American countries and Latin American countries are very Catholic but it's it's they get kind of melded these frictions with.
Yeah indigenous beliefs and then you have these crazy rituals and like we actually have a belief and it's very true that you know when somebody is completely in love with this girl and this girl is like maybe.
You know not very nice or not very nice to that guy but he's still completely into her so.
There's this word that we say that that he's been like underwared or something like that and and the reason behind this is that one of these rituals that I talked about is that the girl would.
Make tea right would take a tea pot and in it would put her her underpants used underpants to make the tea water and then would serve it to the guy so the moment that he drank it this was like a magic potion and he would continuously be in love with her.
So yeah, it's very strange.
It's gross if you like to do that.
No, it's not something that you do now it's but it's something that has that people knew about that used to be done way way before.
Okay, so people now it's part of the language where you see that someone has been like underwared or something.
She casts a spell and yeah, maybe what we would say.
So things like this that of course aren't really done anymore, but still people make reference to it because we know it from our history that that it's been there before.
How cool. Well, I'm really curious to know if our users have any similar stories or have any scary stories they want to tell.
That they do.
I'm sure they do and this advanced me lesson is a great place for you to do that because we expect that a lot of advanced level learners are going to be listening to it and practicing your writing is really important.
So we hope that you'll put some comments on this lesson and of course ask us as many questions as you want.
All right, so we'll see you guys there and have a happy Halloween happy Halloween.
Thank you.