Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we are here with an advanced level lesson. That means that
we're going to listen to it pretty long and exciting dialogue and we'll talk a little bit about
what you've heard and some of these cool interesting phrases. That's right today we have a lesson
about planning a crime. We're planning a bank robbery. My favorite. There have been lots of movies
about this topic. Very fun movies. From the beginning of movie making so now it's a very popular
topic. That's right. I'm this occasion as Katherine said. It's a nice fun dialogue and we're going
to have a lot of colloquial terms. So maybe you won't really understand a couple of different phrases
because they're very colloquial. They're very American terms. And the accents are also they're
a little bit from like Boston kind of like New Jersey, maybe or something. Right. So keep in
ear out for some of the strange or unusual phrases. We will be talking about them in a moment.
But don't worry if you don't understand this dialogue the first time you'll be hearing it again later.
All right. Let's run through this one more time from the top. I will be position here across
from the bank on this park bench. Now according to the intel we got from Jimmy.
Geez Ralph pay attention. Well yeah. Jimmy's our mole. You know the guy on the inside. He's been
snooping and passing on the info to us so we can pull this high stuff. Yeah Ralph clean the
mouthballs out of ears and listen up. This year's important. We don't want to end up back in the
doya. Your role is pretty important here with depending on you man. Okay okay I'm listening.
More balls. All righty then where was I? Oh yeah okay. So I'll be on the lookout
sitting here on the bench across from the bank. Nobody moves until I give the go ahead. All right.
And what's the go ahead Ralph? You um you uh oh yeah you'll take off your hat and scratch your head.
Right. When I take my hat off and scratch my head you do what? Again the box.
Right you get in the box. I'll make sure it's all sealed and then posing as the delivery guy.
I'll drop off a special package for the manager. Now according to Jimmy the bank manager's
leaving early on Tuesday because it is wedding anniversary. He and the wife are having a romantic
rendezvous in the country so any packages deliver will be left unopened in his office until it gets
on Wednesday. Which gives us access to his office for at least 12 hours. Okay Ralph this is where you
come in. Where are you? I'm standing right next to you Sammy. Oh sorry Sam I'm in the box right here
in that box. And what do you do once I deliver you to the manager's office? I stay in the box until
the bank is closed and then I get out of the box. And then what next Ralph? Oh for Pete's sake this is
never going to work. Hey come here chance your fellows. I crack the safe and then
then I take the money and then I um well I get back in the box. Add a boy Ralph in the morning.
I come back to the bank say there's been a mix up with the delivery I made and take the special
package back here. All right let's get some sleep it's a big day tomorrow fellas.
A perfect plan Sammy it went off without a hitch. Let's open this up and get Ralph out of here so we
can start counting the money. Feel I sure I'm glad to see you guys I was sure getting lonely with
no one to talk. That's nice okay how much? Really really really really glad. Money Ralph money.
Oh man a new one forgot something damn it.
All right we're back so um obviously the this guy Ralph I don't know why always the the one
Robert whose name is Ralph is not very clever. No it doesn't mean that Ralphs are generally
not smart people but yeah I think you're right there's usually like in bank robberies or something
like for example in the old movies always Ralph was the one that was messing things up.
Oh Ralph well let's find out what Ralph screwed up today first of all we've got um we've got the
guys Sammy Ralph and Frankie we're talking about the plan okay and Sammy mentions that he had
the Intel from Jimmy okay so when we talk about Intel we're talking about information right
that's right so Intel is a word that's short for intelligence or facts or information that's
right so you can talk about intelligence as maybe you're very smart you have your very intelligent
but when we talk about intelligence we talk about gathering information in order to help us
accomplish an objective. For example in movies about the CIA we often hear them talk about gathering
Intel that means collecting facts. Right very good so they had Intel from Jimmy about the bank and the
layout and well they were like who's Jimmy in in and Sammy says that well he's our mole you know
the guy on the inside a mole so mole is an animal right but in cases of intelligence or maybe in this
case a bank robbery spying a mole is a person who's basically stealing information. So for example
if I work in the CIA but I'm selling information from the CIA to the French government I'm a mole
right so you're basically like a spy yes you're you're a person on the inside and and that's
what they mean when he says he's our guy on the inside you're inside the enemy territory or
inside their organization. Exactly so for example have you seen the show 24 yeah with Jack
power well they often have this problem of moles inside the organization so maybe the terrorists
the terrorists have a guy on the inside. That's right he's a mole. So they have somebody that has penetrated
their organization. Exactly okay so they talk about the mole and how they are going to pull this
off. Okay so the phrase here is to pull off a heist first of all what's a heist? Well a heist is a robbery
is a is a basically a robbery. Yeah it's another word for robbery so it's kind of old though you don't
really say it anymore right? No you can say that's a heist movie or it's a movie about a heist. It's almost
like a genre you know there's a there's a basic storyline where they plan the robbery they do the
robbery something goes wrong what's going to happen so that's a heist. Very good so a heist is
something that was planned out like a robbery that's planned out it's not really if you come up to
someone and it's a give me your wallet that's not really I know that's a stick up. Right but a heist
is something that you pull off so to pull off is to succeed to accomplish. We'll accomplish so
I pulled it off I was able to do it. So you pulled off the heist very good and well they were talking
about if they do it they don't want to get caught because they don't want to go back to the slamer.
Oh the slamer yeah well I don't blame them I wouldn't want to go to the slamer either. So what is
the slamer? The slamer the big house right lock up the slamer the big house all these are
collocials hidden in them for prison for jail jail so normally we say prison or jail like it's a
maximum security prison like prison break the TV show. Right but in collocial English we often say
slamer. Okay the slamer or the big house. Okay so they were talking that they don't want to go
back to the slamer and now when they were actually planning out the crime yeah he says well you
wait until I give you the go ahead. Okay so this is the plan he's going to wait for a sign. The go ahead
means a sign that indicates that it's time to do something. Okay so for example so in this case what
is that sign? The sign or the go ahead is he'll take off his hat and scratch his head. Okay so that's
a sign that means it's okay to proceed it's okay to continue. Right so you can also say okay when we're
ready to go Marco I'll give you the go ahead. Okay just wait for me to wait. Okay very good so that's
the go ahead. The signal. Exactly. All right very good. Now moving on we have a French word here
but it's used very commonly in English and they said okay we have a rendezvous. Okay so a rendezvous
is a meetup or a time or place where people are connecting together. So for example in a
high you could say we're going to wrap the bank and then we will rendezvous at our favorite restaurant
in two hours. Okay so rendezvous is to meet up to get together. Right but in this case they're
talking about a romantic rendezvous so this means a trip with a lover. Aha so it's a little bit
different right he and his wife are having a romantic rendezvous in the country. Okay that means that
they're going to have a romantic meeting. Aha okay very good and now this next phrase is very very
interesting it's it's very common to hear it as well. I think like mom say it a lot.
Oh for Pete's sake. Oh for Pete's sake. Well I don't know who Pete is honestly but this means
my gosh or come on or I'm so tired of this. So you're a little bit exasperated maybe you're a little bit
irritated. Oh for Pete's sake Marco stop giving me examples. I'm just I'm done hearing them. Yeah
so there are a lot of other ways to say this right? Yeah so you could say for goodness sake.
For goodness sake or oh for heaven's sake. For heaven's sake and finally for god's sake. Right but
this one you have to be careful because some people who are religious might be offended if you use it.
So if that's the case and you would just rather go with Pete's sake heaven's sake or or goodness sake.
Okay for goodness sake. It's a very common phrase and as you say it's for when you're a little bit
irritated like oh for goodness sake stop complaining. Exactly right. Okay and now for our last word
you may have seen the word fellas fellas. So this comes from the word fellow person man.
But oftentimes in in these kind of movies or stories about heists or crimes the men talk to each other
using the word fella or fellas. So come on fellas let's go. That means come on guys come on everyone.
Okay yeah so this is always about men not like a group of women with these this. Right.
And and it's something that's a little bit older we don't really say this like oh me and my
fellas we're gonna go to the store. You would say this more in old time English. Yeah you can see
it maybe in some movies when somebody comes up and greets other people other guys. He would say hey fellas.
Exactly or there's a mafia movie it's about the american mafia called good fellas.
Uh-huh very good. It's a very famous one so kind of gives you that feeling of an older English like the
1940s with the 1970s. Okay very good. A lot of interesting things going on in this
bank robbery why don't we go back listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a little bit.
All right let's run through this one more time from the top. I will be positioned here
across from the bank on this park bench. Now according to the intel we got from Jimmy.
Geez Ralph pay attention will ya? Jimmy's our mole you know the guy on the inside. He's been
snooping and passing on the info to us so we can pull this high stuff. Yeah Ralph
clean the mouth balls out of ears and listen up. This year's important we don't want to end up
back in the slam at doya. Your role is pretty important here with depending on you man.
Okay okay I'm listening. Mark balls. All righty then where was I? Oh yeah okay. So I'll be on the
lookout sitting here on the bench across from the bank. Nobody moves until I give the go ahead.
All right and what's the go ahead Ralph? You um you uh oh yeah you'll take off your head and
scratch your head. Right when I take my head off and scratch my head you do what?
Again the box. Right you get in the box. I'll make sure it's all sealed and then posing as
the delivery guy. I'll drop off a special package for the manager. Now according to Jimmy the bank
manages leaving early on Tuesday because it's his wedding anniversary. He and the wife are having
a romantic run day boo in the country so any packages deliver will be left unopened in his office
until he gets back late on Wednesday. Which gives us access to his office for at least 12 hours.
Okay Ralph this is where you come in. Where are you? I'm standing right next to you Sammy.
Oh sorry Sam I'm in the box right here in that box. And what do you do once I deliver you to
the manager's office? I stay in the box until the bank is closed and then I get out of the box.
And then what next Ralph? Oh for Pete's sake this is never going to work. Hey give me a chance
your fellas. I crack the safe and then then I take the money and then I um I get back in the box.
Add a boy Ralph in the morning I come back to the bank say there's been a mix up with the delivery
I made and take the special package back here. All right let's get some sleep. It's a big day to Mara
fellas.
A perfect plan Sammy it went off without a hitch. Let's open this up and get Ralph out of here so we can
start counting the money. Feel I'm sure I'm glad to see you guys. I was sure getting lonely with
no one to talk. That's nice okay how much? Really really really really glad. Money Ralph money.
Oh man a new way for God's something. Damn it.
Okay so someone proclaimed at the end of the dialogue that everything went off without a hitch.
Is this true? No. What does it mean if something went without a hitch?
It went off without a hitch means there was not even one problem. It went off. It went perfectly.
Smoothly. Smoothly yes. Okay and it didn't because well these robbers didn't actually
rob any. Right he forgot to get the money. Right so it kind of an idiot.
Right but there are actually a lot of good movies I think the most recent one about main
robberies is uh oceans 11 oceans 12 oceans 13. Yeah that's right those are all about big
heights. Big heights and I think they mentioned the word heist a couple of times and that would be.
Yeah definitely so there was a movie with Clive Owen a few years ago called the inside man
that was maybe one of the best heist movies I've seen in a long time. Yeah that was a really good
movie. I think also Swordfish was a pretty good movie with John Gwaltou. Yeah I remember that one too.
Yeah I like it when the bad guy's win. You know because it's it's a it's a little bit more
interesting. Yeah I guess you could say that. I don't think the public likes this.
Well in the inside man the bad guy is kind of a good guy but he wins. Uh huh. Yeah like that. Yeah
so uh but it's a very interesting topic and uh I don't know I haven't really heard of many
bank robberies nowadays anymore. Not so much I think security and banks is pretty good but uh
I'd be very curious to hear from our users if they have any favorite heist stories or movies real or fake
both are okay. Now you can let us know on our website EnglishPod.com. That's right all right we'll see
everyone there. Bye. Bye.