Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got a very advanced dialogue for you. This is all about
what we call the miracle of light. That's right today. We're going to talk a little bit more in depth
about our bodies, about what's going on inside and how and where babies come from. That's right.
So you're going to learn very technical terms for parts of people's bodies, men and women and also
about the beginning of life. So before our baby is born, what do you call some of these
parts and some of these things? So let's check out today's dialogue and when we come back,
we'll be exploring in depth these topics.
Continuing with our class, today we are going to study briefly the miracle of life.
Many of you may think you already know how babies come to be, but I'm sure that some of the
things we will be talking about today may surprise you. Billy, can you turn on the projector please?
Thanks. Okay, does anyone know what this is? It looks like a goat had to me.
Nice try, but this is a woman's womb which contains her uterus and ovaries. The ovaries are packed
with eggs and each month during the middle of the menstrual cycle. The ribest one will be sucked
up by one of the philopiantups. This is called ovulation and the exact time of ovulation depends
on the length of a woman's cycle. In an average 28-day cycle, ovulation will most likely happen
between the 12th and 15th days, counting day one as the first day of your last period.
That's amazing. So each month the woman produces these eggs and then waits for them to be fertilized.
Actually, every woman is already born with over 400,000 eggs. Some will start dying off immediately
and others are released during her fertile period. What about the guys? I know they produce sperm
and stuff. That's right, the man's body has a tiny factory. They produce his sperm 24 hours a day.
Each ejaculation will release about 100 million sperm so the factory is always pretty busy.
The sole purpose of a sperm's life is to fertilize the woman's egg. So, then we basically need to put
one one together so we can have babies, right? Yes, the man will have an orgasm during intercourse
and ejaculate sperm and semen. Now, this is where the race begins and all those millions of
sperm will race and swim from the cervix through the uterus and to the philopiantubes. This could
take anywhere from 45 minutes to 12 hours. Not all of the make it since some of them go the wrong
way and get lost or simply die. Many will actually reach the egg with only one will penetrate it
and fertilize it. Once this happens, the egg instantly changes and creates a protective shield once
the sperm is safely inside. And then that's it? Well, the egg will be fertilized within about 24
hours of its release. The genetic material from the sperm combines with the genetic material in the
egg to create a new cell that will rapidly start dividing. The woman is not actually pregnant
until that bundle of new cells known as the embryo travels the rest of the way down the philopiantubes
and attaches itself to the wall of her uterus. Any other questions? Then let's move on.
All right, we're back. So very interesting. Actually, this type of lecture or class that
that we just saw is very common in biology class or anatomy class in the US, for example.
That's right. We also have a class called sex ed or sexual education. And this is all about sex
and bodies and biology that most students have to learn before they go into high school. That's right.
We actually had a previous lesson about sex ed. We talked about contraceptives and well continuing
on on the topic. This is why we have this advanced lesson. Now it is a little bit more difficult
because we have medical terms and specific names of parts inside of our body. So why don't we
start with the first one when the teacher explained about a woman's womb? So this might look like a
very hard word to pronounce. There's a B there. So WOMB we don't pronounce womb but we say womb.
And this is basically where the baby will grow when a baby is produced. So it's a part inside
of a woman's body that we also call the uterus. Okay, so I guess the uterus is the specific
name of that area, right? But I guess the whole thing kind of like the women's belly where the
baby is going to be is called the womb. That's right. Okay, so now taking a look at
other parts of the women's body. We have the womb, we have the uterus. Now what about the ovaries?
So ovaries are actually there are two of them in a woman's body and ovaries are where eggs are
stored. So women have eggs and this is what will one day become in some cases of baby. And so
they are stored in ovaries and when it's time to come down they come down through the uterus
through these tubes to either come out or to be met by a sperm. Right, and these tubes are actually
called phlobion tubes. So hard word phlobion, again there are two of these, right? One from each ovary
and they come down and that's basically a passageway for eggs. That's right, and it's interesting
because in English some women that don't want to have any more kids, they very
locally say I have my tubes tied or I had my tubes tied. That's right, so this means a woman has
had an operation so that she will not have children in the future and her phlobion tubes are
closed off so that eggs cannot come down. That's right, so this is kind of now you more or less
if you've heard this phrase before now you understand why the phlobion tubes and that's what women
say tubes tied. Yeah, she had her tubes tied. All right, so now all of this is going on because
well a woman can potentially get pregnant and during this period of time this is when the woman
is ovulating or this is called ovulation. That's right, so ovulation is a cycle. That means
it's something that happens again and again and again we call it a menstrual cycle and it happens
once basically it's a process that takes 28 days and it's the process of an egg coming down
and either being fertilized or not. That's right, so during ovulation there is a certain period
of time where it's a precise for a woman to be able to get pregnant, right? And now what about when
we move on to the men? Now we talked about the women's side, what about the men's? So basically
women have eggs, men have sperm. Okay, these are a little, they look like fish almost, they swim around
and they are past two women through semen and men have, I don't know, like 10 million of them
or something crazy. It's a huge amount of sperm. Now this is an interesting thing to differentiate.
You said two things, sperm and semen, right? So sperm are the little creatures or little fish
as you said that that swim and semen is kind of actually like the liquid that contains them.
That's right, so it's almost not bigger than but it's the liquid that they come in to a
baby basically attack an egg and try and fertilize an egg. And so remember, in English,
sperm can fertilize an egg. Semen cannot. Right, and now this is interesting, we're talking
about two fertilize. Maybe we've heard this in gardening or something like this, we've heard a fertilizer,
but what do we mean by two fertilize or fertilization? Okay, basically fertilization or to fertilize
something is to, in this case, put a sperm together with an egg. So to make a baby. That's right.
And so an egg that is not fertilized will come down and will never become a baby.
Sometimes sperm, they don't find eggs and they just, you know, they die. Now there's another
interesting word that's very related or close to this when we say when a man or a woman is fertile.
That's right, so this only applies to women, not to men. You can say she's fertile. That
means she has eggs, her eggs come down and she can have a baby at some time. But a woman who is
in fertile, she's not fertile, can never have babies. That's right. So a lot of these women
adopt babies. Now what about guys? You know that some men can't have babies as well. Maybe their
sperm is not very good or they have something, the same thing, medical condition that prevents
their sperm from fertilizing. So you don't say that he is in fertile or not know. No, you don't.
What do you say? He is sterile. Okay. So a woman can be fertile or in fertile.
In fertile means she cannot have babies. If a man's seem and cannot fertilize an egg properly,
he is called sterile. Okay, very good. So this is all of what's going on inside the man's body as well.
And we'll actually once they finally combine and get together and they
and the sperm fertilize the egg, we have a little thing called an embryo. Okay, so obviously it doesn't
become a baby for a little while. This is a point of contention, a point of argument, for a lot of
people because they don't know when a grieve went a baby becomes a baby. But basically when an
egg and a sperm come together, they create an embryo, which is a combination of
genetic information and tissue and all these things and that starts to grow and to become a fetus,
which will one day when it is born become a baby. That's right. So the embryo is basically the
first stage of when the baby is forming. But it's not really, as you said, this word fetus,
it's not in our dialogue, but a fetus is actually a formed being, sort of say, inside a woman's body,
right? It's growing. It's because it's starting to get the pieces that it needs to become a human being,
but maybe has not fully developed yet. So it's still inside the woman's womb, you can say.
Very good. Okay, a lot of interesting things going on. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again
and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Continuing with our class, today we are going to study briefly the miracle of life.
Many of you may think you already know how babies come to be, but I'm sure that some of the things
we will be talking about today may surprise you. Billy, can you turn on the projector please?
Thanks. Okay, does anyone know what this is? It looks like a goat had to me.
Nice try, but this is a woman's womb, which contains her uterus and ovaries.
The ovaries are packed with eggs and each month during the middle of the menstrual cycle.
The ribest one will be sucked up by one of the philopiantubes. This is called ovulation and the exact
time of ovulation depends on the length of a woman's cycle. In an average 28-day cycle,
ovulation will most likely happen between the 12th and 15th days, counting day one as the first
day of your last period. That's amazing, so each month the woman produces these eggs and
in weights for them to be fertilized. Actually, every woman is already born with over 400,000 eggs.
Some will start dying off immediately and others are released during her fertile period.
What about the guys? I know they produce sperm and stuff.
That's right, the man's body has a tiny factory that produces sperm 24 hours a day. Each
ejaculation will release about 100 million sperm, so the factory is always pretty busy. The sole purpose
of a sperm's life is to fertilize the woman's egg. So, then we basically need to put one
one together so we can have babies, right? Yes, the man will have an orgasm during
intercourse and ejaculate sperm and semen. Now, this is where the race begins and all those
millions of sperm will race and swim from the cervix through the uterus and to the philopian tubes.
This could take anywhere from 45 minutes to 12 hours. Not all of the make-it since some of them
go the wrong way and get lost or simply die. Many will actually reach the egg with only one
and will penetrate it and fertilize it. Once this happens, the egg instantly changes and creates
a protective shield once the sperm is safely inside. And then, that's it? Well, the egg will be
fertilized within about 24 hours of its release. The genetic material from the sperm combines
with the genetic material in the egg to create a new cell that will rapidly start dividing.
The woman is not actually pregnant until that bundle of new cells known as the embryo
travels the rest of the way down the philopian tube and attaches itself to the wall of her uterus.
Any other questions? Then let's move on.
All right, so this whole aspect we understand how the miracle of life works, right? This is what it's
called having babies the miracle of life. It's even the name of the video we are forced to watch
when I was 12 years old and I still have nightmares about it. Well, it is interesting. It is
almost a miracle because you are basically creating something out of nothing almost, right?
That's right. And what's amazing about it is that two people who have different genetic material
and who have different experiences and who have different parts to their bodies come together
and create something that's a combination of all those things. So it's almost kind of like a
game of surprise. You don't know what's going to happen. Are they going to have red hair or green eyes
or the me taller, shorter, or fatter, then? Exactly. Now talking about this aspect that you mentioned
before, it's controversial when there is life or when if the embryo is a baby or it's not,
this is because of many countries or cities or states that are discussing the legalization or not
abortions. That's right. So the reason this is a problem for a lot of people is because no one
agrees on when a fetus becomes a baby. And so that will determine for a lot of people when it is
okay to abort the fetus or to kill it and when it is not. Right, because I've heard that some
people say well in your first month, if you've already been pregnant for a month, the baby already
has a certain parts formed or even I think the hearts beginning to form. So they say you are
already pregnant. I mean, you already have a life inside you. Well, they're saying well no,
it's actually after two months because then the baby has a heartbeat. I'm not really sure about the
time tables that I'm giving you. I'm giving you more or less a rough outline, but this is the controversy.
That's right. And so it affects laws in many countries, it affects what medical practitioners
like doctors and nurses can do. And it's always, I think, been an issue as long as I've been alive.
Yeah, actually the whole abortion topic is a big political debate between people who are against it,
who are in favor of it. So it's very interesting and actually it's still very much illegal in
many places in the world. Absolutely. And it's it changes, I think, according to where you are in
America as well. So some states have different laws about it and some states are more lenient, for example.
And actually this is a spondy whole new controversy that with the emergency pill,
that basically, if you maybe are in risk of being pregnant, then you take this pill in a kind of
prevents fertilization or if fertilization occurred already, then it kind of prevents further growth
of the embryo. Right. Basically, it's called the emergency contraceptive and it's taken after you
think you might be pregnant. So maybe if you didn't use other contraceptives like a condom,
and you think maybe one of your eggs as a woman was fertilized by sperm, it makes you have your
period. It makes you menstruate. I mean, your whole, your whole, the lining of your uterus and any egg,
even if it was fertilized, comes out. Right. And it's in some cases, people think of it as a kind of
abortion. That's right. So yeah, it's very interesting how the more that we understand about medicine
and how how life works. Well, there have been advancements as well, like contraceptives that
not only prevent unwanted pregnancies, but also prevent transmission of disease, sexually transmitted.
But at the same time, other things like this, like the emergency contraceptive and abortion
start popping up. So I think it's exactly. So a very interesting topic, as we said, controversial,
but at the same time, very much beautiful because we are talking about how our bodies work and how
everyone came to existence. And how babies are born, everyone loves babies. That's right. So we're
really interested to get your insights, your opinion about anything that we've talked about today.
And if you have any other questions or comments, you can always reach us at EnglishPod.com.
Yeah, we hope to see you there. And I hope this will start a nice conversation on our website.
Remember, keep it clean. Yeah, that's right. All right. So we'll see everyone there. Bye.