Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have an advanced level lesson for you. This
one's a bit difficult. It's all about science.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about physics specifically about things like
Stephen Hawking and wormholes, black holes and general theory of relativity and all that good stuff.
Right. So we're in class. We're learning about physics today and you're going to hear a lot of terms.
Don't worry if you're not really sure what they mean, we'll be back in a moment to talk about them.
Good morning everybody. Welcome to physics 101. My name is Ed Brown and I will be your professor
for this semester. Since the days at first day, I wanted to give you an overview of what this
course will look like, how you will be graded and what we will cover this semester.
Will we be focusing more on theoretical physics or experimental physics professor?
This is an introductory course. And my aim is to give you a broad overview of the field of physics.
The term physics encompasses many different areas of research and study,
and I hope this course will provide you with a conceptual understanding of physics,
which will prove useful whether or not you choose to further your study in the field.
We will begin the course by looking at the fundamental concepts of physics.
Then by the middle of the semester, we will begin exploring the more theoretical side of physics.
It is essential that you first have a firm grasp of the fundamentals,
so that you can better understand the theoretical concepts when we get to them.
Will we learn about black holes, worm holes and string theory?
We will learn about the general theory of relativity, including black holes.
We will also explore the developing theories in quantum mechanics, such as string theory.
We will discuss some hypothetical features of space-time like worm holes.
We will also explore some of the more influential developments in the field of thermal dynamics,
electro magnetism and nuclear physics. All of which have had significant impacts on modern life.
Now I'm going to have the TA's pass out the syllabus for this class,
so you can see how this course will be graded.
Oh man, it looks like this isn't going to be the easy AI thought it'd be.
We're back. Obviously we are in a class as you said, and the professor is pretty much
introducing the course and what's going to happen during the semester.
That's right, so he's talking about the different kinds of physics or the different elements of physics.
That will be a part of this course. There's a very eager student. He's very excited and he wants to know
are these interesting things going to be a part of the course?
So when we start out, we talked about these two different fields of physics and I think maybe it
will be helpful to start there with these two branches of this field.
That's right, he mentioned this boy Matt said if they're going to be focusing more on theoretical
physics or experimental physics. Now theoretical physics and experimental physics are what we call
two different branches of physics. That means they're both physics, but people who do them have
different methods and maybe focus on different things. The theoretical comes from the word theory.
Right. Right. So I have a theory about something and I'm going to think about if whether or not
it's possible and maybe there's some math involved. But with experimental physics, the keyword here
is experiment. Experimental. That means we actually build experiments to test our theories.
That's right. So I guess theoretical physics we can just have theories about how things happen
or explain them, but we can't really prove them. We can just have theories around them. Maybe
we can try and prove them mathematically. But experimental physics you can actually, as you said,
create an experiment to prove it or not. That's right. And so those are the two main branches that
the young man asks about. But the professor says, you know, listen, we're going to be talking about
the fundamental concepts of physics. And so fundamental concepts are things that you often hear
a professor talk about in your introductory class. So introduction to mathematics or introduction to
physics. So fundamental concepts are the basics. That's right. So the most important, but also
the ones at the very bottom, the foundation. Because you can learn about more difficult or more
complicated things later. But first you have to have a foundation. So those are the fundamental
concepts. Right. And actually after the professor said that this guy met went on to ask if they
were going to learn about black holes, worm holes and string theory. Okay. So three very important
parts of physics, but very complicated things. The first two are related, right? So we've got
astrophysics, astramine star. So astrophysics is the physics of things bodies in space, planets,
stars, things like that. That's right. And so two concepts that we often talk about in astrophysics
are black holes and worm holes. That's right. So I think many of you have already heard this word
black hole. The concept of it is basically a huge hole in space that just sucks up everything.
The gravitational force. So the pull of gravity is so strong that nothing can resist it.
Everything that comes close to the to a black hole. It's like an adrine.
Everything that comes close to it. It gets sucked into it. No light can escape it. That's right.
And the other concept there is a worm hole. So it's basically a sort of bending of space and time
in which you can travel from one point to another a lot faster than going in a straight line.
Or from one time to another. So this is a very, very popular concept in science fiction movies and
books. For example, Star Trek, the the most recent movie, the new movie Star Trek,
there is a worm hole. So one ship goes from the future and it comes into the past.
That's right. So it has to travel through this worm hole. That's right. So and actually,
yeah, you say science fiction and it obviously it's hard to prove it, but this is one of the
concepts that physicists think they can prove someday. Someday. This is why it's a part of
theoretical physics. That's right. And what about this other concept? String theory.
Okay, string theory is a theory about the way the world works basically. And it is a theory
that actually competes with Einstein's view of the way the world works, right? And string theory is
about basically strings that are vibrating. And that's the way the the entire universe is kind of built.
Yeah. So basically at the subatomic level, usually you suppose to have an atom, but also supposedly
these atoms are made up of strings that depending on the frequency at which they vibrate,
they can constitute different elements or different parts of matter. Exactly. And so we're talking
about the very, very, very, very, very, very smallest building blocks of the things in the world,
atoms and even quarks and jewels and those things. Exactly. So it's actually one of these new things
that people are talking about string theory. It's kind of this new way of seeing the world and
explaining the unexplainable because there are so many things still in the world that we can't explain.
And people argue about this because obviously if you can't prove it, it's hard to say what is
right and what is wrong. Exactly. But actually one thing that was proven was Einstein's general theory
of relativity. So this is something we all learned back in high school or in college. That's right.
So basically the general theory of relativity is this idea that space and time are not fixed.
They're relative to each other. So an example of my teacher used to use is that when you travel
very, very, very fast, imagine going around a jet around the world, counterclockwise, time slows down
the faster you move. Okay. So that proves that time and space are not fixed. That's right.
Actually, the general theory of relativity and specifically this aspect of speed and time
was proven with the example that you give with a two atomic clocks that you kept one on the ground
like, I don't know, your house. And you put one in an airplane that was traveling faster than the
speed of sound. And so after maybe an hour the plane would land and the clocks would have not the
same time anymore, but they would be one of the clocks that was in the airplane traveling faster
would be maybe half a second off or something very, very small. But you would see that time
moves slower because your speed is faster. All right. So that's a general theory. Oh, that's a
part of the general theory of relativity. It's a very important theory in the history of the world,
but also in the history of physics. Another thing though that the professor mentioned that is very
important in physics these days is quantum mechanics. Yes. This is actually a very interesting
field of physics, but very hard to understand in my opinion for me it's very very hard.
I find it very complex too. Well, mechanics are the way the way things work, right? And so quantum is at
the atomic and subatomic level. Right. And so you're talking about basically the building blocks
of the things in the universe. And the people who people who are studying this are working on this
quantum mechanics, they don't like the Einsteinians. They don't like the people who follow Einstein
because these two theories, they don't actually go together right well. You either have to believe
one or you have to believe the other. Well, the problem is that when you're talking about
when you're talking at the macro level, the way things work and the way things move, like for
example you and me, of course, they're formulas and they're everything that explains and that
prove that things are the way they are. But the problem is that in quantum mechanics at a
somatomic level, it's so different. Like for example, electronics, the reason why we're able to
have micro processors and an electronics is because for example, atoms can be in two places at the
same time, which is impossible in our world is like saying, you know, Katherine can be in two places
at the exact same time. And there's also this problem of observation that I've read about. So there are
some kinds of particles like electrons, for example, that if you're observing them, sometimes
appear as waves, but if you're observing them, sometimes appear to have mass. Exactly like light.
Yeah, so you're talking about these things that seem to have a whole different set of rules
from the rules that we have here walking around and eating food and going to work. And so I think
that's what's fascinating about physics, that you can break things down to the very smallest
parts and they seem very different or you can think about the stars and the moon and these planets
and they have their own rules too. And so, you know, that's why physics is such a very,
I think it's it's it's frustrating and it's exciting at the same time. That's right. And actually
some of the other fields that the professor said they were going to explore are the fields of
thermodynamics, electromagnetism and even nuclear physics. So very important branch is I think
of physics as well. So when you're studying physics or science, you will definitely hear about
the laws of thermodynamics, thermo means heat and dynamics means, you know, changing, changing
state and electromagnetism of course is the combination of two words electricity and magnetism.
You know, like magnets, you have the plus and the minus end and they attract or they repel.
Then finally nuclear physics, nuclear physics is very important because it's again about
the about atoms and breaking down atoms and finding out what their parts are.
So you might have heard about the haydron super collider. This is like a big, it's like a big
racetrack for atoms and they basically spin these atoms around the racetrack, going faster and
faster and then they put objects in their ways so that they break. And they crash and they study
what the what the pieces look like and what happens and how much energy is is released. It's all
very interesting and and it seems like things that are out of science fiction because it's not
something mainstream that you hear about in the news very often or that sometimes we understand
like obviously we all hear about the gossip magazines and who's dating who and all this
other type of news but very rarely do we really pay attention to this type of information or news
because it is a little bit complex to understand and it seems that I think sciences are not the
best writers for average people like you and me they write in their own language almost.
Oftentimes that's the case but I have to say I recently read Bill Bryson's book a short history of
nearly everything and it talks about the history of the world and us and the animals and plants
in it and he talks about physics especially and I think that if you're interested in that I don't
know I mean if you're an advanced English learner it might be challenging it was challenging for me
but but it's definitely a good book to read to learn about some of these things. Yeah it's actually
a very good idea and I don't know many of us I think many of us as well growing up maybe we had a
hard time with some of these exact sciences like chemistry or physics so we obviously find it
hard to be interested in it but you know it's very different because it's not math and formula
you don't really have to know how to derive you know the formula or anything you just kind of
have to understand the theory and it's very very interesting I must say. It is and it's fun because
you can talk about it's like philosophy sometimes you can talk about you know if this were the
case then what would happen. Right. It's hypothetical situations and I think that's maybe more
in line with theoretical physics but it's just it's really interesting to think about and to let
your mind go into these very strange places. That's right so actually we are curious to know if
you believe that maybe someday we will be able to travel in time or do you believe that
live in other other planets or we'll have a space travel as a part of our holiday making.
Yeah they supposedly already are arranging tourism to the moon right. Yeah they are so I wonder if
if one day like in the fifth element we're going to have these bruises to space. Yeah that would be fun.
So let us know what your opinions are about this topic and also if you have any of the suggestions
or questions you can always visit us on our website EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there and
until next time bye.