Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Markle. My name is Catherine and today we have
a very complicated topic for you.
That's right, this is an upper intermediate lesson a little bit more difficult and we're
talking all about taxes, paychecks and all the information for when you work in the United
States. That's right, it confuses me and I'm American. So take a close listen. We're going to
listen to this dialogue one time and we'll be back in a moment to discuss what's going on.
Hey Susan, have you got sick? I have some questions about my paycheck. You better,
my name, poor aperture. Oh, this is my first paycheck here in the States and there are
a few things I don't understand. First off, what is this feaker and S-U-I-S-D-I tax? And why
are there deductions both from Medicare and from my health insurance plan? Okay, let's
start from the top of your paystop. This number here represents your gross pay. Yes, that's
easy enough to understand. Then here we have a series of deductions. First off are the federal
ones, feaker stands for federal insurance contribution act or something like that. It's
your federal income tax and then there's social security and Medicare which are both federal
programs to help you out after you retire or if you're unable to work. All right, I see.
So the Medicare isn't actually a health insurance I can use now. That's right. Below the federal
deductions are the state deductions. There's the state income tax and then this S-U-I-S-D-I
tax you were asking about is paying into an unemployment and or disability fund that our
state has set up. But you can see that it's a pretty small quantity that they take.
Yeah, I don't mind giving them a dollar fifty for that. So there are two separate income
taxes. One at a state level and one at a federal level. That's right. Not all states have
an income tax. Some use higher property taxes or sales taxes instead. I see. All right.
Well, I think everything else I can figure out on my own. The deductions for health
insurance and my 401k a pretty self-explanatory. Thanks to your help, Susan. No problem. All
those deductions do add up and nobody's net pay as as high as they'd like. I can understand
why you'd want some explanation. Yeah, I guess it's the same in the UK. I just never
paid much attention. See you later.
All right. We're back. So obviously a lot of vocab there. A lot of acronyms as well like
Fika and all that stuff. We'll take a look at that in a little bit first. Let's start
off with some language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So when you get paid, there's a very important number you want to look at or a couple of
numbers. These are called deductions. Now why do deductions make people sad Marco?
Because a deduction is to take away or reduce. So obviously if your salary is let's say
a thousand dollars and you have five hundred dollar deductions, then you only get five
instead of a thousand. All right. So deductions mean what money is being taken away from you.
All right. That's the money that's deducted for certain taxes or certain programs. It's
important to remember that deduct to deduct is the opposite of to add. It means to take away.
To take away that's right. So Emily had some questions about her salary and so she brought her
pay stub to Susan to ask her why are all these deductions? Well why am I not getting all my salary?
That's right. So pay stub are very important pieces of paper. Basically when you go to a store
and you buy something, you get a receipt. Well, when you go to work and you get paid,
you get a receipt for your payment. That means that it shows you how much money you earn and all
of these deductions. Right. So if you if you're paid every month, you get a paid stub every month.
If you paid every two weeks, you get a pay stub every two weeks. Okay. So it's basically a little
receipt that tells you you have been paid and how much you were paid. That's right. All right. So
Susan started explaining about her gross salary and her net salary. All right. And these are the two
most important numbers on your pay stub. On your pay stub, it will say gross pay. Okay. Not
gross like itky gross but like total. Total. So in total, you earn $1,000 a month. But that's not how
much you money you have in your bank. Because the money that you earn is actually a little bit different
because of these deductions we mentioned. So the net pay is the actual amount of money you get to
right. Right. So the company will pay $1,000. But with taxes and all these deductions,
the actual money that you get is less and that's called the net pay. So it's important when you're
looking at these numbers, look at your gross pay is that correct. And then afterwards, look at your
net pay. Is that what money you actually received? That's right. All right. So now getting into a
little bit of taxes and and its type of taxes that we have out there, not considering
the taxes for the salary. This is a different one. We have a property tax. That's right. So some
places in America tax you on the amounts of money you earn at your job. But a lot of others like
to collect taxes from different areas. So property taxes, one of those. If you own land, if you own
a house or a condo, you will pay a property tax every year. Every year you have to pay for owning
this property. That's right. Because basically you're paying the state for the land that you have
or the space that you have. And the bigger your house is, the bigger the land is, the more money you pay.
And you have to pay the same value every year or does it change over time? It can change over time.
You hear that sometimes property taxes are or property value increases and so then property
tax will properly increase as well. Okay. And what about sales tax? I think this is a very straightforward
work. Well, it's straightforward, Marko. But I don't think they have this in many other places in
the world. China, for example, we don't really have a sales tax. So people don't have to worry about it.
But the sales tax is a small tax that you pay every time you buy something. Right. All right. If I buy
TV and the TV is $100, it's possible that the sales tax is 3% I pay $103. So that's another way that
that you are taxed not on how much money you make, but on the purchases that you make. I make sense.
If I buy a lot of cool things, cars, TVs, you know, I'm paying more money to my state to provide
services like schools and roads and things like that. Uh huh. Okay. So a lot of interesting things
here. I think we can move on now to specifically talking about the taxes related to people salaries
or how they are how it works in the United States. This is a remember that we are talking
specifically about the United States here. So let's take a look at that now on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right. So one of the scary acronyms here, Marco was FICA. The FICA
FICA. It looks very strange here. What is this FICA? Well, this is an acronym. And remember acronyms
are words that stand for other words. So F federal, I insurance, C contribution and A. Act. So federal
insurance contribution act. Basically this is a federal tax. That means that it's everyone in the
country. Everyone has to pay it. No matter where you live. Yeah. Eleanoi, New York, California,
everyone has to pay. And how much is this tax? You know? I do not know. It's called a graduated
income tax. That means that people who earn very little pay very little. People who earn a lot
pay more. Uh-huh. Okay. So this is something that everyone has to pay. And that's why it's called
federal tax, right? That's right. So in America federal means national and state means more local
for your own state. Okay. Now she is obviously paying the federal tax that everyone has to pay.
And what about Medicare? All right. So this is not a tax per se. This is actually a deduction
that goes into a kind of a fund. You know, it's a government program. And when you're older,
when you're retired, you will receive benefits from the federal government, from the United States
government to get healthcare. So Medicare is a kind of healthcare that is paid for by the U.S.
government. I see. So when you're older, you don't really have to pay for your hospital bills
then because you worked and contributed to this Medicare fund then you can go and get treatment.
That's right. Or you pay for part of it and they pay for part of it. So it depends on the
the system. But yes, it's a way to get healthcare through the government. Okay. And now our next
word is interesting because we've heard about social security before you have the social security
card, which is basically your ID or it states also that you are in American. But what is the social
security fund now that you are contributing to? Well, basically this is another government program
that is designed to make sure that people are comfortable when they stop working. Because when you
stop working, you don't have any income anymore. You need money to live. Right. And so your whole life
you, your paying into this fund and the government will then give you the money back. So money
to to basically live off of when you're retired. Okay. And so how long do you actually have to work
in order to be eligible for social security? I believe you have to be 65 to be eligible for social
security, but I'm not sure. Is he just 60 or 65? Okay. I'm not there yet. All right. And actually
another one that's very similar is you have this 401k, which is actually a very interesting
name for this tax or fund. Yeah 401k is more of an investment. So 401k is something that you
put money into every month or a year to access later on when you're retired. So again, it's a
kind of security for you. If you work every day, every year for 30 years, 40 years, you want to have
some money when you're all done. Right. And this is basically a retirement savings plan.
So what is the difference between social security and the 401k or are they the same?
I think the difference is the way the money goes. I'm not 100%. But all of these are like you
have to give the government this money or can I say hey, hey, I don't want to
don't worry about me. I don't need social security. I'm set. I'm saving all on my own.
And can I refuse to pay you these tax? For a one ks, you can refuse. It's not a tax. It's just
something that you can, usually this is not a government program. This is something that the
company that you work for will set up for you. Uh-huh. Okay. But Medicare and social security,
these are things that you have to pay into. Because even if you're rich and you have all this
money, you know, there are a lot of people in America that don't have any of this. And so we
consider it something that we do for each other as much as ourselves. Because also, you know,
Medicare and Medicaid, these are programs that you can also be eligible for. Even if you're 25
years old or 30 years old, you just, you're poor, you don't have a job. So these are social programs.
Okay. Very good. It's very, very interesting. You see that obviously this is why in movies,
you see that people make fun of taxes and how much tax in America there is and how you can't
escape taxes. But it's interesting to see how it's made up and why you are giving your money
to the government. That's right. So this wasn't today's dialogue again. It was pretty complicated.
So hopefully you've understood a little bit more after we've talked about it now.
Hey Susan, have you got sick? I have some questions about my paycheck. You better, Malin.
Pull up a chair. Oh, this is my first paycheck here in the states. There are a few things I
don't understand. First off, what is this feaker and SUI-SDI tax? And why are there deductions
both from Medicare and from my health insurance plan? Okay, let's start from the top of your pay
stop. This number here represents your gross pay. Yes, that's easy enough to understand.
Then here we have a series of deductions. First off are the federal ones.
Fika stands for federal insurance contribution act or something like that. It's your federal
income tax and then there's social security and Medicare which are both federal programs to help you
out after you retire or if you're unable to work. All right, I see. So the Medicare isn't actually
a health insurance I can use now. That's right. Below the federal deductions are the state deductions.
There's the state income tax and then this SUI-SDI tax you were asking about is paying into an
unemployment and or disability fund that our state has set up. But you can see that it's a pretty
small quantity that they take. Yeah, I don't mind giving them a $50 for that. So there are two
separate income taxes. One at a state level and one at a federal level. That's right. Not all states
have an income tax. Some use higher property taxes or sales taxes instead. I see. All right,
well I think everything else I can figure out on my own. The deductions for health insurance and
my 401K a pretty self-explanatory. Thanks to your help Susan. No problem. All those deductions
do add up and nobody's not pay as high as they'd like. I can understand why you'd want some explanation.
Yeah, I guess it's the same in the UK. I just never paid much attention. See you later.
All right. So another interesting thought that came up was, well where does the money for
government spending come from? So because you have all these taxes that are for you basically
you have property tax or maybe does it come from sales tax that maybe the government can make roads
and parks and stuff like this? Well that's the thing. Remember, earlier we talked about federal
and state taxes. Well if it's a state tax like sales tax, you know, in America I can pay sales
tax in California but maybe in New Mexico there is no sales tax. So this is the state tax and that
means that the state government can use the money for state projects. Parks, roads, things like that.
But then the federal insurance contribution act, the the fight for this federal tax,
that is something that's used for our military or government. You know, this pays the
paychecks of people in Congress, the president. This is where all the money to pay them comes from.
And so basically the state taxes pay for state benefits and programs and the federal taxes pay
for these nationwide programs. So that's I think one of the most interesting things about this
topic is that the United States is like 50 small countries that kind of have their own little
government. You know, they have their own taxes and they have their own rules like in some
states you can start driving when you're 16 and others when you're 15. And so it's like all
these little small countries but at the same time you have this one mega country that has federal
taxes and federal insurance and military and all this. That's true and you know it's interesting.
It's an interesting fact about American history that the most conflict in our country
has really come down to the two groups. One group believes that the federal government so
that's the national government should have more power than the states. And another group believes
that the state should have more power. And that is a big problem, you know, this disagreement
that we've had in America that goes back to 1776 and the founding fathers. And so I don't think
it's something that is fixed. You know, these things change, you know, sometimes more federal
power sometimes lasts. But it's a very interesting part of American history. And also it would be
interesting to hear from our users how it works over there because I know that approximately
a rough estimate is that around 30 to 40 percent of Americans income goes to tax.
Right. About that. Yeah. So almost half of your money goes into taxes. So I wonder how much it is
in other people's countries. Maybe they have 60 percent of taxes or maybe 10. Maybe 10.
Yeah, so let us know our website is EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there.
All right, see you guys.