Hello everyone and welcome to English Mod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and a very Merry Christmas to everyone.
That's right. Merry Christmas. We are at that time again where we are celebrating Christmas.
We're having dinner with family and friends. We're giving presents.
And of course, there are some other traditions that come into play like for example Santa Claus.
Santa Claus. So we've got a very special advanced level lesson for you today.
Poem. It's a very traditional poem that is red or listen to on the holiday.
And we're going to talk a little bit about some of the interesting words and phrases that are used in this.
But first off, let's just listen to the poem itself.
It was the night before Christmas when all through the house.
Not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care in hopes that seat Nicholas soon would be there.
The children were nestled all snug in their beds while visions of sugar plums danced in their heads.
And mama and her curchip and I and my cap had just settled down for a long winter's nap.
When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter.
I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.
Away to the window I flew like a flash tore open the shutters and threw open a sash.
The moon on the breast of the new fallen snow gave the luster of midday to objects below when what to my wondering eyes should appear but a miniature sleigh and eight tiny reindeer.
With a little old driver so lively and quick I knew in a moment it must be seat Nick.
More rapid than eagles his corsers they came and he whistled and shouted and called them by name.
Now Dasher, now dancer, now prancer and fixing, on comet on Cupid, on Donder and Blitzson,
to the top of the porch to the top of the wall, now Dasherway Dasherway all.
As dry leaves that before the wild hurricane fly when they meet with an obstacle, mount to the sky.
So up to the house top the corsers they flew with the sleigh's full of toys and St. Nicholas too.
And then in a twinkling I heard on the roof the prancing and powing of each little hoof.
As I drew in my head and was turning around down the chimney St. Nicholas came with a bound.
He was dressed on fur from his head to his toe and his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and suit.
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back and he looked like a pedlar just opening his pack.
His eyes how they twinkled. His dimples how merry.
His cheeks were like roses his nose like a cherry. His drool little mouth was drawn up in a bow and the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.
The stump of a pipe he held tight in his teeth and the smoke and encircled his head like a reef.
He had a broad face in the little round belly that shook when he laughed like a bowl full of jelly.
He was chubby and plump a right old jelly elf and I laughed when I saw him in spite of myself.
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.
He spoke not a word but when straight to work and filled all the stockings then turned with a jerk.
He laying his finger aside of his nose and giving a nod up the chubby he rose.
He sprang to his sleigh to his teen gave a whistle and the way they all flew like the down of a whistle.
But I heard him exclaim air as he drove out of sight.
Happy Christmas to all and to all a good night!
All right we're back so the poem is very nice it's it's long and just to kind of recap what the poem is talking about.
What is the general story of the poem?
The story of the poem is that Santa Claus is coming to visit someone's house and there's a person in the story who is watching Santa Claus arrive.
And he's seeing Santa Claus take the reindeer up onto the roof come down the chimney and lay the presence out for the children filling the stockings as well.
Okay so it's basically a nice poetic description of Santa Claus and also it goes into describe in a very nice way the way Santa Claus looks like.
It's very descriptive we have we have descriptions of what Santa Claus looks like what he's wearing his smile.
How he's a little bit fat.
We also have descriptions of the animals these special animals that we hear about so often that are called reindeer.
All right so we've divided up the poem into by line so then it's going to be easier for you to go to the line that we're talking about.
Let's start with the first line with this first word that's actually very interesting.
It was the night before Christmas when all through the house.
So what does this first word mean?
It was is an abbreviation so it's shortened version of it was.
Okay so but do you actually use this now in like if you're writing?
No this is not something I would use now and writing and it's not something I would say.
It's actually more of a an archaic form something that you might hear in poetry or historical writing.
Okay so it was the night before Christmas right so we're talking about December 24th.
The night of December 24th that's right.
All right so the first two lines talk about how it was the night before Christmas and in the house there was nothing stirring not even a mouse.
So not even the smallest little animal so it's very quiet in the house is what's happening.
So now we jump to line number seven where the poet describes and mama in her curchiff and I in my cap.
So we know that the person talking is the dad because he's talking about himself and mama mother they're in bed together.
And mama in her curchiff and I in my cap so I'm wearing a night cap a cover on my heads like a hat and mama has a curchiff.
What's the curchiff?
A curchiff is another abbreviation short for hand curchiff.
Okay and a hand curchiff is a piece of fabric or cloth that sometimes we use for our noses when we have to blow our nose.
But also you can use a curchiff in your hair to cover your hair.
Okay so if you can imagine that this must take place I don't know maybe 50, 60 years ago and dad used to wear hats to bed and women also hand curchiffs on their head.
Or longer maybe 200 years ago when people wore these long night hats.
Right caps the pajamas and everything.
All right now let's jump over to line 18 and 19 when he's talking about the reindeer and the sleigh arriving and he says,
I knew in a moment it must be Saint Nick.
This is another way of calling Santa Claus right?
Saint Nicholas is his name but you also call him claws or Santa Claus.
Okay and then he said more rapid than eagles his coarser they came.
So the word order is a bit strange here. This is common in poetry.
We could also say his coarser's came more rapidly than eagles.
They were very very fast.
But what are these coarsers we're talking about the animals pulling Santa Claus and what are those animals again?
They're called reindeer reindeer.
So the reindeer are very very fast.
Okay that's right because he's making the comparison about how fast eagles are compared to them.
Okay and we hear their names right exactly.
He goes on to say now dasher now dance or no prancer and all of their names.
Vicks and comet, Cupid, Donder and Blitzson.
All eight reindeer each animal has it so name.
That's right so all eight reindeer actually we're missing one though.
That's very common nowadays.
The reindeer that goes in the front lighting illuminating the sky.
Rudolph the red nose reindeer you might know the song.
That's right that's right.
So they're actually nine reindeer nowadays but I guess the story was before the Rudolph story came out.
All right so those are this is interesting because those are the names of all the all the reindeer.
Now I'm not sure which order they are.
I don't know who's in the back was in the front.
I don't know either but it's important to know that they're very fast and they come down and then they go up.
They have to take Saint Nicholas to the roof of the house on top of the house.
That's right so now he arrives to the top of the house.
Line 32 we see down the chimney St. Nicholas came with the bound.
He came quickly down the chimney boom and at the end he's all dressed in fur from his head to his foot.
So top to bottom he has fur on.
That's right and I think he's got fur because he lives in the north pole right.
That's right it's very cold where Santa Claus lives.
So he has to wear these clothes that are very warm.
Okay and obviously since he is going up and down chimneys in line 34 we see and his clothes were tarnished with ashes and set.
So to tarnished or tarnished means dirty something is tarnished if it's dirty so his clothes his fur clothes were dirty with ashes and suit.
This means that in your fireplace when the fire is gone there's some gray and black stuff.
And that's what's on Santa Claus's clothes.
Okay very good.
So and then we go on to line 35 a bundle of toys he had flung on his back and he looked like a pedlar just opening his pack.
All right a pedlar now this is not just something we talk about on Christmas you know we have pedlers all year round.
What are pedlers what do they do basically they go around selling things.
So maybe you see them in a small market or sometimes in different places and maybe not in on the streets.
You see them selling little things like toys or combs or books something like or in jesus or a fruit pedlers people who sell fruit or you can see those watch pedlers you know they say would you like a Rolex watch pedler.
So that's what they do right they just they're informal salesmen.
They don't have a store they work on the street so this is why Santa looks like a pedlar he isn't in a store he has a bag and he says look in my bag.
Right exactly now online from line 37 we go on to describe the way Santa Claus looks like so he says his eyes how they twinkled his dimples how Mary.
Dimples are those small circles on your your cheeks so some people when they smile they have these small holes or circles those are dimples they're very cute.
That's right so not everyone has them right some people when they smile you can see those dimples.
All right so and his cheeks were like roses his nose like a cherry so that's we're saying that they're red they're red their pink.
Okay now in line 39 he says his draw little mouth was drawn up like a bow.
Now draw is a word that some people still use it's pretty common in places like England we don't use it as much in America we say funny instead but something that is draw D.R.O.L.L. Draw is funny.
Okay so his his mouth his his face is funny looking okay his face is funny looking alright and going on to line 45 we're describing how he was chubby and plump so we're basically saying he was a little bit fat.
Yes okay and a right jolt a right jolly old elf so what is an elf?
An elf is actually normally we talk about elves so one elf two elves as people little people who help Santa they're mythical creatures who live in the north pole and who make presents.
So an elf is a small creature who who makes presents.
Maybe lives in the woods there are many different stories with elves right right okay and in 1946 we say and I laughed when I saw him in spite of myself what does he mean by in spite of myself.
This is really important and this is something we say in English all the time in spite of myself so I laughed in spite of myself so I didn't want to laugh.
I wanted to be serious but I did laugh so in spite of myself I didn't want to laugh I laughed anyway so you say in spite of myself when you did the thing you did not want to do.
Okay and finishing off we are going towards the last three lines where we say and away they all flew like the down of a thistle what is a thistle.
They're talking about the part of a flower that's a fistle.
Okay so they just they all flew away like quickly rapidly like like the little flower.
Well you know when a flower is sending it seeds out it's down it's white so maybe if you blow on a flower with the white seeds they blow away.
That's what it looks like it looks like the seeds of a flower being blown away.
It's easy.
Okay line 55 says but I heard him exclaim air he drove out of sight.
So this is an older way of saying as he drove out of sight so as he's flying away I can't see him anymore almost I can't see him anymore.
He exclaimed something so air means you know while this is happening.
Now this is another one of those maybe old English words that we don't use anymore right you wouldn't really use air.
Air I was walking to school I saw right the milk man no we don't say this anymore but you will find it in poetry and you might also find it in stories.
Okay and line 56 he ends and this is very the the famous way that this poem ends by saying have be Christmas to all and to all a good night.
Yeah this is the and the first line of the poem are the most famous everyone knows these okay very good so a beautiful poem why don't we listen to it one more time.
The night before Christmas when all through the house not a creature was stirring not even a mouse the stockings were hung by the chimney with care in hopes that see Nicholas soon would be there.
The children were nestled all snug in their beds while visions of sugar plums danced in their heads and mama in her curchid and i and my cap had just settled down for a long winter's nap.
When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.
Way to the window I flew like a flash tore open the shutters and threw open a sash.
The moon on the breast of the new fallen snow gave the luster of midday to objects below when what to my wondering eyes should appear but a miniature sleigh and eight timey reindeer.
The old driver so lively and quick I knew in a moment it must be Saint Nick.
More rapid than eagles his corsers they came and he whistled and shouted and called them by name.
Now dashor now dancer now prancer and fixing on comet on cupid on donner and blitzon to the top of the porch to the top of the wall now dash away dash away all.
As dry leaves that before the wild hurricane fly when they meet with an obstacle mount to the sky.
So up to the house top the corsers they flew with the sleigh's full of toys and Saint Nicholas too.
And then in a twinkling I heard on the roof the prancing and powing of each little hoof.
As I drew in my head and was turning around down the chimney Saint Nicholas came with a bound.
He was dressed on fur from his head to his toe and his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and suit.
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back and he looked like a pedal just opening his pack.
His eyes howly twinkled. His dimples how merry.
His cheeks were like roses his nose like a cherry.
His drool little mouth was drawn up in a bow and the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.
The stumbo of a pipe he held tight in his teeth and the smoke had encircled his head like a reef.
He had a broad face in the little round belly that shook when he laughed like a bowl full of jelly.
He was chubby and plump a right old jelly elf and I laughed when I saw him in spite of myself.
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.
He spoke not a word but when straight to work and filled all the stockings then turned with a jerk.
And laying his finger aside of his nose and giving a nod up the chimney he rose.
He sprang to his sleigh to his team gave a whistle and the way they all flew like the down of a whistle.
But I heard an exclaim air as he drove out of sight.
Happy Christmas to all and to all a good night!
All right, so this is one of the very famous poems you can listen to.
Usually people listen to it or read about it during Christmas.
That's right.
It's a classic.
It's something that you think about people listening to in front of the fireplace.
They're drinking their egg nog and talking about how wonderful you know family is.
And so yeah, it's a classic.
It's something that we often talk about and read and listen to.
All right, so it's very interesting because it's part of the American tradition of Christmas.
I think maybe also another part of the world the poem might be translated or also might be popular.
But you know, Santa Claus and all these things are traditions that are observed in some countries.
And it's very interesting to understand them.
Absolutely, and I'm very curious to know about your Christmas traditions.
What do you what do you do in your home country on Christmas Eve or on Christmas Day?
Do you know any poems like this or do you listen to this poem and translation?
Let us know our website is englishpod.com.
All right, guys, we'll see you there and have a Merry Christmas Merry Christmas.
Bye!