Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we're going to be purchasing some wine today right Marco.
That's right. Today we're going to go to the shop and we're going to try to look for some wine that will go well with the type of food that we're having.
All right. So we're going to be learning a lot of specific terms. This is an advanced lesson. So we expect that most of the basics you already know, but some of these more difficult words and phrases are going to be our focus.
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
Hello there. Welcome to Wine World. Let me know if I can help you out at all.
Um, yes, please. I could really use some help. I'm going over to my boss's house for dinner tonight and I don't know what kind of wine I should bring.
Okay. Do you know what kind of food will be served?
Well, his wife is Japanese. He said she makes really good sushi.
That's a bit of a challenge.
Sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine.
Well, let's see.
It'll have to be a white wine, of course.
Why wouldn't the red wine go well with sushi?
No, I don't think so.
Sushi is a very delicately flavored food and red wine would be a jarring contrast. You need a white wine which has more subtle flavors to compliment the fish.
I see. So I should get a bottle of Shardene. That's a white wine, right?
Yes, Shardene is a white wine, but I'm not sure it'd be your best bet.
Shardene is one of the more full-bodied whites and tends to be a bit ok.
I suggest you go for something brighter like this Sauvignon Blanc from New Zealand.
Oh, the Sauvignon Blanc? What's that?
That's another variety or type of grape, just like Shardene.
Let's see. The label says it's got attractive citrus and grassy aromas that give way to crisp mineral flavors and a bone-dry finish.
Serve chilled. Oh no. How long will it take to chill the wine?
I'm on my way to dinner now. Oh, it's ok. Don't worry. We'll just choose a wine from the cooler.
We don't have quite as extensive a selection over here, but this Rome Valley White would be lovely.
Alright, what variety it'll is that?
Well, this is a French wine so they don't always specify the variety on the label.
The French believe that the soil-a-grapes grown in is one of the most important factors in the final flavor of the wine.
This wine is probably a blend of a few different types of grapes. Mostly Vignet, I guess.
And you think this is a good wine? Yes, this is one of our best sellers.
It's not quite as dry as the Sauvignon Blanc we were looking at earlier, which means it's more approachable.
It's light and crisp with a bit of a vanilla aroma. Perfect. I'll take it.
Alright, we're back. So now we're talking about wines.
And one of the first things that really pop up is when we're talking about sushi and how we're trying to get a wine to go well with sushi.
Alright, so the phrase here was to pair with wine. So sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine.
Alright, so when you're talking about wine, you talk about pairing it with food, P-A-I-R to pair.
That's right, so for example, if you have a meat or poultry or chicken, you try to pair it with a wine, so basically that the flavors go well together.
So commonly we say that red wine pairs well with red meat or fish and white wine pair well together.
So you're pairing these two things means you're using them in the same meal.
That's right, okay. So when we were talking about pairing a wine with sushi, the girl said, well, what about red wine?
When that pair well with sushi and the attendance said, no, the red wine would be a jarring contrast.
So first of all, we have this word jarring. Something is jarring if it's loud, shocking, abrasive, difficult, annoying.
So something that's jarring is loud and a contrast is something that shows the differences in something.
That's right. So when we're saying that it would be a jarring contrast to have sushi with red wine, we're saying that there's just two different sushi is two different from the red wine flavors.
So they wouldn't go well together.
That's right, since jarring means it's a bad thing, we think the flavor will be wrong, but bad.
So we need to look for something else and these sales person suggested a wine that has more subtle flavors. White wine.
That's right. So this word subtle is actually spelled as U B T L E, but the B is silent.
That's right. So we say subtle and it's actually great because it's kind of like the opposite of jarring.
Something that's not jarring is subtle.
So it's a little bit more, I don't know, like relaxed, like not as loud.
It's not obvious. You have to really think about it and look for it. Something that subtle is not obvious.
That's right. Now talking about one specific type of white wine, we have a shardeney.
All right. So we know that there are many, many different kinds of wine out there, but there are some very common ones and shardeney is one of those.
And shardeney tends to be a bit fruitier. Australia has some famous shardeneys. California has some famous shardeneys.
So just remember that shardeney is a kind of white wine.
That's right. And one of the ways that they used it to describe shardeneys is that it's one of the more full bodied whites.
All right. So whites here, we're talking about white wines, but something that's full bodied. What does that mean, Marco?
So if a wine is full bodied, it means that it has a little bit of a stronger flavor, like it's a more complete flavor. It's not as subtle.
All right. So we know that white wines are a bit more subtle than red wines.
In this case, but within white wines, you can have one that's very full bodied.
So this is a great phrase for describing wine. We don't really talk about other things being full bodied, but wine can be full bodied if it really has what you say, Marco, this big full taste of grain taste.
That's right. And actually the sales attendant suggested that will sense the shardeneys to or is more full bodied. Then he would recommend maybe a Savignon Blanc.
All right. So Savignon Blanc is the French word for whites, but we use this all the time in English. Savignon Blanc being the kind of wine. Again, it's a white wine.
And it's a bit brighter than the shardeney. That's what the sales person said.
That's right. And when we're talking about wines, either red wines or white wines, this, the way to describe it or the different varieties is actually a variety of the wines or the type of grape.
Right. So Varietal, so you think of Varietal, Varietal, right? It's a specific wine word that we use to describe the kind of grape that go into a wine.
So we know wine generally comes from grapes, they're crushed down and then the alcohol comes from all the sugars.
But each different kind of grape has a different flavor and that's the Varietal, the kind of grape.
That's right. So just think of it as the variety of the wines that you have. And it's a word used specifically for wines.
And well, when the attendant kept talking about the wines and the types of wines they have there, he mentioned that they have a small selection in the refrigerator.
Or in the cooler. So selection in this case means what the store has to offer. It means all the wines that they sell.
Right. So maybe you have an extensive selection. It means you have many, many, many different kinds to choose from.
But if you don't have an extensive selection, you have very few wines that means that you have fewer things to sell.
That's right. So a wide selection of wines or a small selection of wines.
And lastly, talking about Varietals, we also have what we call a blend, a blend of a few different types of grapes.
All right. So you can have blends of different things, but in terms of wine, we're talking about using different grapes together to make one wine.
All right. So this is something that's pretty common and it's a way to achieve different flavors.
That's right. So a blend. You also talk about it in, I think whisky's. You have a blended whisky's.
That's right. So you can have a single malt, which is one grain in one barrel, or you can have a blend, which would be different grains from it in different barrels mixed together later.
Okay. So a lot of great stuff here. All about wines. Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
Hello there. Welcome to Wine World. Let me know if I can help you out at all.
Yes, please. I could really use some help. I'm going over to my boss's house for dinner tonight, and I don't know what kind of wine I should bring.
Okay. Do you know what kind of food will be served?
Well, his wife is Japanese. He said she makes really good sushi.
Hmm. That's a bit of a challenge.
Sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine. Well, let's see.
It'll have to be a white wine, of course.
Why wouldn't the red wine go well with sushi?
No, I don't think so. Sushi is a very delicately flavored food, and red wine would be a jarring contrast.
You need a white wine, which has more subtle flavors to complement the fish.
I see. So I should get a bottle of shardenade. That's a white wine, right?
Yes, shardenade is a white wine, but I'm not sure it'd be your best bet.
Shardenade is one of the more full-bodied whites, and tends to be a bit ok.
I'd suggest you go for something brighter, like this Sauvignon Blanc from New Zealand.
Oh, the Sauvignon Blanc? What's that?
That's another variety, or type of grape, just like Shardenade.
Let's see. The label says it's got attractive citrus and grassy aromas that give way to crisp mineral flavors and a bone-dried finish.
I'm sure it's served chilled. Oh, no. How long will it take to chill the wine?
I'm on my way to dinner now. Oh, it's ok. Don't worry. We'll just choose a wine from the cooler.
We don't have quite as extensive a selection over here, but this Rhone Valley White would be lovely.
All right. What variety does that? Well, this is a French wine, so they don't always specify the variety on the label.
The French believe that the soil of grape is grown in is one of the most important factors in the final flavor of the wine.
This wine is probably a blend of a few different types of grapes.
Mostly Vignet, I guess. And do you think this is a good wine?
Yes. This is one of our best sellers. It's not quite as dry as the Sauvignon Blanc we were looking at earlier,
which means it's more approachable. It's light and crisp with a bit of a vanilla aroma.
Perfect. I'll take it.
All right. So obviously there are a lot more varieties out there.
We only talked about two types of wine. We had a Shardine and a Sauvignon Blanc.
That's right. And the only wines we talked about were white wines. Of course, there's a whole world of red wines out there.
And then between red and white, you have rosé, which are those pink wines.
Those pink wines, yeah.
But actually it's interesting because this, the culture of drinking wine is not as extensive as we think it is.
In many parts of the world, they're not really used to drinking wine.
That's right. But then you go to places like France and Italy and South America, like Argentina, Chile.
And you experience these different cultures of wine that are quite interesting because they're so different.
Yeah, that's right. And it's become even healthy to drink wine.
Medical tests show that if you have one glass of wine with dinner every day, it reduces your chances of heart disease.
That's right. There's some special ingredient. I'm not sure what it is.
But obviously you don't want to drink too much. But if you have a little bit, it's good for your heart.
I think red wine they say is a very hard wine.
Yeah, red wine. So it's interesting. But obviously, maybe in your countries, you don't drink wine.
Maybe you have a particular type of wine like in China. They have his in it plum wine or rice wine.
Rice wine in China and plum wine, I think in Japan.
So maybe you have a specific type of wine that you want to let us know about.
And of course, if you have any questions or comments, we're always there.
Check us out at EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you again in a fight.