Hello everyone, welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today with Erica, we have a very aggressive lesson for you today.
That's true. We've got a revolutionary lesson.
Yes, today at EnglishPod we're protesting.
So, Erica, why don't you tell us what a protest is?
Well, when you protest something, you go into the streets and show your disagreements.
Right. And you yell and you have signs and everyone's just protesting.
And the news comes and if it's not clear now, it'll be clear after the dialogue. I'm sure.
Definitely, definitely. So why don't we start with our vocabulary preview?
The vocabulary preview. We have two words in our vocabulary preview today.
The first is bankrupt.
Bankrupt. Bankrupt. Bankrupt.
Bankrupt.
So if a company goes bankrupt, what happens?
It means a company doesn't have any more money.
So it can't pay salaries. It can pay any.
It can pay its bills. Yeah. So basically if it's bankrupt, it's probably going to close.
Exactly.
Okay, our second word today is bail out.
bail out.
P-A-I-L bail out.
So bail out is when the government gives money to a company that is about to go bankrupt.
That's true. It's emergency money that will help save the company.
Well, these two words are taken directly from our dialogue.
And in today's dialogue, we're going to bring you live to a newscast.
Right. So why don't we just listen to the dialogue?
This is Action 5 News Reporter Sarah O'Connor, reporting live from Washington, DC.
Where protests has broken out.
Thousands of angry citizens are protesting against the proposed bailout of the auto-manufacturing industry.
Sir, sir, Sarah O'Connor, tell us what's happening.
Yeah. Yeah. We're here because we feel this is an injustice.
But financial and responsibility of big business has to stop.
We're here to show the government that we don't like the way they're spending our tax dollars.
Sir, but what exactly is making everyone so angry?
It's an absolute outrage, Sarah. The US government wants to give $25 billion of taxpayers' money
to the auto industry. These are companies that have been mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt.
I see. But many supporters of the bailout argue that it could help save the jobs of millions
of hardware from the Americans. That may be true. And I for what don't want to see anyone lose their job.
But how can these CEOs ask for a bailout when they're making millions of dollars?
And then they have the nerve to fly to Washington in private jets.
This cost hundreds of thousands of dollars. They're asking for money.
That is just not right. Good point. This is Sarah O'Connor, reporting live from Washington, DC.
Back to Utah.
Wow, these people are really angry.
I think they're furious. Well, I think they have some good points and we'll talk about that later.
But now it's time for language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
There was some great language in this dialogue. A lot of language we use to express our
anger. Right. And one of those words and the first one for language takeaway is injustice.
In justice. In justice. And injustice. So an injustice is something that isn't fair. It's totally
unfair. It's unfair. Yeah. This isn't injustice. Let's look at our second word, outrage.
Outrage. Outrage. And outrage. So Erica, why don't you give us an example on how
you would use outrage? There's no more coffee. This is an outrage. Yeah, that's it. That's an outrage.
Okay. Let's go to our next word now. Breakout. Breakout. Breakout. Breakout. Breakout. Breakout.
So we have some great examples on how we use breakout. So let's listen.
Example one. War is broken out in Antarctica as countries of the world fight for control of the
icy continent. Example two. Officers are warning that fighting could break out in the border regions.
Example three. A forest fire broke out last night.
Well, this is a wonderful phrasal verb that means to begin suddenly. Okay. So I think that's pretty
clear. Yeah. Breakout. Let's go to our next word now. Miss managed. Miss managed.
Miss managed. So when something is mismanaged, it's not managed properly. Managed poorly,
right? Yeah. Our final word today is have the nerve tube. Have the nerve tube. Have the nerve
tube. I think this one also is a little bit difficult to understand. Yeah, but we have some great
examples prepared for you. So let's listen to them. Example one.
I've been in love with you since the third grade, but I didn't have the nerve to tell you.
Example two. I don't believe it. You have the nerve to ask me from one ear when you know I've just lost my job.
Example three.
What? You have the nerve to bring your new girlfriend to visit my mother.
So have the nerve tube is like dare to do something right? Yeah, how dare you? Yeah. Have the nerve
tube. It's like I can't believe you would do that. Yeah, I think that's quite clear. Yeah. Okay.
A lot of great words in our dialogue today. And also we have some really interesting
grammar in today's dialogue. Right. So today let's look at some grammar breakdown.
Gramma breakdown. In this section, grammar breakdown, we show you a particular grammar structure
and explain a little bit about how that structure affects meaning. So it's not really about
getting the grammar perfectly right? It's about understanding the meaning. Right. And in today's
lesson, we saw some really great examples on how we use the present perfect tense. Let's listen
to an example from the dialogue. We're protests has broken out. We're protests has broken out.
See the verb here break out like a protest has broken out happened in the past, right? Right.
And it's still going on now. Exactly. So present perfect is used when we're talking at a
about event that happened in the past and is continuing on now. Exactly. Or is continuing to affect
now? Exactly. Okay. I think that's pretty clear. Yeah, but now if you want to indicate or if you
want to demonstrate that the action has finished the event is over, then you would say it like this.
A protest broke out. A protest broke out.
This form you see that the protest is over. It happened yesterday already. Right. And I think it's
really emphasizing the fact that it is no longer affecting the present moment. Exactly. So remember,
the difference between present perfect and simple past. Now if you want to know more about
these tenses present perfect and simple past, be sure to go to our website at englishpod.com.
In the grammar section, you can find some more great examples and a really clear explanation
about how these tenses are formed. But now we are ready to listen to our dialogue a second time.
This is action five news reporter Sarah O'Connor, reporting live from Washington, DC,
where a protest has broken out thousands of angry citizens are protesting against the proposed
bailout of the auto manufacturing industry. Sir, Sarah O'Connor, tell us what's happening.
Yeah, yeah, we're here because we feel this is an injustice. But financial irresponsibility of big
business has to stop. We're here to show the government that we don't like the way they're
spending our tax dollars. Sir, but what exactly is making everyone so angry? It's an absolute
outrage, Sarah. The US government wants to give $25 billion of taxpayers money to the auto industry.
These are companies that have been mismanaged and are now nearly bankrupt. I see. But many supporters
of the bailout argue that it could help save the jobs of millions of hardware from the Americans.
That may be true. And I for what don't want to see anyone lose their job. But how can
me CEOs ask for a bailout when they're making millions of dollars? And then they have the
nerve to fly to Washington in private jets. This cost hundreds of thousands of dollars. They're
asking for money. That is just not right. Good point. This is Sarah O'Connor, reporting live from
Washington, DC. Back to Utah.
Okay, Erica. So what do you think about this situation?
About the bailout of the auto industry. Yes. I think it's a bad idea. Why? There's so many reasons.
I mean, I don't think it's fair for us as taxpayers. Well, I guess I'm not really an American
taxer. But I don't think it's fair for the taxpayers to have to pay for the mismanagement
of these companies. I mean, they've got so much debt. They've produced cars that nobody really
wants to buy and now they're in trouble. And it's not our money that should be spent on saving them.
Yeah, I would agree with you on that. But you do have to take into consideration the fact that
if these companies go bankrupt, thousands of people will lose their jobs and not only the people that
work at the factories, but also people that work for other companies that supply these factories.
Yeah, I mean, I see what you're saying, Marko. But at the same time, we can't support an industry
that isn't working properly. I mean, if one of these companies goes bankrupt, it's going to be
terrible. But it will force the other two companies, perhaps to manage themselves better,
to streamline and become more efficient. I just think it will be better in the future.
Mm-hmm. Well, it could be, but also maybe all three companies can go bankrupt.
It would be sad because the American car, the American auto industry is a symbol of prosperity.
Yeah. It's also the symbol of like the American culture in general. I guess that's true.
So, so it would be a shame for it to go bankrupt because everyone owns a car in the United States
or most people. And it's just something that we can't lose. But it is an interesting topic and we
also want to know your opinions about it. Yeah, listeners, please come to our website at EnglishPod.com
and tell us what you think about this bailout and about this lesson. On the website, we'll post
the link to the news article where you can read a little bit more about this because this is actually
going on now. That's true. Well, everyone, thanks for listening and until next time. Bye.