Hello English learners, welcome back to another great lesson here with English
pot my name is Marco and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you an upper intermediate lesson
a special lesson about the new president right it's been a hot topic in the US the new president
elect president Obama yes so today we're bringing you something that you might see at his
inaugural address that's true so Marco can you explain this word inaugural address
the inaugural address is the first speech the president gives at the ceremony when he is officially
president okay all right so it says first presidential speech exactly great so let's take a look at
some other words that we're going to find in the dialogue today in vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
all right I'm vocabulary preview today we have two words the first one is
swear in swear in swear in swear in we'll see this word in its past tense in the dialogue right
so born in sworn in so it means so to swear someone in is to officially give that person a very
important position usually in government yeah yeah and our second word is oath oath oh oh
oh and oath goes hand in hand with swear in right that's right when you swear someone in they make an oath
a promise right promise an official promise to carry out the duties of that job right so they promise that
they will do their job okay great so now let's listen to our dialogue for a first time where are we
well we're actually watching a news reporter on tv she's in Washington and she's going to tell us
all about what's happened great so let's listen
this is the maddening right for bcc news reporting live for Washington dc
where very shortly the new president will deliver his inaugural address just moments ago the president
was sworn into office following the United States Constitution the president's war to announce
faithfully execute the office of the presidency and what exactly is going on now maddening
well tom true to american tradition the band has just played hail to the chief and the president has
been honored with a 21 guns salute now we're waiting for the president to take the stage and deliver his
speech tom is like the who's who of the political world here on capital hill with dignitaries representing
several different countries what's the mood on the ground like maddening in a word the mood here
is electric the excitement in the air is palpable i've never seen a larger crowd here on capital hill
the audience is shouting crying and embracing each other on this a most historic day you can feel
the hope and excitement in the air the 20th of January will go down in history as well
oh tom it looks like the president is about to begin my fellow american
okay some technical problems at the inaugural address yeah i certainly hope this doesn't happen
well if it does you heard it first at english pod predictors of the future here okay let's take a look
at language takeaway language takeaway on language takeaway today we're bringing you four words
the first word is deliver deliver like deliver a pizza no let's listen we got three examples that
will show the meaning of this word example one who's going to deliver the welcome speech
example two i've been asked to deliver a presentation on the findings of our research project
example three
Dr. Rosen is delivering a lecture on macro economics
okay so deliver a speech say a speech to say a speech yeah so you wouldn't say say a speech you
would say deliver a speech exactly okay okay our second word of language takeaway the who's who
the who's who the who's who this is a funny expression hey it's kind of weird the who's who is the
important people in a particular field right right so for example there was a party last night
and the who's who of the film industry was there whoa so all the important stars and direct
yeah okay you could also say the funeral was like a who's who of the political world okay so
all the important political figures were at this funeral exactly let's move to our third word
dignitaries dignitaries dignitaries dignitaries okay we have some great examples you can
understand what this word means so let's listen example one several important dignitaries
represented the opening ceremony including the president of Brazil the king of Spain and the pope
example two they're going to be a lot of foreign dignitaries at the dinner
so basically we can understand that dignitaries are really important people right right
important political or religious figures I see all right now our last word for language takeaway palpable palpable
palpable palpable when something is palpable is so strong you can feel it okay so it's a very strong
feeling you can almost touch it yeah like the excitement was palpable or the fear was palpable okay
you're just in word palpable let's listen to our dialogue again and now let's try and listen
to all these words we just talked about
you
this is a maddening right for bcc news reporting live from Washington DC where very shortly
the new president will deliver his inaugural address just moments ago the president was sworn into
office following the United States Constitution the president's word and oath to faithfully
execute the office of the presidency and what exactly is going on now madden
while tom true to american tradition the band has just played hail to the chief and the president
has been honored with the 21 guns salute now we're waiting for the president to take the stage and
deliver his speech tom is like the who's who of the political world here on capital hill with dignitaries
representing several different countries what's the mood on the ground like madden in a word the
mood here is electric the excitement in the air is palpable i've never seen a larger crowd here on
capital hill the audience is shouting crying and embracing each other on this a most historic day
you can feel the hope and the excitement in the air in 20th of January will go down in history as
we're all ton it looks like the president is about to begin
my fellow american's
i stand before you today
okay so if you noticed in our dialogue we have some really interesting phrases there yes
so i think it's time for us to take a look at fluency builder fluency builder today we're going to
be looking at three phrases that are very interesting because we can change them a little bit
and form different patterns yeah so the first phrase we have is in a word in a word in a word
in a word we use this expression when we want to describe something in one word right pretty simple
hi it's really simple let's look at the pattern we've got examples of how you could use this phrase
example one
in a word the situation is serious example two
what's it like there in a word it's amazing okay so in a word this podcast is
awesome amazing okay okay let's look at our second phrase today
go down in history go down in history go down in history so this is a really common phrase i'm sure
you guys have heard it yeah basically something that is really important that everyone will remember
for a very long time let's look at this pattern with a few examples example one
this is going to go down in history as the worst disaster the world has ever seen
example two
he'll go down in history is the best president we've ever had
example three
this day we'll go down in history
okay so as you can see the pattern is we're using a superlative that's right the most the best the biggest
the worst the worst right and our final phrase in putting it together is
my fellow Americans my fellow American my fellow Americans so obviously you can change this one up a
little bit hey right you can say my fellow co-workers uh-huh my fellow citizens
my fellow family members yes so basically fellow just means like deer yeah in some way
it's a similar similar similar yeah so we looked at some great vocabulary and phrases and now
let's talk a little bit about these American traditions when electing a new president yes
today in the studio we have JP who's joining us hi everyone hey JP and he's going to be talking
to us about these traditions oh I am okay yeah what are we going to talk about 21 guns salute what's
that all about the 21 guns salute is the military salute where they say and now we will have the 21 guns
salute so 21 soldiers with their rifles they go and they all shoot them off the same time and they
don't know why I think it's a sign of respect hey yeah you'd respect those well I think in Europe
they would do a cannon or something oh right can it's a loop no we'll just can it's maybe just one
cannon maybe our European listeners know the answer to maybe okay and what about this song
held to the chief you know anything about that I do not know anything about except that it's a
march and I think it's Susa I think John Phillips who's eroded and whenever the president walks into
a room they play that song really yes and I played it once for president bush the first one I was a drummer
you did and my marching band had to play that song for him oh my god you feel like famous
you yeah this was back in like 1986 or something was that even an election year in eight
out of the well you did play for the president so you know yeah so JPD have any other sort of
traditional things that happen when the president becomes the president well um I can tell you that
Jimmy Carter you know when when he was elected president this motorcade was going down
Pennsylvania Avenue and he stopped the car and got out really yeah to walk he wanted to walk down
Pennsylvania and you wanted to walk down the you know down the street to like to be with the people
yeah I think so and I think it made the I think it made the secret service insane and maybe the
car smelled better so I think that is my memory of it I might be confusing with the West Wing but
to which the yeah maybe when the president walks it's a big deal so JPD you do anything special
for the inauguration ceremony I always take the day off to watch you do I love watching and I love you
you know the I love the the swearing in ceremony the ritual of the the the the speech
alright everyone we're out of time I hope you enjoyed this political lesson and I hope you have a
happy inauguration day happy inauguration there you want yeah okay all right great we're definitely
going to take the day off to watch it with JP and um hopefully you guys can too well thanks for listening
everyone and until next time goodbye