Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we have a great lesson for all our upper intermediate students
that's right. We're talking about airplane travel today
airplane travel. So we're going to be in an airplane
yes and we're going to be listening to some of the common things you might hear on an announcement in the airplane
yeah usually the flight attendant or the capital will come on and say something and well usually it's an English
so we got to understand what they're saying. That's right and we'll also learn some great phrases that you can use when you want to describe
flights to your friends when you talk to them. Yeah that always happens you arrive somewhere and people are like hey how was your flight?
now you know how to answer it. Exactly. Okay so why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview?
very vocabulary preview. Well we've got three words for you here in vocabulary preview all about flying.
Okay so what's our first one? Terbulence. Terbulence. Terbulence. Terbulence. Terbulence.
So turbulence. How can we describe this? Well turbulence when you're in an airplane basically is air that is moving in all directions really fast.
Okay so what happens? So the airplane will start to shake. Okay. Right. Yeah it's the same thing if you're flying a kite maybe some turbulence is in the air your kite will maybe fall to the ground.
Oh yeah. So it's air that's moving in all directions. It's really turbulent.
All right well we'll hear how this word is used in the dialogue. But another airplane word we hear a lot.
I'm crew crew. Flight crew. Yes CREW crew. So the flight crew is basically the team.
Yes. Right. Yep. It's all the people that are in the airplane. So it's basically the captain and the co-pilot and all the flight attendants.
Exactly. Yep. That's the flight crew. Yes. Okay. And what about our last word?
Bumpy ride. Bumpy ride. Bumpy ride. Bumpy. Not smooth. Not smooth. Yeah. So what would be an example of a bumpy ride? Okay imagine if you're driving in your car and you're driving on a dirt road like with many holes in it and everything rocks.
You're driving on that road and it would be really really bumpy. Right. So your car will be moving a lot.
Yeah. Yeah. So a bumpy ride is a trip where you move and shake a lot. It's kind of uncomfortable.
So you can say that is a bumpy road. Or it was a bumpy ride. It was a bumpy ride. Okay. So now let's listen to a dialogue.
We're going to be listening to these people on an airplane and the captain is going to give some instructions.
And the next thing you know, we're running towards the, oh, did you feel that? Yeah. Don't worry about it. We're just going through it. But it's turbulence.
Light and gentlemen, this is your captain speaking. It looks like we've hit a patch of rough air. So we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes.
This is why I hate flying. At this time, I'd like to remind of our passengers to fasten their seat belts and remain seated until the fasten seat belts
sign is turned off. Please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stowed under the seat in front of you. I'll be back to update you in a minute.
Did you hear that? Oh my god.
Brint! Don't worry about it. This is totally normal. It happens all that.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain again. We've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us. And so for your safety, we will be suspending in flight service.
I would ask all the in flight crew to return to the seat at this time. I would also ask that all our passengers are fine for using the laboratory until the seat belt sign has been switched off. We can expect.
The most important thing is to have a flight attendant and the flight attendant.
Here we are with another dramatic dialogue, another explosion and English fog. What's happening?
I don't know. A lot of adventure is going on, so we'll see what happens.
Sure there are, right. Don't worry everyone else.
It's kind of making me nervous for my next flight.
Alright, so let's take a look at some of the words that the captain used in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, all of these words you'll hear really, really often when you're flying.
And the first one we have for you is fasten, fasten, fasten, your seat belt.
Now this is a great word, fasten means to do up, do up or put on or connect.
Connect, right. So usually it'll be with seat belt or a belt or something like that, right?
Yeah, now the pronunciation here is interesting.
Yes.
It's felt, F-A-S-T-E-N.
Right, so it would be fast and no.
No, right.
Fasten, fasten, the key kind of becomes silent.
Mm-hmm.
So it's fastened.
Yep.
Okay, let's look at our next word, laboratory.
Laboratory.
Okay, so what is laboratory exactly?
Because I'm always confused, what's the difference between bathroom, restroom, washroom,
WC, laboratory?
I know, so many words for bathroom.
A laboratory is a room with a toilet and sink only.
Only a toilet and sink.
So no bathtub.
No.
No shower either.
No shower.
So it's very, very common to find a laboratory in boats, airplanes, or trains.
Yep.
But never in your house.
Never in your house.
Even if your room in your house is only a sink in a toilet, it's still not a laboratory.
It's a bathroom.
Yeah.
Okay.
I don't know why.
That's just the way it is in English.
And something interesting that you told me today, double you see.
Huh?
Right? That's a common thing that you'll see on a bathroom.
Yep.
What are your closet?
Water closet.
Yeah.
Wow.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
Water closet.
Okay.
Anyways.
Let's take a look at our next word.
Stowe.
Yes.
Stowe your luggage.
So if I stowe my luggage, it means you put it in a place where you can get it easily,
but it is very safe.
And maybe it's not even visible, right?
Yeah.
So you put it away in a safe spot.
So usually in airplanes they will tell you to stowe your luggage under your seats.
Yes or stowe your luggage in the overhead bin.
Over a hidden bin or overhead compartment.
Yes.
Okay.
And our last word.
Refrain.
Refrain from doing something.
So this is a verb meaning a void doing.
A void doing.
Do not do.
Exactly.
Something interesting about this grammar wise is it's usually followed by from.
Yeah.
Refrain from.
And the verb that follows is always a jaren.
Right.
So refrain from i and g.
Refrain from using the laboratory.
Yes.
Refrain from smoking.
Okay.
So refrain from.
Yeah.
All right.
So some really great examples in language takeaway.
Yeah.
And well, now let's take a look at Fluency Builder and see some of these great phrases.
Fluency Builder.
All right.
Three phrases we have for you here.
The first one.
Remain seated.
So to remain seated.
Really simple.
To stay sitting.
To stay on your seat.
Don't stand up.
Yes.
This is really important in airplanes, right?
Yeah.
Because otherwise, if there's turbulence, you could, you know, end up flying around
airplane.
They're falling exactly and hurt yourself.
Remain seated.
Now, one of the reasons they had to remain seated was because they were going to go through
a patch of rough air patch of rough air.
So patch.
Now interesting.
Okay.
So patch is a small area, right?
Yeah.
So a small area of turbulence.
A small area of turbulence.
Now what would be another example of patch?
Maybe a patch of strawberries.
So it's like a little strawberry garden, right?
Or a patch of grass.
Patch of grass.
Usually in front of your house, you have a little patch of grass.
Yep.
Okay.
So patch of.
And now our last phrase.
Suspend.
In flight service.
Yeah.
So stop for a short time.
Stop for a short time.
So you could suspend your work.
Yeah.
And if you're going on vacation, you could suspend your subscription to the newspaper.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So suspend to temporarily stop.
Yes.
Okay.
So we've covered a lot of vocabulary and some great phrases.
Mm-hmm.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue one more time and we'll come back and talk about
Line.
And the next thing you know, we're running towards the... oh.
Did you feel that?
Yeah.
Don't worry about it.
We're just going through a bit of turbulence.
So I didn't gentleman.
This is your captain speaking.
It looks like we've hit a patch of rough air.
So we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes.
This is what I hate flying.
At this time, I'd like to remind of our passengers to fasten their seat belts and remain seated
until the fasten seat belts are just turned off.
Please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stowed under the seat in front of you.
I'll be back to update you in a minute.
Did you hear that?
Oh my god.
But don't worry about it.
This is totally normal.
It happens all that.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain again.
We've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us.
And so, for your safety, we will be suspending in flight service.
I would ask all the in-flight crew to return to the seat at this time.
I would also ask that all our passengers are free from using the laboratory until the seat
of flight hasn't switched off.
We can expect.
The second hour.
A whole different style of flight.
I don't know.
Erica, have you ever had a turbulent flight like this?
No, no, never this bad.
A little bit of turbulence.
Actually, a kind of like turbulent flight.
Why?
It's sort of like, I don't know, it's kind of fine.
You get shaking around, you're like stomach moves up and down.
You don't like nervous?
No, I get a little excited.
I get a little excited.
Well, it is true that flying is actually very, very safe, right?
Yeah.
I know we all hear that more people are killed in car accidents
than a flight accidents.
So it's very, very safe.
So yeah, I don't worry about the turbulence.
Yeah, not on wood.
Yeah, so flying is really safe.
And as long as you remain seated,
you're fast in your seatbelt,
and you follow the instructions,
you shouldn't have any problems.
Yeah, actually, that's a really good point
because actually when I was reading about turbulence
for this dialogue, I kept reading all these stories
about these people who, you know,
when they got into some turbulence air,
were, you know, knocked over or they ended up like,
actually literally flying through the cabin
and getting really badly hurt.
Yeah, yeah.
Everyone, you got to fasten your seatbelt.
Yes, remain seated.
Yeah.
Flying tips here at English-Police.
Flying tips at English-Police.
We don't want you to get hurt.
And we know that you travel that's so be safe, right?
Yeah, and use this language to describe your flight.
Okay, so come to our website, English-Pot.com
where you can leave questions.
You can also leave your comments.
Yeah, Marko and I are always there.
And actually, in fact, we have to go check this right now.
So yeah, we're out of time.
So we'll see you guys next time.
Thanks for listening.
Bye.