Welcome back English learners. My name is Marco and I'm joined here by the lovely
Erica. And today we're going to be bringing you another great lesson. One of the lessons
that you requested. Yes, that's right. Actually, Maxa, Maxim S requested this one. Right. I think
he's really into research and investigation. So we're bringing you a great lesson about this topic.
Okay. So I'm really excited to hear this dialogue all about research. So why don't we start
listening to two university professors discussing an important question?
We've been over this a thousand times. The data is irrefutable. Look, we've done
extensive research, built studies and read the literature, and there is conclusive evidence
to support my theory. Horowitz, I beg to differ. Evening your most recent study,
the investigative approach was flawed. You know as well, Lydu, the collection of data was not
systematic and there's a large margin of error to draw a definitive conclusion based on that
data would be misleading. The doctors preposterous. You are trying to single-handedly solve one of
the world's greatest mysteries and yet you're oblivious to the fact that you're wrong or are not
wrong. Look, chicken came first. No, the egg came first. Look, chicken. Egg, look,
chicken. The egg. Look, chicken. The egg. Look, chicken. The egg. Look, chicken. The egg. Look, chicken. The egg.
All right. So interesting, which came first the chicken or the egg? It's an age-old question, isn't it?
And apparently they are not going to agree anytime soon. All right. Well, what they can agree about
is this awesome language. So why don't we take a look at it now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay, on language takeaway today, we have some really great words and this first
one is really good. Irreffutable. Irreffutable. Irreffutable. The data is irreffutable. Okay, so
if the professor says that the data is irreffutable, what does he mean by that? He's saying that
you cannot deny it. It is really, really true. It is really true. There is no way this is a lie.
Exactly. Okay. Irreffutable evidence for example. Yeah, that's a great phrase. All right. So the
professor complained that Dr. Harlwitz's experiment was flawed. flawed. So flawed. Is that an
adjective of rubber and noun? Hmm, it is an adjective. Oh, here. Now when something is flawed,
there is a problem with it. Okay, so there's an mistake. An error. Yeah. Okay. So there's an adjective.
There's a way of saying that his experiment has a flaw. A mistake. Exactly. So flawed is the
adjective of a flaw. Right. Okay. Now the reason that his study or his experiment was flawed
is because it was not systematic. systematic systematic. So systematic. That's an interesting word.
Hmm. Now I think we can recognize the word system in here, right? Right. So when something is
systematic, it follows a process. A certain order. Yes, a certain system. Right. So that's basically
what systematic means to follow a certain order to be more organized, right? Exactly. Yeah. Okay.
And what about our next word? Propostress. Propostress. Propostress. That is prepostress. I love this phrase.
It usually goes together, right? That is prepostress. Yeah. Okay. So what does it mean when I say that?
It means it's absurd. It's ridiculous. Right. It doesn't make sense. Hmm. I can't believe you said that.
All right. Well, this is a really interesting phrase. But I think it's a little bit more common
when it's used by older people. Yeah. I don't think I don't really see a young person going up to
someone and say, hey, that's prepostress. Yeah. But it is a wonderful phrase. Now our final phrase
for takeaway, oblivious. A oblivious. You're oblivious to the fact. Hmm. So a person that is oblivious
to something. They don't know or they're unaware. Okay. So they ignore maybe the fact. So
exactly. They don't see it. Yeah. You're oblivious to the fact that we're in a recession. Okay. Or he is
completely oblivious. Hmm. You can just say like that, right? Yeah. He doesn't know. Hmm. Okay. So we
took a look at some of the great vocabulary we found it in the dialogue. But there were also some
really good phrases that I think we should look at. Okay. And let's take a look at those and putting it
together. Put it together. You know, Markle, one of the things I love about
English is the way that words seem to fit together. Like like blocks coming together. And here we
have a lot of great examples of these words that fit together really nicely. Okay. So why don't we look at
those? And our first one now is extensive research. Extensive research. Extensive research. All right. So we
know extensive means a lot. A lot. Yeah. So that's really good when you put it together. Extensive
research. It means you have a lot of research. You have really studied. You have really looked
things up. Okay. Extensive research. Another great research related phrase here is conclusive evidence.
Conclusive evidence. Inclusive evidence. All right. Now the first word they're conclusive. When
something is conclusive, you can't argue with it. It's it's the final decision. All right. Well,
the professor complained that Harlwitz's that Harlwitz's investigative approach was flawed, right?
So this is our next phrase investigative approach. Investigative approach. Investigate of approach.
Okay. So I remember the word investigative is a verb. Yes. But in this case, it's a
it's an adjective. It's an adjective. When something is investigative, it's obviously having to do with
an investigation. So the approach or the so when he said investigative approach, just the,
I mean, just simply the way you investigate. Okay. The problem, the way he investigated. Okay.
Very interesting. What about this other phrase that I saw it was really interesting? Definitive
conclusion. Definitive conclusion. So a definitive conclusion. All right. Well, again, I think we
know the word conclusion, right? Okay. So it's a final judgment or decision. All right. When something
is definitive, you can't argue with it or change it. Okay. So the conclusion or the final
result is is final. Like there is no way of arguing it. Exactly. Okay. All right. Inative conclusion.
This is some great language. So why don't we listen to it one more time in the dialogue?
We've been over this a thousand times. The data is irrefutable. Look, we've done extensive research,
built studies and read the literature, and there is conclusive evidence to support my theory.
Horowitz, I beg to differ. Even in your most recent study, the investigative approach was flawed.
You know as well, Lydu, the collection of data was not systematic and there's a large margin of error.
To draw a definitive conclusion based on that data would be misleading.
Doctors preposterous. You are trying to single-handedly solve one of the world's greatest mysteries,
and yet you're oblivious to the fact that you're wrong or am not wrong. The trick and claim first.
No, the egg came first. The trick and egg. The trick and the egg. The trick and the egg.
The trick and the egg.
So, an interesting question. What do you think? What came first? The chicken or the egg?
Well, if you ask me, it was the egg. It was the egg. Yeah, interesting. What about why did the chicken cross the road?
To get to the other side? Do you think that's really the reason?
Well, there's a million different reasons, but this is great. I'm glad you brought that up because this is like the classic English joke.
The classic English joke. Why did the chicken cross the road? And the answer is always,
well, there are a million answers. So, do you guys know any chicken jokes? Yeah, why don't you come to our website,
EnglishPod.com and on the comments section, why don't you leave us your thoughts on what came first?
The chicken or the egg? And why do you think the chicken cross the road? All right. Well, we really look forward to hearing your ideas.
And Marco and I will be around to answer your questions. So, I think we're out of time for today, but thanks for listening.
And we'll see you there. Goodbye.