Hello English learners. Welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. Today we're bringing you an upper intermediate lesson and something that we all do.
Right. Talking to ourselves. Talking to ourselves, right? I think everyone does it. You think to yourself or you talk to yourself.
Yep. And we're going to be doing that today, but we're going to be looking at some specific vocabulary.
Erica, why don't you tell us about that? Well, unfortunately we're going to be following a guy.
He's an in a really embarrassing situation. And we're going to hear him calm self some bad name in his mind.
So he's a little bit nervous and he thinks he is not very smart, right? That's right.
Okay. So before we start with this dialogue, there are a couple of words that we should look at in vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. All right. We're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue. And the first one is
Famished. Famished. Famished. Okay. So,
Famished is an adjective. That's right. Meaning very, very, very hungry. Very, very hungry. Okay. So just very, very easy. Yes.
Famished. Now what about our next one? Sexist. Sexist. Sexist. Another adjective to describe a person, right?
Right. Or a thing, I guess. So like, yeah, an idea. Okay. So a sexist person would be
somebody who judges people by their sex. Okay. So like all women are stupid for them.
Which is not true, of course. No, of course not. Right. So sexist works both ways.
Yeah. Women can be sexist. A man could be sexist. Exactly. I mean, the women thinks all men are stupid.
Which is also not true. Yes. Let's just be clear about that. All right. So now that we've
taken a look at these two phrases, let's start with our dialogue. And we'll be back to talk about all the
great words.
Miss, your salad. Mmm, looks good. And positively famished. And for you, sir. Thank you.
Enjoy. Thank you.
I can't believe she's on a team with me. I'm so lucky. I must be the luckiest guy in the world.
I want to scream at the time of my lungs. I'm luckiest dude in the world. Oh, shut up. Don't be such a
dumbass. She's so hot. Wait, I can't say that. Good sexist. She's so hot. She's making me sexist.
Oh my god. I'm such a tool. Okay, get it together. Oh, she's eating salad. All right.
Never salad. Don't crap. Which fork do I use? Damn it. She's gonna think I'm a moron. What the hell are
all these ports for? Which one did she use? Okay, chill. You're all, you know. Just take a fork.
You're salad.
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
Oh, sorry. What were you saying? You're eating my salad. Oh, yes. It's delicious.
Okay, embarrassing first date, huh? Yeah. I mean, I really do feel sorry for this guy. Well, it
happens to us. Sometimes we are in the company of a very beautiful girl and we just get really nervous.
All right. Well, I mean, you know, psychologists call this negative self talk. Really? Yeah, this
sort of calling yourself names and talking negatively about yourself. But actually, you can use some
of this language to talk negatively about others. Yeah. So why don't we look now at this language in
language takeaway? Language takeaway. So on language takeaway today, we have five words. Let's start
with our first one. Dumbass. Dumbass. Dumbass. Okay. Now, this is in a very polite word. I was definitely
not polite. Okay. But what is a dumbass? Well, it's obviously a dumb stupid idiot. Okay. So it's a
person that is not very intelligent. And our next word is also quite similar. Moron. Moron. Moron.
If a person is a dumbass or a person is a moron, what's the difference? Well, basically, a moron
is someone who is not smart, who is very unintelligent. Okay. So they don't know what one plus one is.
Okay. All right. But a dumbass is a person who does stupid things. Okay. So maybe a dumbass,
like you're planning a bank robbery and the dumbass forgets to bring the gun. Okay. That is a dumbass.
So maybe Moron is a little bit less offensive. And it's actually you'll find it in the dictionary.
Right? Yeah. Whereas a dumbass, I don't think you'll find it. Yeah. It's slang. It's slang. Exactly.
Now, what about this next? It's also a negative name. You can call people a tool tool.
Tool. This is very strange because I don't know how a tool can be something negative. Yeah.
So it's a person. Yeah. But it actually means the opposite, right? If a person is called a tool,
it means they are useless, right? Yeah. So if you ever call the tool, they're saying that you're
useless. You're good for nothing. All right. Well, these are three interesting words. So why don't
we hear some examples of each of these words in use? Example one. I hate Tom. He's such a dumbass.
Last week, you borrowed my mobile phone and dropped it in the pool. Example two.
I don't like Kevin very much. He can be a real moron at times. Example three.
It was looking for a job, but he didn't even have a resume prepared. He's such a tool.
Okay. So great examples. And here at EnglishPod we're bringing you real street to talk. Exactly.
Language as it is spoken by today's youth. Okay. Now let's take a look at our last two words.
All right. Well, these phrases you can use when you're trying to calm yourself down and make yourself
relax a little bit, right? Right. Let's take a look at the next one. Chill. Chill. Okay. Chill.
So again, relax. Calm down. Yeah. You need to chill. Yes. And then you also need to be cool.
Be cool. Now if you can tell the pattern is related to temperature. Right.
Joe is cold. Cool is similar to cold. Yeah. So again, that's what it means to relax.
To calm down your emotions. Right. Make your emotions not so hot. Exactly. Yeah. All right. So chill.
Be cool. Exactly. And you use them together like that. Don't you? Yeah. Yeah. Now chill also has another
another way of using it. Right. Exactly. You can say I'm chilling with my friends. Yeah. We're chilling here in the EnglishPod
which means we're just relaxing. Yeah. You're just having fun. Yeah. Not doing anything, right? Exactly.
But you can't say chilling. You have to you have to drop the G. Yeah. You have to
try. Right. You can't say I'm chilling. Yeah. You have to say I'm chilling. I'm chilling.
Okay. So that's all for language takeaway. But now let's take a look at some of the really
useful phrases that we saw in this dialogue in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
Okay. So this guy is so happy he's on this date that he wants to scream at the top of his lungs.
Scream at the top of my lungs. Scream at the top of my lungs. So basically he just wants to
like scream to shout really loudly. Really loudly. Yeah. He's so excited, right? Exactly.
Okay. So for example, sometimes you're at a concert. Yeah. And you need to talk to your
friend and you're like screaming at the top of your lungs because the other person can't hear you.
Exactly. Or maybe you're lost in the woods and you need to scream at the top of your lungs so
that someone will hear you and find you. All right. Very good. Okay. So scream at the top of my lungs.
Our next phrase. Get it together. Get it together. Get it together. So if I tell you,
Erica, you need to get it together. Basically you're telling me to calm down. Relax. So
pull your emotions together. Yeah. Get your ideas straight. Right. So it kind of gives you this
idea that you've got to pull like you said pull your emotions together in a little box and tie them up.
All right. So get it together. Yeah. So Marco, when would you use this phrase? Get it together.
I guess when somebody is either very emotional, maybe crying or very nervous, you know,
you tell the person, oh, get it together. You know, relax. Yeah. Or when somebody maybe is not
doing something good in their life, you know, like making bad decisions or not being responsible.
You tell that person, you need to get it together. Exactly. Right. Exactly. I couldn't have said
it better myself. Okay. So now what don't we move on to our next phrase? And this is really,
really high frequency. I think you would hear it all the time. All right. So what the hell? What the hell?
So why would you say what the hell? Well, obviously you're asking a question, right? Because you got
your your W, you got your what? But when you say the hell, you're putting emphasis on the what?
So you're asking a really strong question. Right. But it's not polite. It's not polite. Yeah. Okay.
So if I say what the hell is going on? What's happening? Really, really what's happening. All right. Yeah.
So and we can change it a little bit. We can replace the what with another WH like why? How?
How? Where? Where or when? Yeah. Okay. So why don't we hear some examples of how this expression is used
using different WH words. Example one. Where the hell are you? I've been waiting for hours.
Example two. How the hell did you do that? That was amazing.
Example three. When the hell are you going to find a job? I'm tired of pay for everything.
Example four. Who the hell are you? I don't know you?
Here. All right. Now our final word also a little bit strong. But pretty high frequency.
Oh, yeah. Very high frequency. Oh crap. Oh crap. So it's a little bit strong but less strong than maybe
saying a really bad word, right? Yes. But it's definitely saying like you made a mistake, right? Yeah. It's like a
really strong. Oh no. Oh no. Exactly. A really strong. Oh no. But I guess not many people say oh no.
Oh no. I just lost $10 million. Exactly right. You would not say that. Yeah. So it's a very strong.
Oh no. But it's not as strong as it could be. There are other words out there that are stronger.
But we are not going to go into them here. But maybe you guys know so let us know. Yeah. We can
definitely keep an eye out on the common section. But don't write the words in the comments actually.
Okay. So we saw some really great phrases. Some really great words. A lot of informal language.
But it's very high frequency and you'll use that with your friends or you'll see it in movies,
TV shows. Yes. Really common in movies and in TV shows. Exactly. So let's listen to this dialogue
one more time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
Mise Yosalad. Mmm looks good and positively famished. And for you sir. Thank you.
Enjoy. Thank you.
I can't believe she's on a date with me. I'm so lucky. I must be the luckiest guy in the world. I want to scream
and tell my lungs I'm luckiest dude in the world. Oh shut up. Don't be such a dumbass.
She's so hot. Wait I can't say that. Good sexist. She's so hot. She's making me sexist. Oh my god.
I'm such a tool. Okay. Get it together. Oh she's eating salad. All right. Never salad.
No crap which fork do I use? Damn it. She's gonna think I'm a moron. What the hell are all these
forks for. We're going to choose. Okay chill. You go. You go. Just take a fork. You're salad.
Um hmm. Oh sorry. What were you saying? You're eating my salad. Oh yes it's delicious.
So these these slang words they're actually very common right? Yeah. I think like you said
you it's not likely that you'll find them in a dictionary um of course and you can find them in
movies or sometimes when you're having a conversation and very informal conversation with a native speaker
yeah these words will slip out and these uh slang terms will come up. Exactly and you know what? There's a
great resource out there for wonderful English slang terms called urbandictionary.com. Exactly if you ever
see a word that maybe you can find in the conventional dictionary you're probably gonna find it there.
Yeah we'll put a link up to it on the site. All right so also if you have any questions or comments
be sure to come to our website englishpod.com. Marco and I are there to um answer all your
questions and we also've got lots of resources like links to urbandictionary. Right and also if you
have any questions on any other slang terms that you may have heard or how to use them be sure to
post it on the comment section. Well guys thanks for listening to this lesson and until next time
bye