Hello English learner. Welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today we're going to be looking at another kind of science fiction lesson related to aliens.
That's right. And I think in this lesson we'll actually have an alien sighting here at English Pod.
Right, an alien encounter. So we're going to be learning about the stars. We're going to be learning about aliens and UFOs today.
That's right. And we're also going to learn some language that you can use to describe negative results.
Things that happen that are bad. That's right. So let's start by looking at vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview. Okay. We have two words for you that we're going to hear in the dialogue.
And the first one is constellation. constellation. A constellation. All right. So we've all looked up in the sky and
seen shapes or figures that are formed by the stars. That's right. So a constellation is a group of stars
that makes a shape and has a name. Right. There are a total of 88 known constellation. So the most popular ones.
I think maybe are the little dipper, the big dipper, etc. I never knew it's such a fan of a astronomy
Marco. A little bit. All right. What about the next one? The next one is earthlings. Earthlings.
So earthlings are people who live on planet earth on earth exactly. And in the dialogue we're going to hear
greetings earthlings. This is the most typical phrase that you will hear and almost every single alien movie.
Exactly. So it's like saying hello people from earth. Yes. Every single alien in the world says this phrase.
So those are the two words that we are going to find in this dialogue today. So why don't we start
and listen to what happens with our UFO experience?
Oh honey. This is so romantic. I've never seen like so many stars before. It's beautiful.
See that constellation there? That's Orion. And the very bright star? Well it's not a star because it
doesn't blink. That's actually Venus. What's that big flaxhew one? I don't know. I think it's a UFO.
Oh
Greetings earthlings. I come from afar from the sink out. See no only two of you. Why are you here? Where did you come from?
We have been observing UFOs in the past 3,000 years. We have seen the amazing capacity that humans have to create such
wonders as the touch of the hall or massive pieces such as the half-nourced infinity. Unfortunately,
your intelligence in creativity does not come without consequence. Your vision and desire
from world will be your downfall and we are very distinguished by your planet from you.
You think you have us figured out? Who gives you the right to come and judge us? Who are you to play
God with our fate? Silent Earth is an adventure in attitude that has caused the years of pain and
anguish and on yourself now you'll pay the price.
Well that didn't work out so well for the earthlings. Just now did it.
I think the aliens are a little bit
belligerent themselves.
All right, so why don't we start
by looking at some of those difficult words
that we might have found in this dialogue
in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay, well the aliens are using a lot of language
to describe some of the negative results
that are happening because of the humans behavior
on earth, right?
Right.
And so one of the things they said was that
your intelligence and creativity
does not come without consequence.
Consequence.
Without consequence.
All right, so the consequence of an action
are basically the results.
Yes, exactly.
And here the phrase without consequence
suggests the negative results.
All right, so the negative results from your actions.
Very good.
What about our next word?
Well, the aliens also talked about human ambition.
Ambition.
So what is ambition exactly?
So ambition is the desire or the want
for things to be better to improve,
to get rich, to be technologically advanced.
Okay, so to want more.
Yeah, you have ambitions in your life
and your professional life and your personal life.
So basically we have ambition and we have desires
and these are the reasons for our downfall.
Okay, so downfall.
Downfall.
It will be your downfall.
So the downfall of something is something
that causes failure.
Okay, so the loss of wealth or the loss of reputation
that it gets ruined.
Exactly.
The downfall, we can say like for example,
the downfall of the Roman Empire.
Or you know what?
This guy is a great employee, but his lack of ambition
was his downfall.
Very good.
All right, coming up to our next word,
the alien described that humans have a belligerent attitude.
belligerent.
All right, this is a very nice word.
So why don't we listen to some examples
of how we can use it in context?
Example one.
Don't take that belligerent tone with me.
I don't want to argue with you.
Example two.
Thomas is always so belligerent.
It is impossible to talk to him.
Example three.
Stacey was fired for her belligerent attitude.
Okay, so I can understand that it means sort of aggressive
having a strong willingness to fight.
Exactly, a belligerent person, a belligerent attitude,
a belligerent country.
Okay, very good.
And our last word for today.
Anguish.
So to cause great anguish.
To cause a lot of terrible, emotional or physical pain.
Okay, so it is a syndrome of pain of suffering.
Yeah, but really intense suffering.
Really intense.
Why don't we give a few examples?
Um, the end of his marriage caused him great anguish.
Or for example, the loss of his dog caused him great anguish.
Okay, so anguish.
All right, so we've covered five great words on language
takeaway today.
Why don't we move on now to putting it together?
Let's do it together.
Okay, we're gonna look at three phrases that we heard
in the dialogue and see how we can use them in different contexts.
So the aliens were praising some of the master pieces
that the humans have created, right?
Right.
We said, you humans create such wonders as the Taj Mahal.
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Okay.
So let's look at this phrase, such wonders as.
All right, so we have a noun here, a wonder.
Mm-hmm.
An amazing thing.
An amazing structure.
Yes.
So he says such wonders as.
Now we can change this noun and replace it with another one, right?
Yeah, we can replace that noun with anything.
So why don't we hear a few examples?
Example one.
To finish this house, we need such materials as cement, wood,
and steel.
Example two.
I need to write a report on a social topic
such as psychology, health, or marriage.
Example three.
Companies have found that social networking sites
which is Facebook and Twitter are great marketing opportunities.
So this is a really useful structure to use
when you want to give examples of many different things.
Okay, and as the alien was criticizing the humans,
the guy said, what gives you the right to come and judge us?
So interesting phrase, what gives you the right?
What gives you the right?
All right, so if I tell you
what gives you the right to and then a verb,
yeah, what am I saying there?
You're basically saying you don't have the right to do this.
You shouldn't do this.
Why are you doing it?
Or why do you want to have this control over me?
Yeah, so when would you use this phrase?
If somebody is trying to control you
or maybe somebody is judging you
or doing something to you against your will, maybe.
Yeah, you would say what gives you the right
to take my phone away?
What gives you the right to tell me what to do?
All right, it's a good phrase to tell that other person
that they shouldn't do that.
They're doing something unfair.
Unfair, okay.
And our next phrase is very similar.
Who are you to play God with our fate?
Okay, so I want to look at this.
To play God.
All right, so to play God is making these arbitrary decisions
like he is the master of everything.
Right, controlling everything.
But this phrase, who are you to?
So basically saying you don't have the power or authority
to do this.
And you can use it in exactly the same way.
Who are you to tell me what to do?
Who are you to take away my phone?
Exactly, so you don't have the power to do this.
Very good.
So these phrases are a little bit aggressive,
almost a belligerent, wouldn't you say?
A little bit, but I guess if you are being treated unfair
or if you are angry at a situation,
it would be a good phrase to use to put your point across.
Yes, and as we saw, these humans are pretty angry.
So why don't we listen again
as they're telling the aliens who are you to do this to us?
Oh honey, this is so romantic.
I have never seen so many stars before.
It's beautiful.
See that constellation there?
That's Orion.
And the very bright star?
Well, it's not a star because it is a blink.
That's actually Venus.
What's that big flash you want?
I don't know.
I think it's a UFO.
She thinks her wings are come from afar.
From a distinct galaxy known only to a few.
Why are you here?
Where did you come from?
We have been observing you for the last 3,000 years.
We have seen the amazing capacity that humans have to create such wonders
as the touch of the hall or massive pieces such as the half-nerce symphony.
Unfortunately, your intelligence and creativity does not come without consequence.
Your ambition and desire for world will be your downfall.
And we are very pleased to say your planet from you.
You think you have us figured out?
Who gives you the right to come and judge us?
Who are you to play God with our fate?
Silent Spirit is an apple-drained attitude that has called you the pain and anguish
among yourselves.
Now you'll pay the price.
Okay, so UFOs and constellations and stars and planets.
Have you ever had an encounter with one of these?
Well, definitely not an encounter with a UFO, but maybe with some of the wonders of the night sky.
What happened?
Well, you know, when I was small, I used to have my vacations up in Northern Canada.
And because it was so far away from the city, it was really dark.
And you could see all of these shooting stars.
So these stars moving across the sky and lighting up the whole sky with their brightness.
And it really is one of the most beautiful things I've ever seen.
So shooting stars are like balls of fire that move across the sky, right?
Yeah, exactly.
And I saw once, actually, I was in an astronomy class and turned around and over the horizon,
like at the end of the sky where the sky meets the earth, I saw this huge ball of fire move across the sky.
And it looked like it landed in the field next to us.
It was so close.
Wow, that's nice.
Yeah, pretty amazing.
Well, I imagine that it is really amazing.
And I guess Canada is the place to be when you want to see these things.
I know, we've got like Northern lights.
We've got shooting stars, lots of stuff.
All right.
So what about you guys, you should tell us if you have ever seen a shooting star or a meteor
or something of this type of astronomy things, right?
Or even a UFO.
All right.
So come to our website, englishpod.com.
And be sure to leave your questions and your comments.
And Eric and I are there to answer any questions or doubts.
Well, thanks for downloading you guys.
And until next time, goodbye.
Bye.