Hello English learners, welcome back to English pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another part of our sports series and today we're
going to be talking about volleyball. That's right and we're going all the way to New Zealand to
visit the Men's volleyball championships. So we're going to be looking at some great words and phrases
related to volleyball and also how to describe a sporting event. So before we start on the dialogue
let's take a look at two words on vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview.
All right we're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue. Now the first one in counter
encounter and exciting encounter. All right so if we have an exciting encounter it means we have an exciting
meeting of two people or two teams or two groups. If I say I had an incredible encounter last night
with my best friend. You met up your best friend with your best friend and something happens.
Okay so that's what an encounter would mean. Yes. Looking at our second word now, powerhouse.
Two powerhouse teams. All right so we have two powerhouse teams, China and Brazil. That's right.
So a powerhouse team is basically a strong, powerful, really energetic, great team right?
Okay so we can use it for teams such as in this case but we can also describe
maybe a company or a person at powerhouse. That guy is a powerhouse. You can lift 500 pounds.
Now I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the first time. We're going to be
listening to this great sporting event as we are taken to New Zealand to see China and Brazil play.
Hey.
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the Men's volleyball world championship. My name is Rick
Field and I'm joined by the man of the plant Bob Copeland. Thank you Rick. We've got a very
exciting encounter ahead of us today is two powerhouse teams, Brazil and China. These off against each
other and try to qualify for the next round without a doubt. Both teams are in top shape and this
will prove to be a competitive match. The ref signals are started the game and here we go.
Rebeiro serves and China quickly receives the ball. Chun bumps it to the center and very nice
set by Chun. She was spiced. Wow, what a great hit. The Brazilian blockers anticipated the play
and tried to block him but he managed to get the ball in great play. It's China service now.
What a superb jumpserv by Lee. Oh, oh and we have a let's serve. The ball was coming
in fast and almost made it over the net. Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back
after a short commercial break.
Well sounds like a pretty exciting encounter between these two countries. Very good teams and both of them
as they mentioned our powerhouse teams. Well, why don't we take a look at some of the vocabulary
that we came across in this dialogue. We're going to be focusing on volleyball words here in
language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay, so in language takeaway today we're going to have six words
and let's start with the first one. Chen bumps it to the center. All right, two bump. All right, so
in volleyball when you are going to receive the ball, you put your arms together and you hit it
with your four arms. That's right. So at the top of your arm. Right, and that's how you pass it to
another player. That's called a bump. So it is a noun and a verb, a bump too bump. Exactly. Now
another type of way to move the ball in volleyball we heard in the dialogue is a set. A very nice
set by Chen. So a set or two set. Right, the word can be used as a verb and a noun and again,
you take the ball and you move it with the tips of your fingers. That is actually done by the
center. Right, that is done by the center and he does this. He sets the ball. So then the attacker can
spike the ball. That's our next word. Two spike. So two spike the ball or a spike is when you
hit the ball very hard and very fast with the palm of your hand. That's right. And that's how you
score your points. Exactly. So you'll see three basic moves. The bump set and spike. But what about
the serve? All right, so our fourth word in volleyball is service. So it's China's service now.
Right, so the service is the opportunity for the team to serve the ball. Yeah, pretty simple.
Right. And that means basically to start the game by hitting it to the other side. Now,
one type of serve is the jump serve. Jump serve. Now, this is very popular and you will see
some players do this. They will throw the ball in the air and then jump in the air and hit it. That's
right. All right. So that's a jump serve. And our last word for today is let serve.
Okay. We have a let serve today. So a let serve is when you serve the ball and it sort of brushes
over the net. Right. It'll hit the net, but it will still pass to the other side. That's right. And
that's an illegal move in volleyball isn't it? When you are serving, yes. So a let serve. Right. So those
are the six terms related to volleyball that we're going to be looking at today and well with this
in mind, let's move on to looking at some phrases now in what is it? Fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right. So our two announcers, Bob and Rick said that we've got an exciting
encounter ahead of us. Right. So they use this phrase ahead of us ahead of us. So basically, what does that
mean? Something will happen in the very near future. So they are expecting it or they will encounter
it maybe. Yes. So why don't we give a few examples of this phrase? Marco, we've got a long day ahead of
us. We have a very exciting trip ahead of us today. Mm-hmm. Okay. So ahead of us. So we know it's an exciting
game. And we heard the announcer say without a doubt, both teams are in top shape. Okay. So the phrase
without a doubt. Without a doubt. So if I start a phrase using without a doubt, you're basically
saying there's no question. It's so obvious. This definitely is true. It's very true. Okay. So without
a doubt, English pod is the best podcast out there. Without a doubt, this is the strategy we should
take. Okay. Very good. So without a doubt, why don't we move on to our third phrase now? This will
prove to be a competitive match. So let's look at the phrase, will prove to be something will prove to
be. Okay. So before we get into it, why don't we listen to some examples? Example one.
And I think you'll prove to be the greatest president we've ever had.
Example two. The new HR policy is proving to be a waste of time.
Example three. We were worried that we were going to get laid off, but our fear is proved to be untrue.
Okay. So when something will prove to be, it will show itself to be this thing, right? It will
demonstrate. We will see it. We will see for sure how it will be. And now for our fourth phrase,
very simple one, but very common in sports commentators or when you're watching a game.
You'll say, Great play. Great play. Great play. A great play. Now we know play is usually a verb, right?
But here it's acting as a noun. A play is basically a move in a sport or a game. So when somebody
says a great play, it means all the succession of moves and passes and hits to make the point.
Yep. So it was a great play. And that you can use that for any sport. Right. So why don't we
listen to our dialogue now for the second time? And then we'll come back and talk about this very
popular sport volleyball.
It's a beautiful day here in New Zealand at the Men's volleyball world championship. My name is Rick
Field and I'm joined by the man of the plan Bob Copeland. Thank you Rick. We've got a very
exciting encounter ahead of us today is two powerhouse teams, Brazil and China.
Face off against each other and try to qualify for the next round without a doubt. Both teams are
in top shape and this will prove to be a competitive match. The ref signals are started the game and
here we go. We bear who serves and China quickly receives the ball. Chun bumps it to the center
and very nice set by Chun. She was spiced. Wow, what a great hit. The Brazilian blockers anticipated
the play and tried to block him but he managed to get the ball in great play. It's China service now.
What a superb jump serve by Lee. Oh, oh and we have a let's serve. The ball was coming in fast
and almost made it over the net. Brazil calls for a timeout and we'll be right back after a
commercial break. So you were volleyball fan Marco? It's a very nice sport. It's very fast
and it's very hard. But it's very interesting to get together with friends maybe at the beach and
play some beach volleyball or something like that. Yeah, I think that's the best place to play volleyball.
You know, we even have beach volleyball up in freezing cold Canada. And do you have sand?
Occasionally. All right. So volleyball is a great sport but now we want to know what sport you
want to learn about. We've covered soccer, we've covered basketball, we've covered volleyball.
So tell us what other sports you would like to learn vocabulary and phrases on. That's right.
You can tell us this and many more things at EnglishPod.com our website. So check it out.
Right. Leave your questions in comments and we'll see you guys there.
Thanks for downloading and until next time. Bye.