Hello, English learners. Welcome back to another great podcast here at EnglishPod.
My name is Marco. And I'm Erica. And today we're going to be talking about one of our favorite
topics as always. Food. Food. We're going to be at a restaurant. And you know, one of the most
difficult or embarrassing things to deal with at a restaurant is what to say when you don't like
the food or when it's bad quality food. Right. So maybe we have to complain about the food or maybe
even the service, right? That's right. And in this lesson, we're going to be learning some
some really wonderful words and phrases that you can use when you need to complain about the food
or the service in a restaurant. Okay. So before we listen to what happens in this restaurant with this
food, let's take a look very quickly at vocabulary preview. Very cablory preview. Okay. We're
only going to do one word today. And this you'll hear in the dialogue. And establishment.
Establishment. This kind of establishment. Okay. So when I say enestablishment, that's a noun.
What is enestablishment? It's basically a fancy word for a business or a restaurant in this case.
In this case, it's a restaurant. Yeah. But in general, you can say it's a business. So you have a very
fine establishment. That's right. So an establishment, a type of business, a place of business.
Really. Very good. All right. So now it's time for us to listen to our dialogue. We're going to
find out what's going on here. Apparently there is a very angry customer and we're going to find out why.
Excuse me. Waiter. Yes, sir. What can I do for you? I've been sitting here for the past 20 minutes
and no one has offered me a glass of water brought any bread to the table and our appetizer
haven't been served yet. You know, in this kind of establishment, I'd expect much better service.
I'm sorry, sir. I'll check on your order right away. Relax honey. The place is busy tonight.
And I've heard the food is amazing. Anyway, here you are, sir. The fog off of the lady in a mushroom soup
for you. Waiter. I heard a cream of mushroom soup with a spare guess. The soup is obviously
too runny and it's over season. It's completely inedible. Okay, I do apologize for that.
Can I bring you another soup? Or would you like to order something else? Take this flock
high back as well. It's rubbery and completely overcooked and look at the portion size.
How can you charge $25 for a sliver of duck liver? Right away, sir. Honey, come on. The
fog off was fine. Why are you making such a big deal? Are you trying to get our meal
calmed again? What do you mean? You're paying for this and I'm showing out my hard earned
bucks. I expect value for money. Here you are, sir. I hope it is all right now. The chef has
prepared it especially for you. Yes, fine. Honey, are you all right?
Let's go.
Well, I guess that's one lesson. Hey, if you're in a restaurant,
don't be too rude to the waiter. You never know what's going to happen. The waiter and the cook.
Mm-hmm. Yeah, you don't want to offend that kitchen staff. All right, so we'll talk about that a
little bit later on, but now I think we had some really interesting vocabulary of how to
describe food that is not well prepared and we can take a look at that now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right, so the guy in this in this dialogue, he ordered a mushroom soup and he
complained that the mushroom soup was too runny. Okay, the soup is too runny. Runny, so he wanted a
cream of mushroom so it should be a little bit thicker. Yep, but in this case it was runny.
So when something is runny, it's too liquid. Who liquid? And I think we can relate it to a runny nose,
right? Exactly. Okay, so when liquid is coming out of your nose, a runny nose in this case, the soup is
runny. All right, and another thing that he was complaining about, the food was over seasoned.
Over seasoned. The food is over seasoned. Okay, so if the food is over seasoned, it's too salty.
So it's another way of saying it's too salty. Yeah, it's kind of a fancy, um, a cooking term.
Now can I say if there's too much pepper in the food, can I say it's over seasoned? Well,
I'm technically no, when when a cook says something is over seasoned, he's talking salt only.
Only salt. Okay. So the the cream of mushroom is very runny. It's over seasoned and he said it's
completely inedible. Inedible. It's inedible. Inedible. Now this word edible. You can eat it.
You can eat it. So we have this prefix inedible. You cannot eat it. This is not possible. Yeah, and it
doesn't mean that physically you can't eat it. It just means it's pretty disgusting. Okay, this food is inedible.
And then he started to complain about the other dish and he said that it's rubbery.
rubbery. The the the fog grout was rubbery. All right, so I think we noticed the word rubber.
So obviously if if a food is rubbery, it tastes or it it's too chewy. It's like chewing on the bottom of your shoe, right?
Okay, so it's it's too hard to chew or to swallow. Exactly. All right. Apparently the food was rubbery because it's
completely overcooked. Overcooked. All right, we have overcooked. So when something is overcooked, I mean it's
easy to understand that it's cooked too much. But it doesn't mean that it's burnt, right? No, so
maybe you've ordered your steak to be rare, but it comes to you well done. So it's not burnt,
but it's cooked too much. So also I guess we can say like chicken. Sometimes if you overcooked
chicken, it comes out too dry. Yep. All right, so to overcook something. Mm-hmm. And finally
he was complaining about the size of the dish and he said, um, this is a sliver of duck liver.
Okay, a sliver. A sliver. All right, now this word sliver is like a slice, right? A very small,
tiny little slice. Okay, so we can say, okay, I just want a sliver of bacon for breakfast. All right,
why don't we hear a few more examples of how we can use sliver? Example one.
No, John's on a diet. He'll just have a sliver of cake and no ice cream. Example two.
I'm really full, but it looks so delicious. Can you just cut me a sliver? Example three.
You call this sliver of beef on my plate of meal? There's almost nothing here.
And those are all the words we had for language takeaway. Now you have, so we've given you different
adjectives of describing food that is not well prepared. So now let's move on to some other phrases
that the customer used to complain in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay, so before we get to the
customer complaining language, I want to look at a phrase that the waiter used to apologize. He said,
I do apologize. I do apologize. I do apologize. Now why is this phrase so interesting? Well,
I mean, it's pretty easy to understand the meaning, but I want to look at why he added this
verb do. Well, he added the verb do it to this phrase to make it seem a little bit stronger to give
it a little more power to his apology. Right, so if you have an affirmative phrase like I apologize,
it's good. Yeah, but if you want to give it a little bit more emphasis, you can say I do apologize.
Why don't we give an example? So I might say this. Marco, I didn't know we had a party tonight.
And I might say what? I did tell you about it last week. Right, so you're just giving a little bit
more power to the statement that you told me. So this due did does, it becomes an auxiliary to make it
more powerful to give it more emphasis. Yeah, exactly. So an neat little phrase,
something you can use if you want to make your apologies sound maybe a little bit stronger.
All right. Now moving on to the next phrase, he was complaining about the food and was terrible. And he
said, I'm shelling out my hard earned bucks. Okay, let's let's break this one down into two
sections. We'll start with shelling out. All right. So to shell out. So when you shell out,
you pay for something. All right. But this gives you the sensation that you are,
that you don't really want to pay. You're a bit unhappy about it. Right. So you want to shell out your
money. Mm-hmm. Why don't we listen to some examples to show us how we can use this phrase to shell out.
Example one. Great. It's my girlfriend's birthday this month. So I'm going to have to shell out for a present.
Example two. I really want those shoes, but I can't really afford to shell out $400.
Example three. I can't believe it. Ella showed out the 800 bucks for the tickets. I thought I would have to pay.
All right. So now that we understand shell out, let's move on to the second part of that sentence.
My hard earned bucks. Hard earned bucks. My hard earned bucks. Okay. So bucks are dollars, right?
Dollars. Only dollars, right? Yep. Not not pounds, not your owes. But his hard earned bucks is money.
He had to work really hard for it. Mm-hmm. So I can also save my hard earned money,
right? Or my hard earned cash. Exactly. Very good. So you worked hard to get it. All right. So three,
three great phrases that can be used when you're complaining in a restaurant. And why don't we hear
them one last time in context by listening to the dialogue?
Excuse me. Waiter. Yes sir. What can I do for you? I've been sitting here for the past 20 minutes
and no one has offered me a glass of water brought any bread to the table and our appetizer
haven't been served yet. You know, in this kind of establishment, I'd expect much better service.
I'm sorry sir. I'll check on your order right away. For a laks honey, the place is busy tonight
and I've heard the food is amazing. Anyway. Here you are sir. The fog off of the lady and a mushroom soup for you.
Waiter. I heard a cream of mushroom soup of the sparigast. The soup is obviously too
runny and it's over season. It's completely inedible. Okay. I do apologize for that. Can I bring
you another soup or would you like to order something else? Take this fucker I back as well.
It's rubbery and completely overcooked and look at the portion size. How can you start
25 dollars for a sliver of duck liver? Right away sir. Honey, come on. The fog raw was fine. Why are you
making such a big deal? Are you trying to get our milk pumped again? What do you mean? You're paying
for this and I'm shelling out my hard earned bucks. I expect value for money. Here you are sir.
I hope it is all right now. The chef has prepared it especially for you. Yes fine.
Honey are you all right?
Oh, yeah.
So complaining in a restaurant and actually sending food back is not uncommon in the US.
Yeah, of course. If the food's bad, of course you're going to send it back. But maybe another
culture I think people would be a little bit more reluctant to do something like this. Yeah, but hey,
you know what's an interesting thing about the way Americans eat in restaurants is sometimes at the
end of the meal. They haven't finished everything. They might ask for a doggy bag. A doggy bag, yeah.
So what is that a doggy bag? Well usually if you order a big meal or you know half your stake
is left over on the plate. You would ask for a doggy bag and they would bring you a little
box or a bag and you would take it to supposedly give it to your dog. Right. So it's sort of like
like you tell the waiter, oh you know the stake was so good. I couldn't finish it. Can I take some
home to my dog? Right. So you would just ask, wait, can I have a doggy bag? Right. But it's sort of like
code for I'm going to eat this tomorrow for lunch. Exactly because people wouldn't really give it
to their dog. Yeah. You know that the stake wrapped up in a fancy sort of foil so on is going to be
a pretty delicious the next day. Right. Yeah, it's actually very common in the US, but in other
countries people will leave. Yeah. Entire plates of food. Like they totally impolite to ask the waiter
to pack up the food for you. Exactly. Yep. So a little bit of cultural differences but we want to
know what you think and how things are done maybe in your country with complaining or sending food
back or even this whole doggy bag situation. That's right. Want you to visit our website
EnglishPod.com and tell us about it. All right. We'll be there to answer any questions or comments
but we gotta go now so until then. Goodbye. Bye.