Hello English learners. Welcome back to English.
Pod, my name is Marco. And my name is Katherine. And today, Marco and I get to share with you
the thrilling conclusion to the, well, very popular. I'm gonna say series. I'm sorry. I love you.
That's right. Today is the finale, the final episode. Episode 10. This is where it all ends. So,
what do you think is going to happen? If I guess you're just going to get angry at me because I
actually know how it ends, let's just say I hope that it ends well for protagonists.
There was a lot of controversy around it because, you know, I wanted to know if people wanted
a happy ending, a sad ending, unexpected. I guess everyone wants a happy ending, right? Absolutely. So,
we're gonna, well, keep our fingers crossed for Steven and Veronica and check out this dialogue one time.
What's your name? Steven, good to see you, brother. How are you? How was your trip?
It was fine. I've been better, but it's a great to be home. If missed you all, how's mom?
She's great. All she ever does is talk about you or little boy that have entenied its
state. You're her pride and joy. You know that. I can't wait to see you. You, what's new with you?
Well, Nishai and I are expecting. You'll have another nephew, Nisu and... That's great. Wow!
Congrats! You two are great together, you know. You have such a beautiful family.
I hope that one day I can have that. Of course, man. Come on. I mean,
everything was said here for you to marry Shalini. You know, she is still planning after you.
I don't think she'll ever get over you. What are you talking about? I hardly knew her.
How could she be in love with me? I can go through with it even though she is a great woman.
No, I left my hardening night at states. I just hope Veronica is happy. Get over it. You're home now.
Everyone here thinks so highly of you. They'll be girls trying themselves at you. You can marry anyone you want.
I don't want to marry anyone. I want to marry her. Don't you understand?
You are incorrigible.
See you then. My baby, how war are you? I'm Mrs. Soma.
You are great to see you. You look so thin. Did endo some American's feed you? Come, come.
Let's have some time. By the way, there is a girl here waiting for you.
Hi, Steven. Veronica, how did you get here? How do you know where I live?
I waited for you at the airport, but you never showed. I also have some little secrets that I haven't told you about,
but we can discuss that later. I realized that I was just scared. Scared of how much I love you and
of the commitment that marriage requires. I'm here now. Now, there's something I want to ask you.
Steven, will you marry me?
I now declare you husband and wife. You may kiss the bride.
All right, so they got married. You got married. I got married.
Wow, I should have called my mom. Not only did you get married, but you got married.
Bollywood style with music and everything. Those weddings are like four days long.
I hope you enjoyed the finale of this story. Absolutely. I was glad to see that it was a happy ending.
I have to say that if it had been a sad ending, I would have been a little bit disappointed
because, well, Veronica and I, you get along. We get along. All right.
So apart from this happy ending and this happy finale that we had, we did look at a lot of great words
and phrases. So why don't we start now with language takeaway? Language takeaway.
So the first couple of phrases I want to talk about here have to do with maybe catching up and
talking about family or gossip because we're talking to family.
Stevens in the end family hasn't seen for a long time. The first thing he's talking to his brother
about his brother and his wife. So Goulaman Nisha are expecting we find out.
Right, they're expecting. So I've Goulaman Nisha are expecting. What does that mean?
Exactly. They're expecting a letter. Expecting a baby maybe?
Ah, yeah. So here we go. I'm expecting is very common English way of saying,
I'm going to have a baby. I'm pregnant. All right. So don't get this confused.
As somebody says, oh well, I'm expecting. You don't have to say expecting what exactly. When it's
only expecting when it's not a thing afterwards, I'm expecting means I'm pregnant or she's expecting.
She's going to have a baby. So they are expecting a baby or they are expecting. Well, and they were
talking about well, so Stevens, he was supposed to get married in India and his brother said
a very interesting where he said, well, these girls are still, this girl is still pining over you.
So the Shalini, some girl that Steven used to know when he was living in India, she's pining
after you. Well, pine has many different meanings. Right. But in this sense, we're talking about
having a crush on or being in love with. And also it's a way of saying that you are that you
desire you yearn for this person very, very much. But that you don't have them. Right. You want
them. So you're pining over this person. Now, can you pine over an object? No. No. Usually,
it's maybe related to love or to in a person. Right. Yeah. So she stands by the door every day,
waiting the letter that doesn't come. She's pining away for her dear love, Thomas or whatever.
And you know what I read recently is that people can get addicted to pining. Really?
Yeah. After a breakup, maybe you can pine after a person not because you miss them or you
want to put you kind of grow a custom to it and you become addicted to this pain that's kind of
pleasurable. Hmm. There is a way to describe this. It's called Petrarch in Love. Well, it's this kind of
traditional idea in poetry where you have a love that's never consumated. It's never filled.
You never get to be with the person that you love that you desire. And so it's a way, yeah. It's a way of
distinguishing the two different kinds of love. One where you're with the person and the other where you
always want them, but you can never have them. Well, but hopefully none of our listeners are pining
over anyone or get to experience that, huh? Exactly. But if you do pine away or if you pine after
someone, you have to hope that one day you'll get over that person. Yeah. You have to get over it.
And that's what his brother says, hey, get over it. I don't think she'll ever get over you.
So what does it mean when you're supposed to get over someone? Okay, this is a good question because,
you know, we're talking here not about actually getting up on top of a fence or a wall. We're talking
about emotions. So getting over someone, so I have to get over him means that I have to stop feeling
so sad about what what happened, right? Because usually you say this when someone's sad or angry.
And also it kind of means that you have to forget or let that person go, you know, like get over it.
We're going to move on here too to the last word in today's language takeaway, which is
incorrigible. Okay, an incorrigible person. All right, incorrigible. What could this mean? Well,
let's look at the sentence where we find it. You are incorrigible. Mm-hmm. Gulam says this to Stephen.
Right. So it's an adjective and basically it means that you have no correction of some sort.
We're this an argument between Stephen and Gulam. So their brothers and Stephen says, I don't want to
get married. I don't want to marry her. Ah, he's complaining and his brother says, you are incorrigible.
You just won't stop. Right. So someone's, someone's feelings, their emotions, their ideas about
something. They just can't be changed or altered, they're fixed. You know, this guy, he's like,
I'm not going to get married and his brother says, oh, you're incorrigible. I just can't change your mind.
It's kind of like being stubborn. Yeah, yeah, exactly. And we hear this phrase a lot
together. So you're incorrigible. Right. So this is often just kind of a, it's not an insult.
But it's a way for us to kind of be sarcastic or to make fun of someone. Mm-hmm. You're in
a hard or a mark. Oh, you usually say when you're like, you know, you're being nice. All right.
Mm-hmm. Okay. Cool. So five great words in language takeaway today. And well, before we move on
and listen to the dialogue, again, why don't we take a look at fluency builder? Fluency builder.
All right. This first phrase is something that parents often use and grandparents as well,
because obviously, parents and grandparents, they're very proud of their children,
they're grandchildren. So they describe something as being their pride and joy.
Hmm, my pride and joy. So it's usually a person that's your pride and joy. It could be a thing, too.
It could be a thing. His poor spockster is his pride and joy. He goes out every morning and he washes it.
He changes the oil. He checks the gas. He checks the tire. So it's his pride and joy. All right.
It's his most valued possession. So it always goes together, right? My pride and joy.
Pride and joy. Yeah. Just think of it as a phrase. Pride and joy. All right. So
I'm my mother's pride and joy. I think you are. Mm-hmm. All right. So you know, my mom.
All right. So somebody's pride and joy. So now in other phrase that we took a look at and it's a
way of making conversation, especially with a person that you haven't seen in a while. He said,
hey, what's new with you? What's new with you? Uh-huh. What's new with you? All right. So this
might sound a little strange because normally we say, how have you been? It's been a long time. How are you?
But this is like, you know, it's a fluency builder phrase. So it's very colloquial. It's very
spoken language. So this you hear often between friends or family members. Hey, Marco, what's new with you?
So how do you, I would answer this by saying, oh, well, not much or, uh, I just bought a new house.
So basically, you're asking for news from the person. I haven't seen you in a long time. You look,
you look happy and healthy. So what's new with you? Oh, I got married. I got a new car.
These things that you can say, these are changes in my life. All right. And usually after somebody
asks you, what's new with you? You say something. And then you usually would follow up and ask
that person as well, right? What's new and what's new with you? Exactly. So, you know, I got an
house coming in job. What's new with you? Yeah. Or what about you? What about you? So it's a nice,
very relaxed, informal way of asking someone for news in their life. Perfect. All right. What's new with you?
What else? Now, he was supposed to get married, right? Right. So this is news. He was supposed to get
married. He didn't get married. What's going on? His brother, his mother, they all want to know what's
going on. And we find out that wedding, that girl, he just couldn't go through with it.
So I can't, I couldn't go through with it. Okay. This past tense. So he's saying,
before I came to India with this girl, I couldn't go through with it. So present would be,
I can't go through with it. And going through with what here, we've got it to this kind of magical
strange word. It, what it would could this be. So basically, what he's saying is that he couldn't
complete or maybe finish something that he started, right? So in this case, we're talking about
a relationship or marriage. So maybe we love each other, but I couldn't go through with it. I couldn't
go to the finish line. Mm-hmm. Right. I couldn't get married. You see that a lot when maybe in
movies, two people are supposed to get married. They're at the altar. And all of a sudden, the bride says,
I can't, or she goes away crying. I can't go through with it. Exactly. Right. So because she
loves somebody else, so can't go through with it. Mm-hmm. Great. So really good phrase. I can't
go through with it. He couldn't go through with it. And we find out that, well, not such a bad thing.
Steve and he's very popular in India. The girls love him. We've got a great phrase for describing
having lots of girls who love you. Right. He says, there will be girls throwing themselves at you.
Literally like, oh, that might be a horror. I can't imagine that. Like, just somebody
throwing themselves at you. No. It's not literal. It's basically saying girls are very
interested in you. Girls are so interested in you that they'll be chasing you almost. All right.
So many, many girls, they will follow you. They'll want to be in a relationship with you. They like you.
So he's saying, listen, there are other girls. Don't worry. Girls here, they love you.
And it doesn't only work with girls, right? I can say they'll be boys throwing themselves at you.
Right. So this is something we say about both genders. Boys and girls. You can say, oh, God,
all the boys were throwing themselves at her. I'm so jealous. Right. So, but it's only basically
in a loving way. Right. It can't be anything else. Like, somebody's chasing you for other reasons.
Now, this is saying that they have crushes. They have feelings. They want to be romantic.
It's not like a, it's not a bad thing. But sometimes it's too much attention. So it can be kind of
All right. Well, interesting phrases on Fluency Builder today. I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue for
one last time. Get up and dance. Yeah. Get up and dance. And we'll be back in a little bit.
Music
Steven, good to see you, brother. How are you? How was your trip? It was fine. I've been better, but
it's a great to be home. I've missed you all. How's mom? She's great. All she ever does is talk about
you or little boy that have entangled in the United States. You're her pride and joy. You know that.
Can't wait to see you. You, what's new with you? Well, Nishai and I are expecting. You'll have
another nephew, Nisu and that's great. Wow. Congrats to a great together. You know,
you have such a beautiful family. I hope that one day I can help that. Of course, man. Come on.
I mean, everything was said here for you to marry Shalini. You know, she is still planning
out for you. I don't think she'll ever get over you. What are you talking about? I hardly knew
her. How could she be in love with me? I couldn't go through it even though she is a great woman.
No, I left my hard night at the States. I just hope Veronica is happy. Get over it. You're home now.
Everyone here thinks so highly of you. They'll be girls trying themselves at you. You can marry
anyone you want. I don't want to marry anyone. I want to marry her. Don't you understand?
You are incorrigible.
Steven, my baby, how war are you? I'm Mrs. Soma.
Nima, great to see you. You look so thin. Did I know some Americans feed you? Come, come.
Let's have some time. By the way, there is a girl here waiting for you.
Hi, Steven. Veronica, how did you get here? How do you know where I live?
I waited for you at the airport, but you never showed. I also have some little secrets that I haven't
told you about, but we can discuss that later. I realized that I was just scared,
scared of how much I love you and the commitment that marriage requires. I'm here now. Now,
there's something I want to ask you. Steven, will you marry me?
I now declare you husband and wife. You may kiss the bride.
All right, so it's over. Sad, sad, but sweet. Sad, but sweet. We went from them meeting casually
by a bike accident. Yeah, we had nice music. Then it turned out that she was angry. They kind of
broke up. They got back together. He was being strained with all of these secret trips to save people.
It was interesting. We went a lot of different ways people. She was pregnant. She wasn't
pregnant. The doctor was stalking the doctor. He's in the secret service. It was an
interesting ride. Very interesting. Well, now we need to think of a new drama and new soap opera
or novel. So we need your input. Maybe we should open it up. What did you like? What didn't you
like? And what kind of genre are you interested in? Because you know, there's tons of different
kinds of stories we could tell. Right, maybe we can do something scary, like a thriller or horror.
I'm a big fan of sci-fi. Or sci-fi, maybe we can do something sci-fi. Maybe we can do a comedy,
something maybe like friends. I don't know. That'd be kind of cute. Yeah, it could be. All right,
so listeners, why don't you give us your input? We need your feedback. Tell us what series you
would like next? What type of series? Maybe like we said drama, sci-fi, action. What would you like?
And please get in touch with us, leave comments and questions on our website, EnglishPod.com.
We'd like to check those and answer you. So yeah, get in touch with us and have a great day.
All right, we'll see you guys there. Bye.