Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today we're talking about being on the road
yeah we're gonna be on the road but we're gonna encounter a little bit of a car problems
my favorite kind
I think it's happened to everyone you're on the road or maybe you're coming back from work
you get a flat tie or something happens to your car right
and it's always when you're in a rush
and most of the time it's raining
yeah we're just knowing so all of the circumstances definitely well they don't help
let's just say alright so before we listen to this dialogue let's take a look at some of the words in today's vocabulary preview
very cablery preview
alright so we're gonna take a look at two words
um they're kind of strange I don't know kind of difficult to understand so that's what we're gonna explain them
um the first one is spew to spew
it's a verb okay to spew
um well what can spew volcano can spew?
exactly an engine can spew a person can spew
yeah that's not very nice
no so basically it's to like expel or to shoot out shoot out from your mouth or something
liquid so in the case of a person right
so if a person spews it means a person throws up but it's usually very forceful
alright it's very messy
volcano can spew lava
exactly so volcano is spewing lava
now for the next word that we have it's uh it's a informal way of saying that something is broken
because it's busted
it's busted my DVD player is busted
man my phone is busted
so it's an informal way very popular very common I would say
uh to describe that something is not working
I don't think many people actually say well it's broken or it's damaged
yeah they're pretty pretty much mixed I think but you you will definitely hear busted
if you're talking to native English people
or even like for example your arm oh he's got a busted arm
exactly so busted
alright so let's listen to our dialogue for the first time let's see what's going on with this card trouble
and then we'll come back and explain something
howdy nice card what seems to be the problem
I don't know the stupid old car started being white smoke and it just died on me
luckily I managed to start it up and drive it here
what do you think it is not sure yet how about you pop the hood and we can take a look
mmm doesn't look good
what do you mean my daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month
it's brand new
well missy the white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator
you overheated your engines so now the pistons are busted and so is your transmission
you should have called us and we could have told you over here when you car died
so how long is this going to take an hour
how much freight a bit more than that we need to order the spare parts
take a part of your electrical system fuel pump and engine and then put it back together again
you're going to have to leave it here for at least two weeks
what? how am I supposed to go to school or go shopping?
this is not happening
so if I were the mechanic I would not be very happy to be dealing with someone like this girl
I think it's well maybe it's a little bit stereotypical that we put it as a as a girl
because guys and girls so many people don't know anything about cars or mechanics
and in the states there's a lot of female mechanics too so it's mix
but definitely it's something that happens all the time
and probably the mechanic will overcharge her as well because apparently she doesn't know what she's doing
and that's one of the reasons we want to give you the vocabulary to deal with these situations
so let's look at some of those car words in today's language takeaway
language takeaway
all right so we're going to take a look at very specific words related to cars and the engines and everything
so let's start with the first one
radiator
all right so the radiator of the car
so radiator is something that you normally find in the front of the car near the engine
it usually gets very very hot right?
yeah so one of the biggest issues is radiators getting too hot because there's no way to cool them down
so if you live in a place that's very hot the radiator keeps your engine cool because it has water in it
so if it overheats or maybe you didn't put enough water in there then it'll start spewing
steam like in this dialogue
and if you have a problem with your radiator you could actually do a lot of damage to your engine
which is why this is important
and exactly and that's what happened in this dialogue
so a radiator
now because the radiator wasn't working well it overheated the engine and he said they had some busted pistons
so broken pistons pistons are important because they're kind of like valves that go up and down
right so inside your engine you have many explosions and the pistons move up and down and that's what actually moves your car
right and so pistons in general are things in mechanics so like a trumpet has pistons things that go up and down
and that allow for the flow of air or something like that very good
so that's a piston and well another very common mechanic term is the transmission
all right so the transmission what happens if your transmission dies can you still drive
you basically can't move or maybe you only have one gear or two gears
all right so think about transmission is coming from the word to transmit that means to transfer
so this is the part of the car that transfers energy or the power to actually move the car
so the transmission and we've got the mechanic who says well we've got to order you some spare parts
so first let's look at the word spare what's another word for spare
additional maybe extra extra right so spare means extra parts are well pieces
so he's talking about ordering a new transmission new pistons things to replace the broken things
spare parts so this is where you go to the mechanic to get some spare parts and get them installed
you probably don't have many spare parts at home right you got a transmission lying around
oh yeah so spare parts and the last word that we're going to take a look at is a fuel pump
okay so a pump is you could have a bike pump a water pump water pumps so these are
something these are something that we use very very often but a fuel pump is something that
allows gas gasoline to get into your engine so it's basically a device that pushes gasoline
into the engine so you can start and that's the same thing with the water pump it's a device that pushes
water or an air pump is a bit pushes air into your tires and your bicycle
exactly so a fuel pump water pump etc.
wow I feel like we know a lot about cars apparently we do see alright so now that we've taken
look at all of these great words let's move on to a couple of phrases in low and
see builder.
Alright these are phrases that you hear sometimes when you're talking about electronics
but in today's lesson we're all talking about specific car phrases you're going to hear these
all the time with mechanics.
Right and the first one is the car suddenly died on me.
Alright so we keep these two words together die on.
Oh man so while you were driving your car died it stopped moving.
So that means that it it doesn't work anymore and it's not only for cars right you can say my
MP3 player died on me today.
Exactly and what it means is it's not like you left it and you forgot about it and you try it again
that didn't work it means while you're using it it dies.
Exactly.
So I think this phrase is a good one to give some other example so let's listen.
Example one.
My CD player died on me and I had to listen to the radio.
Example two.
Get that medicine over here fast or this guy's going to die on me.
Example three.
I forgot to charge my mobile phone it's going to die on me soon.
So this next one is a phrase you hear the first thing you hear maybe when you tell someone you have a car problem.
Right you tell them to pop the hood or let's pop the hood.
This means let's open the front part of the car the hood to look at the engine transmission all those parts.
Exactly.
So you can say open the hood but but the most common one is pop the hood.
So the reason is because there is a little spring and you have to pull inside the car and goes
And there's a little there's a little jump.
Yeah.
So it's literally popping.
Right or you can also say the trunk right the back part of the car.
Hey can you pop the trunk for me I've got to put some stuff inside.
Exactly so pop the hood pop the trunk.
And next we've got this this girl actually who's talking about her car because she just got this car.
So it's another way to say it's a new car.
It's brand new.
Is that more new than new?
It's like newer newer than new.
All right so brand you think about brands like Ford or good sheet.
These are brands but brand new means she maybe got it like today.
So it's brand new.
It's very very new.
Did you see my brand new watch?
Oh it is nice.
We're to get it.
All right so brand new and well the last phrase that we have for you today is to take apart something.
All right so this is very popular with young children like they like to take things apart.
You can find out how they work but to take up more it means to take all the pieces and to pull them out.
Yeah I used to do that a lot when I was a kid I used to take apart any any electronic device to kind of see how it works and then I would try to put it back together again.
That's why you're so smart.
Well it never really worked.
It worked half the time.
So the problem is always putting them back together again.
Exactly so you can take it apart but then you put it back together and there's always a screw missing or a screw that's extra or two or three parts.
Very not a good sign.
All right so we're taking a look at a lot of great words and phrases so let's listen to this dialogue for the last time.
Howdy nice card.
What seems to be the problem?
I don't know the stupid old car started being white smoke and it just died on me.
Luckily I managed to start it up and drive it here.
What do you think it is?
Not sure yet.
How about you pop the hood and we can take a look?
Mmm.
Doesn't look good.
What do you mean?
My daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month.
It's brand new.
Well Missy?
The white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator.
You overheated your engine so now the pistons are busted and so is your transmission.
You should have called us and we could have told you over here when you car died.
So how long is this going to take an hour?
I'm afraid a bit more than that.
We need to order the spare parts.
Take a part of your electrical system, fuel pump and engine and then put it back together again.
You're going to have to leave it here for at least two weeks.
What?
How am I supposed to go to school or go shopping?
This is not happening.
All right.
So car travel.
Have you ever had any very serious car travel or something weird happened to your car?
Actually.
The week before I decided to leave Chicago, I had this 1991 Honda Civic hatchback.
So only two doors.
Nice.
And I was driving home from work.
I was on the highway.
I had the radio on.
The windows open.
And then...
Do...do...do...do...
It died.
It died in the middle of the highway during rush hour.
Right?
So that's when there's tons of cars.
And I didn't know what to do.
I'm calling people and then all the sudden I see someone tapping on my window.
And there's cars everywhere.
And it's this guy.
And he's like, listen, do you need a hand?
I said yes.
So I put the car in neutral so that there's no break.
Uh-huh.
And he pushed it to a side road and gave me a right home.
He was the coolest guy who's so nice.
And he was just there with his truck.
He's the gardener and just gave me right home.
It was super, super cool.
Wow.
And so it turns out my engine dot.
I mean, no, the engine was new.
It was a transmission.
It was shot.
It was totally broken.
Wow.
But I was very lucky to have such a kind person.
Yeah, that's a good story because usually people are too afraid or maybe a little bit reluctant
to stop and see if you're okay or if you need a ride or something because you can't really trust
people these days.
So, um, but it's good.
I once, I saw somebody on the side of the road and had a flat tire.
It was two girls and they didn't know what to do.
So I was like passing by.
It was actually raining.
And I was like, hey, do you guys need a hand?
And then like, yeah, please, we can't, we can't locate my dad or whatever.
So I was like, changing the tires.
It's not a big deal, right?
And then like, oh, I think, and they wanted to tip me.
They wanted to give me some of the things.
And like, oh, please say this is just so kind of your time and your old way.
And I'm like, no, no, don't worry about it.
No, it's just a nice thing to do.
If you know anything about cars, I mean,
yeah, yeah.
Or if you can offer someone, I'll lift, I know it.
It's not terribly safe to ride with strangers, but this guy totally helped me out.
So nice.
All right, well, maybe you guys have some cool or maybe some interesting stories of what's happened with your cars or maybe you've helped somebody out.
So come to our website at EnglishPod.com and let us know.
And of course, if you have any questions about the vocabulary of phrases that you heard today, please ask away.
Don't hesitate and, well, again, we hope to see you on the website.
All right, we'll see you guys there.
Bye.