Hello English learners. Welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marko.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about something very, very important in the computer age internet internet and internet connections.
Right, I think well so many people use the internet now and have it but it's sometimes a little bit complicated to maybe get a plan or maybe if you're not too familiar with the terms.
That's where we're going to be looking at today.
So listen out for some of these words today where we're talking on the phone with someone who's going to help us get a plan.
When we come back we'll be talking all about what some of these words and phrases mean so if you're confused just wait a couple seconds and we'll be back.
Welcome to Galenet. How can I help you? Hi. I would like to get an internet plan for my house. Of course.
We have three different plans with different prices you can choose from. The first one is the cheapest
but most basic plan which is $30 a month. This is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps.
I have no idea what kbps means. I just want to be able to get online, play games and chat with my friends.
Oh and watch movies online as well. Well this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs.
I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month which includes a connection speed of two megabytes.
That way you can play games online without any lag. This package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall.
Absolutely free. Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you, this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee. You're saving yourself a hundred bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive. Awesome!
All right so interesting. A lot of these technical terms specifically for internet and computers and
connection and all that stuff. Yeah and the nice thing about some of these words is that they can be used in
other ways as well. So we're learning about these and expanding our vocabulary but they're useful in
many other contexts as well. Okay so let's get started with these words now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So this first phrase for example is something that you see advertised all the time and it's
well it's a kind of internet connection. Broadband Internet. Okay so internet is pretty clear but
broadband you might be asking what the heck can this mean? Okay so you have broad. So broad means wide.
Wide and a band is basically kind of like a frequency that which something works. Like bandwidth.
Band with. So you have broadband you have fast or high speed internet. That means the bigger the space is the
more information can be transferred. So it's it's a fast connection. Exactly. Before broadband we had dial-up
internet. Yeah. Remember AOL? Yeah. So you have to use your modem and call a number and then get
connected by my telephone toy was a dial-up connection but it was so slow. And every time it broke the
connection would break. You had to dial-up again and again the whole process is so annoying. Exactly so
fortunately now not many people use dial-up anymore and we have broadband internet. Now if you have
broadband internet it's really convenient because you can download any type of application or music videos,
right so this is another key computer word that actually has a couple of different uses. For example
as you said you can download music or download photos. That means you find a photo on the internet that you
like and you could save it on your computer. But you can also have a download so it can be a thing too.
Okay so if maybe you're downloading three different files you have three downloads. Okay so
two download and download. Very good. So now we internet you have different speeds as we talked
about right. How fast you're downloading something and the guy mentioned 512 KBPS. Oh no not number one of
these KBPS so this man actually this is pretty simple. You can think about kilobytes. You've heard
about megabytes kilobytes. This is a size. Mm-hmm that how fast you can receive these packets of
information. So 512 kilobytes per second. Per second that's I have no idea how much that is.
It's maybe a lot it sounds like a lot. Right well basically it is a lot but we saw later that
he was asking for a connection speed of two megabytes. Ooh so mega is bigger than KBPS right?
Right. All right so these are different speeds of transferring information right so this is a way for you
to see what kind of internet plan you want. Exactly and so you have kilobytes we have megabytes
and basically you want a faster connection speed because you want to avoid lag.
Ooh lag. All right this is a word that you can use in a lot of different ways for example
my brother always lags behind. Okay so it's it's a verb but in this case we don't have the
noun so lag is slowness. Yeah it's like a delay. Yeah it's delay and in something so in this case
I can't even play my video games because there's too much lag. Mm-hmm. So I mean the internet's too slow.
Too slow exactly. So that's what happens when you have a slow connection speed you have lag and
as you can say it refers to something that's slow or delayed so you can use it in other contexts
when you want to say something is a little bit slow. Mm-hmm. Well another key thing here as we're
talking about internet connections is the router so router is something that helps us to
route an internet connection so it for example. It's basically distributes the internet
connection to different computers or to different users. And some of these you plug in and some of
them are wireless that means without a wire. So a wireless router is something that a little box
in your house that allows you to maybe have three or four computers on one broadband connection.
So it's very popular now you go to Starbucks and you have Wi-Fi in order to have Wi-Fi or wireless
internet you need a router, a wireless router. Okay so wireless router and finally what is something
that might get in the way of a connection? You have a firewall. Very important security measure
when navigating the internet. All right so a personal firewall is a firewall that you have in your
computer to keep people from spying on you. This keeps other people out. Mm-hmm. So it's exactly
that it's a wall between your computer and the outside world. So it protects you from any type of
maybe malicious intruders. Right and oftentimes governments and public offices things like that
law offices they have firewalls to protect the information that they store because it's so important.
That it's secretive. Yeah so firewalls there are many different types of firewalls but a
personal firewall is just a basic one. Great so that is our language takeaway for today. Let's
check out this dialogue again and slow it down a bit this time.
Welcome to Galenet. How can I help you? Hi I would like to get an internet plan for my house. Of
course we have three different plans with different prices you can choose from. The first one is the
cheapest but most basic plan which is $30 a month. This is for broadband internet with a download
speed of 512 KBPS. I have no idea what KBPS means. I just want to be able to get online, play a
game and chat with my friends. Oh and watch movies online as well. Well this connection might be a
bit too slow for your needs. I suggest you get the premium package for $50 a month which includes
a connection speed of two megabytes. That way you can play games online without any lag. This
package also includes a wireless router and a personal firewall. Absolutely free. Do I have to pay
an installation fee? Lucky for you this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee. You
are saving yourself 100 bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive. Awesome.
All right great so we just heard all these awards that we looked at before but now why don't we take a
look at some of these phrases in fluency builder fluency builder what's this first one I can't read
I have no idea what did you write it down I have no idea what you're talking about. All right
enough game no I have no idea this is it's gonna treat this as a phrase that gets said as is we're not
gonna take bits and pieces of it so I have no idea or he has no idea is it a bit of say listen I
don't know I don't know I really don't know right the guy was talking about KBPS and all these things
and and the other guy was like I have no idea what you're talking about I don't understand and I can
definitely am I late yeah well we'll leave that for another one but after this it got a bucks all right
so bucks what is this slang bucks 100 bucks 200 bucks a lot of money right so bucks is basically
another way of saying dollars all right so this is a way for well this is the way that most Americans
talk about money it's a one buck is one US dollar all right so kind of brought 10 bucks Marco right
so yeah sure there you go now bucks you can only use it for American currency right you can't use it for
like a euros or no you can't say like 10 euros would be 10 bucks no no no no usually you say this about
American dollars and you say this just when you're hanging out or how much is this cost oh five bucks
yeah very good so the guy was telling him about the price of the internet and everything and he said
if he's gonna throw in a pendrive right he's gonna throw it away I don't know he's gonna throw in a
pendrive for free oh see so throw in means to to add or include include so listen sir here's your
large popcorn and I'm gonna throw in a small die at coke for free wow so you don't
so you throw in something it's you include it for free right exactly so this is usually a complementary
item great I think this word is really interesting or this phrase so why don't we listen to a couple
of other examples using throw in example one if you buy two pizzas we will throw in another one for free
example two tell you what I'll buy this computer if you throw in a pair of headphones deal
example three the salesman threw in a subscription to the local newspaper for buying his product
isn't that great all right great so good examples I think it's clear now the phrases all these words
related to the internet absolutely and so useful right so why don't we listen to this dialogue
for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more welcome to galinit how can I
help you hi I would like to get an internet plan for my house of course we have three different
plans with different prices you can choose from the first one is the cheapest but most basic plan
which is thirty dollars a month this is for broadband internet with a download speed of 512 kbps
I have no idea what kbps means I just want to be able to get online play games and chat with my
friends oh and watch movies online as well well this connection might be a bit too slow for your needs
I suggest you get the premium package for fifty dollars a month which includes a connection speed
of two megabytes that way you can play games online without any lag this package also includes
a wireless router and a personal firewall absolutely free do I have to pay an installation fee
lucky for you this month we aren't charging our normal installation fee you're saving yourself
a hundred bucks right there and we'll throw in this pen drive awesome
so the internet it's a big deal nowadays and now you can do so much on it not only navigate
websites anymore but watch movies download applications photos, Facebook all this type of things
now that you can do on the internet you can even do it from your phone like when you're in the bathroom
or on the train and you're scary you're there's we're always connected right so it's it's interesting
you're always connected you're always online with people and it's actually very noticeable when
you maybe live somewhere else before you used to have to write letters I don't think many people
will receive handwritten letters anymore never I'm speaking for myself I never received and I
don't write them either so yeah I guess I'm guilty of it so now people just send emails obviously
it's more convenient but maybe it's a little bit less significant maybe than actually going to
the post office or taking the time to write a letter going to the post office and stuff well
I don't know there's something nice about having a physical thing you can hold on to but I wonder if
one day we're gonna forget how to write yeah you know like write with a pen with a pen and pencil
exactly we're gonna have these little pda's and little iPhones and they're gonna just you're
gonna talk and they're gonna take everything down a note form for you well now it's kind of
happening with the Kindle right now you can have books on this electronic device that lets you read
through them and you can carry a hundred books with you so now you don't even really need
physical books and you're which is good on on some level because you know you're saving trees
and space and all that stuff but but there's something I don't know physical about reading a book
you hold it you flip the pages you know how many pages you have left I don't know we'll see
maybe I'll be a convert one day but for now I'm good with paper books all right so well what are
you guys think about the internet about electronic book you can also tell us any problems or
confusion you have with the things that we talked about today hopefully everything is clear but if not
we are here to answer your questions would like to do so so check out our website EnglishPod.com
all right we'll see you guys there and until next time goodbye everyone bye