Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine.
So, Marco, what are we talking about today?
Today we are taking a look at a guy who is a little bit too afraid of people in general.
There's a good word for this in English.
Someone who's almost too afraid all the time, someone who is overly cautious.
We call this person paranoid.
Okay, so if you are paranoid, you think that everyone wants to hurt you or that everyone is out to get.
Wait, did you hear that?
Did you hear that?
I didn't.
Some of the door.
Marco, can you check that?
Okay, that's paranoid.
You know, you're always hearing voices and noises and things.
So, a paranoid, somebody that is paranoid.
All right, so why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time and see what this person
is all paranoid about.
There it is again.
Good day in.
Damn.
Dude, you have to come over to my house right now.
Is everything okay?
Just get over here.
Come in.
Quickly.
So, since when is your house a bank?
What do you mean?
I mean, what's up with the four locks and iron bars on your windows?
Security, Dan!
Security!
You can never be too safe, you know.
A lot of sickos out there.
Just the other day, they cut that heaping term.
Red handed.
And a high power hell so thin.
The knife of us by his window.
What's the matter with you?
Why are you acting all paranoid?
I'm not paranoid!
I'm cautious!
You see, Dan?
We have to be unguarded all the time.
People just invade your privacy as if they knew you.
Tell a marketers, solicitors, even your bank.
They have way too much information.
I like to keep everything on a need to know basis.
Okay.
Well, what did you want to see me about?
You're being watched.
Be careful, Dan.
Be careful.
Alright, we're back.
So, yeah, I think this guy is a little bit too cautious.
I would have to agree with you.
And I would go so far as to call him paranoid.
But there's a lot of great stuff in this dialogue
that we can use in a lot of different situations.
So, let's take a look at some of these new words
in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, the first word on language takeaway today is Siko.
Siko is also the name of a movie that was a documentary
famous in America by Michael Moore actually.
But Siko, in this context, means someone who is a bit weird
in a bad way.
So, if you tell somebody you're sick,
but like in that tone, you're sick.
You're a sick person.
You're gross.
You're saying you're gross.
Or in a pro, people who have inappropriate humor,
who make jokes about not so nice things.
Right.
Yeah, they're sick.
But in this case, Siko's are people who maybe like to hurt other people,
or people who are a little bit crazy.
People who are not normal.
So, it's not a nice way of calling someone crazy.
If you say, oh, he's a Siko, it's not really nice.
Not at all.
It's a way of saying that you're almost scared of this person
because they're kind of weird and almost, they have problems.
Alright, so Siko, moving on to our next word,
we saw that the guy was afraid of telemarketers.
Exactly.
So, what are these guys?
Well, we've got two words being put together here.
Tella and market.
So, tella, like telephone.
Telephone.
Community overcommunications.
So, they're not in person.
They're people who call you up.
And market things.
They try to sell you stuff over the phone.
So, this is very common.
You get a phone calling yourself on.
And they ask you if you're happy with your long distance,
calling plan, or if you need new TV cable, or something like that.
And they always call during dinner, or late at night,
which drive me nuts.
Exactly.
So, these are telemarketers.
These are people who call you trying to sell things to you.
And very similar to these is a solicitors.
Exactly, but the big difference here with solicitors and telemarketers
is that solicitors actually go to your house.
They knock on your door.
So, they're also called a door to door salesmen or saleswoman.
That's right.
So, door to door salesmen, they go from door to door,
trying to sell things.
But in this case, a solicitor is someone who comes to your house
to try to get you to do something, to buy something.
All right, very good.
And moving on to our next word, we have a peeping tom.
That's right.
We heard this a little bit earlier in the dialogue.
And a peeping tom is, again, a negative thing to say about someone.
A peeping tom, well, the word peep means to look.
But kind of like, yeah, it's a quick look.
So, peeping tom is a person who spies on other people.
So, a synonym of a peeping tom would be a voyeur.
A voyeur.
So, someone who, without getting caught tries to look at other people while they're in their homes.
And so, it's really bad because it's usually inappropriate.
It's usually people who are watching women get on dress or...
Right.
So, a peeping tom is just an informal way of saying a voyeur or somebody who is spying on people.
So, those are the words for today in language.
Take away, let's listen to our dialogue again, and then we'll be right back.
Then, then, dude, you have to come over to my house right now.
Is everything okay?
Just get over here.
Come in.
Quickly.
So, since when is your house a bank?
What do you mean?
I mean, what's up with the four locks and iron bars on your windows?
Security, Dan.
Security.
You can never be too safe, you know.
A lot of sickos out there.
Just the other day, they caught that peeping tom red handed.
Had a high power telescope and binoculars by his window.
What's the matter with you?
Why are you acting all paranoid?
Parenthoyed?
I'm not paranoid! I'm cautious!
You see, Dan? We have to be on guard at all time.
People just invade your privacy as if they knew you.
Tell marketers, solicitors, even your bank.
They have way too much information.
I like to keep everything on a need to know basis.
Okay. Well, what did you want to see me about?
You're being watched.
Be careful, Dan. Be careful.
Now we're back.
We had some interesting phrases in the dialogue.
The first one being, you can never be too safe.
Fluency, buildup.
Alright, so this is a common mom phrase.
You often hear mothers say this when they're sending their kids off to school,
whatever.
They don't talk to strangers and the kid says,
Oh, why not?
You can never be too safe.
It's good to air on the side of caution.
So it's okay to be extra safe for extra cautious.
Just in case.
Exactly. You never know what's going to happen,
so it's better to be cautious than not.
And that's what this person is saying.
He's saying, well, security, it's important.
You can never be too safe.
You never know what might happen.
Is there another way that we can combine it?
Like, you can never be too careful.
Exactly.
Basically the same thing.
Same thing.
Alright. What's our next phrase?
Our next phrase is about this peeping tom,
this person that they caught.
They caught him red handed.
We caught you red handed.
Or he's been caught red handed.
So what does that mean?
It's a very colorful phrase.
And I don't just mean that because we're calling him red handed,
but to catch red handed means to catch someone
while they're doing something wrong.
So if I see you breaking into someone's house
and I say, Marco, stop.
I'm catching you.
Stop now.
I just caught you red handed.
You saw me doing the act.
Exactly.
Another way of saying this is you caught him with his hand
in the cookie jar.
Okay. This is another great phrase.
You can imagine a child who sees the cookies
in a very special jar on the counter in the kitchen.
And Mom says, don't eat the cookies.
Well, the child goes into the kitchen
and sees the cookies and opens the jar
and puts his hand in the jar.
And Mom comes and says,
you, that's the boy with his hand or a child with their hand
in the cookie jar.
So it's the same thing.
I can say, I caught you with your hand in the cookie jar.
Or you are caught red handed.
All right. And our last phrase for today is
you are on a need to know basis.
All right. This is a great one.
This is often said in spy movies.
Yeah.
So we say you're on a need to know basis.
That means that if you really need to know something,
then I will tell you.
Right.
But if not, I won't.
So you only have the information that is necessary.
No more or less, right?
You're on a need to know basis.
All right.
So I say, tell me Mark,
tell me what happened.
I want to know.
All right. And I can say, no, no.
You're on a need to know basis.
And you don't need to know this.
All right.
So a need to know basis.
As you say, very popular among spy movies
and government movies and stuff like that.
And steer, see movie.
Yeah.
All right. So let's listen to this dialogue
for the very last time and we'll be right back.
So then, then, dude, you have to come over to my house right now.
Is everything okay?
Just get over here.
Come in.
Quickly.
So, say,
come in.
Quickly.
So since when is your house a bank?
What do you mean?
I mean, what's up with the four locks and iron bars on your windows?
Security, Dan.
Security.
You can never be too safe, you know.
A lot of sickos out there.
Just the other day, they caught that heaping term.
We're at hand and a high power council
that binoculars by his window.
What's the matter with you?
Why are you acting all paranoid?
Parenthood?
I'm not paranoid! I'm cautious!
You see, Dan?
We have to be unguarded all the time.
People just invade your privacy
if they knew you.
Tell a marketers, solicitors, even your bank.
They have way too much information.
I like to keep everything on a need to know basis.
Okay.
Well, what did you want to see me about?
You're being watched.
Be careful, Dan. Be careful.
All right, so the guys a little bit paranoid.
There's another word for this as well.
Similar, right?
It's schizophrenia is a disease.
A lot of people have it and it's not too uncommon.
But a popular slang word to say someone's crazy is schizophrenia.
So if you guys remember this movie, a beautiful mind.
It's all about this famous mathematician named John Nash.
And while he was a genius, he came up with game theory and a lot of subsequent usage
of this for economy for many things.
But it was proven that he was schizophrenic, right?
Apparinites get a phrynek.
So not only did he kind of have experience reality in different ways,
but he's also paranoid.
So he was afraid that the government was trying to kill him.
And so he was he was irrationally afraid of everything going on around him.
And it made him very unsafe because he could hurt himself or other people.
And the interesting thing about this is that there is no actual cure for it.
You just learn to cope and live with it.
So you never really get cured.
You just kind of live with it.
Learn how to understand what's real and what's not.
So it's interesting.
It's a great movie also, by the way, if you ever, if you've never seen it or you get a chance to watch
it and that's all the time we have for today.
So if you have any questions, doubts or comments,
please come to our website EnglishPOP.com and we're there to answer them.
Yeah, we hope to see you there and until next time EnglishPOP.
Alright, bye bye.