Hello everyone and welcome back to the EnglishPod. We have an upper intermediate lesson
for you today. My name is Marco. And my name is Katherine. So today we're talking about something
that everyone who's ever lived away from home has felt before. Right. And that's the where
we're going to preview today. The word is homesick. Alright. So let's take a look at that in today's
language preview. Very cabbiery preview. Alright. So homesick. If you feel homesick, or you are homesick.
Well, yet you, you could say, I'm homesick right now. Or are you feeling homesick? So it's a word
that means I miss my home. I miss my family. I'm far away or I haven't seen my family
a long time. And for some reason you just feel sad. Okay. So it's a feeling. You feel a little
bit depressed. You feel sad because your homesick. Right. Okay. So this is what's happening today in
our dialogue. So let's listen to it for the first time.
Tom, how are you? Hey, we missed you at the party last night. Are you okay?
I don't know. I didn't really feel like going out. I guess I'm feeling a little homesick.
Come on. We've been through this already. Look, I know the adjustment was hard when you first got here.
But we agree that you're going to try and deal with it. I was. It's just that the holidays
are coming up and I won't be able to go home because I can't afford the airfare. I'm just
longing for some of the comforts of home, like my mom's cooking and being around my family.
Yeah, I can get pretty lonely over the holidays. When I first got here, I'd get depressed and nostalgic
for anything that reminded me of home. I almost let it get to me, but then I started going out,
keeping myself busy and before I knew it, I was used to it. I see what you mean, but I'm still
bummed out. Okay, how does this sound? Let's get you suited up and hit the dance club tonight.
I hear that an awesome DJ is playing and there will be a lot of pretty single girls there.
You know, I could really go for that. You know, mind being my wingman for tonight? Not at all.
It'll be fun. It will be like a boy's night out. Well, kind of. Great. I must warn you, though,
whatever happens, don't let me go on a drinking binge. Trust me. It's not a pretty picture.
Alrighty, we're back. So, yeah, I guess he's very homesick. Very homesick. And his friend is really
worried. Yeah, but actually, I think this is common, right? To be homesick during the holidays.
Like Christmas, for example. Oh, man. It's the worst during the holidays because you think of all
the traditions and all the things that you normally do at home and you're not doing them.
So, this is something we're going to talk more about a little bit later on, but let's take a look at
some of the language that was used in language takeaway. Language takeaway. This first one is key,
right? So, when you move away from home or when you move to a new place, you have a period of
adjustment. So, adjustment is kind of finding the right balance or doing something so that you can
kind of feel comfortable. Okay. So, you have to adjust to your new life, life away from home.
Or you know, environment. So, many times people say, wow, moving to China must be a big adjustment.
So, means there's so many differences that it must take a long time to feel comfortable again.
Okay. All right. So, that's adjustment. What else do we have?
Well, we've got this next phrase that's, uh, this is really important I think, but often gets overlooked.
We say the comforts of home, right? comforts of home. So, comforts are pretty easy, right?
Feeling comfortable. So, you have comfort, but the comforts are of home are things that are
different with every person, but are those are things that you have at your home or your childhood home
or your parents home that make you feel good and feel happy. So, they're not only physical things or
objects, right? They can be like your mom's cooking or maybe even just spending time with your family.
Right. Or reading the newspaper with your dad or things that you're used to that you don't have
anymore. And so, those are the comforts of home. I could say, Mark, go, do you miss the comforts
of home in Ecuador? I mean, do you have anything that's really? Of course. Of course. I think
one of the main things is actually not living in the city because I used to live in the valley a
little bit further away and kind of almost countryside. So, that's one of the comforts of home that I miss.
And making me nostalgic and I never even been. All right, well, this is our next word actually.
Right. Miss nostalgic. Miss nostalgic. It's a feeling I'm feeling nostalgic or he's just really
nostalgic. And so, to be nostalgic is to kind of think about a time before, you know, think
positively about something that you experienced before. So, it's not usually a bad thing. It's never
bad thing. It's right. The nostalgia is a good, warm, fond memory of something. Of something from
your past. So, you start thinking of something from your past that maybe brings nice warm feelings.
Maybe a little bit said because you missed those times, but it's usually thinking about the past.
All right. So, I've nostalgic for my childhood. I loved, you know, summers in Chicago when
it was hot and the kids would play in the sprinkler and I had my dog and, you know, it uses it's a
happy feeling. Right. So, nostalgia would be the noun and nostalgia would be the adjective.
Exactly. All right. And our last word for today on language takeaway is
bumped out. Bummed out. I'm bummed out. I've got another feeling here. So, we're all full of feelings today.
Bummed out is a sad feeling. So, to be bummed is kind of slang and it means to be sad.
Okay. Or disappoint. It's a point. So, you, you come into the office marker and you look a little
tired and say, are you okay? Are you bummed out about something? I can say, yeah, I lost my wallet last
night so I'm really bummed out. Oh, or something like that. So, yeah, you feel bummed out when
something bad or sad happens to. Right. All right. So, why don't we move on now to a couple of different
phrases on fluency builder? Fluency builder. All right. This first one is something that you
often say to old friends or family. You know, when your friends or someone, they go through periods
of happiness and sadness. And so, when someone's going through a down period again, you say,
we've been through this already. We've been through this already. Or, you know, when you're
giving someone advice and they never take your advice, you say, listen, we've been through this already.
You should know by now that I and then, you know, whatever the advice. So, this has happened before
or we have experienced this before. Or we already solved this problem or situation. Right. You can
imagine two bank robbers who are growing over their plan for the tenth time and then the one says to the
other, hey, we've been through this already. You should know the plan by now. Exactly. All right.
So, we've been through this already. They were talking about the adjustments and everything. And then
what other phrase did they use? Well, the next couple of phrases have to do with the friends
suggestions because she has a lot of ideas to to cheer her friend up the depressed one. And the
first thing she says is, hey, let's hit the dance club. Okay. Let's hit the dance club or let's hit
the dance floor tonight. All right. So, hit in this case doesn't mean like hit. Doesn't mean you're
punching someone. It means to go to or to do. All right. So, we can say, let's go to the dance club tonight.
Let's hit the dance club. Exactly. And doesn't have to be a dance club. But let's hit that concert tonight.
Yeah. We're going to go there. Okay. So, you can hit pretty much any place, right? Exactly.
And that this is a very kind of spoken language. So, you wouldn't say this in your essays, but it's a
good way to to talk about plans with friends. All right. And our next word actually is kind of
interesting because it's very colloquial and it's a wingman. I can be your wingman tonight. So,
wingman, you have to think about wingmaning side, not like a bird's wing. So, a wingman side
and a wingman is a guy who will go with you to a bar or a club to kind of help you find a date
or a girl or someone to talk to. Okay. So, this person, this wingman, usually keeps you company
and helps you decide maybe what girl to talk to or maybe even introduces you to someone. Right.
Add a club or add a restaurant or bar or whatever. And, you know, the key is that people don't
like to go along to bars, right? Because you feel sad and then you're, you look weird because you're
all along. And the same is true for girls. And so, if a guy wants to go a bar and he sees two girls,
well, he has to have a friend to talk to the other girl. Right. So, wingman also helps
and that sense he helps balance things. All right. So, there's a whole science behind the wingman.
I'm sure if you look it up on Wikipedia, you'll find ten pages of information. All right. So,
since they are going out tonight, they said it could be boys' night out. Okay. So, this is another
phrase. You hear all the time, especially among young people. Boys' night out and girls' night out.
And so, you know, sometimes you spend a lot of time with your husband or your wife or your boy
for a new girlfriend and you just want to have some time with your friends. Right. And so, you call
this girl's night for me, girls' night out, you just go out, you do girl things.
Guys, they're not you do other things. Okay. And so, in this case,
girls only, or guys only, boys' night out is only guys. Exactly. And that's why this is funny,
because it's the girl who says, hey, let's have boys' night out and she's not really a boy.
All right, great. And, well, he agreed to go out and everything, but he warned her about
him going on a drinking binge. Okay. And this is important. A lot of people who were,
were depressed or sad when they drink, they drink a lot. And so, binge means to do something
in excess, to do it too much. Okay. So, a drinking binge would be drinking alcohol in excess, too much.
Too much. So, getting drunk right away. And it's not healthy. And we did not end on it. Right.
Exactly. Very good. So, some very interesting phrases in this dialogue today. I think we should
listen to it one more time and we'll be right back.
Tom, how are you? Hey, we missed you at the party last night. Are you okay?
I don't know. I didn't really feel like going out. I guess I'm feeling a little homesick.
Come on. We've been through this already. Look, I know the adjustment was hard when you first got here,
but we agreed that you were going to try and deal with it. I was. It's just that the holidays are
coming up and I won't be able to go home because I can't afford the airfare. I'm just
longing for some of the comforts of home, like my mom's cooking and being around my family.
Yeah, I can get pretty lonely over the holidays. When I first got here, I'd get depressed and nostalgic
for anything that reminded me of home. I almost let it get to me, but then I started going out,
keeping myself busy and before I knew it, I was used to it. I see what you mean, but I'm still
bummed out. Okay. How does this sound? Let's get you suited up and hit the dance club tonight.
I hear that an awesome DJ is playing and there will be a lot of pretty single girls there.
You know, I could really go for that. You know, mind being my wingman for tonight? Not at all.
It'll be fun. It will be like a boy's night out. Well, kind of. Great. I must warn you, though,
whatever happens, don't let me go on a drinking binge. Trust me, it's not a pretty picture.
All right. We're back. So, speaking of home sick and holidays, do you actually get very depressed
or homesick during Christmas? I do. Well, my family has a lot of Christmas traditions that are just
really kind of wonderful. We do them every single year. And so the first time I spent Christmas away,
I was living in Italy and it was kind of similar, but then the second time was when I was living in
China and China was just not the same, no oven, so no Christmas cookies. And no granny who, you know,
pours vodka and eats meatballs and like my mom not running around the kitchen. You just, you feel
lonely and then all of a sudden you get a phone call. And it's the entire family and they're all together
eating, having an amazing Christmas and they think it's going to help you feel less homesick,
but it makes you feel more homesick. So you definitely have have nostalgia for those days during the holidays.
What about you? I rarely get homesick, but yeah, sometimes during Christmas or new years,
new years we usually have more unique traditions in Ecuador. So it's very fun. The family gets together.
We dance, we eat, but yeah, I've been away from home so long that I rarely get homesick anymore,
but it's great to go back and spend time with the family. So after my visit to Ecuador, then I might
get homesick for a little while, but then it goes away. Well, you guys should tell us, do you
ever feel homesick? And if you do, what do you feel homesick about? What do you miss?
Maybe moms cooking, maybe family, maybe the comforts of home. Mm-hmm. Yes, we're curious to hear
your answers. We have website EnglishPod.com. You can of course also leave us questions.
We're happy to answer those and until next time everyone. Bye bye.