Hello everyone and welcome back to English Pod My Name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about something we talk about every year.
Every year after Christmas or while during the Christmas holidays we talk about new years,
new years day and a very important topic, new years resolutions.
All right so we're not going to preview anything today. It's all in the dialogue but when we come back
we'll be talking more about what you hear and something great phrases you can use at the new year.
Did you read this? It says that the number one new year resolution people make is to spend more
time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it. We are society that
is always on the go. Not because we have to but because we want to. Why? We work hard and spend
less time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with goods and services that are usually
unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should start thinking of a new year's resolution
yourself. But it's the point we always make new year's resolutions and by February we will have
forgotten about them. It's pointless. Well maybe then you should resolve to sticking to your
goals and objectives. What about you? Your gym bag is gathering dust and you still have brand new
running shoes that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to
gym with me every day. Yeah yeah whatever. All right great work back so this is very typical
a new year's resolution that you make but then people don't really stick to it etc. It don't.
Usually they don't. All right but you're probably wondering what is a new year's resolution so why don't
we take a look at this word and many more on language takeaway? Language takeaway. Okay so
new year's resolution let's break this phrase down the first phrase is new year so the new year
is January 1st in the West and it is celebrated on the 31st of December of the at night when the
clock changes to the new year and a new year's resolution remember that S there is something that
you want to do or to change in the new year. It's a fresh start. Okay so you pretty much
the verb that you use there is to resolve to do something so my new year's resolution is to
go to the gym every day. It's like a promise to yourself. Right so and this is very common
right among Americans they try and because it's a new year it's a fresh start so they want to
start doing something great. Exactly we can talk about this at the end but a lot of companies
try to use this to sell Americans stupid things so we'll get there in a minute but the two people in
this dialogue we're talking about the idea of spending more time with friends and family and the other
person said well sometimes it's hard to do that because you have to provide your family with goods and
services. All right. This phrase goods and services is very common especially in economics and
sociology so what does this mean? And they go together right so goods are tangible items things that
you buy you know like food or you know clothes clothes a TV etc stuff stuff and services of course
are other things like for example going to the doctor or the dentist or any other service you get.
So service usually includes another person doing something for you but you might not actually
get something physical like a TV right so goods and services it's included in this phrase always
goods and services. Very good and well moving on as we mentioned with the new year's resolution
we had that verb there to resolve so what does it mean if I want to resolve?
Okay well to resolve as we said is to decide or to promise yourself to do something so it's a
decision that you don't want to change your mind about for example I this year I've resolved to quit smoking
that means I've made a decision for myself and I'm going to do it. Okay very good. Very strong and not
to be confused with like to solve right it has no no real relation there right? No resolve to
to do something is to have a strong passion or interest in doing something for yourself or changing
an action. Very good and well our last word for language takeaway is brand new a brand new
something that's brand new. Brand new so by a brand new car come down to Captain's car lot.
So brand new is something we hear a lot of marketing it's also something that well these words
just go together very often and something is new okay you just bought it or it just came out
but something brand new is really fresh really new so brand new a brand new car a brand new watch etc
a brand new movie a brand new movie or brand yeah brand new cereal had you have for try it?
Very good so a great phrases there very good so great words there why don't we listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back with three phrases.
Did you read this? It says that the number one new year resolution people make is to spend
more time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it we're society
that is always on the go not because we have to but because we want to why we work hard and spend
less time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with goods and services that are
usually unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should start thinking even new years
resolution yourself. What's the point? We always make new year's resolutions and by February
we will have forgotten about them it's pointless. Well maybe then you should resolve to stick into
your goals and objectives. What about you? Your Jim bag is gathering dust and you still have brand
new running shoes that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise of going to the
Jim with me every day. Yeah yeah whatever.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at these three phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay this first phrase is very common at gas stations and food like fast food chains
and we can say on the go. Alright so he mentioned that we are a society that is always
on the go and means we're always moving. Exactly so you're always going to work going home from
we're going to the store going to the school to get the kids always moving moving moving so that
that kind of action that kind of life is on the go. You can also say eat on the go. That means
I eat while I'm going somewhere while I'm doing something I don't sit down. Okay so on the go
and we're talking about New Year's resolution and we say that well many people resolve to do
something but they don't really do it and we have a phrase that is used here to stick to something,
stick to your resolution. To stick to it so you think of tape or glue these things that help
things stick together. Okay so in that sense it's kind of it's a way for you to describe
continuing to do something or not stopping not quitting not ending it. And so I could say
remember how I said I wanted to quit smoking. Well I'm really going to stick to this resolution
because I think it's important. That means I'm not going to give up. Right very good so you're going
to stay with it. You're not going to give up. Alright so stick to something like for example our
English learners they'll stick to learning English. And we could say as a word of as words of encouragement
he stick to it. Stick to it don't give up. Don't give up. Alright and well finally they were discussing
more arguing about the gym membership and everything and he mentioned that the gym bag is gathering
dust. Alright this is a very nice phrase I think because it's very visual. I like I like phrases
where you can see what's happening. So gathering means collecting that means that the dust in the air
it's building on this bag and something is gathering dust if we don't use it. So we haven't gone
to the gym because our bag is in the corner and it's just filled with dust. Exactly we could also
say this about the computer. Why should I buy you a new computer Marco if you never use the old one?
That's just sitting in the house gathering dust. Very good okay so it's another way of saying
you never use it you never do it. etc. It's for an object though you can't say you are gathering
no it will be a little weird you might be that. Alright great phrases so why don't we listen to this
dialogue one last time.
Ha ha ha did you read this? It says that the number one new year resolution people make is
to spend more time with friends and family. Why would that be funny? Well think about it.
We're a society that is always on the go. Not because we have to but because we want to. Why?
We work hard and spend less time at home because we're trying to provide for our family with
goods and services that are usually unnecessary. I don't agree but anyways I think you should
start thinking the new year's resolution yourself. What's the point? We always make new year's
resolutions and by February we will have forgotten about them. It's pointless. Well maybe then you should
resolve to sticking to your goals and objectives. What about you? Your gym bag is gathering dust and
you still have brand new running shoes that are yet to be jogging. Well I would go if you kept your promise
of going to gym with me every day. Yeah yeah whatever.
Alright we're back and well as you mentioned there are some interesting things about this
dialogue especially when they talked about a society that's always on the go and you mentioned that
well sometimes you eat on the go and I've seen people in the United States that are actually eating
while driving. I'm guilty of doing that. Yeah you have no time to actually sit down for like 15 minutes
and eat. Now I remember being in high school at home and you know you just have so much stuff to do.
You have school then after school there's like you know soccer practice after that there's
music lessons and you never have time to eat so you have to grab food in the car and then on the
way home you're picking things up and you get home and you get home and you get your homework or whatever
there's so much stuff to do and it doesn't stop. It doesn't stop when you grow up. It doesn't stop
as if you're an older person it's just the way life is in America. Wow yeah that's that's
really interesting because I think many of our listeners that are in other countries would find that
a little bit peculiar if they actually went to the United States and saw somebody in their car
you know like having a hamburger while driving you know and sipping on their soda. Yeah it's kind of sad.
Well that's the thing you don't have much time but actually this is based on
true events kind of on the fact that many Americans do want to spend more time at home with their
friends with their family because as you say you're always so busy. And I think it's the nice
resolution to to resolve to have dinner with your family once or twice a week at home where you
sit down and you talk about your lives it's nice because you get to share and you get to know each other
better and you know otherwise you're always just on the go in different places. Yeah exactly.
So we want to hear your comments in your opinions about this topic so why don't you visit our website
EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there. Don't forget to share with us your new
years resolutions everyone's got one so I'm very excited to hear those. All right until next time everyone. Bye.