Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an upper intermediate level lesson for all of you.
That's right. We're going to be talking business on this occasion on EnglishPod but specifically
about planning a business. Right. So before a business opens a lot of planning has to happen.
That means people will decide what kind of a product they want to sell, what kind of a market
they want to sell to etc. So that is the focus of today's lesson. Let's take a listen to the
dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a minute to talk about what's going on.
I've had it. I'm done working for a company that has taken me nowhere.
So what are you going to do? Just quit? That's exactly what I'm going to do.
I've decided to create my own company. I'm going to write up a business plan, get some investors and
start working for myself. Have you ever written up a business plan before? Well, no. It can't be that
hard. I mean, all you have to do is explain your business. How are you going to do things and that's it,
right? You can be more wrong. A well-written business panel will include an executive summary
which highlights the idea of the business in two pages or less. Then you need to describe
your company with information such as what type of legal structure it has, history, etc.
Well, that seems easy enough. Wait, there's more. Then you need to introduce and describe
your goods or services. What they are and how they're different from competitors. Then comes the hard
part, a market analysis. You need to investigate and analyse hundreds of variables. You need to take
into consideration social economic factors from GDP per capita to how many children on average the
population has. All this information is useful so that you can move on to your strategy and
implementation stage where you will describe in detail how you will actually execute your idea.
Jeez. Is that all? Almost. The most important piece of information for your investors will be
the financial analysis. Here you will calculate an estimate sales, cash flow and profits. After all,
people will want to know when they will begin to see a return on their investment. I think I'll just
stick to my old job and save myself all the hassle of trying to start up a business.
All right, we're back. So the guy wanted to open up a business but his friend explained that it's
not so easy and gave a lot of interesting words and phrases there. He did. He seemed a little naive.
Like he didn't really know how much work is involved in opening a business. Exactly. So I think we should
take a look at some of the words used on language take away. Language take away.
The first word is the heart and soul of the process before you open a business. It's the business plan.
All right, so the business plan, as you said, it's a noun and it's basically a document that explains
what's going on in the business. Exactly. It's a paper that you write about the business that you
want to open and it's a plan. So the name says you have to tell what you will do, how much money you
will spend, how much money you will need. Because if you're asking people for money, they want to
know where the money will be spent if it's going to be spent on wise decisions. Exactly. And as you
mentioned, so you show this business plan maybe to a bank but also maybe to an investor. That's right.
So, investors are next word. It's another noun but this noun is a person. A person is an investor.
If he or she gives money to someone else and expects more money to come back. Right. So a person
that's starting out a business maybe has enough money himself to open up a business but sometimes
you need extra money. So you look for investors. People who are interested in giving you money.
For example, I have a cupcake company. I want to sell cupcakes to people and I need a thousand
dollars. So Marko, do you want to be an investor? Do you want to invest someone? Yes. For sure.
A cupcake company. That sounds great. I know but what happens if I don't sell cupcakes? That's a problem
for you because you have made a risky investment. That's right. So that's what happens with investors.
But now if you want to attract the attention of your investors with your business plan,
I think part of the most important aspect of this plan is the executive summary.
A summary is usually an outline of the important points of a paper or document. So in this case,
I could say, Katherine's cupcake company will sell delicious cupcakes of 10 different flavors to
the market of five-year-olds. People will love them. She has a great secret recipe and she plans
to triple her investments by next year. Right. That's exactly it. So if an investor reads the executive
summary, which shouldn't be more than two pages long, you can pretty much get the idea of what the
business is about. So if you want more details, you have to read the rest of the business plan,
but mainly with the executive summary, you can more or less know what it's all about. Exactly. So
a summary, like I said, is something that should be short and it should give you all of the
most important information about something. Exactly. And well, they were talking more in depth about
analyzing things and doing some research. And among those things, the girl mentioned that
it's the social economic factors. Okay, when I said we're going to sell cupcakes for my company,
two people between the ages of five and 55, we need to analyze, we need to look at those
their socioeconomic factors. Sociocups from the word social means we're in society. They are
their upper class middle class or lower class economic means how much money do they make? Do they make
$10,000 a year or $100,000 a year? And so the the kind of people we want to sell my cupcakes to
will be will change according to their socioeconomic factors. That's right. So as you mentioned
socio comes from the word social or from society. So you're analyzing these factors from society.
And well, part of these factors is the GDP per capita. So we have two different words there,
an acronym GDP GDP gross domestic products. Okay. That might seem confusing because gross means
different things at different times. But in this case, domestic means our country. So within a country,
all of the products added up together. Right. And gross is basically that just all the products
added up together without taking into consideration any other things. So the GDP is basically
all the goods and services produced in the country within a given time. And what about per capita though?
So per capita comes from Latin per means for or each and capita is ahead. So this is per person.
So GDP per capita means how much how many goods and services are made divided by the number of
people in that place. Exactly. So you probably have these indicators in your country or your
own language as well. But that's basically it and the acronym is gross domestic product.
And just to explain a little bit, if you see this in Wikipedia or in an encyclopedia,
normally a very low GDP per capita is $500 American dollars. And a high one would be 35,000. 35, yeah.
And that's usually per year, right? Because you, um, that's usually how it's taken into consideration.
The time is a year. All right. So those are the words that we have for you on language takeaway.
Now why don't we move on to a couple of different phrases on fluency builder? Fluency builder.
Okay. So this is important. First phrase, Marco has to do with our last first phrase. We have a
business plan. So what do you do? You write up a business plan. Right. And that's a common way of
saying to write or to create, to work on a business plan, to write up. Right. So it's something that we
say that's very colloquial. It's something that is very spoken. And I can't explain why we say it.
But you'll sound very fluid if you say to, I'm going to write up a business plan. Or why don't
you write up a business plan? Right. So it would be correct to say, I'm going to write a business
plan. Or I have to write a business plan. But if you use this phrase, I'm going to write up a business
plan. It's just it's more fluent. Right. It's just more native like exactly. All right. And our next
phrase is a return on investment. Okay. So early we talked about investors. The money that they
invest is called an investment. Okay. These words are all very closely related. And when Marco
decided to give money to my cupcake business, he expects the money to come back and he expects
more actually to come back than what he put in. So that's called a return on investment. The money
that's the difference. So if he gives me a thousand dollars and I give him back $1,500 in a year,
he made $500. That's amazing. That means it's a good return on his investment. Right. So that's
the term that we use a return on investment. So you don't say to return on investment. You see
a return on investment. Exactly. It's a thing. It's a number. It's a quantity. It's something
you can count. Right. And well, in the end, after seeing that this business plan is not so easy,
the guy said, you know what? I'm not going to quit my job and just save myself the hassle. What's
a hassle? The hassle. That's an interesting word. So if I'm going to save myself the hassle,
the hassle is like the problem or the hard work that it involves. It's a lot of trouble. A lot of
trouble. So I was going to cook some dinner tonight, but I'm going to save myself the hassle of going
to the grocery store and buying it and cooking it by just ordering food. Right. So that's a good
example. Instead of doing all the work of cooking, you just save yourself the hassle, pick up the phone
and get food delivered to your house. Right. And the word we change here, you can say save myself,
save yourself, save his self. So you change that pronoun. The pronoun. Exactly. So you can save
yourself the hassle or I'm just going to save myself the hassle. Okay. So that's about it for fluency
builder. Let's listen to today's dialogue one more time and we'll be back in a minute to talk
about business.
I've had it. I'm done working for a company that has taken me nowhere. So what are you going to do?
Just quit? That's exactly what I'm going to do. I've decided to create my own company.
I'm going to write up a business plan, get some investors and start working for myself.
Have you ever written up a business plan before? Well, no. It can't be that hard. I mean,
all you have to do is explain your business. How are you going to do things and that's it, right?
You can be more wrong. A well written business plan will include an executive summary
which highlights the idea of the business in two pages or less. Then you need to describe
your company with information such as what type of legal structure it has history, etc.
Well, that seems easy enough. Wait, there's more. Then you need to introduce and describe your
goods or services. What they are and how they're different from competitors. Then comes the hard part.
A market analysis. You need to investigate and analyse hundreds of variables. You need to take
into consideration socio economic factors from GDP per capita to how many children on average
the population has. All this information is useful so that you can move on to your strategy
and implementation stage where you will describe and detail how you will actually execute your idea.
Jeez, is that all? Almost. The most important piece of information for your investors will be
the financial analysis. Here you will calculate an estimate sales, cash flow and profits.
After all, people will want to know when they will begin to see a return on their investment.
I think I'll just stick to my old job and save myself all the hassle of trying to start up a business.
So, it was pretty interesting that he wanted to quit his job and set up a business. But
actually, many people say that business plans are unnecessary. Really? Do these people have lots of
money and they don't need investors or? I think the problem is that there are many books out there
that give you clear examples of companies, Fortune 500 companies that started out without a business plan.
So, I think many people take this as a rule. A rule? They didn't need one or it's not really
necessary. Why should I write up a business plan? Well, I'm not an entrepreneur and I'm not a business
person, but my feeling is that a business plan is as much for investors as it is for yourself.
It helps you clarify your goals. It helps you explain your objectives to your future colleagues.
And I think it's just a really good way to map out the first year of a business because it attempts
to want a business as fail in that first year. So, I think this is a really important step.
Yeah, exactly. So, it's very interesting. We've talked a little bit about business here, but we would
like to know your ideas or your comments or any other suggestions that you have about this topic or
any topic on EnglishPod. So, why don't you send us a comment or a personal message? We are at
EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there. Bye, everyone. Bye.