Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very weather focus lesson. It's all about all the
horrible things that can happen to you with the weather.
Exactly. So as you know there are many different types of weather and not only rain or sunshine
but many other phenomena. So we're going to take a look at some of those but before we go into it
let's take a look at one word on vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. Okay so we're talking about extreme weather today. That's not rain or drizzle
or sunshine. We're talking about really interesting unique and sometimes devastating things that can
happen. So today's vocabulary word is Armageddon. All right so Armageddon. Now you're probably
seeing the movie Armageddon. So what does this word mean?
Okay so this word is a reference to the end of the world. It means the time when the
world will end because of a great catastrophe or a great disaster. Okay so everyone talks about
Armageddon. It's mentioned in the Bible and as you say it's when the world stops existing.
Exactly so think about that one as we listen to today's dialogue we will be back in a minute to
talk about what's going on.
Those are the headlines for today and now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you Bob. This past week has been the beginning of Armageddon for many.
As a series of unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world, in Switzerland,
a major avalanche was reported in the Alps. Fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme
coldest winter, a Blizzard has struck the US Midwest causing classes in schools and universities
to be temporarily cancelled. Moving on to Latin America, Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that
has not only affected farming but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant
that provides electricity for the entire country. In Chile, a major earthquake that registered
7.5 on the Richter scale struck the southern region, losses are reported to be in the billions.
Authorities have not yet released an official statement. Not a great week for the world.
Any good news? I'm afraid not Bob. One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted,
causing major floods and landslides in the region. Meanwhile Mexico's coast has been hit by
Hurricane Liliana and officials say that all the seismic activity leads them to believe that
he's tsunami made hit Central America, affecting Honduras, Guatemala, and Panama.
That's all the news we have for today but stay tuned for updates on the six o'clock news.
Back to you, Bob.
All right, we're back and well this weather report is not really far from the truth. I mean,
stuff happens every day all over the world. That's correct. And unfortunately, it's been happening
very frequently in the past couple months. We've heard of a lot of earthquakes, volcanoes,
things like that. So this is very valuable stuff when you're trying to talk about current
events as well. Okay, so why don't we start now and losing a couple of different words and phrases on
language takeaway? Language takeaway. Well, the first vocabulary item we have here is
meteorological event. It's a real mouthful to belong where meteorological. So for example,
meteorological means having to do with the weather, something that's related to the weather. So
a meteorological event could be rain snow. Okay, so it has to do with meteorology.
Meteorology is the study of the weather and someone who does this is a meteorologist.
So usually the weathermen that you see on TV, they're meteorologists.
So let's go now to Marco are resident meteorologists. Right. Okay, so meteorological events.
Now moving on, one of the first events that we're going to look at is an avalanche.
avalanche and avalanche has to do with snow. This means that when
mountain that has a lot of snow on it, maybe part of that so breaks off and starts to roll down,
you have a wall of snow that comes down. That's an avalanche. That's an avalanche.
So you could say, ah, the little one. When the snow comes down and it's actually very dangerous,
because people can get buried under the snow. Yeah, exactly. All right. So another event that
has to do with snow is a blizzard. Okay, a blizzard is different from an avalanche because an avalanche
maybe it's not snowing. The snow just falls. But in a blizzard, you're talking about a storm of snow.
But it's like a lot of snow coming down from this guy. So much snow that you probably can't see anything.
There's just white everywhere. Okay. All right. So that's a blizzard. A lot of
snow coming down from this guy. Now moving on at the opposite of snow and things being wet is
we have a drought. Yeah, this is the opposite of wet actually. So there's no rain in a drought.
A drought means the things are very dry. The land is very dry. Okay. So it's a period of time that
there's no snow. There's no water. There's no rain. There's nothing. It's very, very dry. We're going
through a drought. Correct. And the problem with a drought is very dangerous is because people cannot
grow food in a drought. And so lots of people starve when this happens. Okay. So we've got to
watch out for a drought. Now in this case, it not only affected farming, but also we have a hydro
electric power plant that can't work, obviously, because there's no water. So hydro means water.
Hydroelectric means electricity that is generated by flowing water. And so, for example, a mill,
something that turns water on our river is a way to get power from water. But a hydro electric
project that can give you electricity is maybe like a dam or an electric mill. Right. So usually
you have these and rivers and they just take advantage of the flowing of water to turn some huge
turbines and generate power. So that's all we have for now. Why don't we listen to the dialogue
again? And we'll be back shortly to take a look at some more words.
Those are the headlines for today and now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you, Bob. This past week has been the beginning of our Megan for many. As a series of
unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world, in Switzerland, a major avalanche
was reported in the Alps, fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme cold this winter,
a blizzard has struck the US Midwest, causing classes in schools and universities to be temporarily
cancelled. Moving on to Latin America, Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that has not
only affected farming but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant that provides
electricity for the entire country. In Chile, a major earthquake that registered 7.5 on the Richter
scale struck the southern region, losses are reported to be in the billions. Authorities have not
yet released an official statement. Not a great week for the world. Any good news?
I'm afraid not, Bob. One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted, causing major floods
and landslides in the region. Meanwhile, Mexico's coast has been hit by Hurricane Nileana,
and officials say that all the seismic activity leads them to believe that he's tsunami made
hit Central America, affecting Honduras, Guatemala, and Panama. That's all the news we have for today,
but stay tuned for updates on the six o'clock news. Back to you, Bob.
Well, a word that many people are unfortunately familiar with is Richter or Richter scale.
And now this is something that a lot of people are talking about right now because of the earthquake
in Sichuan, China last year, and the earthquake in Haiti, very recently. And so the Richter scale,
that's a big arm because it's a proper name, is a way for us to determine how severe, how big
the earthquake was. Right, so people talk about a 6.0, a 7.1, so that's on the Richter scale.
The lowest is zero and the highest is 10 correct. Right, the 10 is like impossible apparently.
Apparently, and a lot of them are actually underwater, but the very serious ones are maybe 8.0,
all right, so Richter scale. Now we talked about earthquakes, we talked about snowing.
Now let's talk about a volcano. A volcano in Mexico has erupted.
Okay, so we've got two words here, Volcano. Volcano is a mountain that has an opening in the
center where lava from the middle of the earth, the center of the earth can come out. So it's very
dangerous, obviously, because it's very hot. Right. But a volcano doesn't open. It erupts. So the
verb here that we use without Volcano is too erupt. Okay, so it doesn't explode. It will
can't erupts. That means to open violently very quickly. Okay, so when this happens,
obviously you have a lot of lava, you have maybe snow that melts and you have floods and landslides.
Okay, land slides. A landslide is one word, but it's made up of two words that you probably
already know. So land obviously it's the ground that thinks like that the earth. But a slide is to
move down across the ground. And so a landslide happens when you've got something
like lava or water that's pushing all of the earth, all of the ground down. And it's destroying
houses and trees and land and it's very, very destructive. Right. So usually see this that happens
on the side of mountains or on the side of hills where all that land starts to slide down or to
go down. And it's very similar to an avalanche, right? But instead of snow falling down, it's a mud and land.
Yeah. All right. So we have a landslide and because of all the eruptions and the earth quakes,
they said that they have a lot of seismic activity. This word seismic is something that I've heard
a lot recently in movies like 2012. So seismic means having to do with the movement of the
plates under the earth's crust. So you know, the earth is not everything that we see. It's also
activity. Things happening underneath the ground. And so underneath the ground we have these big plates
and seismic activity is what happens when these kind of things start to move. Activity is movement.
And so seismic activity refers to earthquakes and volcanoes, things that are changing under the ground
that will affect us. Okay. So that seismic activity is pronounced seismic, right?
seismic. So seismic. Okay. And because of all this activity, people say that they may have a tsunami.
Well, this doesn't sound very English. Doesn't. I know. tsunami. And actually, if you see the
spelling, it's with a TTS. Right. I think it's a Japanese word, but I'm not positive. I think so too.
tsunami is the name that we give to a giant tidal wave. So that's a wave of water in the ocean.
That's very, very dangerous because it can get to a hundred two hundred feet tall.
And this means that when it comes down, it can destroy houses, cities, cars, things like that. Right.
And there was a very, very famous tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004. Do you remember that?
Yeah. And in Indonesia, right? That's right. Indonesia and Thailand. Yeah. It was intense. It was big.
And it was also because of a earthquake, right? I think so. All these earthquakes, they move the earth around.
And then all of a sudden, the reaction is that there's water that moves in the water.
It's a water. Yeah. It turned into a wave. Yeah. Just imagine what happens with you. If you have a bucket of
water and then you start moving the bucket just a little bit and just you see how it just water starts
to splat all over the place. That's right. All right. So tsunami was our last word for today.
When we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
Those are the headlines for today. And now for the International Weather Report with Mike Sanderson.
Thank you, Bob. This past week has been the beginning of our beginning for many.
As a series of unprecedented meteorological events occurred around the world,
in Switzerland, a major avalanche was reported in the Alps,
fortunately no one was injured. Due to the extreme coldest winter, a blizzard has struck the U.S. Midwest,
causing classes in schools and universities to be temporarily cancelled.
Moving on to Latin America, Ecuador has suffered a six-month drought that has not only affected farming,
but has also forced the closure of the hydroelectric power plant that provides electricity for the
entire country. In Chile, a major earthquake that registered 7.5 on the Richter scale struck
the southern region, losses are reported to be in the billions. Authorities have not yet released
an official statement. Not a great week for the world. Any good news? I'm afraid not, Bob.
One of the major volcanoes in Mexico has erupted, causing major floods and landslides in the region.
Meanwhile, Mexico's coast has been hit by Hurricane Nileana, an official say that all the
seismic activity leads them to believe that he's tsunami made hit Central America,
affecting Honduras, Guatemala, and Panama. That's all the news we have for today,
but stay tuned for updates on the six o'clock news. Back to you, Bob.
So, Marco, these are all pretty terrifying. Have you ever experienced a meteorological event
like one of the ones that we talked about today? I've actually lived it through like three
earthquakes, like pretty big ones. Plus, because you used to live in Los Angeles.
So, you get them all the time in L.A. Apart from that, I actually, if you see a volcano
erupt a couple of times, because you know, Ecuador is part of the volcano alley, right? It's
all the Andes Mountains, and it's part of the circle of fire, what they call. So, we have a couple
of different active volcanoes, and from time to time they will start to smoke or to spew some
lava, but nothing major, like there hasn't been a major catastrophe with the volcanoes. Hopefully,
won't either. Well, in these days, they have a lot of equipment, seismic equipment, and
meteorological equipment that can help meteorologists to determine when things will happen. Like,
when a volcano will erupt, or if there will be an earthquake, because they can study the
tremors in the ground. Right. Yeah, and I think probably the most famous volcano is, I think it was
an Italy, right? Mount Mesuvius. That's right. So, you've got Mount Mesuvius in Naples, which
famously destroyed a number of cities in this ancient civilization in ancient. What is a
main attraction? It was, and what's amazing is that they still have a lot of the buildings
underground. Under the ash, because when all the ash settled, it preserved the bodies, like a
mummy. And so, you can see the bodies and the things that they're jewelry and their money,
and it's fascinating because it's this horrible, horrible natural disaster, actually helped us
in the future learn about this old civilization. Yeah. It's crazy. Actually, in a enekora, you can see
a huge hole that has like a lake in the middle. And you're like, oh, wow, that's beautiful. But that's
actually caused because the entire mountain just kind of blew the top off, like the cone,
because of this major eruption. So, you can just imagine how powerful these eruptions are.
I can just imagine what it would have been like Mount Mesuvius. But anyway, on a brighter note,
if you have any questions, any comments or any stories of your own, maybe you've
lived through a typhoon hurricane or tornado, you can come to our website EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there. All right. Bye guys. Bye.