Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we are covering a very important health issue.
That's right. We are. That's right. In case of an emergency, maybe somebody stops breathing.
So we need to apply CPR. Now what is this procedure? Well, let's take a look at it in vocabulary
preview.
Very cablory preview. CPR in English is an acronym that means CPR all stand for different words.
Mm-hmm. The big phrase here is cardio pulmonary resuscitation.
All right. So you don't have to remember that. Well, it's pretty hard. What if you break it down?
So what is cardio? Cardio means half. It has to do with your heart.
And then pulmonary pulmonary means lungs. That has to do with your lungs. And what about
resuscitation? That means to bring back. So two resuscitate is to bring back to life. That's right.
Okay. So this is a very popular procedure. You probably see it in movies when somebody
almost drowned the lifeguard performs CPR. Oh no. The love of my life is just drowned and then someone
comes and they push their chest. There's one, two, three. They count. And then the person
bits out water in everything and they're like, all right. All right. All right. So that's CPR.
Why don't we listen to this dialogue? See what's going on? And we'll be back shortly.
What does that mean? Well, basically if your heart stops pumping blood or your lung stop pumping air
that we need to get them going again. That's when we have to apply this procedure. Let's begin.
I need a volunteer. Me. Me. All right. Come here and lay flat on your back.
Let's suppose this young woman has stopped reading. We must lift the person's chin so that we clear a
pathway for air to get into the lungs. Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth
and blow air two or three times like this. Wait. What are you doing? I'm a married woman.
You can't just try to kiss me like that. Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you. I'm trying to demonstrate
how to apply CPR in the case of an emergency. Well, okay. Oh no French kissing.
As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner. Once this is done, we must
try to get the heart going again. To do this, we place our hands over the person's chest and press
down firmly two or three times. Wait. What are you doing? You can't just kiss me then go for second
base. All right. We're back so a couple of pretty difficult words and phrases there, but don't worry.
We'll explain them now in language takeaway. Language takeaway. The first phrase we've got today is
cardiac arrest. All right. So cardiac arrest now cardiac. I think that has to do with the heart
again, right? Exactly. Your heart. And what about arrest? Well, arrest means two things. Maybe you've
heard of this meaning to arrest somebody. The police arrested someone. Well, this means to stop.
To stop. Okay. So we're not talking about the police here. We're talking about the heart stopping.
Okay. So cardiac arrest means when your heart stops. Okay. And another word that's right next to it,
pulmonary arrest. So I'm guessing, again, pulmonary has to do with lungs. That's right. And arrest
stops. So your lungs stop a pumping air. Exactly. So cardiac and pulmonary arrest. These are
two times when your heart or your lungs, they stop doing what they are supposed to do. All right.
And interestingly enough, the heart pumps blood. The lungs pump air. And that's our next word.
What is this word to pump? To pump means to fill something with. Okay. So for example, the heart
pumps blood to the rest of your body. That means it's always making sure your body has blood going into it.
And the same thing with your lungs. Your lungs help oxygen and air get to the rest of your body. So they
pump it. They fill up with air. Okay. And we can do the same in other things. For example, you pump air
into your tire. That's right. If you have a flat tire, you're writing your bicycle and your bicycle
won't move. Oh, no. You have to pump it with air. That means fill it up with air. Okay. Or maybe
even pump water, right? Licking your house. Or pump your car up with gas. Okay. All right. Very good.
So now the man is going to explain how to perform this procedure CPR. And he asks for a volunteer.
Okay. A volunteer. This is a word that can be both a noun. So a thing. And it can be an action.
A verb. Okay. So who is or what is a volunteer? A volunteer is someone who offers to do something
for free. For free. Without you asking them to do it. Right. So are there any volunteers in the room?
Right. And so I'm sorry that someone is going to be me. Me me me me me. Me me. I do. Okay. You can also
volunteer to help people who need help. So for example, in Haiti, there's an earthquake. And there are
many people who offered to volunteer to help patients. So that means they said, I will work for
free to help these people. A volunteer. A volunteer. Our two volunteer. Very good. So now we have
our volunteer and the man is explaining what to do. Lift the person's chin so that we clear a path
away for air to get into the lungs. Oh, this is a good one. So a path is like a road. It's where
something can go. Can move. To clear a pathway means to make some room. Okay. Clear path. So that
means think about it. If you can't breathe, someone has to find a way to make room to make a
hole for you to breathe. So that means to move whatever is blocking you to clear some kind of space.
Okay. So that's a pathway, a clear space. And now well, he's demonstrating how to perform CPR.
So what does this verb to demonstrate? To demonstrate is very important. We use this in most
kinds of teaching. So to demonstrate is to show or to give an example. Okay. So for example,
here in English, but we are demonstrating how to use these words. In sentence. Exactly. So an example
is a good way to demonstrate the word or the phrase. Very good. All right. Why don't we listen to
this dialogue again? And we'll be back in a bit. Hello, everyone and welcome to our CPR for Beginners
First of all, does anyone know what CPR stands for? Cardiopominary resuscitation. That's right.
We apply CPR in the case of cardiac arrest or pulmonary arrest. What does that mean? Well,
basically, if your heart stops pumping blood or your lung stop pumping air,
then we need to get them going again. That's when we have to apply this procedure. Let's begin.
I need a volunteer. Me, me. All right. Come here and lay flat on your back. Let's suppose this young
woman has stopped breathing. We must lift the person's chin so that we clear a pathway for air
to get into the lungs. Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth and blow air two or three
times like this. Wait. What are you doing? I'm a married woman. You can't just try to kiss me like that.
Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you. I'm trying to demonstrate how to apply CPR in the case of an emergency.
Well, okay. Oh, no French kissing. As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner.
Once this is done, we must try to get the heart going again. To do this, we place our hands
over the person's chest and press down firmly two or three times. Wait. What are you doing?
You can't just kiss me then go for second base. All right. We're back. So now let's go with fluency
builder. Fluency builder. Well, the first phrase in fluency builder we hear in the beginning of today's
dialogue, the teacher says, well, basically, if your heart stops pumping blood, then we need to get it going
again. Okay. So that's a whole phrase there to get something going, to get it going. What do you mean by this?
This means to start it up again. Okay. So we could say, I used to teach an English class for my colleagues,
but we stopped having it. I'd like to get it going again. Okay. So you'd like to start it up again.
Exactly. So usually you're talking about turning something on or getting something started. For example,
maybe your car won't start. So if you push it, you can get it going. Right. To get it going or to
turn the key is to get it going. Okay. Right. So to get something going. Now moving on, we have two
key phrases here that are a little bit spicy, right? Yeah. They're very romantic. All this shouldn't be
very romantic. All right. Well, this phrase that we have coming up is French kiss. Two French kiss
someone or a French kiss. So the volunteer says, okay, I'm happy to help you, but no French kissing.
Okay. What is French kissing? No one wants to answer. All right. What is it? Well, it is
when you kiss someone, but your tongue goes into that other person's mouth. Yeah. All right. So there's a
normal kiss. You can kiss your friends on the cheek, but a French kiss means that you use your tongue.
Okay. So I wonder why they call it a French kiss. Maybe Americans just were too shy.
They blamed it on the French. Maybe the French listeners out there can tell us. All right. So now
moving on and she says, okay, no French kissing. Now the man is going to perform CPR and obviously
he has to firmly press down on her chest to get her heart pumping blood, right? Right. This is a
part of CPR. So first of all, you try to give the person air so they can breathe and then you
have to push their chest to start their heart. And this woman, the volunteer says, hey, what are you doing?
You can't just kiss me first and then go for second base. All right. So what is second base? Okay.
This is a sports metaphor with baseball, right? So baseball has four bases. First, second, third
base and home plate or exactly. So in romance, and we're talking about dating, we have a
a way to say first, second, third and fourth base. First base is kissing. That's kissing, right?
So second base would be second base. Well, in this example, it means touching. Touching certain parts
of the body. Romantic touching. All right. So second base. And then obviously we have third and fourth,
but we're not going to get into that. You can look it up on Google, third base and fourth base.
We trust that you can find it. But first and second base are very common. It's it's okay to
talk about it's not a bad word. So you'll probably see it in movies. Young kids talking about
first base or going to second base with someone. So it's kind of saying this in a different way.
As a metaphor, as you said. It's more polite. This is subtle. Yeah. All right. So that's all the
words and phrases we have on fluency, but let's listen to this great dialogue one last time.
Hello everyone and welcome to our CPR for Beginners Course. First of all, does anyone know what CPR
stands for? Cardiopominary Resultation. That's right. We apply CPR in the case of cardiac arrest
or pulmonary arrest. What does that mean? Well, basically, if your heartsteps pumping blood
or your lung stop pumping air that we need to get them going again, that's when we have to apply
this procedure. Let's begin. I need a volunteer. Me. Me. All right. Come here and lay flat on your back.
Let's suppose this young woman has stopped breathing. We must lift the person's chin so that we clear
a pathway for air to get into the lungs. Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth
and below air two or three times like this. Wait. What are you doing? I'm a married woman. You can't
just try to kiss me like that. Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you. I'm trying to demonstrate how
to apply CPR in the case of an emergency. Well, okay. Oh, no French kissing.
As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner. Once this is done, we must try to
get the heart going again. To do this, we place our hands over the person's chest and press down
firmly two or three times. Wait, what are you doing? You can't just kiss me then go for second base.
All right. We're back. So a CPR class. This is actually a very popular thing to take up. You
never know when you need to to perform it, right? That's true. And I think it's a really smart
smart class to take. You can usually take them for free at a community center or a fire department
the red cross. The red cross. I have a red cross certification. Oh, really. So you know how to perform this.
Wow. It's actually as I said, it's I think it would be very useful and I've never taken a course
like this up, but I know how to perform the procedure. So I'm not certified though. So I'm not a certified
CPR. That is certified CPR person. But it's interesting. Let us know if in your country, maybe you can
take CPR classes or maybe you're a CPR certified technician or maybe you are trained in other ways.
So we're curious about those as well. Let us know if you have any questions about today's lesson
or website is EnglishPod.com. All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye everyone.