Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson for you all about money.
That's right. We are going to talk about the stock market. So a very interesting topic, very
current as well because well throughout the world, stock markets are not doing very well.
That's right. And you may have seen on a television a lot of information about this.
So today we're going to hopefully explain some of the things and phrases and words that you've been hearing.
But first we've got a couple of important indicators, a couple of acronyms actually that you're going to hear about.
So let's look at those in today's vocabulary preview.
Very cabbiery preview.
All right. So the first word that we have on vocabulary preview is the NASDAQ NASDAQ NASDAQ.
N-A-S-D-A-Q. So this is basically the American stock market.
Right. It's an acronym. It's a really, really long acronym. So we're not going to get into it.
But it is basically the American stock market where all these companies are trading stock.
Publicly traded companies. Right. So publicly traded companies, you're basically trading their stocks through NASDAQ.
Right. And now the next one that we have is an indicator that which tells us how well some companies are some stock are doing.
And that's the Dow Jones indicator. Dow Jones indicator. So maybe if the Dow Jones is really
low for something, we think it's not doing so well. Right. So it goes up. Things are improving.
Right. So usually the Dow Jones has the it's based upon the 50 biggest companies in the United
States. The 50 biggest publicly traded companies. Now you can divide it into like industrial companies
or pharmaceutical companies, etc. But in general, that's the indicator in how it works.
Great. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and find out how these words are used in context.
And we're back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Sorry to bother you sir, but I have some bad news. What is it? Well, the stock market just took a
huge plunge and we've lost a lot of money. What do you mean? What happened? There are many factors that
weigh in. But NASDAQ is down 200 points. The Dow Jones indicator also suffered. Our portfolio is
worth half of what it was worth one week ago. How is this possible? You are supposed to be talking
to our stock brokers and making sure that our securities and investments are safe and making a
profitable return. I know sir, we didn't expect a bull market to become a bear market all of a sudden.
On the other hand, you still have some high yield trash bonds and government bonds that will give
us enough liquidity to cut our losses and reinvest in emerging markets. We could potentially
make this tragedy work for us and make us think outside the box.
Who would you have to do? One other thing, don't tell the rest of the stockholders about this.
If they find out it's the end of this company.
All right, we're back. So a lot of interesting words there. I think a lot of them were very specific
to the stock market and very maybe a little bit difficult. So why don't we take a look at a
couple of those and language takeaway? Language takeaway. Okay, so this first word is a very
important word in banking and finance. We talk about portfolios a lot. Support folio.
Right. So basically a portfolio is the variety of things that you own. For example, in the stock market,
it could be stocks, it could be bonds, it can be mutual funds, et cetera, or for example,
if you're a company, your product portfolio could be all the products that your company owns.
That's right. So in this case, our portfolio is worth half what it was a week ago. And so this is,
this is a sentence that means, we've lost half of the money we invested. Right. All of our
investments are in a portfolio. We talk about them as a portfolio and when we lose money, we mean
our portfolio is worth less now than it was before. Exactly. And well, moving on, he starts to
talk about the bull market and the bear market. So what is, what is this all about? Well, a bull
is an animal with horns. Right. And a bear is another animal. So we're not talking about animals here.
Right. We're talking about special finance phrases. Right. So the bull market would be a, again,
talking about companies and trading. It would be maybe a market that's growing very rapidly. That's
very, very strong. That's a bull market. So people often talk about China's bull market. Right.
I would try to continue to grow and grow and grow and grow and grow. But a market that slows down
like the United States last year would be a bear market. Right. So think of a bear, maybe it's sleeping.
It goes into a hibernation. That's a bear market. So a slow market. It's not really growing.
Very good. But talking about a portfolio again, we might have stocks. But in this case, the two
people are talking about their bonds. Right. So he says, you still have some high yield to trash bonds
and government bonds. What's a high yield bond and what's a trash bond? Okay. So when we think
about the word yield is how much it gives. Right. So how much we are getting from it. So something
that is high yield means that you're getting a lot from it. For example, this orange tree yields
300 oranges per year. Okay. So how much we get from it? Exactly. So we're getting 300 oranges.
That's how much it's yielding. And so so basically that's what yield means. So when we talk
about trash bonds, this on the other hand, it's a word that's maybe a little bit tricky. But
a bond is a promise that you get from the seller that he's going to pay you back the money that
you give him with interest. Right. But a trash bond is a very risky bond. It means that the seller
might not pay you back because, you know, he's still trying to get all the money. All right. But a
high yield to trash bond means that you might make a lot of money from this bond. Unless, of course,
it's not very dependable. Exactly. So it's risky. Of course, since it's riskier, it has more yield.
Great. So high yields trash bond. And then what about this? They will give us liquidity to
cut our losses. Liquidity. We hear all about liquidity and finance. Exactly. Maybe in your company,
the accountant will talk about this. And that's basically just to have money cash in hand. So you
have money to pay things or to buy things, right? Not with. Okay. It's available.
Available. Yeah. Not with credit. The opposite of credit. Okay. The liquidity. And finally,
instead, what are we going to do? Let's think outside the box. We could reinvest in emerging markets.
And this is a very hot topic lately talking about emerging markets. So to emerge means to come
up, right, to rise. Yeah. It's come out. So it's almost like new or growing markets. So in this case,
a market and emerging market would be, for example, the Southeast Asian market, which is growing
quickly or even you could say West African market. We're talking about places in the world that
aren't established. They're not old and dependable. They're new and exciting. Right. So they're coming
up. So that's an emerging market. So a lot of very interesting words and phrases. They're very
related to our topic. And so why don't we move on now? Let's take a look at two key phrases on
fluency builder. Fluency builder. This first phrase is something we've heard a lot about in the last
year or two with things not going so well in the world of finance. The first one here we go to cut our
losses. Okay. So let's cut our losses. So when you talk about cutting your losses, that means to
try and stop losing money somehow. Maybe sell early. That's right. So in this case, we're losing
money. Let's stop now. Let's stop everything. Cut our losses. That means cut them away. Forget about
them. They're the more and start again. Okay. So we could say, my business is failing. I'm going to
cut my losses. Sell the business and start again. Right. That's exactly it. So to cut your losses,
means to stop doing something maybe sell it and stop losing money. Basically, you accept the
fact that you lost it. You can't get it back. Right. Again. So when they were talking about
investing in emerging markets, he said, well, maybe we could do this and that would force us to
think outside the box. Okay. This is a great phrase and you might hear this in meetings a lot or
from your manager. What's going on here is these two people are talking about how they lost a lot of
money. The economy is bad and they've been doing things in a normal way for a long time. It's not working.
Let's think outside the box. That means let's be creative. Let's try and discover new ways of doing
things that will yield positive results. That's right. This is a very, very common phrase. Very widely
used in business or when you're talking about ideas is people tell you to think outside the box.
To maybe break some of the rules. Right. Right. Don't just think the way that you always do. Don't
do the same thing over and over. Do something new. Be creative. Come up with something great. So
that's thinking outside the box. Right. Very good. So a lot of great phrases there. I think that we've
learned quite a bit. Why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a
little bit more about this very interesting topic. Sorry to bother you, sir. But I have some bad news.
What is it? Well, the stop market just took a huge plunge and we've lost a lot of money.
What do you mean? What happened? There are many factors that weigh in, but Nasdaq is down
200 points. The Dow Jones indicator also suffered. Our portfolio is worth half of what it was
worth one week ago. How is this possible? You are supposed to be talking to our stock brokers
and making sure that our securities and investments are safe and making a profitable return.
I know, sir. We didn't expect a bull market to become a bear market all of a sudden. On the
other hand, you still have some high yield trash bonds and government bonds that will give us
enough liquidity to cut other losses and reinvest in emerging markets. We could potentially
make this tragedy work for us and make us think outside the box.
Who would you have to do? One other thing. Don't tell the rest of the stockholders about this.
If they find out it's the end of this company.
I remember being a little kid and watching TV with my parents and on the news, there was always
the business segment. You'd always hear the Nasdaq is down 10 points. The Dow Jones industrial
today is down 10 points. Yesterday was up to that's an average of 8. Okay. It's very complicated.
Especially if you take a look also in the newspapers. Sometimes it shows you different
publicly traded companies and it has a bunch of numbers. It's a very interesting topic. It's
almost a science, I think. Very much a science and some people have made a lot of money playing
this always a playing the stock market and trying to buy stocks in their low,
wait and sell their high, sell them off and make tons. It's pretty much analyzing risk.
So making calculated decisions. That's why they use all these formulas and all these
different ratios and ways to ponder how much they should invest or what with a gain.
And so it's very very interesting. Many people compare it to gambling, but it's kind of like
gambling but not really because you don't really depend on luck. You kind of make calculated decisions.
And sometimes you're trading for big companies or even parts of big markets like parts of
entire countries. Yeah. A lot of people for example stock brokers will invest
a group of workers retirement funds. They will take those funds and be like, hey,
you're maybe getting 5% from the bank for keeping your money there. Give me the money and I'll
give you 25% yield on your investment. So that's and so obviously they're playing not only
their reputation but also with other people's life savings. And that's why a lot of people lost money
when two years ago the bubble really burst with a lot in a lot of areas like real estate. Stock prices
went down. The United States went into a recession and all these people's retirement funds,
savings, they lost it. So you got to be careful with this kind of stuff and do your homework.
But that's about it for us today. Hope that you've enjoyed this lesson. If you have questions or
comments, please do visit us on our website EnglishPod.com. All right, we'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.