Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very serious dialogue for you.
That's right we are going to talk about a will and testament, the last will and testament
of someone.
Alright so what is a will and testament?
Basically this is a document that someone writes usually with a lawyer that explains what
to do with the person's body and their possessions, their things after they die.
So many people write these and the family will then use it to discover who gets to receive
certain objects and what to do with this person's body.
Right exactly.
So that is a last will and testament.
We are going to take a look and add an example of one.
You would see more or less in English how one is written.
Now obviously they can be very long and very complex.
So we've taken one that has some interesting words there that are a little bit more specific,
very a lot of legal terms there.
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time and we'll be back shortly.
Last will and testament of Luke Thompson.
I, Luke Thompson, residing in California, being of soundmind to hear by declare this
instrument to be my last will and testament.
I hear by revoke all previous wills and codicills.
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
I'm to be cremated and taken to the summit of Mount Everest where my ashes will forever remain
at the ceiling of the earth.
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to my spouse, Betty Thompson.
Should she survive me for 60 days?
If my spouse, Betty Thompson, does not survive me.
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to English pod.
If neither Betty Thompson nor English pod survives me, I give all the rest and residue
of my estate to my airs as determined by the laws of the state of California, relating
to descent and distribution.
I appoint Robert Porter to act as the executor of this will, to serve without bond.
Should Robert Porter be unable or unwilling to serve, then I appoint Jason Smalls to act
as the executor of this will?
I hear with A.F. my signature to this will on this, the 23rd of May 2010, in the presence
of the following witnesses, who witnessed and subscribed this will at my request and in my presence.
Alright, we're back.
So now we're going to take a look at five key words on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, the first word here in language takeaway comes from the very beginning of this,
well, monologue, we're reading the last one, testament, right?
I Luke Thompson, residing in California, being of sound mind, sound as an adjective.
What does this mean?
That's very interesting.
So he says, I am in sound of mind and the sound is an adjective to describe.
I am in a good state of mind.
That's right.
So it means not having any problems or logical or unspected.
Basically, I'm not crazy.
Right.
I'm not crazy.
I don't have any problems.
We can say this about other things, too.
We can say he's of sound body.
Right.
That means that he is healthy.
He has no problems with his body.
Or I could say, Marko, that's a really good decision.
It's a sound decision.
So again, that's also a way of saying good or it will work.
It will work.
It's a good decision.
So you can use this adjective with sound bodies, sound mind, or a sound decision.
Or sometimes some people even say, I think in Ireland, they say, oh, he's a really sound
guy.
Oh, so he's a good guy.
That's a good guy.
Very interesting.
Yeah.
So sound a body, sound mind, sound guy.
Moving on, he was talking about the will and he says, I hear by revoke all previous
wills and caracels.
The verb here is two revoke.
Two revoke.
This is something that a lot of people hear in America when they drive their car too fast.
The police catch them and the police revoke their driver's license.
And that basically means to take away.
That's right.
To take right.
To take away from.
So this man here, Luke Thompson, what he's saying is, I revoke all previous wills.
That means any other will that I wrote before, it's not good anymore.
Right.
This is the only one that will exist.
So you can use this word revoke with many aspects.
For example, sometimes employees will get their benefits revoked by the company because
maybe they don't have enough money anymore.
Or maybe they're bad employees.
Or maybe they were bad employees.
Oh, that's too bad.
All right.
So to revoke, now moving on, he was talking about his estate.
So this is very interesting because he says, I give all the rest and residue of my estate
to my spouse.
OK, estate.
It sounds like a very fancy word.
It is a fancy word.
Sometimes we use this word to mean someone's property or house.
But in a will, this means everything the person owns.
House, car, things, pets, stocks, investments.
The estate is essentially everything the person owns as a kind of one unit.
Right, exactly.
So anything that is yours or you may have bought, just consider the estate is a big
bag, right?
That's your estate and inside this bag is everything that you own.
You might see advertisements in fact in America or in England for estate sales.
This means that when someone passes away when they die, their family will sell their things.
And this is in a state sale.
You can find beautiful, interesting things that are sales.
Exactly.
Very interesting.
So that is a person's estate.
Now remember, this is in the legal terms because you also have other things like real estate
and as you mentioned, which would be a house.
Okay.
Now apart from his estate, he was telling everyone to how they should take care of his body
or what they should do with it and he said, well, I am to be cremated.
Okay, this is important.
When a person dies, there are generally two options.
Their body can be buried in a casket in the ground.
That means they're put in the earth.
But a lot of people choose to be cremated.
Okay, that means that their body will be burned and their ashes, that means the things
that are left after they are burned, they will be taken somewhere else.
Right.
Like in a bowl or a pot.
And in this case, that's what the person wants.
He wants to be cremated.
So that would be the verb two cremates and the now would be a cremation.
cremation.
And what is going to happen to all this stuff?
Basically, it's going to be given away to his wife, to English pod and to his ears.
This is our next word.
What is an air?
Now, if you notice the age is silent there, so his ears.
And those are basically his children, his daughters or his sons.
Right, my ears are the people who are related to me, who in this case will receive
some of my things.
Now is it only the children or also maybe any other relatives?
It could be any other relative.
You could say, I'm his heir.
He's my great uncle.
I mean, we're related, but we're now necessarily father and daughter or grandfather and
granddaughter.
An heir is someone who is related to the family.
It doesn't have to be a certain relationship.
And now it's interesting because from this word, we can get inheritance.
Now we didn't find it in the dialogue.
So it's very interesting because it comes.
They're very similar in spelling, right?
In heritons and air.
Right.
Good to remember.
Yeah, good to remember.
You can switch the E in the eyes, right?
That's right.
So inheritance is a thing.
You can receive this.
So I received an inheritance from my great grandmother.
That means I received some money or some things.
That means you were that person's heir.
That's right.
Okay.
So you know, in his inheritance, he received a large house.
He was the heir to a great fortune.
Okay.
Interesting.
So again, inheritance wasn't in the dialogue, but I think it's worth mentioning.
And I think now we can move on to for very interesting items that we have for you on Fluency
Builder.
Okay.
These first two are words that we normally read or hear in legal documents.
And I want to place emphasis on the fact that we don't really say them in spoken English.
So remember that these are more formal terms.
Yeah.
The first one is hereby.
Hereby.
I hear by declare.
Right.
That means now.
Now with this word, with this spoken sentence, this will happen.
I think we've seen it like in movies sometimes.
It was like, I hear by declare this country in the name of England.
I hear by declare you man and wife.
Exactly.
Okay.
That means in this moment, this happens.
And a very similar word that we also signed a dialogue is here with.
So in the will and testament, we hear Luke Thompson who says, I hear with a fixed my signature.
That means with the action of signing my name, signing my signature, this will be completed.
Okay.
So I hear with, you have to have an action not just a word.
So I hear with, I hear with a touch my seal.
Okay.
A seal is like a stamp.
Very common in the old days when you had real letters.
But I hear with us, you know, I hear with a touch my seal and give my approval to this document.
Okay.
So it has to be something physical.
Yeah.
Right.
So if maybe you're writing like this very classic letter and you say, I hear with
include a lock of my hair.
Oh, how romantic.
Okay.
That's kind of creepy.
You're including or attaching physically, right?
I guess I guess the modern version of here with would be attached.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here with here by, oh, we have got another phrase here that you might hear more commonly.
The beginning of the will and testament.
There's a phrase as follows.
Okay.
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
So with my body do as follows.
So basically this is a very common way of putting this in a sentence to indicate that
you're going to start to list items.
That's right.
Or give instruction instructions.
So for example, to make a loaf of bread do as follows.
Number one, get some flour.
Number two, add some water.
So this is a way for us to say listen.
I'm going to give you instructions or a list pay attention.
So please do as follows.
Okay.
Very good.
And our last word that we have here going back to here with, he said, I hear with a fix my signature.
What does it mean when you fix?
Okay.
A fix is a word we have a number of other words for these days.
So you rarely hear it.
It means to attach or to include.
Okay.
So I hear with a fix my signature would be attached my signature.
Right.
I provide my signature.
Or I hear with a fix my address or I hear with a fix something.
Okay.
Very good.
Really interesting stuff.
You'll obviously see this very commonly with legal documents such as these, even though
it is like older English, it's still very commonly used.
I guess it's a lie.
So old.
That's right.
Definitely.
And I think that it's worth listening to today's monologue one more time.
Think about some of the words that we've just discussed and we'll be back in a moment.
Music
Last will in testament of Luke Thompson.
I, Luke Thompson, residing in California, being of sound mind, do hereby declare this instrument
to be my last will in testament.
I hear by revoke all previous wills and kodacills.
I direct that the disposition of my remains be as follows.
I'm to be cremated and taken to the summit of Mount Everest where my ashes will forever
remain at the ceiling of the earth.
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to my spouse, Betty Thompson.
Should she survive me for 60 days?
If my spouse, Betty Thompson, does not survive me.
I give all the rest and residue of my estate to English pod.
If neither Betty Thompson nor English pod survives me, I give all the rest and residue
of my estate to my airs as determined by the laws of the state of California, relating
to descent and distribution.
I appoint Robert Porter to act as the executor of this will to serve without bond.
Should Robert Porter be unable or unwilling to serve, then I appoint Jason Smalls
to act as the executor of this will.
I hear with a fix my signature to this will on this the 23rd of May 2010 in the presence
of the following witnesses who witnessed and subscribe this will at my request and in my presence.
Alright we're back so this is a very interesting topic now.
I wonder within the will or within the estate do you also acquire a person's debts?
Ah that's a good question.
I know in some countries you don't, in some cases some airs have found themselves in some
legal problems because all of a sudden they inherited that person's debts.
I think that does happen especially for people whose properties are mortgage.
For example if your uncle has a house and he didn't pay for it with cash, he's a mortgage
and he dies and you inherit this house.
You also inherit the mortgage.
So sometimes, inheritances are not always a good thing.
I think this happened more in the past.
There are more protections and safeguards for people today.
But definitely what is it like an record or do people inherit debt?
Yeah I think most obviously most banks when they give out loans or a mortgage you are.
They have somebody that will kind of co-sign on these things.
And I imagine I'm not really very sure but I know that if you inherit in a state that has a mortgage
you are forced to pay it and if you can then they will make that other person who co-sign it responsible if he still exists.
I don't know in these legal systems it sometimes very strange because it seems like there would be a lot of gaps.
That's right and everyone wants to protect themselves.
Yeah.
So we've got the bank that wants to protect itself.
It gives a loan at once the money back and a person who wants to protect himself from maybe a relative who dies and has debt.
Yeah.
So I'm curious to know what our users have to say, what is the situation in your country?
Do most people have a will and testament?
What happens with debt?
Or what happens if somebody dies and they don't have a will and testament?
That's a good question too.
I don't have an answer for that one.
Alright, so let us know and we'll give you guys some information on that as well.
EnglishPod.com will see everyone there.
Bye everyone.