Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we're
talking today about health and getting sick. That's right, we are going to visit the doctor.
So we're feeling a little bit ill. And what we're going to describe some of the symptoms that
we have and the doctor is going to recommend some medicine. All right, so let's take a listen
to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Good afternoon, Chloe. I'm Dr. Evans. What seems to be the problem? Hi, Dr. Evans. Thanks for
seeing me on such short notice. When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat and
a really bad cough. I think I'm coming down with the flu. I see. Yes, you do sound rather
croaky. Well, let's have a look, shall we? Could you please open your mouth and say, ah?
Ah. Good, yes. Your tonsils are a little swollen and red. How are your ears blocked at all?
A little, actually. My sinuses are a little blocked up as well. I really feel terrible.
Okay, Chloe. Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
Wow, you really are all bungged up. You don't sound too good at all. Okay, I'm going
to set you up with a bunch of antibiotics. You will need to take these orange pills twice
a day and these blue pills every evening. You will also have to take this cough medicine
three times a day after meals. Finally, I'm giving you an inhaler to use every time you
feel breathless, just to clear up your lungs. Whoa, so many drugs. Ah, I hate swallowing
pills. Am I able to go to work? Absolutely not. You're highly contagious. You don't want
to infect the rest of your co-workers do you? I recommend staying in bed for at least three days
and drinking plenty of fluids so you don't get weakened dehydrated. You can catch up on all
the latest TV shows and movies. Okay, would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work?
Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it. Ah, sure, no problem. Here you are. Now, off home
in a way to bed. If you have any questions, just give me a call. Feel better soon and take care.
Thanks, Doc. Bye. Bye.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at six key words that we have prepared for you
today on language takeaway. Language takeaway. So oftentimes in the winter time, when the air
is very, very dry and maybe you have a cold, you get this. This is the first thing we're talking
about. That's right. We have a sore throat. Okay, so Chloe in the dialogue says, I woke up this
morning and I had a really sore throat. Right. So let's take a look at those two words. We know
throat is the part of your neck, right? Connects your head to your body. That's right. And the word
sore. So it means it hurts. So I could have a sore back or sore knees. Uh, sore is basically
an adjective that describes pain. Pain. So you have an ache in your throat. All right. So that's
a sore throat. And well, she said that she has this sore throat and the doctor says, I see. Yes,
you do sound rather croaky. Okay, croaky is a way to describe the way a person sounds, especially when
they're talking and maybe their voice, I think, is very deep or rough. Right. So usually if you have a
sore throat or a very bad cough, you sound a little bit croaky. So you're like, hey, my throat
or it's a little bit. Exactly. Not a very nice way to sound. It comes from the way that frogs
croak, right? Yeah, that's the sound that frogs make. They croak. So yeah, sometimes when you do have a
sore throat or a very bad cough, people say that you have a frog in your throat. Right? All right.
So that's the word croakie. Now, moving on, if you have a sore throat, it's usually because
your tonsils are swollen. Okay. So the first word here, tonsils. These are a body part. They're in
your throat. They're very back of your throat. And you usually have two of them. Some people don't have
any though. Right. Some people get them removed. They're like little balls in the back of your throat.
And I don't really know what they do. I think they pick up some, I don't know what they do. I don't
think you need them. Actually, because a lot of people have them taken out when they're young,
but tonsils when they are infected or when they are swollen are very, very painful. You can have
really bad sore throats. Right. And usually they can cause fevers and stuff like that. So some people
get them removed. And well, as we said, your tonsils are swollen. So if they are swollen, that means they
are big. That's right. So swollen means they're bigger than normal. And you can say this about many
different things. For example, maybe someone stepped on my toe. And my toe really hurt. And I
looked down and it's swollen. That means my toe got bigger. Okay. So this is an adjective when something
is swollen. But the verb form to say that something swells. It's to get, it gets bigger. It gets
bigger to swell. Or the adjective, it is swollen. All right. And now she was talking a little bit
about her sinuses that her sinuses are a little blocked up. So sinuses are in your face.
You have them in your nose and under your eyes. And when they hurt, it's actually quite painful.
And people say that sometimes their sinuses are aggravated or they have bad sinuses.
This means they're having a hard time breathing or their faces sore, their eyes are sore.
It's very common. Okay. So that's sinuses. Isn't there actually a condition that if you have
a blocked sinuses all the time, they call it sinuses? I just sinuses. Yeah. So that's a problem
that comes back again and again. Okay. And the doctor also recommended her to rest because she
is highly contagious. Okay. So you want to stay away from people who are contagious. This means that
what disease they have or what illness they have can affect other people. Right. So if I have the
flu Marco and I come to work, it's pretty contagious. It's very likely that you will get the flu.
That's right. So a flu is very highly contagious or many other things are highly contagious. For
example, pink eye. Yeah. It's very contagious. Very. But you know, cancer is not contagious. If you have
cancer, I can't get it from touching you. Right. Very good. So contagious. All right. Why do we go back
and listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit to talk about fluency builder?
Good afternoon, Chloe. I'm Dr. Evans. What seems to be the problem? Hi, Dr. Evans. Thanks for
seeing me on such short notice. When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat and a really
bad cough. I think I'm coming down with the flu. I see. Yes, you do sound rather croaky. Well,
let's have a look, shall we? Could you please open your mouth and say, ah?
Ah. Good. Yes. Your tonsils are a little swollen and red. How are your ears? Blocked at all?
A little, actually. My sinuses are a little blocked up as well. I really feel terrible.
Okay, Chloe. Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
Ha ha. Wow. You really are all bunged up. You don't sound too good at all. Okay. I'm going to
set you up with a bunch of antibiotics. You will need to take these orange pills twice a day and these
blue pills every evening. You will also have to take this cough medicine three times a day after meals.
Finally, I'm giving you an inhaler to use every time you feel breathless, just to clear up your lungs.
Whoa. So many drugs. Ah. I hate swallowing pills. Am I able to go to work?
Absolutely not. You're highly contagious. You don't want to infect the rest of your co-workers do you?
I recommend staying in bed for at least three days and drinking plenty of fluids so you don't
get weak and dehydrated. You can catch up on all the latest TV shows and movies.
Okay. Would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work? Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it.
Sure. No problem. Here you are. Now, off home in a way to bed. If you have any questions,
just give me a call. Feel better soon and take care. Thanks, Doc. Bye. Bye.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at four key phrases that we have prepared for you on
fluency builder. Fluency builder. So Chloe goes into see her doctor, doctor Evans, and she says,
thanks for seeing me on such short notice. What's short notice? All right. So basically,
Chloe made an appointment with the doctor very late or very, uh, suddenly, right? So that's a short notice.
Great. So for example, it's Friday night and she needs to make an appointment for Saturday
morning. That's pretty short notice. That's not calling the doctor in advance. You can say it's
also when you're talking to friends. You know, I'm really sorry to cancel on such short notice,
but I can't go to dinner tonight. Right. So I think it's very interesting. The whole structure
as you see on such short notice. So as you said, your example, I'm really sorry to cancel on such
short notice on short notice on such short notice. That's right. All right. So moving on to her
second phrase, Chloe was explaining that she doesn't feel very well. And she said, I think I'm coming
down with the flu. Okay. So let's look at this verbal phrase here coming down with, okay? So you
can come down with many different illnesses. But the verb here means, um, this is the beginning of my
illness. So I'm starting to feel the effects like you said, Marco, I'm feeling some symptoms.
So I'm starting to get sick, right? I'm coming down with a fever, or I think I'm coming down with a
cold. Very common. All right. And the doctor started to check Chloe how she was breathing and
think he listened to her lungs with his, what does it call the stethoscope? Stethoscope.
Stethoscope. And he said, wow, you are really all bunged up. All right. So here he's basically
saying that she's very congested. That means that her breathing passageways like in her nose and
her throat and her chest. Very stuffy. There's things in them. Right. Usually mucus.
Yeah, I'm flim. Flim. These are things that, you know, it's in your nose and you have a cold and
have to blow it out. That's flim and mucus. Yeah, not not a very, very pretty thing. No. Very
disgusting actually. So maybe we should move on to our next item. All right. So she's all bunged up
and a clear up. And so he recommended a couple of different medicine such as antibiotics,
some pills, and he also gave her an inhaler to clear up her lungs. Okay. So and inhaler
is basically a device that you use to put steroids in your lungs that will help you breathe.
So some people when they're running or they're walking, they're very short of breath and they
can't breathe. Well, there's a problem with this like asthma and they need to breathe this little
inhaler. And it's like a little tube. I think it's you inhale medicine from this little tube.
Yeah. So the medicine helps open up your passageways. It helps you breathe and it's very important
for some people. But in the case of an illness, like your lungs are very congested. This helps you breathe
on the short term. Right. So basically clear up is to allow air or the movement of something
within your body usually, I think. Right. But to clear up isn't necessarily about air. It's
basically a way to say that it will make this problem go away. To clear something up is to
make the problem go. Right. So I guess if you get medicine from a doctor, he'll say,
okay, this will help you clear up your throat. Right. Or if you have a problem with acne,
maybe your doctor will give you some cream to help clear up your acne. Make it go away.
Clear up your skin. Okay. So a lot of great examples there. When we go back and listen to the
dialogue one last time.
Good afternoon, Chloe. I'm Dr. Evans. What seems to be the problem? Hi, Dr. Evans. Thanks for
seeing me on such short notice. When I woke up this morning, I had a really sore throat
and a really bad cough. I think I'm coming down with the flu. I see. Yes, you do sound rather
croaky. Well, let's have a look, shall we? Could you please open your mouth and say, ah?
Good. Yes. Your tonsils are a little swollen and red. How are your ears blocked at all?
A little, actually. My sinuses are a little blocked up as well. I really feel terrible.
Okay, Chloe. Can you please breathe in and out slowly for me while I listen to your chest?
Wow. You really are all bunged up. You don't sound too good at all. Okay. I'm going to set you up
with a bunch of antibiotics. You will need to take these orange pills twice a day and these blue pills
every evening. You will also have to take this cough medicine three times a day after meals.
Finally, I'm giving you an inhaler to use every time you feel breathless, just to clear up your lungs.
Whoa, so many drugs. Ah, I hate swallowing pills. Am I able to go to work?
Absolutely not. You're highly contagious. You don't want to infect the rest of your co-workers do you?
I recommend staying in bed for at least three days and drinking plenty of fluids so you don't get
weak and dehydrated. You can catch up on all the latest TV shows and movies.
Okay. Would you mind writing me a doctor's note for work? Otherwise, they may think I'm faking it.
Sure, no problem. Here you are. Now, off home in a way to bed. If you have any questions, just
give me a call. Feel better soon and take care. Thanks, Doc. Bye. Bye.
All right, so talking about illnesses and being contagious, we mentioned this pink eye
illness before. So this is the colloquial way of saying conjunctivitis, which is, I don't know if
anyone has ever gotten it, your eye gets very, very red for a prolonged period of time. That's right.
And it itches a lot. Itches. And so already your eye is very red or pink like the name says, but
you really want to scratch it and it's really, it's really hard not to. Yeah, and I think you treated
by means of some eye drops. Yeah, and you have to wait. I actually had a very bad taste of pink
eye ones that I couldn't just clear up with drops, but the doctor gave me some eye drops. They were
so strong that I put them in my eye and I can taste them. Wow. Yeah, so apparently it's very strange.
And it wouldn't clear up. So then I had to get some kind of like a clear gel put in my eye and my eye
patched up for like two days. Oh wow. Yeah, so I was running around with one eye. It was crazy.
Well, I've never had it, but I know that it's very, very contagious, like we were saying earlier.
And so if a student at a school gets pink eye, all the parents get very nervous because it's
very, very likely that he or she will give it to another person. Yeah. Because you know kids,
if you touch your eye and you touch someone else, all of a sudden they have this disease. Exactly.
So yeah, it's very common thing. And I think with especially with kids, they always get all the
all the things. Pink eye, measles, they get chicken pot chicken pucks, a lot of different disease. We
actually have a lesson on chicken pucks. You guys should check that one out. But if you have any
questions, any comments or any other doubts, please come to EnglishPod.com where we're there to answer them.
We'll see you there. Bye. Bye.