Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very technical, very advanced lesson for you.
This is all about one of my favorite subjects.
That's right. We're going to talk about music, but specifically we're going to talk about
the piano and learning how to play the piano. So we're going to talk about very specific
vocabularity to this instrument. Right. So piano and playing music, not listening to music.
So we're going to hear a lot of interesting words and phrases here. Some of them actually come from
foreign languages like Italian. So listen up, we'll be back in a moment and when we come back,
we'll be talking about what these words and phrases mean.
Hi Cody. How did practice and go this week? Well, I had several tests in an oral presentation this week.
So I didn't get a chance to memorize the second page, but I think I mastered the tricky section.
Great. Warm up with some scales in our videos first.
Good. Good. This week we're going to keep the rhythm steady when you play the last part with
the 16th notes. Now let's take a look at this tricky section. Charlie, before I start, I was wondering
if it was okay if I put a small crescendo in here and then a decrescendo back to pianissimo again over here.
It might work. I'll have to hear it. Show me what you've done.
Not bad. It was horrible. I played it much better at home.
Oh, it's just nerves. Just play the right hand for now.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 5, 5, 6, 5, 10, triple E, T. Good. Good. Don't forget the accidentally.
The key signature says that note should be a G sharp, but now it's a G natural.
Now add the bass clef. You're going to fast. Remember the tempo for this piece is undanti.
Is that better? Yes, much better. Watch where you lift your foot off the pedal. What was that?
Sorry, the stretch for that octave is always hard to make. That's okay. Keep going. You're
moving ahead by leaps and bounds. Watch your dynamics. Keep your elbows lifted. Remember to
stroke the keys. Don't pound. That's better. Remember that as a pianist or any other musician
your technique will be what separates you from the pack. Just as much or as more so as your musicianship.
Alright, we're back. So you probably noticed that there are a lot of ways to describe certain
aspects of playing the piano. They talked about scales and all that stuff. So why don't we take a
deeper look at this vocab in language takeaway part one? Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first part of the lesson is the warm up. That's when we start to get our fingers
moving and really stretch out. This is an important part of any musicians' routine because it's
also a way to practice some very basic, very fundamental things for the first, the first of which is a
scale. Okay, so actually Cody started warming up with some scales. So what exactly are scales?
Well, basically there are different musical notes. Some people know them as Do Re Mi Fa Solato Do.
Some people call them CDEFGAPC. But each of those and many others have scale. So that's eight
notes together. Okay, so basically when you're playing scales you're just playing a sequence of these
eight notes. Right, going up or down. Okay, to warm up. And what about in our pedgio? I think this is
Italian, right? Definitely. Our pedgio is another kind of warm up where you're not playing every
single note. You're playing some notes in a scale. Right, so da da da da da da da da. That's in our pedgio.
Okay, very good. So as you said, these are usually for warmups, right? Yeah, they're also very
important because they come into play later when you're talking about the key that a song or piece of
music is in. So this helps you memorize the key that some music is in. Okay, very good. So I think
related to this is the rhythm of the piece that you're playing. That's right. So rhythm is really
important. Some people can even say, you know, he's got rhythm or they have rhythm. It's a way to
describe the beat of a kind of music. So sometimes it has to do with how fast or how slow something is.
Other times it has to do with the way that the notes work together. For example, a steady beat would
be 1, 2, 3, 4, 1, 2, 3, 4. This is a complicated beat. It goes, ta ta trippoli ta ti trippoli. So this is a very
difficult kind of rhythm. Okay, so the rhythm is just kind of it gives you the how fast, how slow it is.
And I guess if you can take a look at notes and you can play it in many different rhythms, but not
necessarily they're going to sound correct. Right. And actually it's interesting. In English, we also have
a group of instruments that are called rhythm instruments. So this would be like the drums.
Okay. So it gives the beat. Yes. Very good. And we're moving on. I think some other Italian words
popped up in here when they talked about crescendo and decresendo. Right. So crescendo is when
something becomes louder. So I can make a crescendo. Right. But a decrescendo, day in Italian,
just like an English means it's the opposite. So it means it's getting really softer. Okay.
And what about Piani Simo? Piani Simo is basically an indication. It also comes from Italian.
It's an indication that a player, a musician should play something very, very, very quietly.
It's almost like a whisper. Okay. So all of these these three words have to do with the volume of
or how loud or not so loud you play the instrument. That's right. Okay. Very good. And
well moving on now, we talk about accidental. Okay. This is important. Remember earlier, we were talking
about scales. Well, for example, the G scale has one sharp. So that's an F sharp. So if I'm playing it
on the Piano, there are seven white keys and one black key. Okay. So actually here they mentioned
G sharp. And then something like G natural. All this, just like where everyone that's out there
is complete Chinese, and we have no idea what this is all about. So you have the accidentals and G sharp.
And you're describing something about sharpness with accidentals. That's right. So basically,
if you look at a piano, you have white keys. Right. Those are those are natural. They don't have
a sharper flat. The sharp and flats are actually played on the black keys.
Usually it's a half step from a normal note. So G, it's a half step. Okay.
We're talking about different keys. So if something is in the key of G and all of you music
people know, no, this is key of G, there's one accidental. What's the accidental? It's always F sharp.
And so an accidental means a sharp or a flat in that key. Okay. And when we talk about sharp
on the piano, they're basically the black keys. Yes. Well, sharp and flats can both be black keys.
Okay. Very good. And well, apart from accidentals and G sharp, G natural, the teacher also
talked about a base clef. Okay. This is important for people who play lower instruments like
the base, you know, the upright base that I'm don't don't don't that they won or people who play
the piano, obviously. This represents a way of writing the lower notes. Okay. Okay. So you see the lines,
those five lines on paper and people write the notes. Well, sometimes they're for higher
instruments, you know, the flute or the trumpet. But sometimes when they're for lower instruments,
like the the left hand of a piano or for the upright base, you have to write it in a special
register, a special part of the sound kind of continuum. And that's the trouble. That's the base clef.
Okay. So basically, if everyone has ever seen piano notes, it tells you what to play with your
left hand and your right hand. So I imagine the base clef will be everything that's on your
left hand because that sounds like deeper, graver, right? Yeah. It's lower. No, it's lower on the scale.
Instead of like, a pie up here where it's on the treble clef. All right. So, oh, so the opposite
would be the treble clef. That's right. The treble clef is a pie. It's most other instruments like
the trumpet. The base clef is for lower instruments. And it just means that the way that you read
the music on the page is a little bit different. Okay. Very good. And well, we also got into
things like tempo and the piece it was described as andante. And Dante, this is a very Italian word.
Okay. So and Dante means that something is played slowly. Okay. So apart from andante, if also it's a
style or a or a tempo, I guess tempo is the speed of which is played, right? That's right. But in
you're right to say that it's also a style because in many symphonies, for example, there's a
movement, a part of the symphony that's called the Andante. And that's when everything starts
to get slow and slow and pretty. I've heard, I don't know, in piano, I've heard of something called
the catto. And I think this is also related to tempo, right? Stacato is the way that you play
something. So instead of having these long, pretty notes, you're playing them like this.
Not a very great shot. Right. Like machine gun. Okay. So, but it's not related to the tempo.
It's kind of more just like the way that you press the keys. Exactly. It's a style for playing.
Okay. All right. Well, the teacher also told the student to be careful where they lift the
foot off the pedal. And the students hit, um, just the so sorry, the stretch for that octave is always
hard to make. Okay. So an octave is really, really important in music. Like we were talking
about earlier with a scale, a scale of eight notes. Well, the the root, the the place the word
octave comes from is the number eight, like an octagon. Right. So octave means eight
notes together or like low C high C, that's an octave. Okay. So I think about the piano,
when you're putting your fingers on the keys, covering eight keys means you have to stretch your
thumb and your pinky out really, really far. And so he's saying, ah, sorry, it's hard for me to do this
because the octave, those that that stretch is really hard for my hand. Right. Okay. So this is
different from an eighth, right? Well, it depends. Are you talking about eighth note? I don't know
because they're just giving it to like because an octave is eight and eighth note. That is
a different than I imagine. Yeah. Well, you're you're heard in the dialogue 16th note, eighth note.
That's actually talking about the length of a note. How long you hold it? Okay. So basically you're
saying it's the way you measure the music. You can have four counts or three count, but you
divide that into pieces. It's like a pie in math where you divide it into pieces. So if it's a 16th note
or an eighth note, that's the length based on the kind of music you're playing. So I imagine 16th
note is shorter than eight. Yes. Okay. At least at least I got that one. And 30 seconds note is shorter
than a 16th note. Wow. You have all the way up to 30 seconds. 64th note is okay. It gets very complicated.
Very mathy. All right. And towards the end of teacher recommended for Cody to watch his dynamics.
What does she mean with what's your dynamics? I used to get this all the time in music. So
you're concentrating on your music, you're playing, you're getting the notes and Cody is
stretching his hands. The octaves are so far away and he forgets to play it loud or soft.
Oh, because on the page it says like we heard earlier, Decaresendo. So get much much softer.
So Cody completely forgot. He's not listening. He's not reading the page and seeing what it
says about the volume of the music. So basically the dynamics are like the instructions of
how loud to play it or not or not so loud. Exactly. So it does it say Piano Simo or the opposite
does it say forte? Oh, so it and it will actually say this on the notes. Yes.
Forte will say that. Oh RTE or sometimes just F. Okay. So P is piano. That means like we said earlier
quiet. Pani Simo is PPP. It's very quiet. F is forte. Loud. Okay. So I think if anyone out there plays
an instrument you can relate and you can maybe know about these these things that you may know
it in your original language. I know I know many people who play musical instruments and don't
really know the technical words in their original language. I mean things like Andante and Pani Simo.
Things like this I think are universal right? They're used in whatever language. Exactly. Very
widely used. But things like the accidental or bass clar for scales and stuff like that. I think
it's obviously different languages. For example, you know Italian like scales or accidental or
they do different different. They're different. All of the other words. So the instructions on the page
because music is shared all over the world. The instructions on the page are almost always in Italian.
So piano and Andante or their instrument. All right. But everything else scales, octaves. These are
all in your native language. And so they're very, very important to study if you want to play.
And I think very, very useful if you want to study an instrument. Yeah, of course. I think it's also
very good idea to just have a general knowledge about these things because you know it's sometimes
it's nice to know a little bit about it and maybe if a friend is talking about music you can
maybe understand a little bit more about what it's like or if you see music sheet of music you
can now more or less know what's going on with all those drawings and little scribbles. Absolutely. And
if you have any questions of course you're welcome to come to our website and ask or share your
experiences as Marco has just said so please come to EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you there.
All right. We'll see you guys next time. Bye.