Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very very useful intermediate level lesson for you all about the weather.
That's right so obviously we have seen the news and sometimes on the news we have the weather report.
So today we're going to learn all about that weather report in English.
So let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about the words and phrases that those weather forecasters used.
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers?
I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend Mary. There's a storm system moving through the east coast.
It will be drizzling all day today and there's a 60% chance of thunderstorms this evening.
It will be warm and humid all weekend in the Midwest. Expect strong winds and a low over around 40 degrees.
That's pretty chilly for the summer. Will it rain on Saturday?
Unfortunately yes. It will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a high chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day.
There is a severe thunderstorm warning for some parts of the southeast.
Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding especially in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfall.
That certainly sounds like a jury Saturday.
It gets better on Sunday though the storm systems move east and the skies will clear up at night.
It will still be rather cool with highs in the low 50s. The west coast will be experiencing some unusually chilly weather.
But at least the sun will come out. I advise weekend travelers to be careful especially while driving.
Back to you Mary.
Thanks John and there you have it. Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right we're back so apparently they're not going to have great weather this weekend and they actually started with an interesting word.
And actually the commentator started with asking the weatherman John what does the forecast look like for our weekend?
Okay so the word here forecast is very very important because it describes this part of the newscast.
A forecast is basically a prediction or a description of the future weather situation.
That's right so we're talking about the weather forecast.
Now it's very interesting because we can also use that in business for example in budgets.
You can say what is the financial forecast of the company?
All right so you can't know what will happen but you can predict it and that's what a forecast is.
That's right so we're talking about the weather forecast and the weatherman said that well
there are some storms coming and it will be drizzling all day.
Okay so to drizzle is a verb and it's like the verb terrain except it's less bi-degree so
very light rain. Yeah it's kind of like if I spray you with with water,
not a spray can or something it's like drizzle. It's just little dots of water. It's not like you're getting wet.
You don't really have the normal heavy rain drops you just have a little bit of water coming down.
But it's annoying because do you bring your umbrella? Do you believe your umbrella?
So drizzling is a kind of rain that's very very light. That's right. All right so it's going to drizzle all day.
And the weatherman also said that we might have some thunder storms.
Okay so thunder storms are very different. Thunder storms are kind of storm where there is thunder.
So thunder is the loud noises when there's lightning.
lightning. Okay so lightning is like the flash that you get from the sky and thunder is the
hard sound that comes after the boom. Yeah so remember light lightning. Light is the light.
The comes down from the sky lightning and thunder storms are just those loud noises that the
lightning makes. So usually with thunder storms we have very heavy rain. That's right and that's why
it's different from drizzling which is very light. Okay now we're talking about water. We have
drizzled. We have thunder storm. Now what about a shower? Because the weatherman said there is a high
chance of showers. Well yes there's a high chance of showers. I take showers every day. Thank you very much.
But this is not the kind of shower we're talking about here. Is it? That's right.
Think about it though. It's similar. A shower when you wash yourself is water coming down on top of
you. Well in this case it's a rain shower. So it's rain that's happening. Okay so it's rain water
that's coming down very similar to the shower that you take in the morning. The difference though
is that a shower is a noun and terrain is a verb. So it will rain tomorrow or we expect showers
tomorrow. Both mean the same thing. All right very good. And well talking about showers and thunder storms
there's also another type of water that falls from the sky. This is called hail. Okay so hail
is difficult to describe because it's like ice. But it's not really. It's just usually hard.
Almost like marbles like hard balls of rain that come down. So it's not snow. That's right. It hurts.
When it hits you. Sometimes it's very big. Sometimes it's very small. But it's heavy, hard
things that come out of the clouds. Yeah so just think about it. It's very very similar to ice. It's
small pieces of ice coming down from the sky. So that's hail. But obviously very different from snow
because as we said it's hard. Snow is very soft. Yes. And well with this type of weather going on
on the weekend the commentator said wow that certainly sounds like a dreary Saturday. Okay dreary is a
great word to describe it. So as you can tell it's going to rain it's dreary is not a good thing.
It's not a happy thing. Okay. So something is dreary when it's not very exciting. It looks like
it'll be dull or sad or boring or dark. Now can you describe a person like this as well?
Yes he's a very dreary person. He's never optimistic. He's always down and yeah kind of quiet and
sad and down. Boring. Yeah. Okay so that's what it means. Something that's a boring, not very
exciting or very calm. But also dark. There's a dark element too because it's dreary. There's no
sunshine. There's no light. There's no optimism. So you can say it's a dreary day.
Yeah a dreary day today. No light. No sunshine. Okay very good. We've taken a look at a lot of
vocab there. Why don't we review what we've just learned and listened to the dialogue again?
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers? I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend
Mary. There's a storm system moving through the east coast. It will be drizzling all day today and
there's a 60% chance of thunderstorms this evening. It will be warm and humid all weekend
in the Midwest. Expect strong winds and a low around 40 degrees. That's pretty chilly for the summer.
Will it rain on Saturday? Unfortunately yes. It will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a
high chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day. There is a severe thunderstorm
warning for some parts of the southeast. Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding
especially in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfalls. That certainly sounds
like a dreary Saturday. It gets better on sunday though. The storm systems movies and the
skies will clear up at night. It will still be rather cool with highs in the low 50s. The
west coast will be experiencing some unusually chilly weather but at least the sun will come out.
I advise weekend travelers to be careful especially while driving. Back to you Mary.
Thanks John and there you have it. Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right we're back so now we're going to talk a little bit about some phrases that we've
chosen for you on fluency builder. Fluency builder. So when we're talking about forecasts,
remember that we're talking about things that aren't certain. We have to explain that there is
a possibility of rain or a possibility of sunshine and usually in the weather report they will
use percentages to describe how likely something is to happen. That's right the weatherman said
there is a 60% chance of thunderstorms. 60% is not very likely but it's also not unlikely.
It means that it might happen that it rains. That's right so as you said it's a way to measure
what the probabilities are because you imagine if the weatherman says it might rain tomorrow you're
like well maybe it really will or maybe it's very unlikely that it won't or we don't really know.
Exactly so for example if the weatherman says there's a 95% chance of rain tomorrow do you bring
your umbrella? Yes. What if he says there's a 5% chance of rain tomorrow? No. No. So you have to
think about the probability. 60% it's maybe half and half but 95% it's very likely to happen.
That's right and you also mentioned that there's a high chance of thunderstorms or maybe you
can say there's a low chance of hail. Right so he's basically saying he or she is basically saying
you know it's possible it's not likely it's not likely it's not just trying to help you out.
They can't say this will happen because they don't know. Okay so the word for probability here
the key word is chance. There is a good chance that it will rain so chance is probability.
Right so for example what's the chance it will rain tomorrow? Well there's a high chance.
Okay very good. Okay and now when we talk about the degrees or the how warm or cold it is
so we express it in Fahrenheit in some countries or in other countries in Centigrade. Here we
talk about 40 degrees Fahrenheit but the weatherman also says highs and lows there's a low of around
40 degrees what does he mean at low? This is a really important part of the forecast because you
need to know what you have to bring a coat tomorrow is it going to be hot or cold and so you
think about a day usually during the day at noon or one o'clock in the afternoon it's the hottest
but at night it's the coldest and so the low refers to the lowest temperature and the high refers
to the highest temperature. So for example in the fall maybe the highs are 60 degrees but the lows
are 40 so you should bring a coat. Okay means at night it'll be 40 during the day it'll be 60.
Okay so we're talking about the highs or the highest temperatures or the highest number that
will get and the lows is the lowest so the weatherman will commonly say tomorrow we'll experience
a high of 32 degrees and a low of 25. Right so it's very easy to understand that the temperature
during the day will be between these tuna right. Very good okay and for our last phrase the weatherman
also said that there is a severe thunderstorm warning for some parts of the southeast.
All right so Marko this is a really key phrase because it is it's telling people about potential danger
you know a thunderstorm can be very dangerous so you want to stay inside. So a severe thunderstorm
warning severe means very very serious. It's something you should pay attention to. That's right but
now the interesting thing is that we can change the noun in this case thunderstorm and we can talk
about for example a severe tornado warning. All right so if there's a severe tornado warning
then I really have to pay attention to the weather and be careful not to go outside or even a severe
flood warning. You need to know that the streets might become flooded and prepare. So they're saying
that there's a very high probability that this might happen so they're warning you to take precaution.
All right so pay attention to that last one and we're going to listen to today's dialogue one
more time we'll be back in a moment to talk a little bit more about the weather.
And those are today's top stories. Now let's go to John for the weather.
John what does the forecast look like for our weekend travelers? I'm afraid we're in for a rough weekend
there's a storm system moving through these coast. It will be drizzling all day today and there's a
60% chance of thunderstorms this evening. It will be warm and humid all weekend in the Midwest
expect strong winds and a low around 40 degrees. That's pretty chilly for the summer. We'll
it rain on Saturday. Unfortunately yes it will be clearly Saturday morning but there is a high
chance of showers and thunderstorms later in the day. There is a severe thunderstorm warning for
some parts of the southeast. Folks in those areas might see some hail and flooding especially
in areas that have been experiencing record high rainfalls. That certainly sounds like a jury
Saturday. It gets better on Sunday though the storm systems move east and the skies will clear up
at night. It will still be rather cool with highs in the low 50s. The west coast will be
experiencing some unusually chilly weather but at least the sun will come out. I advise we can
travelers to be careful especially while driving back to you Mary. Thanks John and there you have it.
Looks like it's a weekend to stay at home.
All right so talking about the weather it always seems like the weatherman is always wrong.
Always it's like the opposite of what should happen. That's right. But you know you can't blame
them because all they have is the computer and some sensors and they have to guess about the weather
and help people think around what to do. Have you ever experienced anything severe like a
hard thunderstorm or maybe a tornado or something like this? I have actually because I'm from Chicago
and in America the middle of the country is called the tornado belt. That means it's a piece of land
where tornadoes are very common. And so in the fall and in the spring we often have tornadoes and
I've been in a couple tornadoes myself. All right have you seen them? Yes. There is an amazing
to see. They're very scary. You're always running inside and locking yourself in the basement.
It's very important to protect yourself in a tornado because it's it's very dangerous around the
area of the tornado because the wind is so strong that trucks and cars and telephone poles and
big, big heavy objects can fly through the air and hurt people and that's how most of the damage
happens. Okay so this is interesting because a tornado is also considered a natural disaster.
Yes it is. But it is a it's a it's a weather phenomenon. Whereas earthquakes are a natural
disaster but it's not part of the weather. No yeah you're right it's not something that it
sweeps in and it leaves like a flood for example all of the rain will come down and it will create a
flood and earthquake is an actual disaster that's not weather related. That's right okay interesting
things. So maybe some of our listeners that live in a very cold area have experienced a heavy snowstorm
like a blizzard or maybe people in a tropical area have experienced a hurricane so let us know if you've
ever been in one of these weather related phenomena and also if you have any comments or questions
we're always at EnglishPod.com. We hope to see you guys there. All right bye.