Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have an upper
intermediate level lesson about something very technical. We're talking about marketing strategies here today.
That's right. Today we have an upper intermediate lesson at the office that is the category of this lesson and
we're basically talking about marketing, a marketing plan and a lot of technical words around this
part of business. All right. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in just a
moment to talk about what's going on.
Okay everyone let's begin. I call you here today to evaluate our marketing strategy during this
recession. I wanted to re-emphasize our corporate mission of aiming to give our customers the best
coffee and service in a clean and welcoming atmosphere. Several other shops have been reducing their
prices for the coffees and they are drawing in more customers. Why aren't we doing the same thing?
I know that recent sales have been slow but we are not going to reduce our prices to the level of our
competitors. We offer a superior product and our focus is on long-term growth rather than short-term
sales. If we lower our prices we run the risk of devaluing our product. Customers don't care about
coffee anymore. The only care about price. I disagree highly discerning customers know that our
coffee is far better than the coffee you buy at the other places. Our coffee beans are artisan roasted
and we use state-of-the-art equipment to brew our coffees. When you compare the coffee side by side,
our coffee wins the taste test every time. We have never sought to appeal to the mass market with
cheap coffee drinks and we will not do so now. That's true. We've certainly achieved top of
minor awareness when it comes to the best tasting brews and it's important to distinguish ourselves
from the competitors. I think the main question is how can we show our appreciation to our customers?
That's the main question I would like to discuss today. Money is tight for everyone these days.
So even our most loyal customers may be reconsidering the money they pay for their morning coffee.
Since this purity of our coffee beans is one of our core competencies, why don't we sell the
beans for people to brew coffee at home? That could definitely be a way we could expand our company,
but would we be undermining the essence of the company that way? Let's brainstorm some more ideas
and do some research. The customer always comes first and what the customer wants, the customer gets.
Maybe it's time we started selling coffee beans.
All right we're back. So a very interesting dialogue. I think this is something very common
that would go on in a meeting room when the marketing department is talking about prices and how
do we increase sales, etc. So I think we had a lot of difficult words or maybe words that we didn't
really understand well. So let's take a look at some of those in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So the first word on the top of our list today is recession. Anyone looking at
the news this year or last year probably knows what this word means, but let's talk about it anyway.
What is a recession? That's right. So everyone was talking about the recession and basically
it is a noun. All right. And it means that people don't have enough money like before. And so
consequently services or decrease people aren't buying as much. So there is a lack of commerce going
on in the country, a region, or a city, etc. All right. So basically in economics you have these
different cycles. It's not like the economy is always the same. And so sometimes when there's
not enough money we call it a recession and we can say, hey, I don't have much money to spend right
now. We are in a recession. So that's a very common way to use the term. That's right. So as you
say, it's an economic term and many consequences because of this lack of jobs, it's just as you
say, a cycle. And so apart from a recession that that's why they are brainstorming to see how they
increase sales despite the recession, they also talked about their customers and that their
customers are highly discerning. All right. So this word discerning comes from the verb to discerning.
And it's a really important one because it means to be able to tell the difference to
to understand the difference between two different things. Okay. So let's say we have two cups of soda.
I'm very good at tasting things. So I can discern the difference. I can discern the difference
between these two. I can say one is Coca-Cola and one is Pepsi. Okay. So two discern is to be able
to tell the difference or to notice the difference between many things. And so obviously you are a
discerning person. All right. Or you have discerning taste. This means that you're very good at telling
when something is high quality and when it's not high quality. Okay. And well talking about
customers who know what they want. And so they talked about their coffee beans and it's one of their
core competencies. Okay. So this is something you might actually hear in education as well as in
business. Something is your competency if you are able to do it. All right. So I am able to
write Chinese characters. It's one of my core competencies. Okay. So that's something that I'm
able to do. So I consider one of these central or important abilities. But you always talk about
competencies within the context of some area. So my language skills or in this case at a company
we're talking about making a coffee. One of the companies core competencies is making their coffee
beans. That's something they're good at. That's right. And core when we talk about core we
talk about the center. We talk about one of the most important things. That's right. Okay. And
well for the last word that we've prepared to you on language takeaway we talked about them
worrying that you know selling the coffee beans might undermine the essence of the company.
To undermine okay this is a really important verb and you'll hear this a lot actually in
TV shows and especially in dramas. So he's undermining my authority or he's undermining my
power. This means that someone is challenging it or someone is kind of taking it away from you.
Okay. So to undermine is to as you said challenge or try to take something from you. Very sneaky
and sneaky way sometimes. That's right. So for example if I'm the president of a country and
someone is trying to take that away from me someone is trying to be the president and trying to
take down my government he is trying to undermine my power. Okay. Very good. So for keywords there
on language takeaway now we're going to move on to fluency builder. We prepared a lot of nice and
very good phrases. Fluency builder. All right. So on fluency builder why don't we start up from the
beginning of the dialogue when they were talking about the prices of the coffee and that other shops
have reduced their prices and so they're drawing in more customers. All right. So the key here is
to draw in. This is a phrase. Most people will know the word to draw you know to make a design on a page.
But to draw in has a very special meaning it means to attract. Okay. So you want to attract more
customers. You want to bring them into the shop so you're trying to draw them in. So Marco what's
a good example of a of something that a company will do to try and draw in customers. For example
many of you maybe have seen in fast food restaurants when they have a promotion like you buy one
hamburger and you get another one for free. So that's maybe one of the strategies that they're trying
to do to draw in customers and maybe not make money but give people the opportunity to taste their
good food. That's right. All right. So the next phrase we've got here is a little bit different.
It's a talking about the kind of product that they have. They're talking about their coffee
beans and they say that they're roasted and that they use state of the art equipment to brew the
coffee. So this phrase state of the art. What does this mean? Okay. If something is state of the art.
Okay. We're usually talking about a machine and we're saying that it's the latest in technology.
It's very very new. It's highly advanced. It's a very technologically advanced machine.
So for example, the new iPhone 4 is a state of the art cell phone. That means it's the very
highest that technology has passed to offer. And obviously something that is state of the art
is not state of the art forever because technology changes and so maybe next year there will be
a new state of the art telephone. That's right. So if you notice the spelling as well we have
little hyphens between each word state of the art because we take it as a chunk all together. Right.
And following now we have another phrase that is used to talk about products. They say when you
compare the coffees we have side by side, our coffee wins against our competitors. So side by side.
Okay. The phrase there is side by side and they're talking about comparing coffees side by side.
So I think is this is pretty literal. It's basically saying you put two coffee mugs or coffee
cups together side by side and you have people taste and then you see which one they prefer.
That's right. So you can say this when you're making comparisons. When I look at them side by side,
I think I like the pink one more than the red one. So you are comparing you are literally putting
them next to each other to make a choice of which one is your preference. That's right.
Okay. Now moving on we have a very interesting phrase when they were talking about
the company and they've achieved top of mind awareness when it comes to best tasting bruise.
So this phrase top of mind awareness very closely related to marketing. What are we talking
about here? Well let's look at the individual words. We have top which is on top,
non-unbottom, mind which is your head or your thinking and awareness which is the way that you see
things. And so let's take a guess here and say that when I think of a category of product like
coffee for example, what is the first thing that comes into my mind? That's right. So it's actually
a very cool game that you can sometimes play with friends basically just say okay, when you think
of coffee what is the first brand that comes into your mind? Starbucks. Starbucks. So that for example,
shows that Starbucks has has put in you a certain top of mind awareness. You associate coffee with
Starbucks immediately. You don't say Costa coffee, you don't say coffee, we know any other brand,
right? No, yeah, no, definitely this is a way for you to really test what companies, what
corporations have the most effective marketing because obviously they're the ones who make you think
of this thing. That's right. Starbucks has tons of marketing campaigns. That's right. So it's actually
very interesting. So you can say top of mind or you can say top of mind awareness. You can say
Honda has great top of mind among their clients. Or Ferrari has great top of mind among luxury vehicles.
That's right. Okay. And now for the last phrase when we talked about money again,
this is a very nice colloquial way of saying that you don't have a lot of money or money is very
scarce right now. All right. So the phrase is money is tight. All right. So you know the word tight.
You can hold something tightly or this belt is tight. I'm gaining weight. But in this case,
money is tight. That's the phrase we take as a chunk. And it means like you say Marco,
I just don't have much money right now. So money is tight right now. Now it's interesting because
you can say it money is tight and then the subject. Money is tight for bill right now. Or you can say
bill is tight for money at the moment. So you can switch it up depending on where you put the
subject towards the end or in the beginning. That's right. So usually you hear the phrase money is tight
right now. Or money is really tight. Just kind of on its own. And it's a way to say,
yeah, I don't have much cash. That's right. Okay. So we've taken a look at a lot of words and phrases
here. Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
Okay, everyone. Let's begin. I call you here today to evaluate our marketing strategy during
this recession. I wanted to re-emphasize our corporate mission of aiming to give our customers the
best coffee and service in a clean and welcoming atmosphere. Several other shops have been
reducing their prices for the coffees and they are drawing in more customers. Why aren't we doing
the same thing? I know that recent sales have been slow, but we are not going to reduce our prices
to the level of our competitors. We offer a superior product and our focus is on long-term growth
rather than short-term sales. If we lower our prices, we run the risk of devaluing our product.
Customers don't care about coffee anymore. The only care about price. I disagree.
Highly discerning customers know that our coffee is far better than the coffee you buy the other
places. Our coffee beans are artisan roasted and we use state-of-the-art equipment to brew our coffees.
When you compare the coffees side by side, our coffee wins the taste test every time.
We have never sought to appeal to the mass market with cheap coffee drinks and we will not do so now.
That's true. We've certainly achieved top of minor awareness when it comes to the best tasting
brews and it's important to distinguish ourselves from the competitors. I think the main question
is how can we show our appreciation to our customers? That's the main question I would like to
discuss today. Money is tight for everyone these days. So even our most loyal customers
may be reconsidering the money they pay for their morning coffee. Since the superiority of our
coffee beans is one of our core competencies, why don't we sell the beans for people to brew coffee
at home? That could definitely be a way we could expand our company, but would we be undermining
the essence of the company that way? Let's brainstorm some more ideas and do some research.
The customer always comes first and what the customer wants the customer gets. Maybe it's time
we started selling coffee beans. All right so going back to top of minor awareness, let's
let's test what what brands are in your head. Okay so for example when you think of a luxury
sports car what do you think? Ferrari. Ferrari you mentioned it before. Or Lamborghini. Or Lamborghini,
but you said Ferrari first. When you think of a brand of cigarettes what do you think?
Camel. Camel. Okay this isn't American brand I don't think it's very it's found very commonly
in other places. They have it in Europe it's very popular. Oh really? Yep. Okay what about when
you think of computers what do you think? For some reason IBM. IBM even though you don't own an IBM.
I don't but I grew up around the IBM you know revolution. Okay see this is interesting so
actually it doesn't always work that way that because you have a brand in your mind it doesn't
necessarily mean that you will purchase it in the future if if you have the power to but at least
you are aware of the brand and you recognize it and the chances are that you will buy it. That's right
and you're going to be familiar with it when you read about it or you know when people talk about it.
For example I own a Mac computer you know Apple but when I think of computers just think of IBM because
we used to say remember IBM compatible. Nah that's right IBM compatible because before it was usually
just Mac everything was for Mac Mac or IBM and then all of a sudden it's PC. Right. Right.
Actually that's interesting though because if probably if I say what do you think of when you think of
what brand comes to mind when you think of MP3 players Apple I pot. I think I pot that's probably
one of the most famous ones but maybe if you ask somebody about 10 years ago when you think about
a music player what do you think about Sony the Sony Walkman right or the Sony Discman. That's right
had both. It was like I'd have a walkman was bright yellow. So this is really interesting this is the
way that you see more or less you can start to realize what brands are in your mind and maybe unconsciously
even you may not even be a smoker but maybe some sort of cigarette brand will be in your mind or
maybe you don't even really like sports cars but you will have a sports car brand in your mind.
I'm very curious to hear what you guys have to say because obviously the brands that we're aware of
are dependent on where we come from and the marketing campaigns in our home countries and also our age
you know I was a teenager when I had the Sony Discman so that made an impact on me button.
Let's throw that out to you guys. Let us know what you think of when we say luxury cars or MP3
players or computers or maybe even basic things like detergents like for example if you ask
somebody in the United States they might say tied but if you ask somebody in South America they might say
I don't know oh mole it's it's some type of brand so this is also very interesting to see
what your local brands have been doing. That's right so let us know what you're thinking. We're on
EnglishPod.com we hope to see you there. All right bye bye