Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a special dialogue for you all about this important
test that you need for going to graduate school.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about the famous or very scary g-met.
Alright so the g-met g-met is the test that students will take when they want to go to graduate
school for business management. So an MBA program.
That's right. And it's pretty much a standard test that you have to take as you say to
get into one of these programs. And so today we're going to talk a little bit about the
sections of the test and more or less how it's structured but not too much in depth.
That's right. So let's take a listen to our dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
I come seem to progress up the crey-lated no matter how hard I try.
And I have been here for two years already.
Well have you thought of getting an MBA? I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
And then BA-hae well my degree wasn't in business. The business schools won't be interested in me.
nonsense. The business schools measure your ability through a test called g-met.
G-met what does that stand for and what will the test contain?
Graduate management admission test. It contains three parts.
Analytical writing assessment. The quantitative section and the verbal section.
Not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered but also on the difficulty.
Okay this sounds a little tough. How am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you. You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions.
You can also use free or private computer software.
Going to church might help as well.
No matter what I do I'm going to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cap.
That's the spirit.
Alright we're back so now let's talk about some of the language we found on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright so there's a lot of great stuff here. The first one we've got is actually more about
a job than school. This is the career ladder.
That's right. Ash is complaining how he can't seem to make any progress in the career ladder.
So what is a career ladder?
We know what a ladder is. A ladder is a tool that you use to climb from a low place to a high
place. So for example if you want to go on the roof of your house you have to use a ladder.
A career ladder is it's like an analogy. When you start a career you start at the bottom
and you climb up up to the top. So going from the bottom to maybe the president of an organization.
So that's called the career ladder.
Yeah climbing from the bottom of a career area like for example being the male man at an office
building to being the president of that office. Okay so this is what Ash is complaining about
that it's hard or he can't really seem to go up the career ladder.
And so Mindy suggests that he should take the GMAT and go into graduate school. So as we said
the GMAT is a test that you take but what is it's stand for? What is GMAT?
GMAT stands for graduate management admission test. Okay so that's the test that you take when you
want to go to school. So you have to send your scores to the admissions office of the school you
want to go to and they will decide if they're high enough or not. Okay very good. So
everyone can go to graduate school and you have to take this test and pass it basically.
Well there's no pass fail but certain schools will say that a score is high enough and
other schools will say that a higher score is more important. So you can maybe go to a better
school if you have a better score. Okay and well Mindy went on to explain the three parts of this
test. The first one she said is analytical writing. All right so analytical writing is a very common
part of a test. For example I think the SAT also has analytical writing and basically you're asked
to read something and then write about it and analytical means that you have to really use your
mind to make an argument. It's not just read and repeat, read and repeat. Right so basically
comes from analyzing, you analyze what you read and then you write about it. That's what you have to think
and you have to make you have to understand what you read and then you have to write something that
makes sense. It's logical. Do you put your opinion in analytical writing? No. No so it's all based on
facts. Based on facts and logic and argument. Uh huh okay so you have this part of analytical writing
and then Mindy talks about the quantitative section of the test. So what is this? So the quantitative
section you think of the word quantify, quantity, quantitative has to do with numbers. Okay.
Basically so you have to be able to understand basic math, some algebra, some arithmetic,
some statistics for example. So quantitative sections on tests are the math sections.
Now from my understanding even though it is a math section it's not really like they give you a
problem in equation and you have to solve it. It's more like analysis right? They give you some
information and you have to use math to solve it. That's right so there are a number of different
parts. One of them is like what you say. It's kind of a, it's about logic while using algebra to solve
these problems. I think the other part of it has to do with statistics and being able to understand
trends, graphs, things like that. So this is the math section of the exam. So not only do you have to
be able to read, understand, and analyze what you're reading, you have to be able to be good at
math and then finally we have a verbal section. What is this all about? This is about your English
language and grammar skills and so the verbal section will test your vocabulary knowledge. Do you
understand what a big word is mean? Also will test your ability to read passages and analyze them?
So I guess this part is the most important, one of the most important parts for foreign students
who obviously don't speak English as their first language that this makes sure that you have
a good enough English level to be able to take a graduate program in English right?
Part of it's that there's a special test that will test your English abilities but this is
absolutely an important part for a non-native English speaker on the GMAT. You have to, it's hard
for English speakers who are born speaking English. In native English speakers, yeah. So it's something
that really you should do about your time to if you are a non-native English speaker because
there will be some very challenging words there. Okay so those are the three sections of the GMAT and
so to finish off language takeaway Ash said that he's going to take this test because he wants to
become a corporate fat cat. All right now this is an interesting term with this is not something we
talk about in the office. It's something we talk with friends. So a corporate fat cat you think
corporate corporation has has to do business. So basically we're talking about very important
businessmen but that cat's not a good thing right? No it's not really. You refer to a fat cat,
a corporate fat cat, is a businessman who you consider to have a lot of money but obviously
you make the analogy that they're fat because they have so much money and it's kind of a way of saying
that the businessmen are not the corporate fat cats are not the best people around. No you're basically
saying that these guys these men on top they're rich but they're kind of lazy and so you
he wants to be a corporate fat cat. He wants to be very rich and powerful and not have to work so
hard. Which obviously is not really the case always but this is a common term that as you said
you wouldn't really mention it in the office but it's more of a of a satirical way of speaking about
businessmen. All right so now it's a finish off language takeaway and move on to some phrases on
Fluency Builder. I come seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try and I have
been here for two years already. Well have you thought of getting an MBA? I heard it does wonders
and getting you to the top. An MBA hey well my degree wasn't in business. The business schools
weren't being trusted in me. nonsense. The business schools measure your ability through a test
called GMAT. GMAT what does that stand for and what will the test contain? Graduate management
admission test. It contains three parts analytical writing assessment the quantitative section
and the verbal section not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered but
also on the difficulty. Okay this sounds a little tough. How am I supposed to practice for this?
Up to you. You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions. You can also use
free or private computer software going to church might help as well. No matter what I do I'm going
to ace this test and go on to become a corporate fat cat. Uh that's the spirit.
All right in Fluency Builder today we have a number of really great phrases you can use the first.
The first one is from Mindy she says I heard it does wonders in getting you to the top.
Right. She suggests getting an MBA. I heard it does wonders to you know improve your career.
All right this is actually something that you might hear in a commercial. So it does wonders
means it really helps. It's really beneficial to you. Right. You might hear in a commercial for
example with a face cream. It does wonders you know to your skin. It really makes your skin look
good. So you by using this phrase it does wonders. You're basically saying it's fast,
defective. It's almost a miracle of how much it can improve your career or in this case of the
cream how it can improve your face. That's right. So the MBA does wonders. It's almost miraculous.
How positive and effective will have in your career. Mm-hmm. Exactly. Okay it does wonders.
And then Ash was asking that how he's supposed to study for this and Mindy answered well you know what?
It's up to you. You have a lot of options. So up to you. Up to you. This means it's your decision.
Okay. So we can use this in normal life you know you know you and I are out Marco and I say well
I don't know what to eat. What do you want to eat? Like I say or whatever it's up to you.
Up to me that means I get to decide what we eat and I want pizza. Okay very good.
So up to you is a way to say no you decide. Mm-hmm. It's up to you. It's your decision.
Okay and for our next phrase Ash was saying that he's going to study really hard and he's going to
Ace the test. All right. Now to Ace a test this is a this is a phrase that we use. We can use it
in high school and college as well not just MBA programs and to Ace a test means to do perfectly on it.
Okay. Okay that means to get an A or even 100%. So it's important to remember that we have this
grading system A, B, C, D, F. Mm-hmm. A is the top. All right. And so you Ace it means you don't make any
mistakes and remember that A for Ace. Okay. So you can even use it if it's not really a test like
a job interview you say I ace that job interview. I ace it and in sports oftentimes we we see
this tennis it's a sports analogy tennis when someone serves a ball and the other player is
can't even hit the ball back it's an Ace you get a point. That's right. So it's a Ace for
that or even good sports athletes do call them Ace's. Ace is so after a job interview I can say
you know wow Marco I really ace that interview. I ace it. Okay and Mindy says well you know what
that's really good that's the spirit. That's the spirit. Now this is something you say to someone
when you like their attitude. Okay. So if I say oh man I did really bad this is stupid I don't want to
study you say well that's the bad attitude. Right. But if I say you know what I'm going to do awesome
this is great I'm so I'm going to kill this I'm going to ace it. No you can say that's the spirit.
That's the spirit that means good attitude that's the right way to think about this. So you're
kind of even encouraging that person you're saying you know what I really like your attitude that's
the good way of thinking. Exactly so if you want to if you want to push someone and say you know
good for you this is a good way to approach it you say that's the spirit. Okay awesome so this is
all the language that we have for fluency builder when we take a break and we'll be right back.
I come seem to progress up the career ladder no matter how hard I try and I have been here for
two years already. Well have you thought of getting an MBA? I heard it does wonders and getting
you to the top. An MBA hey well my degree wasn't in business the business schools won't be
interested in me. No sense the business schools measure your ability through a test called GMAT.
GMAT what does that stand for and what will the test contain? Graduate management admission test.
It contains three parts analytical writing assessment the quantitative section and the verbal
section not only does the test score you on the number of questions answered but also on the difficulty.
Okay this sounds a little tough how am I supposed to practice for this?
How to you? You could have a one-on-one session with a tutor or group sessions. You can also use
free or private computer software going to church might help as well. No matter what I do I'm going
to assist and go on to become a corporate fat cat. Uh that's the spirit.
All right we're back so now talking about the GMAT and then MBA this seems to be a very popular
topic nowadays everyone wants to get obviously a good education and go to graduate school which means
getting your master's degree or your doctoral degree. What do you think about the GMAT and the
MBA is it is it a miracle worker like this girl says she does wow it does wonders for your career
that's really the case? I don't know you know maybe if you asked me five years ago I would say yes
but I really believe that it depends on the person. Nothing is a miracle cure. I do think that if you
if you really have a good attitude and you work hard you'll get a lot out of it but if you think it's
going to get you a job you're wrong because you you have to get yourself a job so I think it depends
on the person. Now obviously also it depends on the country right now how popular or how important
is it for people to have a let's say an MBA to get ahead and business in the United States?
I'd say it's pretty important you don't have to have an MBA I mean you can start your own
business and if you're successful you'll probably start more businesses but getting an MBA is also
a very good opportunity to network to meet people to find out more about the industry that you want
to start out in and so I think in that sense it's pretty important because it's a way to start making
contacts. Yeah it you definitely meet a lot of people with work experience from different backgrounds
international students so it's obviously a great thing but obviously to be able to do one of these
programs like a get an MBA you have to take these tests which I understand are very very difficult.
They are very difficult and it can be very expensive I mean graduate school itself is $100,200
and then to prepare for the tests you could spend another $1,000 just getting classes or tutoring.
So I do think that it can be a lot of money up front but there are places that you can go to the
study and you could even study on your own using your computer so yeah exactly I think this is a
very interesting topic because in many different cultures in many different places education or for
example higher learning like getting an MBA has different levels of importance like in Europe
a lot of Europeans maybe don't really even pay too much attention to getting an MBA whereas in
other countries they might really emphasize like you have to have an MBA it's really good it's going
to be good for your career so it's very interesting to see how in different places they handle it.
It is interesting and I'm actually very curious to hear from our users have you ever thought about
getting an MBA or MBA's important to do business in your country but let us know our website is
all right you guys are bye bye