Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and it's the start of a very new year so we have some interesting vocabulary
for you today about the new year.
That's right so we are starting a new year. Why don't we just jump right into this dialogue?
Let's see what's going on and we'll be back in a bit.
It's almost midnight. We're about to start a brand new year.
I know it's so exciting. A new year is always like a clean slate.
A fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives and goals.
Do you have a new year's resolution?
I was thinking about it but I'm never able to keep my new year's resolutions.
Last year for example I joined a gym and only went twice.
Yeah I know what you mean. That's why this year I am keeping things more simple.
Maybe like getting together with friends I haven't seen in a long time or doing some volunteering work.
That seems reasonable. We should get together and watch the ball drop in time squared.
Sure. As long as you don't try to kiss me at midnight.
Well we can't break tradition. It's bad luck.
Alright so we prepared a couple of different words for you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright the first, the first where we have actually a phrase.
We have this phrase brand new. Something is a brand new thing.
That's right. We said that we are starting a brand new year.
And that's just another way of saying completely new.
So I want a brand new bicycle. I mean I want a new bicycle from the store.
Not one from the garage.
That's right. So it's something completely new never been used.
So we're starting a brand new year and we're saying it's exciting because it's a great opportunity
like having a clean slate.
So a clean slate. Now this is an interesting phrase because you may not know what a slate is.
But basically it means that you start from the very beginning.
So there's no history. There's no...
Nothing that you have to worry about. You start completely new. That's a clean slate.
That's right. So just imagine you're in class and you have the whiteboard or the chalkboard.
And you just erase everything and then you start again.
That's kind of what it means to have a clean slate. A new start.
Exactly. And so we have a clean slate. We need to talk about what we will do with the clean slate.
And so one person asks the other, do you have any new year's resolutions?
That's right. So this is one of the most popular things during the new years.
Is people make a new year's resolution.
So a resolution is something that you have decided you will do.
I have many resolutions. I will learn to play the piano this year.
So in the new year I will do this thing.
That's right. So it's basically like a promise. Something that you promise yourself
that you will do in the new year. So as you say, maybe start playing the piano.
That's right. So we call that a resolution or if we want to be specific, we call it a new year's resolution.
Now at the very end of the dialogue we heard another phrase. This is quite strange.
They want to kiss at midnight. And the one person says, well, we can't break tradition.
That's right. To break a tradition or to break tradition. And that basically means to
not do something that we usually do. All right. So you can follow tradition. That means that you do the same
thing maybe every year. But if you break tradition, that means you don't do what you are expected to do.
Remember that verb is to break tradition. That's right. All right. So let's review this
vocablet's listen to the dialogue again.
It's almost midnight. We're about to start a brand new year. I know. It's so exciting. A new year is
always like a clean slate. A fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives and goals. Do you
have a new year's resolution? I was thinking about it, but I'm never able to keep my
years resolutions. Last year, for example, I joined a gym and only went twice. Yeah, I know what you mean.
That's why this year I am keeping things more simple. Maybe like getting together with friends I haven't
seen in a long time or doing some volunteering work. That seems reasonable. We should get together
and watch the ball drop in time squared. Sure, as long as you don't try to kiss me at midnight.
What we can't break tradition, it's bad luck. All right. So let's take a look at those phrases now
on fluency builder. Fluency builder. So there's a phrase in here that I use all the time. We heard
about this resolution to go to the gym more often. And the person said, you know, I never really
go to the gym. And the other said, you know, I know what you mean. Yeah, that's right. She says,
yeah, I know what you mean. And so basically we use this when you agree with the person you understand
what they are saying. Yeah, it's almost like saying I had the same experience. So maybe I also
belong to a gym and I never go to that gym. Just like you. I mean, I know what you mean. I have the
same problem. That's right. So you can just agree with someone completely agree with someone
by saying, yeah, I know what you mean or I know what you mean. I know what you mean. All right. So
well, this year we want to keep things a little bit more simple and we said, well, maybe like getting
together with friends I haven't seen in a long time. All right. So think about this to get together
with friends, lots of words there. But you can see friends, but to get together means to be social
with, to hang out with, to do things together. But it's not very specific. It's a nice way to say just
to be with your friends. That's right. So maybe you are going with your friends out, maybe shopping,
maybe to the movies. So you say, yeah, I'm going to get together with my friends later on this afternoon.
All right. So we can get together with friends as a resolution. That's something we want to do in the
near future. But for now, we're going to get together and watch the ball drop in time square. That's
the new year's plan. That's right. So it made, it makes him strange. It's not actually a
phrasal verb or a colloquial phrase. There is actually a ball that goes down as the countdown begins
to midnight. And once it completely disappears, then you know, you celebrate the new year. So you
actually see this big round of ball coming down in time square. Yeah. It's a way to count down
to the new year. So people often say 10, 9, 8, 7 to the countdown and the ball will drop. And that
means it's the new year. So this is something that we refer to. It's new we talk about when we want
to discuss the new year. So we'll watch the ball drop together. It's an event. That's right.
Okay. So a lot of great stuff there. When we listen to the dialogue one last time.
It's almost midnight. We're about to start a brand new year. I know. It's so exciting. A new year
is always like a clean slate. A fresh start to accomplish any dreams, objectives and goals. Do you
have a new year's resolution? I was thinking about it, but I'm never able to keep my new
years resolutions. Last year, for example, I joined a gym and only went twice. Yeah, I know what you mean.
That's why this year, I am keeping things more simple. Maybe like getting together with friends
I haven't seen in a long time or doing some volunteering work. That seems reasonable. We should
get together and watch the ball drop in time squared. Sure. As long as you don't try to kiss me
at midnight. Well, we can't break tradition. It's bad luck.
All right. So talking about new years, everyone makes new years resolutions and people get together
to watch the ball drop in time squared. Now this is more of an American thing. Do you have
you ever experience anything different from new years? Some other type of tradition because also
here they kiss at midnight. That's right. Well, that's a pretty standard American tradition.
People will get together and they'll have the TV on. They'll have a party or they'll be with friends.
Mm-hmm. And they will maybe watch some fireworks or watch the TV as the ball drop. So I've
done both. I've gone out because sometimes you go outside. It's very cold, but you go to a bridge,
or a park, or somewhere public, or the city government, or the state, will have some kind of special
fireworks display. So then everyone will watch the fireworks or watch a big TV screen and then when
it's midnight, when it's the new year, then everyone will kiss. So everyone will kiss. Maybe
I mean, is it like just between couples or whoever is available? You kiss whoever's there.
Sometimes it's whoever is available. That's happened to me. Where you turn around and you say,
oh, hi, I don't know you. So the tradition is you have to kiss someone at midnight.
So this is for good luck. Yes. For good luck in the new year. Yes. So if you don't kiss someone,
then you're kind of breaking the tradition. I assat. And it's unlucky. And interesting way
of celebrating years. This is as we said in the United States, watching the ball drop, kissing someone
at midnight. So we are really curious to know how you celebrate your new years in your country,
because maybe you have similar traditions or very different things. That's right. I know some places
like Italy even have special foods you are supposed to eat to bring wealth and prosperity in the
new year. So let us know our website is EnglishPod.com. All right, we'll see you guys there. Bye.