Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod. My name is Margo.
My name is Katherine and we're here talking about some special foods today.
That's right today. We're going to talk about sea food. So everything that comes from the sea that we eat.
That's right. So we're in a restaurant and we're going to hear about the different options this restaurant offers.
Let's take a listen to the dialogue.
This is such a nice restaurant. I feel so classy. Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but they serve the best seafood in town.
May I take your order?
Yes, I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and I'll also have the lobster.
Excellent, choice sir. And for you, madam?
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood clatter.
Very good, madam.
Let's see if the platter sounds good. Excuse me, what does the platter have?
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, muscles, calamari and filet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great. Can't sit a lobster and give me one of the same please.
Very well sir. Anything to drink?
Can we get a bottle of your house white wine please?
Superb choice. I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right, we're back so today we're going to take a look at a lot of vocabes.
So we're going to have two parts of language takeaway and let's start with the first one.
Language takeaway.
Now in language takeaway part one today, we have a number of really important and useful
adjectives. The first one is classy. That's right, so we're going to a nice restaurant and so
you feel like you're in a classy place. Now a classy place is a nice place.
You might be expected to dress nicely. It might be a little bit fancy.
Mm-hmm, exactly. So classy is kind of a synonym of fancy or luxurious.
Right, so if you're going on a date with someone, it might be a good idea to go to a classy restaurant.
That's right. But usually if a restaurant is classy, it also means that it's a little bit
pricey. Okay, so something that is pricey is expensive and seafood is famous in America for being
very pricey. That's right. So something that is pricey means that it's a little bit expensive.
Now going to the food that we're going to get today, we had a couple of different ways of describing
how the food was prepared. So for example, the first one is marinated grilled shrimp.
All right, now something that is marinated is covered in a sauce or a liquid before it's cooked.
All right, so you can have maybe a regular steak, but you can also have a marinated steak,
which would be marinated in some kind of flavor like garlic or yogurt. That's right. So usually
you leave it in maybe some sauce, like garlic sauce for a couple of hours or a couple of minutes
before you cook it. Now when we cook it, there are different ways of cooking things. In this
case, we're having grilled shrimp. All right, now grilled is different from fried fried. We do in a
pan with some oil, but a grill. Usually there's no pan, no oil. There's just a grill. So grilled grilled,
grill is the tool that we use. Grilled food tends to be quite healthy. There's very little oil,
it's a bit more dry. And oftentimes we do grilling outside because there's lots of smoke. That's
right because usually you have like maybe a barbecue and you have some charcoal in there or some
wood, that's what you used to cook the food with. Yeah, and grilled food is very easy to notice,
because there are usually black lines on top and bottom. That's from the grill. That's right.
So we ordered marinated grilled shrimp for starters. So what is a starter? Well, think about the
words, starter, start. Now a starter is something you eat at the start of your meal at the
beginning. You eat it before you eat the main course. All right. So it's also known as an appetizer.
That's right. Starters and appetizers are the same thing. And these are small things you eat before
you start to eat your main meal. So they're not very filling. Okay. So yeah, it'll be something small,
like a soup or maybe like in this case some marinated grilled shrimp. Yes. All right. So great
vocab there when we review that part and we'll be back in a bit.
This is such a nice restaurant. I feel so classy. Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but they serve the
best seafood in town. May I take your order? Um, yes. I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for
starters, and I'll also have the lobster. Excellent, choisers. And for you, madam? I would like the
baked oysters and the seafood platter. Very good, madam. Let's see if the platter sounds good.
Excuse me. What does the platter have? It's a great combination of clams, scallops,
mussels, calamari, and filet of salmon and tuna. It comes with a side of butter sauce and French
fries. That sounds great. Can't sit a lobster and give me one of the same please. Very well, sir.
Anything to drink? Can we get a bottle of your house white wine, please? Superb choice. I will be
back shortly with the wine. All right. So now let's take a look at all the exquisite types of
seafood that we have here on language takeaway part two. All right. Now the first thing we have in
language takeaway part two is a very distinctive animal from the ocean. It's bright red and it has two
claws. Right. We're talking about a lobster. Now, lobsters, you don't find everywhere. In fact,
there are some parts of America where they're very famous for their lobster like Maine. Now these
are animals that are hard on the outside and soft and white on the inside and they're quite
difficult to eat. That's right. So they look kind of like crabs because they also have the claws
and everything but they're a lot longer, right? That's right. A crab is round and a lobster is long
and lobsters are also famous for one part for their tails. Right. The tails are full of meat.
They're very delicate, very delicious. Okay. So we're having some lobster and we also ordered some baked
oysters. Now oysters are another kind of thing that comes from the ocean. They come in a shell.
All right. And you might hear about oysters because some people some restaurants like to have an oyster
bar where they serve raw oysters over ice. That's right. So they look like big rocks basically and
when you open them inside you have meat. And actually I think you get pearls from oysters, right?
That's right. So these two are special. They have a nice relationship. The pearl forms inside
grows inside of the oyster. Very good. So now we've taken a look at some oysters and talking about
these things that have shells. We also have clams. Now while oysters are big and sometimes quite shiny,
clams are smaller, usually white or gray and they have lines on them and their shells that you
open up and you eat the meat from inside. Right. So I guess if you've ever been on the beach
and you're collecting little sea shells, usually those are kind of like clams. That's right. They're
quite small. They can be about the size of an American quarter, 25 cents. Okay. So now in this seafood
platter that we're ordering, we have clams. We have scallops. Ooh scallops are one of my favorite
kinds of seafood. They're quite soft and chewy and they're usually white. Okay. And then we have some
mussels also. Now mussels are much different looking. They're also in shells, but they're long
and the shells are black. That's right. So clams are kind of a small and round. The oysters are
pretty big and look like rocks. Mussels on the other hand are long and black and when you open them
inside, they're shiny also. They're orange on the inside are yellow and so they're quite,
interesting looking. But they're also very famous for the French or Belgian rather, the Belgian
dish, mulled fruit, which is a nice specialty. All right. And lastly, we are also having some
calamari in this seafood platter. Oh, this is one another one of my favorites. Now calamari is
kind of food, but the animal is the squid. Okay. So why is it called calamari? Well calamari,
I believe, comes from the Italian word calamaro. Calamari means that it's squid that's been cooked
so that people can eat it. Okay. So basically calamari and squid are the same thing. They are the same
animal, but calamari means that it's prepared to eat. Yes, and usually it's fried. So when
squid is fried, it becomes hard. And chewy. And that's what calamari tastes like. It's quite chewy.
All right. Great stuff. So why don't we review everything one last time with this exquisite lesson?
This is such a nice restaurant. I feel so classy. Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but they
serve the best seafood in town. May I take your order? Yes, I would like some marinated grilled shrimp
for starters, and I'll also have the lobster. Excellent, choisers. And for you, madam? I would like
to bake oysters and the seafood platter. Very good, madam. Let's see if the platter sounds good.
Excuse me, what does the platter have? It's a great combination of clams, scallops, muscles,
calamari, and filet of salmon and tuna. It comes with a sight of butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great. Can't sit a lobster and give me one of the same please. Very well, sir.
Anything to drink? Can we get a bottle of your house white wine, please?
Superb choice. I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right. So seafood we said usually has the connotation of being a little bit pricey. Why do you think that is?
I think it's pricey because the best seafood doesn't come from seafood farms. It comes from
people who go and boats and they collect the seafood in nets. And also, there are fewer and fewer places
in America where you can find this kind of food because some places have experienced overfishing
too many people are trying to fish. And also, some places just don't have the right climate for certain
them. Right. So for example, in the United States, you do have, well, the whole country is covered in
the west coast by the Pacific Ocean, the east coast. You have the Atlantic. So obviously, you do have
some coast, but if you're in the middle of the United States, it's partly hard to get seafoods
away imagine. It's very expensive. It can be very, very expensive. So oftentimes, we get
lake food. It's different kind of fish. We don't have lobster. But you'll find that in the the
west, you get very good salmon because Alaska in the northwest is very famous for salmon from the Pacific.
And in the east, it's very famous for lobster and crab which are delicious. Now, even though you have
its famous for lobster and crab, it's still relatively expensive compared to other dishes. Like,
for example, I think a lobster, how much would a lobster dinner cost? A lobster dinner cost,
$100, $150. Right. And you're getting almost the same amount of meat as maybe having a steak
that would be $20. Yeah, less meat. But we have more cows than we have lobster. And also,
lobsters are famous for being pretty, pretty expensive. It's a very fancy meal to have lobster.
So it's very interesting and actually some countries for, so it's very interesting, but some
countries seafood is very, very inexpensive. Some communities are some countries or communities
that fish or have, for example, shrimp farms. It's very inexpensive, so it's such a treat to be able
to go there and have seafood all you want and not have to spend $300 on a meal. It is indeed.
And it's, it's really nice to be able to get these big prawns, these big shrimp or lobster,
and eat them without worrying about the price. But I'm curious in your country, do you have seafood?
And if so, what kinds? It's cheap, is it expensive? Is it pricey? Let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right, we'll see you guys there.