Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today, Marco, we're talking about some very special places, right?
That's right. Today, we're going to talk about the famous list of the seven wonders of the world.
So you've probably heard about this before. We're not going to tell you what this means.
Quite yet. Take a listen to today's dialogue. And when we come back, we'll talk a little bit more about what these
wonders are and where they are.
Have you seen this news article? Apparently an organization has made a list to name the new seven
wonders of the world and people could vote for them online. Wow, that's really interesting. So who would?
Well, the Great Wall of China, the Taj Mahal in India. I've been there. It really is an amazing work of
architecture and art. The entire complex is made of white marble and in the interior of the tomb,
the walls are covered with gyms and emeralds. Cool. Also amongst the winners is Petra in Jordan,
Machu Picchu in Peru, and the pyramid in Chichini, Sa and Mexico. Wait a minute. It also says that
the Christ Redeemer statue in Brazil and the Colosseum in Rome are one of us. I would love to go to Italy
and see the Colosseum standing in the middle like a gladiator. Well, let's see if we can find some
cheaper fair and we can go towards the end of the year. Good idea. All right, we're back. So let's
talk about these very interesting places all over the world. Now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So the set phrase for this marco is the seven wonders of the world. Now the key
here is the word wonder. What is a wonder? Right. A wonder is something very amazing, incredible.
It's something that's beyond your imagination almost. That's right. You can't even imagine how
man or how someone created it. And so wonderful is a similar word. That's an adjective. Something
that's just great. Fantastic is wonderful. A wonder is something very, very special. And here,
we have seven of them. That's right. So it's a list basically that you can, you can see even
online about these wonders all over the world and they're so special because they are amazing
works of art and architecture. And starting off with one of the most famous ones is in China.
It's the great wall of China. I think what's special about this, I've heard is that when
astronauts are in space, it's so long and so distinct. They can actually see the great wall.
Yeah, that's what I've heard as well. It's a very long wall, thousands of kilometers long.
That's right. And it goes east to west all across the northern border of China. That's right.
So it's a very big wall. And what's interesting about it is that it was built such a long time
ago and that the techniques used to make it were very special. That's right. And sometimes you might
hear us talk about the great wall instead of the great wall of China. And so that's just a hint.
It's it's easy to say great wall. You can say them both ways though. Exactly. Now moving west
towards India, we have another very amazing work of architecture. It's called the Taj Mahal.
Now the Taj Mahal is in North India and a city called Agra. And it's very special because it's
massive. It's very big. And it's all white marble. That's right. And it's interesting because
the this place, the Taj Mahal, is not really a temple. It was actually a tomb. All right. Now that's
an interesting word to look at. A tomb is a place where we bury someone. You know, after someone
dies, maybe if you have a lot of money or very rich, you want to put that body in a very special
sacred place. And that's called a tomb. That's right. So this is actually what the Taj Mahal is.
Now we saw in the dialogue that the entire complex of the Taj Mahal is made of white marble.
So when we talk about the entire complex, what do we mean? Well, complex here's a now. You might have
heard it in other situations where it's an adjective. It means something different. But here
complex means many buildings together. Right. So you can say the Taj Mahal is one building.
But the Taj Mahal complex maybe has four or five buildings together. So aside temple and
a gatehouse. And so we say a complex is a grouping of buildings. That's right. Very good. So now let's
move on. Let's take a look at language takeaway part two. And let's continue talking about these
wonders of the world. Now the top of our list in language takeaway part two is actually a place
I would love to go to. I've never been there. It's in Jordan, which is a country in the Middle East.
And it's called Petra Petra. Petra. That's right. This is actually a city. But it's also known as
the lost city of Petra. Right. That's right. And what's unique about this city is that the city is
built. It's carved out of stone in this cliff. So it's not just pieces of stone put together.
It's actually inside the rocks. Exactly. So it's very famous. You've probably seen it in movies like
Indiana Jones. There's a big part of the scenes that go on inside Petra. Mm-hmm. Very special
place. And again very unique. Now the next site is actually very far away in South America. And
again it's ancient and very intricate. It's called Machu Picchu. That's right. So this is in one of those
very old cities that are actually in ruins now. And the interesting thing about it is that it's very
high up in like a little mountain. And those mountains there. Those are the Andes. Right. That's right.
So Machu Picchu also a very famous place. Many visitors from all over the world go there as well.
And another main attraction around the world are the pyramids. So we have some pyramids in Egypt.
I think those are the most well known ones. That's right. The pyramids in Egypt like the
pyramid of Giza are very big structures. I mean they're huge and they were built thousands of
years ago. But they're still here because they were built so well. But they're also very famous
pyramids like the one we heard about today in the dialogue in Mexico. That's right. It's a little
bit different though because the pyramids as we most of us know them they're very smooth on the
sides you would say. Yeah you can't climb on them really. Right. Well this one in Mexico actually
has kind of like steps. So it's a different type of pyramid but the shape is very similar.
All right so the pyramids here are in a place called Chichinita. You might have heard of that.
And we have another place though which is also in South America in the city of Rio de Janeiro.
Now this one is actually a statue right? That's right. It's called the Christ Redeemer.
It's a very big statue. Very famous. You've seen it maybe in pictures. It's a statue of Jesus
with his arms open. Now the word Redeemer. Okay Redeemer is a person. Someone who does something
who redeems. What does it mean to be a Redeemer? Well a Redeemer is a person that saves
for example. So if you redeem yourself you're redeem yourself of your sins maybe.
Well yeah you're taking value back. Right. And so in the case of Jesus he is taking away the sins
of the world and he's redeeming you know that's why his arms are out. He's redeeming all people.
And that's the idea I think behind the Christ Redeemer. The verb redeemed like you can use it in
everyday life if you take a coupon and you redeem it. That means you yeah you collect the value.
You collect the value right? So you can use it actually this word in everyday life.
And moving on now towards Europe we have the famous Coliseum.
Now I love this one. I've actually been there and I know you have two recently. But this is a circular
like a round stadium. So it's a place where you play sports. Well you did. It's from you know thousands
of years ago the Roman Empire. And it's in very good shape I would say you can still see it.
Yeah so it's generally called the Coliseum. Although a Coliseum as we know it now can also be
the same thing right. A structure where sports or activities are played. Basically yeah
Coliseum is an old stadium. But the Coliseum like you said is definitely the Coliseum in Rome.
That's right. And we've probably seen movies of ancient Rome where sports or activities
were taken place specifically gladiator fights. So that's where they're gladiator. Yeah that's right.
So gladiator is actually a person. And gladiator was a man who thousands of years ago during the
Roman Empire would fight maybe other men or animals. And he had to fight to stay alive.
So that was his profession basically to be a gladiator. So now as you are a boxer back then you
were a gladiator. Yeah and there actually have some very famous movies about gladiators like the
movie Gladiator with Russell Crow. So it's a pretty common word these days. That's right.
Okay so let's take a break. Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Have you seen this news article? Apparently an organization has made a list to name the new
seven wonders of the world and people could vote for them online. Wow that's really interesting.
So who would? Well the Great Wall of China, the Taj Mahal in India. I've been there.
It really isn't amazing work of architecture and art. The entire complex is made of white marble
and in the interior of the tomb the walls are covered with gyms and emeralds. Cool.
Also amongst the winners as Petra and Jordan, Machu Picchu and Peru and the pyramid in
Chicinitza and Mexico. Wait a minute. It also says that the Christ Redeemer statue in Brazil
and the Colosseum in Rome were one of us. I would love to go to Italy and see the Colosseum.
Stay in the middle like a gladiator. Well let's see if we can find some cheaper fair and we can go
towards the end of the year. Good idea.
Alright so this list that we gave you are actually the new seven wonders of the world. It was voted
online. People all over the world that of different candidates or different places that were
considered to be the new seven wonders of the world. Among those like some of them that didn't
win for example was Anchor Wat and Cambodia. Yeah I never understood that you know I think
Angor Wat is such an amazing place and so big and it was the heart of this old civilization.
Right. And instead we have other things like a statue. Yeah I don't know what it is
but actually the statue of Liberty of the United States was also considered as a candidate for
a number of the world. Well that's right. America doesn't have any wonders.
You have natural wonders I think. The Grand Canyon is considered I think one of the
natural wonders. Yes I think Niagara Falls also. Yeah. But that's an interesting point
though Marko we've got the great wonders of the world and we've got the natural wonders. What's
the difference? Well natural a natural wonder of the world means that it's their naturally. It's
not man-made. All of these things that we see here they somebody had to make them whereas for
example the Grand Canyon or Niagara Falls they are naturally it's by nature. All right so man-made
versus natural or made by nature. Right. So it's very interesting because you have like we said natural
seven wonders of the world you have these the new ones you have the ancient world wonders which
like none of them are existing or I'm probably the Pablo. Yeah the gardens. Yeah the hangar
gardens of Babylon and the Colossus road. Yeah those ones are very cool but not like you said.
You can't see them around anymore. So but maybe some of you actually maybe your countries were
considered to host one of these wonders or maybe you voted for some of them. Yeah let us know
what is a wonder where you come from. Doesn't have to be on this list it can be something you think
is wonderful. Let us know our website is englishpod.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.