Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about a kind of education that is quite unique
actually a little bit different from the kind of education that most people get.
That's right. So we normally go to school to learn, but I'm this occasion we're going to talk
about a different way of obtaining your education. We're talking about home schooling someone.
Let's check this word out in today's vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
All right. So the word is home school to home school someone. It's like it's a verb.
And what does it mean if you're home school? Well you think about the word school home
it means that you study at home, but you don't go to school every day. Instead you have a parent
or maybe a friend of a parent who comes to your house to teach you every day.
So it's basically like having a tutor for but not to help you with school, but it to actually
teach you everything that you learn at school. That's right. And some people are home
schooled with their siblings, so brothers and sisters, other people are home schooled alone.
I will talk about some of these things in a moment, but let's take a listen to our dialogue.
I think we should home school our children, but we decided to have kids.
What? Why? Well our home school's here are not very good and prime schools are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some home schooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what? I think that by doing something like that we would be isolating our children from social
interaction. Well first of all, I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school
and more relaxed and fun may. I also think that having one of one classes much better since you
can focus more on his or her strengths or weaknesses. I think neither your parents or mine
would agree to such an idea. I'll bring it up over Sunday, brooch. Good luck with that.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of that language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So as we mentioned in the introduction to today's podcast,
a home schooling is one of many different educational options. The most common ones are in the
beginning of the dialogue public and private school. Right, so in most places you will have
public schools where basically the education is paid for by the government. Yeah, that's right.
So public schools are schools that are available to all students. You don't have to pay to attend
them. These are, this is of course in America and Britain, the system is a bit different.
But in America, you have the public schools which most kids go to. Of course, if your parents
don't want you to study in public school, there's another option that's called private school.
That's right. So a private school as the name says, it's not really private, but what happens is that
it's not available free for everyone. You have to actually pay to go to the school. That's right.
The school has a tuition, kind of like a private college or university. So you have to pay every semester
or every year. And usually these schools also have applications standards. So they interview you,
they interview your parents. So there's a lot of different things you have to do to attend
these schools. That's right. So they're a bit more exclusive. That's right. Now, so these are basically
some three options. You have home schooling, public schools, private schools. And well, the two
parents are kind of discussing the options of why it would be maybe not a good idea to home school
one of the kids. And she says that it would be isolating our children from social interaction.
All right. So let's take a look at the word to isolate this subverb. And I like to think of
island isolate kind of similar in a way. Basically to isolate from is to keep away from. So if you're
student or your child is being homeschooled, he or she might be isolated from other students. They're
not near or with other students. That's right. So to isolate means to keep away from or to keep
separately. So like you said, maybe if you're on an island, you are isolated from the rest of the
world. That's right. Or if I live in the country far away from the city, I feel isolated from other
people. So she's saying that the kid might be isolated from social interaction. All right. Now,
social interaction. This is a two word phrase. We usually take it as a phrase. This basically means
talking to or playing with other people. Other kids. Right. So I guess in this case, it's a
it's personal or physical social interaction because nowadays you have social interaction via the
internet. That's right. But in the case of a student going to school, it would be of course playing on
the playgrounds, attending class. But social interaction means talking to or being with other people.
That's right. Well, and the other parent argued that there are many advantages and specifically
you said that having a one on one class is better for the kids. All right. So this word one on one
refers to one teacher, one student. Right. One parent, one child. It means when you're talking to
someone and there's no one else around. All right. So usually twoters teach you one on one. Right.
You sit at a table and your tutor helps you study. But in the case of home schooling, the student
learns one on one. So learns directly from the teacher. Right. And that's different from public schools.
Obviously because you have one teacher for maybe 30 students. That's right. So that's not one on one.
That's one on many. Right. Exactly. But one on one is also a word you can use when you talk about
meanings. So you could say, hey, Mark, can we have a one on one meeting later? I'd like to talk to you alone.
So that means I'm not going to talk to you with other people. All right. Okay. It's like a private meeting.
Very good. So let's take a listen to the dialogue again. And then we're going to come back and
we're going to take a look at some key phrases.
I think we should homeschool our children. But we decided to have kids. What? Why?
Well, our public schools here are not very good. And the prime schools are just too expensive.
I have been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Like what? I think that by doing something like that, we would be isolating our children from social
interaction. Well, first of all, I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school
and more relaxed and fun way. I also think that having one on one class is much better since you can
focus more on his or her strengths or weaknesses. I think neither your parents are mine would agree
to such an idea. I'll bring it up over Sunday, bro. Good luck with that.
All right. We've picked out four key phrases for you today. Let's take a look at those on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So the first phrase today in fluency builder is the phrase to read up on.
So the sentence was, I've been reading up on home schooling and it has a lot of advantages.
Right. So basically, if you say you have been reading up on a subject or a topic or something,
it means that you've been reading about it. You've kind of been informing yourself.
You're doing research about a topic. Right. So in this case, one parent is researching the home schooling
option. Right. So here she is reading maybe articles in a magazine or books or looking on the
internet. But you don't actually just have to read up on education. You can read up on anything, right?
Right. Exactly. So you can read up on anything that interests you or you can do research on anything.
So you can read up on dinosaurs, for example. I've been reading up on dinosaurs lately. And did
you know that the brontosaurus is not a real dinosaur anymore. That's right. Okay. So we've been
reading up on the advantages of home schooling and he starts by, well, defending his position on
what the advantages are with the phrase, well, first of all. All right. This is an important
little phrase. This is something you can use like you say marker when you're going to have an argument
or maybe a discussion about something and you want to tell your points. You're in your side of
the argument. And so first of all means I have a list. But this is my first point. Right. So it's a
nice little phrase to open up this list of things that you're going to say. Right. That's right.
So you should drink orange juice, Marco, because first of all it tastes good. But second of all
but also it's very good for your body. Right. So first of all is the first main point. So you can say
second of all. Can you go like third of all for fourth of all? Not really. Right.
Yeah. You don't really say it. I guess you could. But so you'll go first of all second of all
and then maybe just go end also or lastly and then lastly to end it. Okay. Very good. Now one of
the other points that he talked about, well apart from the one on one class was that the reason why
a one on one class was better is because he could focus on his or her strengths and
or weaknesses. All right. So strengths or weaknesses or strengths and weaknesses. This is a set phrase
and it's important to remember that these two words are opposites. So strengths. That's the things
you're good at. Right. And weaknesses. Things you're bad at. Things you're bad at. And so
especially when you're studying in a school or your home schooling, it's important that the teacher
understands the strengths and weaknesses of the student. Right. Because something that you're really
good at maybe you should encourage and something you're bad at, you should work harder at improving.
That's right. So it's usually fixed phrase. You'll even get it in job interview. Somebody will say,
well what do you think are your strengths and weaknesses? That's right. So remember that phrase
strengths and weaknesses. Okay. And lastly he said that well even though the idea is interesting,
it might be difficult to make the parents or the grandparents agree with him. So he said he will
bring it up over Sunday brunch. Okay. I will bring it up. Um bring it up. Well you're not actually
holding something. This means that you will mention it in conversation. mentioned the topic. Right.
That's right. So maybe grandma and grandpa don't think home schooling is a good idea. But you will
discuss it or you will suggest it during Sunday brunch. Right. So if you want to discuss a topic,
you usually say I will bring it up with the president for example. That's right. You'll talk about it
with the president. You can also say please don't bring it up. Right. So maybe you told a secret
and you don't want the other person to know. You say, okay, please Marco don't bring it up. Okay.
Very good. All right. Let's listen to a dialogue one last time.
I think we should homeschool our children when we decided to have kids. What? Why? Well our
public schools here are not very good and prime schools are just too expensive. I have been
reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages. Like what? I think that by doing
something like that we would be isolating our children from social interaction. Well first of all,
I would be able to teach them everything they learned in school and more relaxed and fun way.
I also think that having one on one class is much better since you can focus more on his or
her strengths or weaknesses. I think neither your parents are mine. What a great. Such an idea.
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch. Good luck with that.
Okay. So homeschooling is a very interesting option. I think it's very
common more common nowadays in Britain and North America. But how do people that are homeschooled
go to college if they didn't go to a high school? Well I believe that most people when they
finish homeschooling will take some tests to prove that they've actually learned the material
that is required by the state. Because in America each state sets the educational standards.
And so it's important that you learn certain science and math skills. And then once you take
those tests you would get your GED, your graduate diploma. And that means that you've learned
everything that a high school student should know. Right. So it's interesting because it would
seem a little bit strange to not want your kids to go to school. But at the same time there are
many reasons why parents don't want their kids to go to school like in this dialogue. Maybe
the schools are not really good or too expensive. What do you think about homeschooling? Would you
send your kids to homeschool? I don't think I would do homeschooling because I think it's really
important for students to or for children to learn how to get along with others and to learn to
negotiate and to learn to play and to also learn to respect their teachers because you have a
different relationship with your parents than you do your teachers and I think there's a lot of
valuable social lessons you can learn at school. But I do understand why a lot of people choose
this option especially if the schools in their area are poor performing schools so that the
students aren't learning enough or if maybe they're not safe because some schools there's some
bullying or there's some violence and so for those reasons I definitely understand the motivation
to do homeschooling. But then again you can't I mean you can get homeschooled from kindergarten all
the way to up through high school right but I don't there is no homeschooling for university
unless you do like an online degree or something like that you can't really be homeschooling the college.
No there there's distance courses so you could use the internet and learn online but now you
can't homeschool for university. Yeah it's a very debatable topic a lot of people defend it saying
it's good you know it brings parents closer together to their kids that kids enjoy learning
that they learn better etc other people don't really agree with it so what is your opinion
do you agree with homeschooling? Our website is englishpod.com we hope to hear your arguments there.
Okay we'll see you there. Bye.