Hello everyone and welcome to English and hot
My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we're talking about some very interesting stories
where it'll learn some words for stories or tales.
But specifically what kind of stories Marco?
They're popular stories that you hear maybe through emails or maybe in your town.
There's some particular story about maybe a ghost or many different things that
they're kind of hard to believe but that happened a long time ago and people still talk about today.
And they're scary.
Yeah, normally.
So let's listen to today's dialogue.
Here's some interesting stories and when we come back we'll be talking more about what these words and phrases mean.
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
What do you mean?
I was really about how some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and have their organs removed.
Then they're sold on the black market.
Don't tell me actually believe all that.
Don't be so gullible they are just urban legends.
They're just stories people make up to scare you.
Well, I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even satanic messages if you played
them backwards.
Can you believe that?
You really think an artist or songwriter is going to go through the trouble of putting subliminal or
satanic messages in a song?
Don't be so naive.
Well, maybe you are right but how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens which
are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster?
Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true don't you think?
Alright we're back so let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So here on language takeaway today we have some words that will help us understand the dialogue.
The first word is drugged so I was reading about how some people get drugged in their hotel room.
That's right so if you get drugged it means that someone gave you some drugs in order to make
you sleepy or in order for you to not remember what happened.
Alright so he was drugged means someone gave him a drug something that made him go to sleep.
Right and it's not necessarily always a bad thing because obviously if you go to the hospital
the doctor may drug you in order to you know that so you don't feel so much pain or something.
Exactly if you're in an accident you're in a lot of pain the doctor drugs you so you don't
feel that pain.
That's right.
So he was this person is drugged and then what happens?
Well his organs were removed.
Alright so organ and organ is a noun it's thing.
Those are actually the things that are inside our body.
Right so your heart liver, your kidneys, kidneys etc.
These are all organs and this is basically the category for the part of the body.
It's anything really inside your body that has a function.
Okay so this is supposedly the story is that people usually tourists they get tricked or
drugged and then they get their organs removed.
Now what kind of a story is this marker because it's not just a normal story.
Right all of these stories that we saw in the dialogue are called urban legends.
Okay urban has to do with cities.
Right.
Legend is a story that may or may not be true.
That's right.
Right.
So an urban legend is actually a story that is probably not true that you hear from other people
like your friends.
That's right so usually most of these stories fall under this category.
You know there are urban legends.
You don't really know if they're true but people say it happened to a friend of theirs
from a long time ago or stuff like that.
Exactly so a friend of a friend of a friend of mine told me that in hotels sometimes they take
your organs well obviously that's not
All right so after that we have two great adjectives for describing people who like to believe
stories like this what are those two adjectives.
Well we have the adjective to be gullible and to be naive.
All right so there are a little bit different to be gullible means to
believe everything that people tell you.
Right so if you're gullible you pretty much believe anything you see or you or you hear.
Yeah so maybe your friends says did you know Michael Jordan is coming to the office tomorrow.
Right and you believe it then you're very very gullible.
Very gullible you believe what people tell you but naive is similar.
It's similar but I guess it has a little bit of a different meaning in the sense that
you're not it's not that you're so gullible but you wholeheartedly trust people so you're
naive you're innocent.
Your innocent maybe you don't have a lot of life experience.
So you trust people and you can call a person naive you say well he's very naive about these kinds
of things. I guess that that's the main key right that or the main point is that you don't really
have too much life experience so that's why you're naive.
That's right and just be careful because gullible and naive are things that we say about people but
they're not nice things they're not compliments.
Right right so you don't you don't you shouldn't really say it to someone directly like in the dialogue.
Exactly maybe as a joke but not not seriously.
So we have the great adjectives way to describe people and lastly we also have something else that
how to describe this situation maybe it's too far fetched it's too difficult to believe.
So far fetched this is a great word it means basically that something is very difficult to believe
like you say. For example the story about Michael Jordan. Michael Jordan is coming tomorrow you
say oh that's pretty far fetched. I mean I don't really think that could happen.
Right so something that is far fetched is difficult to happen or very very unlikely to happen.
Very unlikely. Okay so very good we've had we saw five keywords there let's take a break and
listen to the dialogue again.
Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
What do you mean? I was really about some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms
and have their organs removed then they're sold on the black market.
Don't tell me actually believe all that. Don't be so gullible they are just urban legends.
They're just stories people make up to scare you.
Well I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even say tannic messages
if you played them backwards can you believe that? You really think an artist or songwriter is going
to go through the trouble of putting subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be so naive.
Well maybe you are right but how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens which
are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster? Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true don't you think?
All right let's take a look now at a couple of phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Now in fluency builder today we're going to start out with the story about organs
this urban legend. Now what happens when the organ is taken the story says that it's sold on the
black market. That's right so you probably hear this in the news or a lot of places the black market
basically it's not really a physical place but it's where things are sold illegally so guns or
gains stuff like that. Exactly so the black market like you say is not a place you can go to it's an
idea and it's basically anything that's illegal that's being sold like guns are often sold in the
black market. That's right sometimes stolen cars are sold in the black market. Also organs can
be sold in the black market and this is a serious problem because obviously all of this is illegal.
That's right so the black market is where all this happens. Now moving on to the next urban legend
that we actually didn't really talk about too much is how many people believe that popular songs
have subliminal or satanic messages in them. All right so let's take a look at the word subliminal
first we all know what a message is right and something that's told to us but a subliminal message
is something that is told to us without us knowing. That's right so it goes into your mind but
you don't even know it right so it's something that a lot of people believe in because they think
that marketing people or big businesses are trying to control our behavior. That's right.
So I could say very quietly Marco by me did our part and that's a subliminal.
Marco says hey you're also going to about getting everyone dinner tonight and then that's that's
basically a way to control your actions. So whether or not this is possible that's another discussion.
That's another discussion but so yeah that's basically a lot of people say that some TV
commercials or ads have the subliminal messages that are trying to convince you or persuade you
into maybe consuming that product. Exactly but they're a little bit different from satanic messages.
That's right so that's basically dealing with Satan or the devil. That's right so the idea
that there are satanic messages means that their their messages about the devil about how maybe
God does not exist or like you know that you should do evil not good. Right. So they're very
dark and very kind of angry messages. Yeah they think they talk about for example
I'm not sure which song it is but like by Ozzy Osbourne that if you play it backwards supposedly
there's this message that says you know worship the devil and stuff like that so that's
where where these urban legends come from but obviously it's either coincidence or not
not true right. That's right. So we've got these messages that are also an urban legend but
the final one is about KFC so KFC would be Kentucky Fried Chicken and what is the legend? The
legend is about their their food. That's right they say that they don't really have real chickens
that will they take chickens and they they just you know super super grow them they the the
chickens are super grown in order for them to get bigger and faster and that's basically that
they don't really even really have heads they just you know have some hoses that go into their bodies
and feed them in four weeks you have a chicken. That's disgusting that's disgusting it's the
ideas yeah super grown chickens and so they're basically they're not real chickens. Right that
that's what the legend says is that they're not I mean they really are but they're not like
naturally grown you know usually a chicken takes three months to grow or something. Yeah all right that's
disgusting I don't want that but the idea of super growing is like using chemicals to do something
that's not natural. That's right that's right chemicals or hormones is stuff so that's they use it
for example on plants you can super grow a plant by adding fertilizer and vitamins and stuff to the
soil that makes it grow faster or maybe you have bigger carrots and normal bigger potatoes because
they're super grown that's right. So all right that's a lot of great stuff let's take a listen to the
dialogue one last time. Have you read all these crazy things that are going on around the world?
What do you mean? I was really about some people get tricked or drugged in their hotel rooms and
have their organs removed then they're sold on the black market. Don't tell me actually believe
all that. Don't be so gullible they are just urban legends they're just stories people make up to
scare you. Well I was also reading about how some popular songs is subliminal or even satanic
messages if you played them backwards can you believe that? You really think an artist or song
writer is going to go through the trouble of putting subliminal or satanic messages in a song? Don't be
so naive. Well maybe you are right but how about the story about how KFC has rows of headless chickens
which are super grown in order to get bigger chickens faster? Sounds a bit too far fetched to be true don't you think?
All right so all these urban legends they are obviously most of them if not all of them are untrue
but they're very popular why do you think that is? I think people like to believe these stories they're
gossipy you know they're scary you get to make your friends kind of nervous about stuff but I think
also we don't trust a lot of these things because we've heard for years and years and years and
years about subliminal messages marketing strategies or about these kind of hidden messages and songs
so there's part of us that wants to believe them but the other part is that you hear it enough you
start to believe it right because you know I was reading up on a couple of them and the most recent
ones are about how they make the connection about how Nostradamus predicted the 9-11 incident
or how Coca-Cola is actually the one that invented Santa Claus and even this KFC one where
you know people just believe a lot of different things I even found one the urban legend about
be careful when you go to the movie theater because there might be a syringe or something on the
seat that if you sit down they're in Fexy with AIDS or something like this so there's so many of them
out there that if you think about it they don't even really make sense they don't and I understand
that sometimes they'll be one news story like about yeah a needle in a candy box and all of
the sudden people say well don't eat candy because there's needles in candy box and right exactly
and obviously you know one time event turns into this massive kind of craze yeah yeah yeah yeah
but it is interesting especially with this whole topic of subliminal messages I do remember that
actually there was a marketing campaign that was banned in movie theaters when there you know
the previews before the actual movie came on they supposedly they had the sound or maybe on the screen
somebody opening up a Coke can really and the smell of Coke actually coming into the theater
and that was kind of like subliminal marketing making people want to go get a Coke definitely
well we used to pump the the exhaust from the popcorn maker when I worked in a movie theater
throughout the lobby there you go everyone smells it and it smells so good you everyone wants to buy it
by pop oh yeah we would totally use that so yeah that is a way of like I guess it's it is subliminal
because you you're not directly telling them to buy it but you are just giving them all the
justing it through audio or visual or oratory cues right and then you have the opportunity to
sell them the most expensive popcorn they'll ever buy exactly 12 dollars for a bag of popcorn all
right so it's a very interesting topic let us know if you have any comments or questions about it
you can find us at englishpod.com we hope to see you guys there bye