Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we're
shoe shopping again. That's right. We are going shoe shopping but this time it's a little bit more
complicated because we're getting women's shoes. That's right. So there are so many different kinds
of women's shoes. I'm not even sure I know them all myself but in this intermediate level lesson
we're going to cover some of the basics for you. That's right. So before we jump into this dialogue,
we have a word that we want to preview with you today and let's take a look at it now on vocabulary
preview. Very cablery preview. Okay so we're shopping today for a certain kind of shoe. It's not a
sports shoe. It's a dress shoe. Okay that kind of doesn't make sense because a dress is a noun.
A shoe is a noun and so you're want to get a shoe that's a dress? No. A dress shoe is a style of
shoe. It means shoes that you wear when you're wearing fancy clothes. So it's kind of like a formal
shoe. A dress shoe is for a shoe that type of shoe that would go well with a dress. That's right.
Not sneakers but don't be fooled. This is not about dresses because men can wear dress shoes too.
That's right. It means shoes you would wear to a conference or to a wedding or to church.
So these are things that are a little bit fancier than everyday shoes. Okay. Awesome. So we're
shopping for a dress shoe and there are so many types and styles of shoes for women. So why don't
we listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a second.
Hi excuse me sir. I'm looking for a dress shoe. My usual pair that I've had for years have
finally been stretched out of shape. They didn't provide any support anymore. Sure. What kind of shoe
were you looking for? We've got strapy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps. If you're looking
for something a little more practical we've got Mary James, ballerinas. Show me some classic high heels please.
Okay. Right this way. What color did you have in mind? Black classic. Of course we've got this
style here that is very popular because it's an open-to shoe. You can wear it any time of the year.
It look great on everyone. Um too shiny and I wear pantyhose with my shoes so let's look for a
clothes to shoe. Okay these are a very nice pair of leather shoes with a two inch heel so they are
very comfortable. I don't like the pointed toes. Let me take a look at what else you have.
To high that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high in-step so I doubt
that one would fit properly. I don't want bows. I find sling backs very uncomfortable.
Those might as well be stillettos. Two modern. Oh finally this is what I'm looking for.
Wood size. Seven and a half. Here we are. How does it fit?
Hmm not good. They're too tight. The length is right but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching
my toes and there'd be no room for my insoles. You know what? I don't think I have the patience for
this today. They just don't make shoes like they used to. I'll come back another time.
Have a nice day. Ma'am.
All right we're back so a lot of shoe styles as you noticed a lot of them are very, I don't know.
I don't even know what they are. So I don't we try and explain them now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So the first kind of shoe we've got here is very popular in the summer.
It's called a strappy sandal. A strappy sandal. So we know what a sandal is. It's kind of like
what you wear to the beach. It's a shoe that it doesn't really cover your whole foot just the bottom.
It's very open. And well what about strappy?
Strappy comes from the word strapp. So strapp is like a thin piece of fabric or leather that connects
other pieces. And so a strappy sandal means that it's it's got many of these different little
straps on it. Many lines everywhere that connect it. So it's very open. It's made of many
different thin pieces. Okay good. So we have a strappy sandal basically a sandal with many straps.
And well she went on to describe a sleek high heel. So this is a two-part thing here.
Sleek is an adjective which basically means really cool looking. Or more like it's it's pretty
and fancy and usually sleek things are also kind of simple like a jaguar is very sleek car.
And so this is the adjective to describe the high heels. So we have high heels.
Okay we have high heels that are kind of fancy shoe. Basically these are shoes that are not flat.
So the heel is very tall. That's right. So basically this is what a lot of women wear with dresses.
Basically the heel has a piece that kind of sticks out and makes the women look taller. So basically
it's like they're walking on the tips of their toes the entire time. Right and they make click
click click click click click click click click click click. But they're different kinds of heels. Okay
high heels obviously means that they're tall. You can have low heels too. Those are shorter.
But high heels that are different kinds. One kind is pumps. Pumps. Okay and the dialer we actually
saw the salesmen describe them as edgy pumps. So edgy what does edgy mean? Edgy means cool.
Core hip. So young people like to wear edgy clothes like rock and roll kind of clothes. Not so
much older people. Okay and pumps are a type of high heel you say but what is the difference?
Well pumps basically are the kind of simple heel that a woman will wear with a pant suit or with
a skirt to the office. And so they usually have a closed toe and they're quite simple heels.
Okay and the opposite or low maybe a little bit different from pumps would be the lettos.
So stilettos are a very special kind of heel. Stilettos. It refers basically to the difference
in the the back of the shoe where you have the heel. Because sometimes heels are kind of thick
and heavy and they make the clunk sound. Right. But stilettos are very, very thin and very tall.
Okay so stilettos heels. I think it's probably easier to walk with pumps rather than stilettos.
Stilettos are famous for being very, very hard to walk in. It's almost like the back of your
heel is a chopstick. Wow. I cannot imagine doing that. All right so this is the classification of
our high heels. Why don't we move on now to Mary Jane's. Okay so we've got high heels and heels
we also have flats. These are flat shoes. So one important kind of flats is a Mary Jane.
Sounds a good name. Yeah it is a name right Mary Jane. Mary Jane. So what type of shoe is this?
This is basically a usually leather shoe but it can be different materials and it's round in the
front and it has one strap and they're very cute. Okay usually little girls wear Mary Jane's but they're
pretty popular these days with older people too. Okay okay so they're round in the
front they are usually black and they have one little strap that goes over the top of your foot.
Mary Jane's okay. All right so we've taken a look at Mary Jane's now moving on to I think it's a
similar type of shoe ballerina shoes. Well ballerina shoes are similar because they're flat but that's
about it. Ballerina shoes are very very thin they're very very weak and usually they're pretty simple
they're pink or white or black and they're almost like a slipper. Okay so they don't have the
strap on top. No they're stretchy and you just lie them onto your foot it's named after a dancer
ballerina's you know the dancers who are pink and they put their hair up and they spin around
and they're not hard on the bottom they're usually quite soft and they're always flat.
So maybe these ballerina shoes they're not the specific types of shoes for dancing if you're
a ballerina but maybe they're more adequate for maybe walking around the house or or something
you don't really go out hiking with ballerina shoes. No you don't go out hiking but they're
very popular to wear now to school or work. Okay and the other type of shoes that we had actually
this was really confusing to me a sling backs sling back shoes. Well sling backs can be hard
because they can be heels they could be pumps but it basically refers to a part of the shoe.
So normal shoes they cover the back of your foot but sling backs have one strap in the back so
maybe if I look at my foot in a sling back I can see part of my heel. Right okay so sling backs
have a little strap on the back of your heel since the shoe doesn't close in the back. Right okay
but you also have high heels and women's shoes that don't close in the back but that you don't have
a strap in the back either right. Those are open shoes. So yeah they're open in the back but the sling
back there's one strap that that keeps your shoe on. Okay a lot of different types of shoes we've
just taken a look at why don't we go back listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back
shortly with fluency builder. Hi excuse me sir. I'm looking at the back of my foot.
Looking for a dress shoe my usual pair that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape.
They didn't provide any support anymore. Sure what kind of shoe are you looking for?
We've got strapy sandals sleek high heels edgy pumps. If you're looking for something a little
more practical we've got Mary Jane's ballerinas show me some classic high heels please.
Okay right this way what color did you have in mind black classic of course we've got this
style here that is very popular because it's an open toe shoe you can wear it any time of the year
they look great on everyone. Um too shiny and I wear pantyhose with my shoes so let's look for a
closed toe shoe. Okay these are very nice pair of leather shoes with a two inch heel so they are
very comfortable. I don't like the pointed toes let me take a look at what else you have
to high that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high in step so I doubt
that one would fit properly. I don't want bows. I find sling backs very uncomfortable. Those
might as well be stillettos. Two modern oh finally this is what I'm looking for. What size?
Seven and a half. Here we are how does it fit? Hmm not good they're too tight the length is right
but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching my toes and there'd be no room for my insoles.
You know what I don't think I have the patience for this today they just don't make shoes like they
used to. I'll come back another time. Have a nice day ma'am.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at five key things on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay well the reason we're shopping today
is because the woman needs a new pair of shoes because her old shoes can't be worn anymore. What's wrong
with a marker? She said that they were stretched out of shape. Okay so to stretch or to be stretched
out this means that maybe they've been pulled and worn and they're stretched so much that they
don't have the original shape anymore. Right so just imagine you have a new t-shirt and all of a
sudden somebody takes you from your t-shirt and pulls you really hard and usually what happens is
this t-shirt is going to be stretched out of shape you pulled it so hard that it loses its original
form so now maybe the neck is very low or the t-shirt is too long on one side. Right so that's what
happens when you stretch something out of shape. Great okay so her old shoes are stretched at a shape
and they don't provide support anymore. Okay so to provide support now what kind of support is
you referring to? She's talking about foot support so for example slippers are kind of shoe basically
that don't provide support they're very soft but can you walk around all day and slippers no
it doesn't help your foot but if you're trying to find shoes that are really good for walking
you need to find ones that provide support that means that always support your foot the bottom of your
foot. Otherwise your foot gets too tired. Not only the bottom but it could be also your ankle for
example if you can't really go hiking with with shoes like these with sandals because obviously
you're walking around rocks and it doesn't provide support on your ankle maybe you can hurt your
ankle if you don't have it. So maybe a hiking boot will provide more support. Exactly.
All right and then the woman also mentioned that it's hard for her to find a shoe because
she said I have a high-instep. Okay so think about the foot you've got toes in the very front
and a heel in the very back but in the middle on top you have the in-step so this is basically the
top of your foot. Okay so if she has a high-instep it means that her foot is kind of thick. That's
right some people have thin feet she has kind of a thick foot so fitting her foot into a shoe is sometimes
hard. Right we're not talking about the width of the foot we're talking about the height
and the tall how tall it is. From the bottom to the top of the foot. Right so that's what she
means by high-instep and well they also mentioned different types of shoes she said she didn't want
an open toe shoe she wanted a closed toe shoe. That's right so this is a really important
classification for women's shoes especially um open toe means that the toe of the shoe the very
very front has a hole or an opening so you can see the toes. Right a closed toe is the opposite so
personally in the winter time might always wear closed toe shoes because I think open toe shoes are
too cold. Okay so that's basically I guess men we don't really have this type of shoe
between open toe and close toe. No maybe no you don't really but heels maybe uh you could have an
open toe you can have an open toe shoe or close toe shoe. Right right okay so a lot of interesting
things this is a useful for women out there and also for boyfriends maybe now you know what type of
shoe your girlfriend may want. That's right all right so let's listen to this dialogue for the last
time and we'll be back shortly. Hi excuse me sir I'm looking for a dress shoe my usual pair
that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape they didn't provide any support anymore.
Sure what kind of shoe are you looking for? We've got strappy sandals sleek high heels edgy pumps.
If you're looking for something a little more practical we've got Mary James ballerinas. Show me
some classic high heels please. Okay right this way. What color did you have in mind? Black classic.
Of course we've got this style here that is very popular because it's an open toe shoe you can
wear it any time of the year. It look great on everyone. Um too shiny and I wear pantyhose with
my shoes so let's look for a closed toe shoe. Okay these are very nice pair of leather shoes
with a two inch heel so they are very comfortable. I don't like the pointed toes let me take a look at
what else you have. To high that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high
in-step so I doubt that one would fit properly. I don't want bows. I find sling backs very uncomfortable.
Those might as well be stillettos. Two modern oh finally this is what I'm looking for. Wood size.
Seven and a half. Here we are. How does it fit? Hmm not good they're too tight. The lead
is right but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching my toes and there'd be no room for my
insoles. You know what I don't think I have the patience for this today. They just don't make shoes
like they used to. I'll come back another time. Have a nice day ma'am.
All right so talking about shoes there's so many types and I think women are notoriously
famous for having a lot of shoes. Why is this? Some women are. Some women are. It depends on the
person but part of the problem is you said earlier is that there's so many different kinds of women
shoes that now we expect women to have a different pair of shoes for every different occasion.
Work shoes, hiking shoes, running shoes, wedding shoes. I don't know. Some are shoes when
shoes fall shoes so you need so many different kinds of shoes you end up buying many different kinds.
I think that that's true and also basically women like to look nice so that's why you
know you do your makeup, you have earrings and they have nice bags so I guess it's also part of
it is that you pay more attention to what type of shoe you're wearing that maybe goes well with the
outfit. I think maybe guys not all guys obviously as well as not all women but guys are a little
bit more generic. It's like jeans pretty much go well with any type of shoe as long as it's maybe
black or brown, right or something like this. True. Although I know a lot of guys who have many different
kinds of shoes. True. True. It takes up a lot of space in the glasses. It does. It does shoes are
hard to carry around. Actually I find it kind of hard to get rid of my shoes. I think they have to be
ripped or just completely unwerable in order for me to throw a shoe away because otherwise it's
you know it's still you can still wear it sometimes. Yeah. That's true. Although I tend to wear my
shoes down. That means I wear them until they die. Really? Actually they're them away. I've had
shoes that I've worn the the the soles down and then I just get it the sole change because I like the
shoe so much. Well let us know do you guys like to buy shoes? Do you have a lot of shoes? Maybe
you don't have that many shoes. We're curious to know about this in other cultures as well because
I know in the States in the United States shoe shopping is very very popular. In Holland they have
traditional wooden shoes. Yeah they do. Those are called clogs. Clogs. So let us know maybe what type of
shoes are also very unique to your country or culture. We're at EnglishPod.com. We'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.