Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we are your English language guides here in EnglishPod.
That's right and today we're going to be taking you to Christmas morning. It's Christmas day.
Oh, one of the best times of the year you wake up. You smell the good smell of delicious eggs and bacon and there's presents.
Hey, I guess that's when you're a kid. I guess when you're an adult, do you really get excited when you wake up for Christmas?
Hell yeah. Sure do. Yeah, I sure do. I love Christmas morning. Yeah, especially I think because of the special breakfast you get like pancakes, scrambled eggs.
But anyways, we're going to be taking a look at a situation here where a kid is opening Christmas presents and we are preparing a meal for Christmas because that day people are going to come over. So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time.
title
iv that that that
Dad, wake up, it's Christmas!
Timmy, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning. Go back to bed.
No way!
Santa already came and left all our presents.
Can we go open them, please? Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on, get dressed.
Fine. Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
Awesome!
All right Timmy, knock yourself out.
We should get ready and head to the market
to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house
so everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes,
ingredients for the gravy and of course, yams.
My dad offered to bring the egg yolk so we should be set.
All right, we're back.
So there were a couple of different and interesting words there.
So let's take a look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, this first word is not a very happy word.
It's a word that we try not to use too much around the Christmas season.
But sometimes you're just tired of people.
Because the holidays is all about people doing stuff.
Family.
Someone who's not being very happy, someone who's a little bit grumpy
is called a grouch.
Okay, so a person that's not very happy,
not very friendly is a grouch.
I don't want to open presents.
This is stupid.
Okay, that's a grouch.
Okay, so a person is a grouch or you can act like a grouch
or be a grouch.
Don't be a grouch.
All right.
Well, they were talking about heading to the market to buy something for dinner.
So to head to.
Okay, to head to is a way to say to go towards someplace or to go somewhere.
All right, so if I'm driving my car and you ask me where I'm going,
I'm saying, oh, I'm heading to to the bank.
All right, so to head to means to be on your way somewhere,
I'm going somewhere.
It's a way to say that you're in the process of going.
You can't say next year, I will head to Alaska.
It doesn't make as much sense.
You usually say, I'm heading to the bank or head to the market.
Let's head to the market.
Okay, and well, they were talking about heading to the market
because they are hosting Christmas dinner.
So to host.
To host is a, well, it's a very important holiday term.
It's a verb, you do it.
And it means that you or the person who has the special dinner
and your friend and family, they come to your house.
Okay.
Okay, so we could say, this Christmas, I'm hosting the dinner at my house.
So I want everyone to come to my house and eat.
All right, and it can also be a noun, right?
You can say, I am a host.
Exactly.
The host of this dinner.
Right.
And you, it doesn't have to be holidays either.
You could say, hey, Marco, how about you host a dinner next week?
Oh, come.
Right.
Okay.
Popping wine.
All right.
So to host a dinner or to host a party, et cetera.
And our fourth word for language takeaway is probably the most popular drink during the Christmas season egg nug.
Okay.
It sounds kind of disgusting.
Yeah.
The drink with egg.
But it's a very popular creamy eggy drink.
It's very thick and it's cream colored.
And normally you add a little bit of rum.
Okay.
To make it alcoholic.
Yeah.
And you drink it warm.
And it's kind of just a thick warm alcoholic beverage.
It's very, very popular.
And my dad loves it.
Very Christmas, right?
You don't have it.
Like, I am any other day.
No, you wouldn't want to.
It's too heavy.
But it's very, very popular.
Like, the days before Christmas and on Christmas.
Okay.
So egg nug.
Very good.
So I think we should take a look at the dialogue again.
And we'll be back soon with Fluffy Builder.
Dad, dad, dad.
Wake up.
It's Christmas.
To me, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed.
No way!
Santa already came and left all our presents.
Can we go open them, please?
Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bell, come on, get dressed.
Fine.
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
Bell, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas
tree.
Awesome!
All right, Timmy.
Knock yourself out.
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
So everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes.
Ingredients for the gravy and of course, yams.
My dad offered to bring the egg nug so we should be set.
All right, we're back so now let's take a look at a couple of phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Okay, so this first phrase is a phrase that I often heard as a child because I never wanted
to go to sleep.
So I'd go downstairs and my parents would say, Catherine, go back to bed.
Go back to bed.
Okay, go back to bed.
So this is just a very common colloquial spoken way of saying, go back to sleep.
Go back to sleep.
Go to sleep.
Don't be awake.
So you can say go to sleep or you can say go to bed or if somebody has gotten out of bed,
you say go back to bed.
Exactly.
And so parents often use this with their kids because they want their kids to sleep.
You can also say to someone who's up at night worrying and you say, come on, go back to bed.
Go back to bed.
Go to sleep.
Relax.
Okay.
And then we also saw this phrase knock yourself out.
All right, Timmy.
Knock yourself out.
So what is this?
Well, I'm not really sure where this phrase comes from.
I mean, to knock is like, to knock on a door, right?
But to knock yourself out, if I think about it, it probably means that you hit yourself
in the head and you fall over.
But the real meaning of this is go have fun.
Okay.
Have as much fun as you can have.
Right.
Have as much fun as you want.
Go knock yourself out.
So the parent is saying, hey, Timmy, go have as much fun as you can.
Much fun as you want, just go do it and enjoy yourself.
Yeah, like go up and all these presence have all the fun you want.
All right.
And then we saw another phrase when they finished talking about dinner and all the things they have to buy.
They said, we should be set.
We should be set or we are set.
Well, this is funny because she says, well, my dad's going to bring the egg knock.
So we should be set.
Which means we should have everything we need.
So we don't need anything else.
We're ready.
Everything's good.
So we can say we are set.
I'm set.
Are you set?
It's the way to say, are you ready?
Are you prepared?
Do you have everything you need?
Okay.
So I also need this one.
I'm going on a trip.
Right.
Are you set?
Are you all set?
Yeah.
All right.
I finished packing.
I'm all set.
I'm ready to go.
All right.
Okay.
So some interesting phrases there as well.
Why don't we have a look at our dialogue for the last time?
Dad, dad, dad.
Wake up.
It's Christmas.
To me, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed.
No way.
Santa already came and left all our presents.
Can we go open them, please?
Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on, get dressed.
Fine.
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
Awesome!
All right, Timmy.
Knock yourself out.
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
So everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes.
Ingredients for the gravy and of course, yams.
My dad offered to bring the egg yolk so we should be set.
All right, we're back.
So as you mentioned, Christmas morning is great.
You open presents and well, breakfast and it's time to be together with parents or family.
As in this case, you can be a little bit of a grouch because you just out of kind of tired because you had Thanksgiving and November and then Christmas and now you're having new years.
So you're kind of just like, uh, yeah, the holidays season can be exhausting.
And I know a lot of families have a special dinner on the 24th.
That's Christmas Eve.
Okay.
And then by the time it's Christmas day, the 25th, you're exhausted.
You didn't get any sleep.
You might have had too much to drink last night.
And so it can be very tiring.
Also because the kids always get up way too early, like six o'clock.
Right, to open their presents, right?
And then they'll be playing with their toys all day and you'll be, you'll have a headache.
But it's a great season to spend time with the family.
And well, we want to know how you spend your Christmas Eve and your Christmas morning.
So why don't you come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments there as well.
We're looking forward to hearing from you again, happy holiday season and until next time.
Bye.