Hello English learners. Welcome back to another podcast here at English Pod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today we have a fun dialogue.
That's right. Well, maybe the language in this lesson you won't use every day.
But it's it's fun. It's interesting. And it's a little bit on the lighter side.
That's right. Today we're going to be looking at baby talk. So we're going to see some of these words that aren't really words.
And that real words that you can find in the dictionary. But native English speakers use them when they're talking to little babies.
Yeah, in many languages, there's there's a rule for how you make baby talk words, right?
Right. But in English, we don't have really clear rules about how you make a word a baby word.
So we're going to teach you a few of these baby words exactly. So before we listen to the dialogue, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very cablory preview.
Okay. We have two words here. We're going to hear in the dialogue. And the first one is diaper.
diaper.
Okay. So a diaper. A baby uses a diaper.
That's right. It's a piece of cloth or material that you put around the baby so that it can go to the bathroom and not make a mess.
Okay. A diaper. Now we also have another word that we commonly use in the English language. It's Nana. Nana.
So Nana is the name we call a grandmother.
Right. So in informal name, just like in Spanish, we would say something like Abuelita or in Italian.
You might say, oh, ma. This is another way that we can call a grandma or granny.
Okay. So Nana. Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time? Let's see how these new parents are talking to their little baby using baby talk.
Honey, the babies up again.
It's your turn. I went last night.
Fine.
Hello, little baby. Why are you crying?
What a baby. I see. You made a do-do.
What's going on, honey? Why is the baby crying?
A little baby made a do-do.
What a good boy. Let's get this Iki diaper off you.
Lucky what I have there. Mickey Mouse jammies.
Who's it easy?
Did the little baby just tink a lot all over daddy?
Yes he did. Yes he did. You just made a wee wee all over daddy.
What's still while I change his yucky diaper?
What's going on in here?
Oh look, it's Nana. Say hi to Nana.
Oh, he's so adorable. I could just eat him off.
Okay, say bye to Nana. Time to go, baby bye.
Okay, well that was pretty cute wasn't it?
A cute dialogue. The baby seemed to be cute and well everyone's excited about the new baby.
But they use some really interesting little words that are pretty unfamiliar.
So let's look at them now in language takeaway.
All right, so as we mentioned before, these words aren't actually words.
They you won't find them in the dictionary.
Right, but you'll hear them commonly when people are talking to babies and you might see them in a movie or something like that.
So why don't we get started with the first one.
All right, the first word that may seem a little bit strange.
The father said hello, little baby.
Little baby.
Okay, little.
So little is just a baby talkway of saying little little.
That's right.
The father saw that the baby was crying because he made a do do the baby made the do do not the father.
Right, the baby made a do do do do.
Okay, so basically a do do is when the baby poos or poops in the diaper.
Okay, so you know sometimes you go to the bathroom and it might take a little bit longer.
Exactly.
That's because of the do do do do.
Right, the actual technical or maybe the proper English word for this would be defecate.
Okay, so make a do do.
All right, now our third words are interesting because he said,
Iki diaper.
That's right.
And Iki diaper.
And then he also said, yaki.
So we've got two words here that mean the same thing.
Iki and Iki.
Mm-hmm.
And basically means disgusting.
Right.
Something that's really, really not nice.
So you would say Iki or Iki.
Now, these words have other similar words.
We might recognize Iki or Iki.
Right.
So you would use Iki or Iki if something is disgusting.
But when you're kind of talking to a baby, you would say Iki.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, mainly.
The adjective.
Mm-hmm.
Now our next word, the the father said he has some Mickey Mouse jammies.
Jammies.
Okay, so what are jammies?
Well, the word jammies is short for pajamas.
So the clothes that you put on when you go to sleep.
Mm-hmm.
Jammies.
All right.
And now for our last two words, they mean the same thing as well.
The little baby tingled all over daddy.
So to tingle.
And then his mom said, a wee wee all over daddy.
You made a wee wee.
Okay.
So tingle and wee wee.
Basically also going to the bathroom, but this time to pee.
To pee, exactly.
To urinate.
We wee.
So the verb, two tingle and the noun, a wee wee.
Mm-hmm.
Very good.
So these are the words that we have for you today in language.
Take away as you can see they're kind of cute and very common when you're talking
to babies and you know, you have to be a little bit nicer.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue another time, a little bit slower.
And you'll catch these words a little bit easier.
Honey, the babies up again.
It's your turn.
I wouldn't last night.
Fine.
Hello, little baby.
Why are you crying, little baby?
Oh, I see.
You made a do-do.
What's going on, hun?
Why is the baby crying?
The little baby made a do-do.
What a good boy.
Let's get this ikki diaper off you.
Lucky what I have here.
Mickey Mouse, jammies.
Whoopsie, Daisy.
Did the little baby just tinkle all over daddy?
Yes, he did.
He just made a wee wee all over daddy.
Oh, still while I change his yucky diaper.
Oh, what's going on in here?
Oh, look, it's Nana.
Say hi to Nana.
Oh, he's so adorable.
I could just eat him off.
Okay, say bye to Nana.
Time to go, baby, bye.
Alright, so now that we've seen those great words,
let's take a look at two phrases that we're going to look at now
in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So the mother didn't really want to get up and look after the baby.
She said, it's your turn.
It's your turn.
So when she says it's your turn.
That means you should do it now.
Right, so she's basically saying now you have to do it.
I did it last time, so now you have to do it.
Mm-hmm.
It's your turn.
That's right, it's your turn.
Well, the Nana, the grandmother, she was really, of course she really loves this little baby.
And she said, I could just eat him up.
I could just eat him up.
Now does she want to really eat him?
No, of course.
Of course not.
So what does she mean by this?
This is a phrase we often use with very cute things.
It just means, oh my god, he's so cute.
Okay, he's so cute that I wish I could just hug him
and kiss him a lot.
Yes, we might use this with babies or maybe with puppies.
I could just eat him up.
All right, so great two phrases that we've just taken a look at.
Let's go back to our dialogue for the last time.
And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about these babies.
Honey, the babies have again.
It's your turn. I wouldn't last night.
Fine.
Hello, little baby.
Why are you crying with a baby?
Oh, I see. You made a do-do-do-do.
What's going on, honey? Why is the baby crying?
The little baby made a do-do-do.
What a good boy. Let's get this Ikki diaper off you.
Look at what I have here. Mickey Mouse jammies.
Whoops, it's easy.
Did the little baby just tink a lot all over daddy?
Yes he did. Yes he did.
You just made a wily all over daddy.
What's still while I change his yucky diaper?
What's going on in here?
Oh look, it's Nana. Say hi to Nana.
He's so adorable. I could just eat him off.
Okay, say bye to Nana. Time to go, baby bye.
Okay, so they are obviously new parents.
They've just had a baby, so they're excited about him waking up.
They're all excited about the baby and how he wakes up and everything.
But an interesting thing, the baby was sleeping in another room.
In English speaking countries, people have sort of two different opinions about how you should sleep with your baby.
You know, some people want to have the baby in the bed with them, right?
But some people think no, the baby should definitely sleep in its own room.
Okay, in another room in a crib.
Yeah, right. I think this is a very important issue because many people consider that it's a good thing for the baby to sleep with a parent.
And if you feel safe and you can make sure the baby's okay.
And it's easier for, you know, waking up to feed the baby and change a diaper.
Exactly. And well, if the baby is sleeping with its parents, it might not wake up as much.
But other people think if you let the baby sleep with the parents, the baby will become kind of spoiled and not a very good baby.
Right, it might become too dependent on the parents.
And for example, if you ever want to go out or leave the baby with a baby sitter or when the baby starts maybe preschool or kindergarten, it might not be really independent.
So why don't you tell us what you think?
Do you think it's a good idea to allow a baby to sleep with you or should sleep in its own room?
Yeah, you can tell us that our website EnglishPod.com, where you can also ask any questions you have about the language in this dialogue.
Alright guys, so we'll see you there and until next time.
Thanks for downloading and goodbye.