Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod My Name is Marco
And I'm Erica and today with Erica we have an upper intermediate lesson
That's right an upper intermediate lesson that's a little bit strange
It's a little bit strange but it's a real English lesson because that's what we give you here at EnglishPod
So in today's lesson we've got a lot of really great language for you
We've got language to help you to gossip better
gossip why don't you explain it a little bit just in case okay so if I gossip I maybe share
News or information about other people with my friends like I might say something like
Marco did you see what happened in ChinesePod today?
You'll never guess what I saw
Exactly that's gossip and we also have language today to describe things to describe strange things
Strange things all right so let's take a look at our vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
So in our vocabulary preview we'll look at a few important words that will help you to understand the
dialogue a little bit better
Exactly and the first word is weird weird weird
Weird now this is a common word you probably hear all the time and in a lot of different situations
So we wanted to explain it today yeah
This word just means strange it's strange yeah weird person is a strange person exactly but the thing about this word is if you are a
Young person let's say under the age of 35 you'll probably use it about a hundred times a day
Weird just such a good sounding word weird it is okay, but the thing is that even though it's probably more commonly used in
American English it's still widely used for British English as well. Yeah, that's true
So but maybe in British English you would say something like odd it's odd. Yeah, that's more common
Okay, let's look at our second word housewarming gift housewarming gift housewarming gift
Housewarming gift now this is a cultural thing it's really common in North America to give a housewarming gift to someone
Yeah, if I move into a new house maybe some of my friends or family will bring a gift over to
Make my house a little bit more beautiful so something like a photo frame or or maybe a plan to
Sometimes even like maybe a basket of pastries or something okay. Yeah, I've never gotten one of those
Really have a home. Oh, where do you live on the street? Well, I don't have them up my own home
So I have never gotten one of those okay, okay, so we're ready now to listen to our dialogue
So we've got two housewives who are gossiping about what's going on in the neighborhood and let's listen to what happens
Oh, I don't know if you've heard that someone moved into that old house down the road
Yeah, I know I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in his name is our mom
Really, it's like you have to film in actually
He's a bit strange. I don't know. I've just got a bad feeling about him really
Why well yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift but our mom started acting really weird and then he
Practically kicked me out. I tried to sort of peek into his house, but everything was so dark inside that I couldn't really get a good look
The whole thing really creeped me out
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning. It's a delivery truck pulled into his driveway and it dropped off a long rectangular
Box
Don't look like a coffin
You see why we're here? Oh, ladies. Oh, our mom. Oh, you scared the heck out of me. This is my friend Doris
Pleasure to meet you. If you're not doing anything tonight. I'd like to have you both for dinner. I mean
I'd like to have you both over for dinner
You
That guy seems kind of weird
You can hear his voice is like a weird guy, right? Yeah
All right, let's take a look at our language takeaway and look at some of these great words
Language takeaway
So our language takeaway focuses on several words from the dialogue that we feel are really
Important for you to know exactly and we have four of them for you today. Why don't we look at the first one?
Okay, so the first word is a bad feeling
Bad feeling a bad feeling a bad feeling a bad feeling
So we've got a few examples that will help you to understand how this phrase works
Example one
I don't like Kelly's new boyfriend. I've got a bad feeling about him
Example two
It's so dark we shouldn't be out here. I've got a bad feeling about this
Example three
I
've got a bad feeling about this trip. I feel like something is going to happen
Maybe we shouldn't go
Okay, so basically you think something bad is gonna happen. Yeah, you have a sort of uncomfortable feeling
Okay, that makes sense. I have a bad feeling about something exactly. Okay, let's look at our second word now
Kick to me out kicked me out kicked me out kicked me out. So when someone kicks you out
It's they force you to leave you don't want to leave, but they force you. Yeah, Marco have you ever kicked someone out of your class?
Yes, I have I really if you miss behave in my class you're kicked out. You're pretty strict
Sometimes I am okay. Also, maybe you've kicked your husband out of bed
I might have done that once or twice or we'll have to ask him. I'm sure he has
All right, so that's what it means you force someone to leave the house leave the class leave the bed
So kick to the class kick to the house kick to the bed
Exactly great. Let's look at our third word now
Creep to me out creeped me out creeped me out
Now this is a really common phrase. I like this phrase a lot and we've got some examples for you to listen to to help you understand this word a little bit better
Example one
Did you know that oh, I think I saw something stop it you're really creepy me out
What
Example two
This place really creeps me out. Let's get out of here
All right, well, I have a confession to make I'm kind of creeped out by clowns you are
I don't know they're just creepy. They're they scare me. Really. Yes, what is it about clowns that scare you so much?
I don't know they're just white faces and weird paint. I don't know it's just creepy you in the way they laugh
I don't know maybe at a bad experience the clowns is a child probably
I watched the scary movie about clowns or something yeah, all right, so creeped me out basically means made me feel uncomfortable
Yes, it scares you. Yeah, well speaking of being scared we have our final word for language takeaway and it is
Scared the heck out of me you scared the heck out of me. Yeah, I think this is a quite common way of saying you really really scared me. Yeah, okay
We're ready to listen to our dialogue again now try and see if you can catch all these phrases that we just talked about
Oh, I don't know if you've heard but someone moved into that old house down the road
Yeah, I know I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in his name is
Armand really what's he like you have to fill me in
Actually he's a bit strange. I don't know. I've just got a bad feeling about him
really why
Well yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift
But Armand started acting really weird and then he practically kicked me out
I tried to sort of peek into his house
But everything was so dark inside that I couldn't really get a good look
The whole thing really creeped me out
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning at delivery truck
Hold into his driveway and it dropped off a long rectangular box
It almost looked like a coffin
You see why would he hello ladies? Ah
Armand you scared the heck out of me
This is my friend Doris a pleasure to meet you
If you are not doing anything tonight
I would like to have you both for dinner. I mean I would like to have you both over for dinner
You know one of the things I really like about this dialogue is there's a lot of great phrases
That will help you to gossip
That's a good observation so I think it's time for fluency builder
Fluency builder
In fluency builder we take a simple phrase or a simple word you already know and show you how to express the same idea a little bit more naturally
Okay great, so let's take a look at our first item for fluency builder
So when you gossip with somebody you often tell them news or information that they don't know already
And you might start by saying did you know that or you can say did you hear?
Yeah, both of those phrases are perfectly fine
But if you want to sound a little bit more native like when you're gossiping you might try out this phrase from the dialogue
I don't know if he've had
Yeah, that's a really good phrase you're saying exactly the same thing but in a really natural way
It's a great one for gossiping so Marco I don't know if you've heard but Chinese pod is up to some pretty crazy things
See that's exactly how you would use that phrase so now let's take a look at our second item now when you're gossiping you want information
That's right so you might say oh tell me about it or something like give me the details
Yeah, and again both of these examples are perfectly fine
But when you're gossiping you might want to try something like this
You have to fill me in
Fill me in yeah, that's that's what I would say fill me in you know give me the details fill me in
Fill me in on today's gossip. Okay, so let's take a look at our third item now if you have some juicy gossipy news and you want to start up a
Conversation you might use this phrase here
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning
That's a really good phrase you can change it a little bit you can say you'll never guess who I saw or you'll never guess what I heard
Exactly very excellent gossip prices
We're teaching you how to gossip because that's really English people really do it so you got to know the language for it
All right, so enough of our gossip. I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue one last time
Oh, I don't know if you've heard that someone moved into that old house down the road
Yeah, I know I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in his name is our mom
Really, it's like you have to fill me in actually
He's a bit strange. I don't know. I've just got a bad feeling about him really why?
Well yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift but our mom started acting really weird and then he
Practically kicked me out. I tried to sort of peek into his house, but everything was so dark inside that I couldn't really get a good look
The whole thing really creeped me out. Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning
It didn't live retruck pulled into his driveway and it dropped off a long rectangle in a book
Don't look like a coffin. You see why would he already?
Armand you scared the heck out of me. This is my friend Doris
Impleasured me to you if you're not doing anything tonight. I'd like to have you both for dinner. I mean
I'd like to have you both over for dinner
Okay, Markle. I have a true story for you. Is it kind of like a creepy story? It is a creepy story indeed. Is it a true story?
No, it's really true. So when I was young, I used to live in the country and you know in the country all of the neighbors know each other
It's a small community so everyone knows what's happening all the time
Okay, and there was some gossip going on in our community about a guy who lived at the end of the road
And he was the owner of a car wrecking yard so a place where you
Take old broken down cars and take the parts apart to sell right anyway a scrap yard. Yes, scrap yard. All right, okay
So you know he had a wife in a couple of kids and suddenly his wife disappeared. Wow
Yeah, and no one knew what happened or anything and so several years passed and suddenly the police start coming in and start investigating this guy
I'm starting digging up all of the land around his property and I guess I don't know what they're doing
But I think they were looking for the wife's body. Wow, and did they find it? I don't know I moved away
Such a great story, but we don't know how it ends. Yeah
We can leave it up to the imagination of our listeners exactly. Maybe that we're looking for an old car
I don't car buried in the ground. I don't think so
All right, that's a true story real English real stories
You're the first here on English hot all right, so we want to hear your comments and suggestions about this topic
I bet a lot of our listeners also have creepy stories maybe ghost stories
Maybe I don't know different types of weird stories, so you guys should definitely log on to English pot and share them with us
That's right go to Englishpot.com and in the comments section of the website tell us your creepy stories
And we're gonna pick out the best story as the story of the week
Well, I'm now sitting our this just in podcast. Yes, so we want to hear all your juicy stories and gossip
Maybe as well. Yes
All right, well, it's time for us to go so be sure to listen to us next time
But until then it's