Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica
and today we're going to be going to one of the least favorite places of many many people
so it must be the dentist
exactly that place where you have to go every six months
but you probably don't go
you probably don't, I know I don't go every six months
so yeah we're going to be going to the dentist and of course we're going to be looking at
a lot of great vocabulary related to teeth and all that crazy stuff dentists do
yes and we'll also learn some really interesting phrases
so Marco let's get started with our vocabulary preview
very vocabulary preview
okay and vocabulary preview today we have two words let's take a look at the first one
tooth ache tooth ache tooth ache tooth ache
okay so we've seen before this this ending ache right
it needs it hurts exactly so again a tooth ache would be hurting tooth
hurting tooth yes we can also say stomach ache headache
yep pretty much everything can
ache ache yeah okay so our next word x-ray x-ray x-ray x-ray x-ray
x-hifin r-a-y okay pretty easy word
so when you go to the doctor many times you'll get an x-ray
it is a picture of your bones right
so that's an x-ray all right well we're going to hear both of these words in the
dialogue so why don't we listen as Gary visits his dentist
Gary great to see you again
please have a seat so tell me what seems to be the problem
things doc I've got a really bad tooth ache
I can't eat anything and look my face is also all in
I think it might be my wisdom teeth
well let's have a look open wide
hmm this doesn't look good well it looks like you have a cavity
and your crown is loose so we'll need to put in a filling before it gets any worse
and the crown probably needs to be refitted
I'm going to order some x-rays
is it going to hurt? no not at all just lay back and relax
okay spit
okay that always happens the dentist says no it's not going to hurt don't worry about it
but it always hurts much more than he says
exactly so in this dialogue we saw some interesting words when the dentist was
describing what problems Gary had yes so why don't we look at those now in language takeaway
language takeaway all right let's take a look at our first word
so Gary said that his face was all swollen swollen swollen
so swollen is an adjective right Marco right so his face is or was swollen
it was bigger yeah his face was bigger than normal yes often when you hurt yourself
that part of your body becomes swollen right so you have to put some ice on it usually and then
the swelling will go down and that's the noun the swelling right the swelling and well the verb
two swell all right three words for the price of one so let's listen to some examples of how we
would use the swelling swollen and two swell
example one my nose is swollen it's the size of a football
example two
put some ice on your foot and the sweating will go down
example three I got bitten by a spider in my hand is swelling up
all right so Gary's face was swollen and he thought that it was his wisdom teeth
wisdom teeth wisdom teeth okay so this is interesting the wisdom is like wise
yeah knowledge so these teeth they're not knowledgeable but they're called wisdom teeth
they're the teeth that grow last in your mouth right they are the last teeth at the very end
of your mouth yes and usually you get them when you're about 20 and since they come out at this age
sometimes they interfere they hurt a little bit so you have to get them taken out yes all right
wisdom teeth wisdom teeth okay now for our next word and something that we all got as children
cavity cavity a cavity a cavity it's a hole in your tooth and it's caused by too much sugar
much sugar right or not brushing your teeth enough yeah so that's why everyone had it I think
as children cavities I never had a cavity really yeah wow didn't have much sugar
I guess I was a bit of a health nut when I was a kid oh no I wasn't my mum was
no I guess not all right but enough about my eating habits let's talk about our next word
crown crown crown so a crown this is interesting we're not talking kings and
we ride that's the first thing that comes to mind right yeah no a crown is actually the visible
part of your teeth okay so there's one part of your tooth that's inside that you can't see right
that's called the root yes so when he said your crown is loose what's he talking really about the actual
tooth so sometimes people will lose a tooth or have a really bad cavity so the dentist needs to make
a new crown or a new visible part of the tooth for you so sometimes it'll be made of gold
yep you know or porcelain or saline yeah exactly so a crown it's like a really really big filling
a crown so his crown needed to be refitted or put back into place yes now our final word
filling filling a filling a filling so I just said this word previously mm now when you have a cavity
you need to fill it in right you need to fill it with something yes it's usually some sort of paste
and it gets really hard and it's like your tooth exactly so then it covers up this cavity filling
a filling I have many feelings I wasn't very healthy as a kid all right not a good tooth pressure
exactly so why don't we listen to this dialogue again and then we'll come back and talk a little bit
about some of the interesting phrases that the doctor used hey Gary great to see you again
please have a seat so tell me what seems to be the problem
things doc I've got a really bad toothache I can't eat anything and look my face is also all
and I think it might be my wisdom teeth well let's have a look open wide
this doesn't look good well it looks like you have a cavity and your crown is loose
we'll need to put in a filling before it gets any worse and the crown probably needs to be refitted
I'm going to order some x-rays is it going to hurt no not at all
just lay back and relax
okay spit
well the dentist used three really interesting phrases and I want to look at the first one
what seems to be the problem what seems to be the problem okay very easy little sentence to
ask somebody what's wrong exactly right and I mean these are small easy words but when you put
them together they sound really natural and and really fluent so if you ask somebody what
seems to be the problem is very polite yeah and it's a very good way of asking what's wrong
yes all right our next phrase also made up of simple words let's have a look let's have a look
let's have a look so this is a phrase that maybe you're mechanic or your dentist or your doctor will
say or anyone right let's have a look let's look at it and see what the problem is
okay let's have a look okay and our final phrase it doesn't look good it doesn't look good
so I can use this phrase for an object right like this house doesn't look good yes but here it's
used a little bit differently so why don't we listen to some examples to help us understand the meaning
example one
John told me it doesn't look good for me I probably won't get the job
example two
it doesn't look good for Michael Jackson he's in a lot of debt
example three you know the economy doesn't look very good
okay so in the examples we can see that they are using it for the situation yeah it looks maybe
problematic yeah so when you say it doesn't look good you basically mean
there are going to be problems all right it doesn't look good yeah okay so great phrases
great words let's listen to our Gary at the dentist one more time then we'll come back and talk a little bit more
hey Gary great to see you again please have a seat so tell me what seems to be the problem
based on I've got a really bad toothache I can't eat anything and look my face is all swollen
I think it might be my wisdom teeth well let's have a look open wide
this doesn't look good well it looks like you have a cavity and your crown is loose
we'll need to put in a filling before it gets any worse and the crown probably needs to be
refitted I'm going to order some x-rays is it going to hurt no not at all just lay back and relax
oh okay spit well Marco speaking of dentists have you ever had an experience like this where you
spat out a tooth of the dentist well nothing so serious as this but actually recently when I was in
Cambodia all right you called us to in Cambodia well our taxi driver offered us to have some local food
and he said well we're going to have dog so that's interesting actually it wasn't that bad it was
pretty good but you know if you get around the fact that it's a dog so what does this have to do with your
teeth I was eating it and I bit a bone that was hidden okay and I chipped my tooth so you broke
part of your tooth yeah like half of it which I had already chipped before so I had to go to the dentist
and so the dentist created a new crown with not with gold or porcelain actually with a paste oh
and then it becomes hard and it just looks normal it doesn't even look like I have a fake crown so
to say but dentists can be really expensive so how much did this cost well this was for the
bargain price of $10 dollars that's how much it costs so we should all go to Cambodia for dentists
yeah because actually he was pretty good he looked really young though I was kind of scared because when
he walked in he looked like he was 19 but I asked him his age and he was like 30 okay well you're very
trusting yeah so I imagine that you guys maybe have some dental experiences so why don't you come
to our website and tell us all about it yeah visit us at EnglishPod.com and you can find lots more
resources for learning English there well guys thanks for listening and until next time bye