Hello everybody and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we hope by now you're very excited about football or soccer.
This is the World Cup time of years so this comes every four years actually and we've
got to lessen all about it. That's right so as everyone may or may not have heard we are
actually in the middle of the World Cup and as you say it's a football or soccer competition.
Now soccer is only used in the United States. That's right. It's used in the United States
although football can be confusing in a place like Australia where they have two different
games that are called football. That's right so it's a little bit difficult at times to
tell someone that you play football and they think you play American football or Australian
football or soccer so it's a little bit confusing. It can be yeah. Alright so we have a great
lesson all about the World Cup we're going to explain a little bit and so let's listen to the
dialogue for the very first time.
What are you doing? What am I doing? What am I doing? Don't you know what day it is?
No. It's only the day when the World's biggest sporting event is kicking off.
What? The World Cup. The first match is today. It's Mexico versus South Africa.
It's going to be a really good match. Both teams have a very strong offense and have skilled
players. I think that South Africa will probably dominate the first half since they're the host
country and all. I have no idea what you're talking about. The only sporting event we watch at home
is the Super Bowl. This is bigger than the Super Bowl man. Teams from 32 countries compete against
each other every four years and fight to win that trophy. They first start in a group stage with
eight groups. Each group having four teams. The top two teams pass on to an elimination stage before
going on to the semi finals and the quarter finals. Sounds interesting but soccer doesn't really
appeal to me. Are you kidding? Over 700 million people watch the final match of the 2006 World Cup.
It's a very exciting and nerve-racking sport. Each nation is cheering on their team,
hoping they will become the next champion. So far Brazil is the team with the most titles under
the belt. They're really good. All I know about soccer is that you can't use your hands and that
players are always falling down trying to get a free kick or penalty kick. It seems like a
scissory sport to me. Whatever. I'm going to go watch the opening match.
The World Championship.
All right we're back so obviously two people discussing or fighting over the World Cup and
soccer. One of them doesn't really like it. But he came up with some really interesting points
and explained a couple of interesting things. So let's take a look at some of that Voka on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay the very first phrase here is a very important one we're talking about
sports. This game is called a sporting event. That's right so a sporting event is an event.
I guess you would say is a performance or something that happens occasionally but related to sports.
That's right so an event can be a game itself or a tournament. You've heard maybe of,
the UEFA Cup. That's the European Federation of Football or whatever it is. So basically you have
this tournament for European soccer teams but World Cup is also an event and a very important
game could also be an event. So this basically means a sporting match or a sporting competition.
That's right. Now it may sound confusing as to why you put the ING in sport. It should be
maybe sports event or sport event. But I'm not really sure why we had the gerant
sporting event. We always just say it this way. It's a set phrase. So let's remember that it's
sporting event. This is the world's most important sporting event for example. Okay very good.
Now we win and we talked about the first match Mexico versus South Africa and they're talking
about the teams and how they both have a very strong offense. Okay so offense is a part of the team.
Basically it's a group of players who are trying to score. That's right. Okay so when you're,
when you're good at offense it means you're good at scoring and the opposite of offense is what?
Defense defense. So offense defense. You can say they have a very strong defense. That means that
it's very hard to score against them because they're defenders. They're goalies. They're all
very strong. That's right. So we're talking about an offense and a defense. Both a very important
parts of a team. And so the guy continued and made a little bit of a prediction saying that South
Africa will probably dominate the first half. Okay so you know that football matches are split into
halves. You have first half and second half. To dominate here means to be stronger than someone else.
So to control the ball or to have possession or to be the one that is the strongest team on the
field. That's right. So you can dominate by having a very strong defense or you can dominate
by having a very strong offense or both. Dominate means be stronger than. That's right. Okay now let's
move on to the other guy who doesn't really like soccer. And he says I have no idea what you're
talking about. All I know is that I watch the Super Bowl. Okay now this is a very American thing.
The Super Bowl. That's right. We mentioned earlier that in America most people call the game
soccer, not football. Well that's because in America we have a different game called football.
That's right. And so the Super Bowl is like the most important game in the football world. It's
the game that happens every year at the very end of the season. That's right. So this is what we usually
call American football. So you've probably seen it on TV as well. And the Super Bowl is basically
the name of the final sporting event of American football. Just like we have World Cup,
we have the Super Bowl. And the winner of the Super Bowl is the best team that year. That's right.
All right so now let's go on to explain a little bit about how the World Cup works.
The guy went on to explain that there are 32 countries competing. And basically we have
three parts and elimination stage, a semi finals and quarter finals. Okay so basically this
describes the different levels because obviously 32 teams can't compete for one trophy.
At first you have to you have to make the numbers smaller. So 32 becomes 16 becomes eight
becomes four becomes two. That's right. And so we have different groups for these. The first one is
the elimination stage when some teams lose and they go home. That's right. And after that then we have
a quarter finals. So what is quarter finals? The quarter finals are when you have eight teams
and that are basically the top eight teams of the competition and they will play against one
other opponent. So the winner passes on to the next stage which would be the semi-final semi-final.
Well the math makes sense because quarter has to do with four right? That's right. So in the quarter
finals eight teams become four. And in the semi finals four teams become two. That's right.
And then what happens after the semi finals? And then we have the final, which we're basically
the two top teams will compete against each other and there will be one champion.
You say you ask and this is when it gets to very nationalistic people. I very proud of their
countries. Of course of course. And so this basically is what happens and how we get our champion.
And well now let's explain a little bit very quickly about two things that happen in the game during
gameplay when we have a free kick and a penalty kick. Okay so a kick you know you just kick the ball
but sometimes when the ball goes out of bounds or when a player is injured or there's a foul
then that player or his teammate can take a special kick. All right and so a free kick is just a
kick from anywhere right? A free kick is a kick that you get basically according to the referee who says
okay stop the game he's going to kick from inside the lines. That's right. So wherever you are
fouled wherever somebody maybe hit you wrong or something happened from that position you will
kick freely towards the goal or wherever you want. You can pass to your other players as well.
That's right. But a penalty kick is a bit different because you have to be in a special place when you
do it. That's right a penalty kick is when you are fouled inside the box what they call is and
an area very close to the goalie. So if you commit a foul there then the other player will receive
a penalty kick and it will just be him against the goalie and he must kick the ball. I think it's
approximately 10 meters if I'm not mistaken. Yes and this is why it's very dangerous because you're
so close to the goalie and no one can stop you and so when fouls happen inside that special box
it's usually bad news for the goalie. Yeah of course. So this is what happens during a penalty kick
and well basically you have no defender so it's just you the goalie and it can get as you said
very complicated for the goalie. So all right so we've taken a look at a lot of things on language
takeaway. Let's move on now to three phrases on the fluency builder. Fluency builder.
Okay so this is a great word to describe how I felt last week when I watched the England versus
America match. I thought it was a nerve-racking game. That's right. And we heard this in the dialogue right?
Yeah you said it was a very nerve-racking game or the dialogue the guy said it's a very exciting
and nerve-racking sport. So if something's nerve-racking what does it mean? Well basically if you break it
down nerves are those things in your body and your skin that make you feel. So if something is someone
hurts you you feel it because of your nerves. So something that is nerve-racking makes you nervous.
It makes you anxious. It makes you feel very sensitive. That's right so of course the
sporting event is so exciting and you're worried that your country or your team will lose that
you're very nervous and you're very excited. You're very anxious. A lot of things are going on.
Maybe you're sweating. Maybe you're drinking a lot. You don't want to know. You don't want to see your
team lose and so you get very nervous. That's right. And of course if your team is in the world
cup you are cheering on for your team or you're cheering them on. Okay so this is an interesting phrase
because maybe you've heard the word to cheer before you know. Go team go team this is cheering.
But we often say I want to cheer him on. Okay so this is on to me means like I want to cheer him
onto victory. I want to push them toward some goal. And so you hear this a lot. Let's cheer them on
or he was really cheering me on. Maybe feel good. Motivating you. Motivating you. So to cheer someone
on cheer them on. All right so obviously this is why we have cheer leaders right?
Girls at that. Give me a bite. Give me a bite. These are the girls that are
group of girls that cheer teams on. Or men too. I've seen male cheer leaders. That's true.
All right and now when we talked about Brazil they are the team with the most titles under their belt.
Okay we're not talking about a real belt here are we? No no. Now under your belt or under their
belt in this case means that in their history they have the most titles. That's right. I think
it may come from boxing or one of those sports where are you actually where about that says your
title and I think fun. I'm mistaken sometimes boxing belts will have various titles on the belt.
Right the championship belts because they were at after a zoo. I've never heard that before but it
does make sense. But the the important thing to remember here is that it's not just sports you could
say he has 10 years of experience in marketing under his belt. That's right. That means he's
good in his experience at marketing. That's right. So that's right as you said you can use it for work
experience you can use it for titles in work or maybe in education you can say he's got three
masters degrees under his belt. All right so a lot of great stuff there we've taken a look at a lot
of vocab so I think we should listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
What are you doing? What am I doing? What am I doing? Don't you know what date is?
No. It's only the day when the world's biggest sporting event is kicking off. What?
The world cup. The first match is today. It's Mexico versus South Africa. It's going to be a
really good match. Both teams have a very strong offense and have skilled players. I think that
South Africa will probably dominate the first half since they're the host country and all.
I have no idea what you're talking about. The only sporting event we watch at home is the Super Bowl.
This is bigger than the Super Bowl man. Teams from 32 countries compete against each other
every four years and fight to win that trophy. They first start in a group stage with eight groups.
Each group having four teams. The top two teams pass on to an elimination stage before going on
to the semi finals and the quarter finals. Sounds interesting but soccer doesn't really appeal to me.
Are you kidding? Over 700 million people watch the final match of the 2006 World Cup.
It's a very exciting and nerve-racking sport. Each nation is cheering on their team.
Hoping they will become the next champion. So far, Brazil is the team with the most titles under
their belt. They're really good. All I know about soccer is that you can't use your hands and that
players are always falling down trying to get a free kick or penalty kick. It seems like a
Sissy sport to me. Whatever. I'm going to go watch the opening match.
Alright so the World Cup as we said it gathers over a hundred million people to watch the final
in 2006. Now this sport is not very popular in North America. It's not well that's not totally true
because Mexicans really follow football. That's right that's right. But I think in America
in United States it is one of the last popular sports. I was thinking the other day maybe number five
on our list of popular sports. Maybe because what you have American football in the NFL,
you have Major League Baseball, you have the NBA, you have the NHL and I think maybe before soccer
you probably either have golf or tennis or tennis before soccer. Even though the United
States does have its own Major League Soccer. Yep, MLS, Major League Soccer and my hometown team
is Chicago Fire, pretty good team. I heard they were very good. And the LA Galaxy, I think is the
other best team in the States. That's right. Now the United States did host the 1994 World Cup.
And I think this is where a little bit of more interest started to come up and I think Major League
Soccer was formed prior to the World Cup in the United States. That's right. Well there's another
part of it. I mean as young people as children we almost all played soccer. I played soccer. I know
a lot of my friends did as well. It's not popular everywhere but a lot of people play it and
there's not really an audience for soccer in America once you're in the professional realm. And so
the problem is when you pass college you don't think of it as the NBA for example because there's
not as big of an audience and so people just end up doing their normal jobs as opposed to being
professional soccer. I think that has a big something to do with it is the fact that there is not as
much money in this sport professionally as for example the NBA or prestige exactly. Although this is
this is the on the other hand these players that do make it and they really want to play. They go
abroad and they go play in European leagues or something like that. That's right. I think a lot of
the American players who are playing the other day against England were playing against their
their teammate because so many of the American team the American national team play in the English
Premier League. It was really awkward. Well it's a really great sport as I think it's one of the most
popular sports in many other countries as well because it's so easy. All you need is a ball. You need a
group of people. You put two rocks and you have a goal and you start playing. And that's probably
why it's the most international sport because it's very easy to set up. People all over the world
love it and hopefully one day the United States will kind of push it and camp in. Yeah well I hope
this year that'll be coming out. My fingers are down like cross because I'm full nose. All right so
it's a great great topic. We want to know if your country is in the world cup have you ever
qualified for a world cup. There are still many countries who haven't made it. Of course
it's a very small pool of 198 and 899 countries compete to qualify for the world cup in only 32
make it. And you can also tell us who you're supporting. We won't judge. That's right. So we're
waiting for your comments at EnglishPod.com. We'll see everyone there. Bye.