Hello everyone and welcome to English mod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about something that is well not so fun when it happens.
That's right today we're going to talk about those situations where people are trying to take advantage of us.
Alright they're lying to us so they can take our money.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and when we come back in a moment we'll be talking about some of these words and phrases that you're about to hear.
I got an urgent email from Tom. He said he's in London and got robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel.
What? That sounds really dodgy to me.
No way Tom is an honest person he wouldn't lie to me.
No I mean it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent that out.
I mean think about it. Why would he email you instead of calling you?
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money?
For sure. There's so many con artists out there you never really know.
Alright we're back so let's take a look at some language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
In language takeaway Marko one of the first things we hear is that I got an urgent email from Tom.
That's right so this is an adjective something that is urgent.
It's urgent that means it needs to be looked at immediately it's very important.
That's right so you can have an urgent email that means it's very important email or something
in a situation can be urgent. Yeah like an emergency.
The urgent care we talk about at the hospital it's something that needs to be looked at by a doctor
immediately urgently. That's right urgently that would be the adverb.
Now we go on to say that the email is urgent because it's from Tom and the email said that he is in
London and he got robbed.
Alright he got robbed. Alright so to rob is the verb ROB but here it's important to look at the the verb
got. This means that whatever's happening it happened to him to the friend by someone else.
That's right so someone robbed him.
Alright he got robbed that means someone took his money right. That's right.
So the verb would be to get and robbed it would be an adjective ending.
ED but we also have the verb to rob and if you rob someone that means that you are stealing his or her
money. Yeah if I rob Marco means I take Marco's money from him but if I got robbed by Marco it means he
took my money. That's right so remember if you use the verb to rob by itself that means that you are
doing the action or someone is stealing from another person but if you get robbed or a person got robbed
that means he or her got money taken from him. Now the friend got robbed someone took his money
and we've been asked to wire him some money. Okay to wire money. That's right to wire money and this
basically means to send money. It's a very old way or form of sending money. Basically you're sending
money electronically. You don't actually buy an envelope and put some money in it and send it
in the mail. You go to a bank or Western Union and you transfer the money electronically.
That's right so to send an electronic transfer of money we usually say you wire someone some money.
Yeah I'll wire it to you. That's right. Alright now continuing on we the main topic about today's
lesson is about people trying to scam other people. Alright here the verb to scam means to lie
or to be dishonest with someone so that you can take their money or to take advantage of them.
That's right so to scam means to take advantage of someone to lie to someone but you also have a scam
a noun which is a situation where people are trying to take your money. So a very famous scam
might be people in a big city like Paris saying oh I'm a tourist I'm lost can you help me
can you give me some money to go to the train station and really these people they're not lost.
They just want you to give them money. That's right. So this is called a scam and what they're doing is
they are trying to scam you. That's right and so we actually have a word for these
type of people we say they are con artists they are conning you. A con artist okay so we know
what an artist is an artist is a person who maybe paints pictures or you know makes something
creative but a con is someone who breaks the law. Alright so a con artist is someone who creatively
breaks the law. That's right so these are basically thieves or people who take advantage of other
people or steal from other people in a very creative way so there are situations where
they may sell something that doesn't even really belong to them. That's right so the thing to
remember here with a con artist is that there's almost always a story you know you have to they
give you this story they make you believe them and then you give them money or you give them some
help that they don't deserve and that that way they take it away from you. That's right.
Alright so if you're taking a look at a lot of language here let's take a break listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back in a bit. I got an urgent email from Tom. He said he's in London got
robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel. What? That sounds really dodgy to me.
No way Tom is an honest person he wouldn't lie to me. No I mean it seems like someone may have
hacked his email account and sent that out. I mean think about it. Why would he email you instead
do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money? For sure there's so many
con artists out there you never really know.
Alright we're back let's take a look at 4 key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So we've got two friends who are talking one friend says that they got an
urgent email from Tom and the other says wow that sounds really dodgy to me. That's right.
So if something sounds dodgy or something is dodgy it means it doesn't really sound
believable or correct or legal. That's right so maybe I can't trust it. Right.
It's something is dodgy if it doesn't sound like something I would want to trust and I think you
can you can say it about a situation so this robbery it sounds quite dodgy.
Mm hmm. You can also say it about food right? Right this food is looks kind of dodgy it means
it doesn't really look safe. Yeah maybe I'll be sick if I eat it so it's it's quite dodgy looking.
Right or even a person can look dodgy so maybe that person is not really someone you want to trust.
A con artist doesn't always look dodgy but if a con a person looks dodgy and they ask you
for money probably shouldn't give it right. Exactly. All right so that's dodgy. Now the person
answers by saying no way you know Tom is an honest person he wouldn't lie to me he's not dodgy.
No way. Right. Now this is a really popular thing to say and it means basically that's not possible.
I don't agree with you. I disagree and it's pretty forceful. Right.
Actually you're expressing your opinion so if I say the Chicago White Sox are the best baseball
team in the world. No way. No you're wrong. I think the Yankees are the best.
We could go back and forth. No way. Right exactly. But basically you're disagreeing.
That's right. Now the situation evolves around the fact that someone may have hacked
Tom's email account and send out that email. All right so the phrase he would be to hack an account
or to hack a website. It's important to remember that the verb to hack is pretty recent. We talk
mostly about computers and the internet when we talk about hacking. Right. And it means to gain access
all right to go into some buddies account without permission. Right. So maybe illegally or like you
said without permission. So if your email account gets hacked, it means someone else
accessed it without your permission or illegally. So when someone has access to your account they hack it
usually they send out an email with your name. So your friends think it's you. But really it's someone
who is maybe a con artist or or someone who's not trustworthy. That's right. That's exactly
so that's the word to hack or maybe the noun the person that hacks is called a hacker.
Now moving on to our last phrase. When we agree with someone forcefully like we said no way
was to disagree when we do agree we say for sure. That's right. This is basically the opposite.
In this situation we were thinking well do you really think someone is trying to hack his account?
The answer was for sure. That means definitely absolutely. That's right. So for sure it's another
way of agreeing strongly agreeing with someone or with what someone said. For sure. For sure.
All right. So that's all we have for today. Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
I got an urgent email from Tom. He said he's in London and got robbed and needs us to
wire him some money for his hotel. What? That sounds really dodgy to me. No way. Tom is an honest
person. He wouldn't lie to me. No. I mean it seems like someone may have hacked his email account
and sent that out. I mean think about it. Why would he email you instead of calling you?
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money? For sure. There's so many
con artists out there you never really know. All right. We're back so talking about scams and con artists
in China. There is actually a very very very famous scam involving tea. That's right. And this
is something that you might experience in Beijing or Shanghai or any big city. I hope you don't.
But basically as a tourist you're traveling around. You go to a major tourist site like Tiananmen
or the people square in Shanghai. And some other tourists, some Chinese tourists, they come to you
and they say hello. Where are you from? Are you traveling here? We're traveling too. And then
after about half an hour maybe one hour of talking they say, hey, we were thinking about going to
have some tea. There's a tea festival. Would you like to come with us? Right. And you go and you
drink some tea and you chat and you think, wow, I've made some nice new friends. These people are
very nice. And then you get the bill. Right. And it's like $200 US dollars which is pretty crazy for
tea. Exactly. It's a scam. These people are con artists. They build trust. They make you trust
them. They make you think, wow, I have nice new friends. And then they steal your money.
They steal your money. That's right. It's a very popular scam in China. So, and basically if you do
come here, just be aware of it. It's usually young people. They say their university students or
they say they are from another city. And like you say, they build trust. You they invite you to have
tea. And you think, well, why not? You know, to learn more about the culture, to learn more about
the country you're visiting. And they turn out to try to scam you. That's right. And another
popular one is the artists. I'm a local artist. I would like to show you my newest work. And then
they take you and the work is very expensive and they make you buy it. So, be aware. I think what
you said is true Marco that, you know, you just have to be careful and have to recognize that
not everyone wants to be your friend. Exactly. Yes. So, be careful when you're traveling. And I'm
sure it happens in many other countries. Maybe you have some stories that you've experienced
or maybe some local types of scams that you may know about in your country. That's right. Let
us know our website is EnglishPod.com. Try and use those new words. Con artist and scam.
We'll be around answering your questions. Let us know in EnglishPod.com. We'll see you there. Bye.