Hello English learners and welcome back to another great lesson with EnglishPod My Name is Marco
And I'm Erica and today we're bringing you a great intermediate lesson with some really useful vocabulary
Some vocabulary you can use to describe your job
Yes, this is a really common situation when you someone asks you what you do and you have to tell them
Exactly so today's lesson is all about facts
So before we jump into our dialogue, let's start with our vocabulary preview
The vocabulary preview
We have two simple phrases today that you'll hear in our dialogue for our vocabulary preview
The first one is VP VP
So the VP of a company is the vice president's vice president, exactly
Yeah, simple little acronym
And the next word is Fortune 500 company
Fortune 500 company Fortune 500 company so a Fortune 500 company is
I'll let you explain
Well, Fortune magazine ranks the 500 biggest companies in the US
So a Fortune 500 company basically is one of the 500 biggest companies in the US
Okay, that's simple. Yep. All right. Well, with those words, it sounds like we're going to be talking to some important people today
Yes, we are going to be talking to some important people
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time now. It's going to be a little bit fast, but you don't have to worry about it
Because we'll come back and explain all of the important vocabulary
Oh, look this caravan of boyfriend she's always going on about him at the office
Great they saw us they come in this way. Oh man Jessica Arthur hi
I'd like you to meet my boyfriend Greg
He's the VP of quality and safety or a top Fortune 500 food company nice to meet you
This is my husband author hey, how's it going? Hello
Caroline talks about you all the time. I guess it must be pretty busy at work
Wow, yeah VP position is not easy to know
Implement policies and procedures nationwide various departments as well as trained junior managers in FDA and EPA regulations
I also have to oversee daily operations of our quality control for the entire East Coast
That alone means I have 1500 employees under me
Oh, yeah, that sounds exciting and what about you Arthur?
What are you doing for living? Oh?
I'm a top gun pilot
All right great music for our dialogue again, huh chosen by by more of course
Yeah top gun is one of my all-time favorite movies and top gun pilot
What a cool profession an excellent profession much cooler than being like the VP yeah
boring. Yeah, anyway this guy was a bit of a jerk. Don't you think yeah?
You can tell a little bit of the sarcastic tone he had in his voice definitely
But he did use some interesting phrases and we can talk about those now right?
So let's take a look at language takeaway
Language takeaway
Our first word for language takeaways is
Implement
Implement. Let's listen to some examples of this word to help us understand its meaning
example one
Our company has to implement this sales strategy
Example two
Sarah will be responsible for implementing the plan
Example three
All right implemented several new policies
Okay great examples and just in case to implement means to put into action put into action
Great exactly our second word for language takeaways policies policy
policies policies
So policies are basically
rules and regulations exactly formal rules for a company or an organization exactly policies great third word
over C
So when you oversee operations it means like you watch it to make sure it's okay. You supervise it
This is an excellent word to use when you want to talk about your job responsibilities right over C
Great and our last word for language takeaway. It's kind of tricky
So let's listen to how it was used in our dialogue
That alone means I have 1500 employees under me
So this guy has 1500 employees under him meaning he supervises 1500 employees right he manages 1500 employees
He must be a busy man. Yes for 1500 employees how many employees do you have under you Erica?
2 and not quite as much as 1500. Yeah, guess I'm not a VP
Right, right, yeah, hey not yet, but you will okay
All right, so with this in mind we are ready to listen to our dialogue for a second time and this time it's gonna be slower
Oh look there's Caroline and a boyfriend
She's always going on about him at the office. Oh
Great, they saw us they're coming this way oh
Man
Jessica Arthur hi
I'd like you to meet my boyfriend Greg
He's the VP of quality and safety for a top Fortune 500 food company
Nice to meet you
This is my husband author. Hey, how's it going? No
Caroline talks about you all the time. I guess you must be pretty busy at work
Well, yeah, the VP position is not easy
You know I implement policies and procedures nationwide of various departments as well as trained junior managers in FDA and EPA regulations
I also have to oversee daily operations of our quality control for the entire East Coast
That alone means I have 1500 employees under me
Wow, yeah, that sounds exciting
What about you Arthur? What do you do for a living? Oh
I'm a top gun pilot
Okay, great stuff with this now we can start with our fluency builder for today
Fluency builder we heard some excellent phrases in this dialogue some phrases that sound really natural
Hey, yes, especially the first one that we have today is whenever someone talks and talks and talks and just and continuously talks without stopping you would say
She's always going on about him at the office
This is a really natural way of saying keeps talking about right keep talking about him
Yeah, so we have a few examples of how this phrase works let's listen example one
My boss is always going on about how we need to save money. It's all he talks about
Example two
Gary is always going on about his kids. He's always talking about how smart they are
Example three
My mom is always going on about how I should get married
Okay, excellent. It's clear now. Yes, okay
So let's move on to our second phrase for today and this is a great one to use whenever you meet someone for the first time or when you start to talk to someone for the first time great
Hey, how's it going?
So this is a really
Relaxed and natural way of saying how are you are you?
Yeah, so yeah, you can just say hey how's it going? Yeah, really natural sounding now our third phrase is the most important one of our dialogue
Yes, and it's a really common situation when someone asks you about your job
They might say this
Who are they're what do you do for living?
So this is a really great way of asking what work do you do or what is your job? Yes, I know I know a lot of students sometimes say
What is your job? Yeah, and that is it's kind of correct, but not really
It doesn't sound very natural right so you want to use what do you do or?
What do you do for a living sounds great?
That's the way you ask someone what is their job and that's how you sound supernatural
Okay, so we're ready now to listen to our dialogue a last time and now you are ready to understand everything
Oh, look this caravan of boyfriend she's always going on about him at the office
Great this so us
They come in this way oh
Man Jessica Arthur hi, I'd like you to meet my boyfriend Greg
He's the VP of quality and safety or a top Fortune 500 food company nice to meet you
This is my husband author hey, how's it going? Hello
Caroline talks about you all the time I guess it must be pretty busy at work. Wow. Yeah, VP position is not easy
I
Implement policies and procedures nationwide very departments as well as trained junior managers in FDA and EPA regulations
I also have to oversee daily operations of our quality control for the entire East Coast
That alone means I have 1500 employees under me
Oh, yeah, that sounds exciting and what about you Arthur? What are you doing for a living? Oh?
I'm a top gun pilot
Oh
Okay, so I have a little challenge for listeners today. What is it two challenges? Okay?
The first one who performs the song that you heard and what is the song called? Okay, I don't know the
I'm looking forward to seeing what users do and the second one is
What is the number one company in the Fortune 500? Oh, I also don't know this answer
Two great questions, so I expect to see your answers on the comments page
But also we want to know about your
Profession. Yes, tell us about your job tell us what you do and use some of the great phrases you learn today to
Describe your answer great so we hope to see you there, but we're out of time now
So we'll see everyone at EnglishPod.com leave all your questions and of course all the comments and Marko and I are always around to answer your questions
Well until then it's goodbye