Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you the second part of Christmas Chronicles
Another Christmas lesson to get you in the Christmas spirit
Christmas and useful language for all of our listeners today
That's right, in today's lesson we'll be learning some great Christmas vocabulary
and police-related vocabulary as well
Now Christmas, police vocabulary how exactly does that fit together?
Well, they don't
But here at EnglishPod we can make anything happen
So that's why we have done this to be creative, to be creative
So let's take a look at our vocabulary preview for this lesson
The vocabulary preview
In today's vocabulary preview we've got two words from our dialogue
that you will need to know to understand this dialogue
The first one is elves elves elves elves
And this is the plural of the word elf right
So elves are little people
Little people with pointy hats with pointy hats since his helpers
Okay, so elves elves are next word is candy cane candy cane candy cane
So a candy cane is a traditional Christmas candy, right?
Yes, it's red and white and kind of shaped like a like a jay like a jay
Yeah, okay, so very traditional yeah, you hang them on the tree and you eat the Merry Christmas time
Yes, he's like peppermint. Okay, well, I guess we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the first time
And it's gonna be kind of fast, but don't worry if you don't understand everything because we'll come back and talk about some of the language later
It's gonna stay
Really, if I was you can't take me to jail don't you know who I am Chris Cringle, you know pop in the world
Perinoelle Bob of Natale, shungna, all right?
Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before haven't we Joe?
Yeah last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy. Can you believe that?
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha
That's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen? We're all children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts on their stockings
Sorry buddy, you're part in a no-pocking zone. You were speeding and you have no idea
Sad that even if we let you go now your slaves been impounded and those reindeer were taken to the city zoo
What
This is unbelievable
What's this world coming to Christmas is ruined?
What's that up ahead? It looks like
Ells
Whoa, there are suitable candycains
Mate, hey, mate, hey, we're under heavy attack. We need backup
Okay, so Santa has escaped from the police car a thank God
It's like a war over there. They were really firing everything. I know. I mean those elves are
Aggressive very aggressive
Okay, well, we can take a look at some great vocabulary from this dialogue. Why don't we start with our language take away for today
Language take away
In today's language take away. We have five really important words that we hope you will take away from the lesson
Exactly and the first word that we have today is book
Bookt bookt bookt bookt bookt is another way of saying arrested arrested. Yeah, it's a slang word, hey
It's kind of slang. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's a slang word. Okay next word
Speedings speeding speeding
Speeding so Santa was speeding because he was
Going too fast driving too fast. Yeah, going over the speed limit exactly
Third word today is
Impounded
That's when your car gets arrested. Your car gets arrested
Yeah, they take your car to car jail
Okay, so my car is in car jail. I think I understand it's impounded
Okay, so the police take my car and I have to
Pay to get it out. Okay, let's move to our next word
ruined
We have a few examples for us to listen to to understand the meaning of this word
Example one
It's been raining for five days
Ofication is ruined
Example two
Look at this hole you've ruined my favorite pair of jeans
Example three
Sam you've been called stealing from the company your chances for a promotion are ruined
Okay great examples and basically ruined of means destroyed destroyed yeah messed up messed up okay
Now for our last word
Back up
So now for our last word
Okay, so now for our last word and language takeaway
Back up back up back up back up
So backup is help help yeah, right? So when you call for backup you call for help
Yeah, you see it all the time and war movies police call for backup. Yeah, right? I think though
It's important to point out that here the pronunciation and stress of this phrase is really important, hey
Yes, yes, you have to say backup backup backup yeah, so both words are stressed at about the same level, hey
Back up because if you were to stay back up that means to move back exactly. Yeah, it's different so backup
Back up yes the stress is important. All right well, you know what? I think with those words in mind it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time
Really fellows, you can't take me to jail
Don't you know who I am
Chris Kringle, you know
Papnawell, Pernawell, Bob and the Tully, Shondan, are you?
Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before having we Joe? Yeah
Last week we booked this guy who claimed to be the truth fairy can you believe that?
Ha ha ha
It's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen when all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts in their stockings?
Side buddy you will parked in a no parking zone you were speeding and you have no ID
Besides that even if we let you go now
Your sleigh has been impounded and those reindeer were taken to the city zoo
What this is unbelievable what's the world coming to Christmas is ruined?
What's that up ahead? He looks like elves
There's shooting candy kings
Mayday mayday we are under heavy attack we need backup
Okay, so without the sound effects and without any noise
I think it's much more clear now, right a little less dramatic a less dramatic but good language yes
Speaking of good language there's some great phrases I want to look at in this dialogue and so let's do that in putting it together
Put your hands together
We have two phrases in putting it together that we want to show you how you can use in many different situations
In the dialogue we heard this
Last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy
So when you claim to be something you're saying that you are something but it might not be true, right?
Right so for example you can say this woman claimed to be your wife
But she's not but she's not okay. We have a few other examples of how you can use the phrase claim to
Example one
Daniel claimed to be the son of a government minister, but later we found out that he was lying
Example two
The criminals came to have a gun
Example three
This man here just claiming to know your father
That's such a great phrase just by putting it together with another verb
Mean something different but still expresses that same idea right claim to have
She claimed to have a baby or something. Yeah, okay, okay, so let's move to our next phrase
Under heavy
Under heavy so when the dialogue they said we're
Under heavy attack right you can also use this phrase in a couple of other ways
Example one
We're in the heavy attack
Example two
We're under heavy fire
Example three
The prime minister is in the heavy security
So if you're under heavy fire means that there's a lot of fire like gun fire gun fire. Yeah, not like fire fire
Okay, and if you're under heavy security
It means that you have a lot of security a lot of body guards or a lot of
Right like a prime minister a president will be under heavy secure exactly okay
Couple of great phrases really good phrases and with this we can listen to our dialogue a third time
You
Really, thoughts you can't take me to jail don't you know who I am Chris Crangle, you know pop in the world
Perino well Bob of no taller sure not all right. Yeah. Yeah. We've heard that one before haven't we Joe?
Yeah last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy. Can you believe that?
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha that's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit what will happen? We're all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts on their stockies
Sorry buddy your partner no pockings on you were speeding and you have no ID
sides at
Even if we let you go now you're slaves been impenoted and those reindeer were taken to the city zoo
Why this is unbelievable once this world coming to Christmas is ruined what's that up ahead it looks like
Ells whoa there are shooting candycains
Mayday mayday we're in her heavy attack we need backup
So Marco the police mentioned something about the tooth fairy the tooth fairy I don't know maybe some of our listeners
Don't know the story about the tooth fairy so
Can I go ahead and say it? Yes go ahead. Okay. Well when you're small and you lose the tooth your baby teeth
Yeah, you put it underneath your pillow and then you go to sleep and then in the night
The tooth fairy comes into the house flies into the house sneaks under your pillow
Takes the tooth and puts money there. I see so this is a story that parents tell their kids about what happens to their baby teeth
And they get money exchange for it right so I guess it takes away the sadness of losing that tooth. Yeah, yeah
But in South America for example, we have the tooth mouse the tooth mouse. Yes, okay mouse
What is it? How does it call this in stash? Oh well some in some places is called ratoncito betis
Like it has a last name betis a really another place is it just called
Ratoncito which means mouse okay, so it'd be like tooth fairy Smith to me. I had to very Smith
And it's the same thing. It's a little mouse that comes in and steals a little tooth from you and leaves money in exchange
Cool very cool. Yeah, so we go from Santa Claus to Guns and Wars to the tooth fairy only yet English pod exactly
All right guys. I hope you enjoyed today's lesson if you have any questions or comments about the lesson
Please visit our website English pod calm. All right well we're out of time. We got to go
We've got some Christmas shopping to do. Yes Christmas shopping so we'll see you guys later and until then it's goodbye