Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today Marco you and I are talking about movies right?
We're talking a little bit about movies but mostly we're having a big argument.
Okay I kind of like arguments. Lots of great words and phrases for you to learn here in English
but we've got an upper intermediate level lesson with some people who are not getting along very well
It's a couple. Guy and a girl and they're having a fight as couples do.
So we're going to be learning a lot of the different language that they are using in this very
heated debate. So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time and then we'll be right back.
Wow the terrible movie is finally over. Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want
a chick flick. Well you should have picked in the end you always complain about everything.
Not everything just this film. Even the title was ridiculous and it's so long. Those are the
two and a half most wasted hours of my life. So much so that I'm thinking about asking them to
give me my money back. I'm thinking of taking you back home. I thought we could have a nice evening
but you're always so negative. I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have rented or bought
and then thrown in the garbage. You see that's what I'm talking about. I can't stand your
sarcastic jokes anymore. Next time go with your gay friend who's more in touch with his feelings.
Well he's more of a man than you are. At least he appreciates love stories. Love stories more like
one night stands. Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start on those fat drunk friends of yours.
There are no saints. My friends fat. What about those whales you call friends? You're unbearable.
You can walk home. I'm leaving. Fine.
I think the guy was exaggerating a little bit. What do you think? I think they were both
exaggerating. You know by the end of an argument, both people are saying things that maybe they don't
mean. I think we'll talk a little bit more about this towards the end of the show but now why don't we
take a look at language takeaway? Language takeaway. All right. On language takeaway today we have
four words and the first one that you probably saw in the very first sentence is a chick flick.
Chick flick. So first of all the word chick means a woman. It's slang and it's not very nice.
It's not very nice you know. Well I mean between guys you would use it and it's like oh this
chick or that chick but you wouldn't really walk up to a girl and call her a chick right?
Now you wouldn't say hey chick what's up? That's not something you want to say so
chick is a slang word for a girl or a woman and that chick flick is a girl's movie.
So a flick is a movie. Another slang word. Exactly so this is the slang phrase for flicks.
So hey Marka what flicks are showing at the movie theater? All right. Yeah so movies. So in the
chick flick is usually a romantic movie, a drama, something that's very like beaches.
Beach is a chick flick. I don't know if they were seen that.
I'm also also he's just not that into you is one of those new chick flick.
Like how do lose a guy in ten days? Yeah how do lose a guy in ten days or the devil wears
Prada. Bright wars. Bright wars. Wow lots of chick. I've actually never seen any one of these
except how to lose a guy in ten days. I've actually only seen that one. All right so chick flick is a girl's
girl's movie and next up we have a word is sarcastic. What's sarcastic jokes?
So sarcastic jokes or somebody being sarcastic. God Marka you're always so sarcastic.
So what would sarcasm sound like? Yeah he's a really funny. All right so it's not really what you're
saying it's kind of how you're saying it. Right so it's kind of like by saying he's really funny.
You're saying yeah he's a funny guy but if I say oh he's really funny. I'm saying he's not funny
he's being mean or he's a jerk. Yeah he's a jerk. The sarcasm is kind of one of those things that
it's a little bit difficult to learn how to do or to actually get it right especially in English right?
Yeah Marco great explanation. Exactly that's the way it goes. Oh yeah you're so funny. So
wow you're amazing you should go to you went to sarcasm school. So my parents would be really mean.
Have that. Sorry you're just kidding. All right so apart from being sarcastic you can
criticize someone. Like you're ever critical. All right sorry I'll stop. You're really into character
right now. All right so critical to criticize someone is to to complain about them or to say that
things that they do are not very good. So you can criticize a person or a movie. Yeah so this movie
wasn't very good. It wasn't funny. The actors were bad. It was really long. These are criticisms.
Criticism. All right well and then moving on the girl was finally tired of the guy and his
complaints and she said he's unbearable. Gosh you're unbearable so the root of this word is to be able
to stand something to bear it. And so if you're unbearable something is unbearable you just can't
stand it. All right so you're tired of it you can't stand it. She thinks he's so unbearable she
makes him get out of the car and she leaves. Yeah she said you can walk home. All right so that's an
unbearable person right? Okay so we took a look at those four main words here in our dialogue.
Let's move on now to some of the phrases that we found in fluency builder. fluency builder.
This first one's a common one especially when we talk about women and men and the relationship
between women and men we say about men that maybe they should be more in touch with their feelings
or their feminine side. Okay so if you're saying to be more in touch with your feminine side what
exactly are you saying? So the question well what you're saying is that you want to
be able to express your feelings more or you want to be able to understand more about
your your feminine side or something like this. So to be in touch with is more about yourself it's
about self reflection and self understanding so so you could say I'm a very serious person but I
want to make some changes in my life so I'm trying to be more in touch with my inner child.
Your inner child. All right so to be in touch with and it's usually related to feelings to
something intangible to behavior. To behavior. All right moving on now a heated phrase a
one night stand. Oh I'll let you explain this one Marko. All right so a one night stand is a casual
and very quick temporal encounter that's usually sexual encounter. It's romantic right so it can be
between two different people they meet each other one night they have a relationship for one night
only and then they never see each other again so it's a it's casual. It's casual very good. So yeah
you would see this you see this a lot in shows like you know sex in the city you know yeah they have a lot
of one night stands in that show. All right so a one night stand and well related to this the girl
was criticizing his friends and she said they're no saints. Okay so you could say this many
different ways he's no saint. She's no saint or I'm no saint. You're no saint. So a saint is a good
person it's a word that we use in religion to say someone who's like mother Teresa or someone who's
just really good and kind and doesn't commit any sins. Exactly and so to say I'm no saint is to say
well I do bad things or I say bad things I'm not perfect okay so he or they they're no saints
they do bad stuff too. Yeah very good so that's the way that you would use he's no saints they're
no saints. All right so I think now we should listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back.
Wow the terrible movie is finally over. Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want
to end up seeing a chick flick. Well you should have picked in the end you always complain about
everything. Not everything just this film even the title was ridiculous and it's so long. Those
are the two and a half most wasted hours of my life. So much so that I'm thinking about asking
them to give me my money back. I'm thinking of taking you back home. I thought we could have a nice
evening but you're always so negative. I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have
rented or bought and then thrown in the garbage. You see that's what I'm talking about. I can't
stand your sarcastic jokes anymore. Next time go with your gay friend who's more in touch with his
feelings. Well he's more of a man than you are at least he appreciates love stories. Love stories
more like one night stands. Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start on those fat drunk friends of
yours. They're no saints. My friends fat. What about those whales you call friends? You're unbearable.
You can walk home. I'm leaving. Bye.
All right so Catherine is this an argument that you would say is a typical among couples or maybe
people that are probably about to break up right? Not couples that are happy. I would say but
yeah you definitely have people who are well I guess it's kind of the battle of the sexes right?
You have people who are different genders and so they don't always understand each other. You
want to have your girlfriends as a girl and your girlfriends behave and talk in a certain way together
and guys do the same thing but with their friends and so sometimes you have these clashes these
interactions that are negative and you know when people are upset with each other they say mean things
and especially I think in this case they don't really like each other's friends.
Exactly. That's a kind of a common thing like a guy doesn't like his girlfriend's friends
because maybe they gossip too much or something like that and the same thing with the girl
right because a guy's friends maybe drink too much. Thanks a lot. I'll explain to him how to say
many car games. So I think a lot of times these problems also have to do with the fact that like
when a girl is with her girlfriend she may be acts differently or with when a guy is with his
guy friends and so that's weird sometimes for the relationship because you see your partner acting
differently with other people. Do you like your boyfriend or girlfriend's friends? Do you get
fights about this kind of stuff? Or you know what the in-laws? That's the whole number of situations.
All right so we want to hear from you and also if you have any questions or comments suggestions
come to EnglishPod.com and you can leave it on our lessons page or you can email us at EnglishPod
PraxisLanguage.com. We hope to see another exciting video future. Please get in touch with us.
That's all for today. So bye. Bye.