Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have another holiday lesson for you guys. It's an intermediate
level lesson but it's not about Christmas and it's not about New Year's. So what's this holiday
moment? It's like, after Christmas but before New Year's. Okay so let's look at this holiday
and today's vocabulary preview. Very cabbiery preview. All right so as you noticed in the title this
is called boxing day. So like fighting boxing. Kind of like boxes right it's more related to
boxes. Exactly so this is a this is a holiday that we don't actually celebrate in America.
It's celebrated in what are called commonwealth countries. That means countries that used to be a
part of Great Britain or that are a part of Great Britain so England. Okay. Scotland, Canada, Australia.
And this is a day where, well it's considered a holiday because it's a bank holiday. That means
all the banks close. No one's at work. It's the day after Christmas. So it's December 26th.
And it's traditionally a day when you give money or gifts to the poor. Okay and so this is more
less what we're going to be talking about but more modern right before it was like that but now
it's kind of become this shopping thing right? It has. It's a day when everyone goes to the sales
after Christmas to return things or to buy new things. So we're going to hear about this right away
in today's dialogue and when we come back we'll be talking about some of the phrases and words that you've heard.
What do you think of this one? Yeah it's so so. And this one? Two flashy?
Nah not too flashy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous? Yes. Are you even listening?
I'm trying to have a conversation with you. And I'm trying to watch the game but you're
yapping on about your new clothes. Well I have to decide which gifts to keep in which to exchange for
better ones when I go to the box and they sales this afternoon. Well could you do me the favor of
making this quick? It's the third quarter you've been blabbering on since the first. Oh your precious
game. You watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at least three
goals. Oh no you didn't. You didn't just insult the sales where he seals did you? Why don't you just
just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until his sales row? I might just
enjoy your stupid game and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas!
I love the genre. All right great so we're back and interesting the the couple fighting right after
Christmas. Well I think it's very common to hear fights around the holidays. People are very stressed
out and tired of of dealing with family and presence and all the stress right? Exactly. But we'll
talk about that a little bit later on right now. I don't we take a look at four key words in
language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay these first two words are words that the wife uses
in talking about some of these clothes that she got as presents. So she says well she asks her husband
is this too flashy flashy? All right so you know flash like the camera flash right this big light.
Now flashy when you're talking about clothes or an object is it it's too noticeable right? It's too
noticeable to bright too loud so for example a black shirt is not flashy. But an orange shirt.
An orange shirt with buttons and bells and black rhinestones diamonds that's flashy. All right okay
flashy. Flashy can also mean something that is it's supposed to look expensive. Okay so that sweater
was a little bit flashy according to her and but also she talked about another sweater being hideous.
So hideous is an ugly word and it means ugly. Ugly okay so I could say this sweater is
hideous. That means it's not only ugly it's really ugly. Okay it's more than ugly. All right a hideous sweater
and moving on the guy now was a little bit irritated and stressed out and he said you keep yapping on
about your new clothes. So what is this yapping on? Well yapping is a sound like yapping. So yapping
to yapping on about means to continue to talk and talk and talk about something. Okay because he's
watching the football game on TV and she's talking and talking and talking and he's annoyed. So this
is rude to say stop yapping about this sorry stop yapping on about your game. All right it's very
rude it means just stop talking I'm annoyed and well then he mentioned another phrase that it's
pretty much the same thing right blabbering on. To blabber to blabber on about means to talk about
something but to not really make sense okay so it's just worthless talk. So you're just talking
to talk you're not really saying anything interesting. Exactly and so sometimes we make fun of
people who blabber on about things because they're not important to us or they sound stupid.
All right okay so four key words there blabbering on yapping on why don't we listen to them again
in the dialogue. What do you think of this one? Eee so so. And this one too flashy.
Nah not too fludgy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous? I guess. Are you even listening?
I'm trying to have a conversation with you and I'm trying to watch the game but you're yapping
on about your new clothes. Well I have to decide which gifts to keep in which to exchange for
better ones when I go to the boxing day sales this afternoon. Well could you do me the favor of
making this quick it's the third quarter and you've been blabbering on since the first. Oh your
precious game you watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses
by at least three goals. Oh no you didn't you didn't just insult the sales where he seals did you?
Why don't you just just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until his sales are over?
I might just enjoy your stupid game and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas!
All right we're back so now we have a couple of different phrases that we want to look at on fluency
builder. Fluency Builder. Okay so this first phrase is very closely related to the the days
after Christmas especially here I'm boxing day. We've got someone who's talking about going to the
stores to the sales to exchange her gifts for better gifts. Okay it took change something for something
better. This is a very common construction it's an important phrase when talking about shopping.
So when we look at this construction you would say to exchange this sweater for a better one of
our larger one. Exactly so you can change the adjective the word that's describing it so you can say
it took change these shoes for bigger ones. I could also joke and I could say I'm going to
exchange my boyfriend for a better one. Right. If he's being rude to me. Okay so to exchange
something for something else. Exactly. All right and then we saw another phrase that the husband
replied to when she offended him with his football team he said oh no you didn't. Didn't what?
I know I didn't what no you didn't what. All right so this like he said doesn't make sense alone
but some cultural context might help. In English we often say um say this phrase to me.
Oh no you didn't just say that. Oh you didn't just insult my team. He's saying I can't believe you just
said that. He's upset because what she said was rude or mean. Okay okay so I could say you know
Marko I think I could or sucks. Oh no you didn't. I did just say I don't think so actually but
it's usually a response right? You have to wait until somebody maybe says something mean or something
that you know really hurts your feelings or you don't agree with when you respond to this but you
are usually very very offended right when you say. Exactly it's always a response to a comment
that has made you angry or upset. Okay and our last phrase is when they finished talking and they
were fighting uh she left and said I might just just what? I know just what? See again these are
common phrases but they don't seem to make my sense alone. I might just so let's listen to this is
a response again. This is a response to the line before it. Um why don't you just just go and return
all of those stupid clothes and not come back until much later and she says hmm I might just I might
just do exactly what you just said. Okay she's threatening him she's saying I might just go out and
not come back for 10 hours. All right I might just do that. Okay so that's a way to say what you said
I might do that and I'm threatening you. So again it's usually a response right or a threat as you said.
So I can say Marco why don't you just leave? All right I might just oh what are they going to
do in this studio now? All right so uh three interesting phrases there why don't we listen to
all the words and phrases again in our dialogue one last time.
What do you think of this one? Eh so so. And this one? Too flashy.
Nah not too flashy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous? Yes. Are you even listening?
I'm trying to have a conversation with you and I'm trying to watch the game but you're yapping on
about your new clothes. Well I have to decide which gifts to keep in which to exchange for
better ones when I go to the boxing day sales this afternoon. Well could you do me the favor of making
this quick it's the third quarter you've been blabbering on since the first. Oh your precious game
you watch the same game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at least three
goals. Oh no you didn't you didn't just insult the sales where he seals did you?
Why don't you just just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until a sales
road? I might just enjoy your stupid game and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas!
All right we're back so boxing day as you said is usually a commonwealth thing and the
United States you don't really have it right? We do not my family I don't know why but my family
sometimes celebrates that we have friends who come over and we have a nice boxing day meal but
I've been told that the tradition in commonwealth countries is to watch sporting events local
sporting events and to go shopping for all these bargans and bargans and exchange all those ugly
hideous annoying or bad gifts that you received at Christmas. Right so it's usually like the after
Christmas sales. Exactly so if you have any special boxing day traditions I'd be very curious to
hear them again not a holiday related to the sport boxing it's spelled the same way and it
looks the same but they're very different. No so if you have any stories or questions about the
things that we talked about today please do let us know on our website EnglishPod.com.
All right we'll see you guys there and until next time bye everyone.