Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you the sequel of I'm sorry I love you
Part two part two that's right I guess a lot of our listeners enjoyed the first part
and since it was such a romantic dialogue and we're bringing part two so it's even more romantic
and I'm sure everyone is gonna find some great and useful language in it
that's right we've got language that we used to talk about dates and date yeah so useful
language for when you're going on a date that's right well before we look at this date language
let's listen to the dialogue for the first time
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken I feel just awful about this whole thing
I want to make it up to you let me take you out to dinner tonight my treat
oh that sounds great I'd love to here's my address pick me up a date perfect
thank you for such a lovely evening the food was amazing and I had a great time
me too you look so beautiful tonight I wish this night would never end there's something that I
have to tell you but what is it I woke up today thinking that this would be just like any other day
and I was wrong it's with the fate brought us together I crashed into your life and you
into mine and this may sound crazy but I'm falling in love with you Veronica
wow such a romantic dialogue it really sounds like they're falling in love
yeah it's a really romantic thing that's going on right now but there was some really useful words here
so why don't we take a look at language takeaway language takeaway today we have three words for
language takeaway and the first one is relieved relieved so we have some great examples on how we
use relieved and I'm really sure you can understand the meaning from the sentences
example one they were relieved to hear that the company would not be making any layoffs
example two I'm so relieved to hear your voice I was worried something happened to you
I guess relieved is like a happy or relaxed feeling that you get if you avoid something bad right
I'm so relieved that didn't happen yeah now for our second word pick me up pick me up pick me up
so when you ask someone to pick you up you're saying basically come and get me okay so let's let's give
a couple of examples um my husband was supposed to pick me up from work yesterday but he forgot
does that really happen yes all right we'll have a talk with him or we could also say oh I need to hurry
up the taxi will pick me up at seven yes so come and get me right mm yep and our final word
in today's language takeaway is ordinary ordinary ordinary ordinary so ordinary is a normal word yes
meaning it's normal uh huh nothing uncommon about it yeah so you can have like an ordinary person
an ordinary day ordinary day ordinary life uh huh nothing exciting about it what else is ordinary
ordinary podcast an ordinary podcast which English pot is not okay yeah so ordinary okay great words
and I guess now we can listen to our dialogue a second time this time it'll be a little bit slower and
this will help you to understand the language more clearly
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken I feel just awful about this whole thing
I want to make it up to you let me take you out to dinner tonight my treat that sounds great
I'd love to here is my address pick me up bad eight perfect thank you for such a lovely evening
the food was amazing and I had a great time me too you look so beautiful tonight I wish this night
would never end there's something I have to tell you what is it I woke up today thinking this would
be just like any other ordinary day but I was wrong a twist of fate brought us together
I crashed into your life and you into mine and this may sound crazy but I'm falling in love with you Veronica
okay so we looked at some great vocabulary and now we can look at some great phrases so let's
start with fluency builder fluency builder today we have three great phrases so why don't we just
start with the first one yeah the first one we heard at the beginning of the dialogue make it up to you
make it up to you make it up to you okay so we have some great examples on how we use make it up so let's listen
example one I'm sorry I forgot your birthday how can I make it up to you
example two I feel terrible for calling your mother fat I want to make it up to her so I got her these flowers
example three John forgot my anniversary again he's going to have to make it up to me
we can see from the examples that when you use the phrase make it up to you you're kind of saying
you want to balance something bad you did with some good action right right so if you call your
mother and law fat you better buy her at least some flowers or a card or something to make it up
right yeah so the bad action was calling her fat and the balancing good action was the flowers yeah
I don't think flowers will be enough though hmm looks like a doomed marriage okay our second phrase
my treat my treat my treat so we use this phrase when we want to say I'll invite you I'll pay for you
I'll pay I'll pay I'll right so I can say hey let's go get some beers it's my treat
oh thanks Marko so I'm paying right yeah my treat and our last phrase for fluency builder
a twist of fate a twist of fate a twist of fate so Erica what is a twist of fate a twist of fate
is an unplanned event that has a big impact on your future or your life okay Marco can you give us
an example of a twist of fate all right for example okay you're supposed to catch a flight
to another country all right but you're late so you miss your flight okay and that flight crashes
wow right so that's a twist of fate so yeah it's like it's like fate it's like destiny
you were you weren't supposed to be on that flight okay so a twist of fate a twist of fate
great on a happier note let's listen to the dialogue a third time
I'm so relieved that your ankle wasn't broken I feel just awful about this whole thing
I want to make it up to you let me take you out to dinner tonight my treat
oh that sounds great I'd love to here's my address pick me up a date perfect
thank you for such a lovely evening the flu was amazing and I had a great time
me too you look so beautiful tonight I wish this night would never end there's something that I have to
tell you but what is it I woke up today thinking that this would be just like any other day
and I was wrong the twist of fate brought us together I crashed into your life and you
into mine and this may sound crazy but I'm falling in love with you Veronica
okay so we're back Erica I know you have a story of a twist of fate in your life
yes recently actually this happened I went to this party and at the party there was a contest like
sort of a lottery you could buy some tickets and win a prize and the prize was a weeklong vacation
okay so I went with some friends of mine and they were tired so they left early and they gave
me their tickets and guess what happened what happened we won we won the weeklong vacation
wow yeah it was amazing so that was a really lucky twist of fate yeah that's a good story yeah
I'm sure it wasn't that good of a twist of fate for your friends yeah but they were very
generous and let me have the prize anyway all right well we want to hear your stories of maybe
some type of twist of fate that you've had yes maybe love stories maybe tragic stories any story
so be sure to leave your questions in comments and your stories at our website englishpod.com
and where you can also find us to answer any questions or doubts yes that's right so
I guess until then it's goodbye