Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
And I'm Erica
Today we're bringing you part two of another great lesson that we had
Yes, new guy in town
Then new guy in town
Part two
Kind of a creepy story
Yes
Yeah, and this one is also a little bit strange, a little bit weird
Yeah, unusual outcome, unusual ending
But it has to do a lot with invitations
That's right
So an invitation is when you ask somebody to do something with you
Right
Adinner invitation
So we're going to be talking about invitations and inviting people to do things
Okay
Well, with that, let's listen to the dialogue for the first time
Oh, Armand, thank you for such a thoughtful invitation
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner
Don't you think so, Ellen?
Oh, yes, of course
We'd love to come over
Can I bring anything?
No, don't worry about it
I'll take care of everything
I'll see you tonight come with an appetite
Then what I will
I don't want to go over to his place with dinner
He gives me the creeps
Why an earth did you accept?
Come on, Ellen
It'll be nice to get to know him besides
He's new to the neighborhood
And it'll be rude to decline his invitation
I guess so
He always wrote me into things like this
Ladies
Thank you for coming
You look delicious
I mean beautiful
Please come in
Oh, Armand, you are too kind
How did I get myself into this?
Wow, I'm really anxious to see what happens in this dinner party
Yeah, I guess we'll have to stay tuned and find out
For part three
Yeah
All right, well, we have some really great vocabulary
So I guess we can start with language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, on language takeaway
Today we have three great words
Erica, why don't you start us off with the first one
The first word is
Thoughtful
So when you're thoughtful
You're kind
You're kind, you're considerate
Yes, two other people
You think about what the other person would like
Right
And you do that thing
It's so thoughtful of you
Yeah
Our second phrase
Give me the creeps
This is kind of a funny phrase
But I think if we listen to some examples
We'll understand the meaning
Example one
Horrible is giving me the creeps
Example two
Stop it, you're giving me the creeps
Example three
I saw this really scary clown
It gave me the creeps
So I can see this one means to make me feel uncomfortable
Right, it makes me feel
Like scared
Yeah, scared
Yeah, it gives me the creeps
And our last phrase for language
Take away
Rope me into
Rope me into something
So if you wrote me into something
It's like you convinced me to do something
But I don't really want to do
Right, so I wrote you into lending me your car
Yes
What's a bad idea
That was a bad idea
And you wrote me into going out for beer
After work
Yeah, that was a great idea
Alright, so I guess we could listen to our dialogue again
This time a little bit slower
And you'll be able to understand the language a little bit more clearly
Oh, Armand
Thank you for such a thoughtful invitation
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner
Don't you think so Ellen?
Oh, yes, of course
We'd love to come over
Can I bring anything?
No, don't worry about it
I'll take care of everything
I'll see you tonight
Come with an appetite
I know I will
I don't want to go over to his place for dinner
He gives me the creeps
Why on earth did you accept?
Oh, come on Ellen
It will be nice to get to know him
Besides, he's new to the neighborhood
And it will be rude to decline his invitation
I guess so
You always write me into things like this
Ladies
Thank you for coming
You looked delicious
I mean beautiful
Please come in
Come in
Oh, Armand, you are too kind
How did I get myself into this?
Well, I guess that's a lot more clear
And with that, we can start putting it together today
Put it together
Today we've got three words and phrases
That we want to show you how you can put together and use differently
The first one is appetites
Appetite
So appetite is like a strong desire for food
Right?
Right, an appetite
We've got some examples that show you how to use this phrase
Let's listen
Example one
Mmm, dinner's meal so good
It's giving me an appetite
Example two
You're sure eating a lot
You must have a big appetite
Example three
I'm getting sick
Have a fever and I lost my appetite
Okay, so we saw some great examples of appetite
You can lose your appetite
That's right
You have a big appetite
Small appetite
A healthy appetite
Right
So it just means a desire for food
Because I prefer food
Okay
Great, what's our second phrase for today?
Get to know someone
Get to know
So when you get to know someone is
You talk to them and you find out what they do
Yeah, you get more familiar with them
More familiar, right?
For example, we can say I got to know her in Spanish class
And she's a really nice person
Yeah, or you can say
Our mom, Ellen and Doris got to know each other at a dinner party
Right
Or you can say if you get to know me
You'll see that I'm not a bad guy
Yeah
That's true
Okay, get to know
And our third phrase is
Why on earth?
This is like a saying
Yeah
You can use it in a lot of different ways
So we've got some examples for you
Let's listen
Example one
Where on earth is my phone?
Example two
How on earth did you learn English in one month?
Example three
What an earth is it?
So when you ask a question with on earth
So why on earth?
How on earth?
What on earth?
It's like you're showing a lot of surprise
Okay, great stuff
So let's just listen to our dialogue at third time
Oh, our mom, thank you for such a thoughtful invitation
It's really very nice of you to invite us over for dinner
Don't you think so, Ellen?
Oh, yes, of course
We'd love to come over
Can I bring anything?
No
Don't worry about it
I'll take care of everything
I'll see you tonight
Come with an appetite
I know I will
I don't want to go over to his place for dinner
He gives me the creeps
Why on earth did you accept?
Come on, Ellen
It'll be nice to get to know him
Besides
He's new to the neighborhood
And it'll be rude to decline his invitation
I guess so
You always wrote me into things like this
Ladies
Thank you for coming
You look delicious
I mean beautiful
Please come in
Oh, Ellen, you are too kind
How did I get myself into this?
We want to know what you think happens next
Yes
What happens in this dialogue next?
So we want you to send us your idea of what happens next
And we're going to choose the best one
That's right, Marco and I will choose the best
Continuation of the story
And we'll use that in part three of the new guy in town
That's right
So you can give it any direction you want
And of course we'll publish the name of the author
Mm-hmm
With the lesson
Yes
I'm really anxious to see what ideas come up
And how we can end this dialogue
I know we've got a lot of really creative users out there
So I'm really looking forward to this
That's right
So be sure to send us your ideas
Either a private message
Or you can post it on the comments section
That's right
This lesson
And any other questions or doubts
Go to EnglishPod.com
And you can leave them there
Yes, Marco and I are always happy to answer your questions
Okay, folks, so until then it's
Goodbye
Bye