Hello English learners, welcome back to English.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about being clean.
Yeah, we're going to be doing the laundry, right?
It's a very important part of everyone's weekly schedule.
And not only important, but I find it to be a little bit difficult because you know like
washing machine and what clothes you should mix with what and you know how much detergent and how long
it's such a complicated process.
Well, let's say this.
It might not be difficult, but it's very easy to mess up.
Exactly.
Yeah, that's the problem.
It's very easy to like just ruin your favorite t-shirt if you don't do laundry correctly.
Or all of your white socks turn pink, for example.
Right.
So we're going to be looking at a lot of vocabulary and phrases related to this topic.
And before we get started with the dialogue, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very cablery preview.
Okay, so central to all of these phrases and words that we're going to be hearing is a thing
and electric thing that helps us wash our clothes.
Right, a washing machine.
All right, pretty simple.
Right, so washing is to wash washing and machine.
So they go together washing machine.
Right, simple.
So it's easy now.
You just put all your clothes in this thing and it washes it for you.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Now you know, a lot of people don't like to use washing machines.
Because it's here, it doesn't really clean the clothes as well as doing it by hand.
Really?
Well, I'd say most clothes get get washed pretty well with the washing machine.
But if you have those hard to, hard to get stains or some dirt, maybe it's good to have
a washing board.
A washing board.
Yeah, where you can really scrub it yourself.
And we'll funny you mentioned that word stain because it's our second word that we're
going to preview a stain.
All right, a stain is some color.
Maybe some food or wine or grass that you can't remove from your clothes.
Right.
So it's very common.
You're having a nice dinner and all of a sudden you spill wine on your shirt.
So you have a wine stain.
I hate that.
And you can also have stain on your carpet.
Right.
So if you spill some coffee on your carpet, it's got a little circle that's brown
forever.
Right?
Or you know, even some people have stain the teeth.
Get them turned back white with a little money to your dentist.
Exactly.
So those are the two words that we're going to be looking at today in vocabulary preview.
So let's listen to our dialogue.
Let's see what's happening with these people that are doing laundry.
Okay.
Let's go through this one more time.
I don't want any more ruined or dyed blouses.
I know.
Okay.
So I have to separate the colors from the whites and put them in this strange looking
contraption so-called washing machine.
Right.
You have to turn it on and program it depending on what type of clothes you're washing.
For example, for delegates, you should set a shorter washing cycle.
Also be sure to use fabric softener and this detergent when washing.
So complicated.
Okay.
What about this red wine stain?
How do I get it out?
This is a white t-shirt.
You can just pour a little bit of bleach on it and it will do the trick.
Cool.
Then I can just throw everything in the dryer for an hour and it's all set, right?
No.
Since you're washing delegates and cotton, you should set the dryer to medium heat
and for 20 minutes.
You know what?
I'll just have everything dry cleaned.
Okay.
So you've got someone who is maybe doing the laundry for the first time.
And he's not really understanding the instruction.
That's good.
Well, that's the thing I tell you.
It's a little bit difficult and it's very tedious at times to try and do laundry like
this.
Well, the first thing it's maybe tedious about it is that you have to really worry about
what colors go together.
Right.
So let's take a look at those words that were related to doing laundry now in language
takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay.
The first word we have is actually related to a joke we made earlier about pink socks.
So if you change the color of something, you're dying it.
Okay.
Die.
So it's pronounced exactly the same way as to die to not live anymore.
But it's spelled differently.
D-Y-E.
Okay.
So it can be a verb or an adjective.
Or an noun.
So something that you put on clothes to change the color is called a die.
But to do this, to change the color of some clothes is to die the clothes.
So that's maybe what happens when you wash a red t-shirt with all your white t-shirts.
Then you have dyeed shirts.
You have pink shirts and now.
And also women when they go to the beauty salon, they die their hair.
Exactly.
So that means you change the color of your hair.
It means it's a long term change.
It's not short.
It's not like one day.
Right.
It means probably for a long time.
So that's the correct word to die.
Very different.
Maybe some people say to paint, which you know, we understand, but the correct form would
be to die.
And next we have a word that describes a certain kind of clothing.
We're not talking about pants or socks.
We're talking about delicate.
Delicates.
So now this adjective delicate, which means it's very easy to break.
Fradial, right?
But this is a noun.
Delicates.
Right.
So you think of something that's easy to break or to ruin.
Maybe you think of underwear.
You know, underwear is something you wear under your clothing.
And so it's generally not as strong as a shirt or pair of jeans.
And so we call these in English, delicates.
Very good.
So you have to be careful when you're washing your delicates because it's happened
to me before.
You put them in with all the clothes and then you have stretched out boxes or something.
Yeah.
So that's why many women I know wash delicates by hand.
So you separate the clothes from the delicates.
Very good.
Now if you're washing delicates or you're washing towels or t-shirts, it's always a good
idea to use fabric softener.
All right.
Fabric softener.
What are these two words?
One of them you understand already.
Maybe it's soft softener.
So it makes it soft.
Yeah.
Something that makes something softer.
We've got fabric softener.
So that's something that makes the clothes that you wash softener.
So fabric is any type of material, right?
Like a textile.
Yeah.
So it could be cotton or silk or nylon.
Linen.
So these are all kinds of fabrics.
So you pour a little bit of this in your washing machine and your clothes come out really
nice and soft.
It feels nice just talking about it.
All right.
And we'll also to wash your clothes to actually make them clean.
You use detergent.
Right.
So many people might want to say the word soap because soap is what we use to wash our hands
and our dishes.
But here we have detergent.
So this is a special soap for your clothes.
Right.
Laundry detergent.
Yeah.
You could just say Laundry detergent or simply detergent.
And now in order to remove those nasty stains that maybe are very hard, you would use
a chemical called bleach.
Oh, right.
So bleach is the dangerous chemical because it smells very strong.
Right.
And it can change the color of your clothes to white or yellow.
So we usually only use bleach with white clothes.
I actually had a friend who changed the color of his hair to white using bleach.
He put bleach on his head and on his hair and it just turned white.
Oh, wow.
So many people do that because they want to go from dark colors to light colors.
And in that case, you wouldn't say you could say that he died his hair white.
But usually you would say he bleached his hair.
It's so we understand that it turned white.
Exactly.
So those five words that we just looked at in language takeaway.
They're important.
They're related to doing laundry.
So before we move on, let's listen to our dialogue again.
But a little bit slower.
Okay.
Let's go through this one more time.
I don't want any more ruined or dyed blouses.
I know.
Okay.
So I have to separate the colors from the whites and put them in the strange looking
contraption so called washing machine.
Right.
You have to turn it on and program it depending on what type of clothes you are washing.
For example, for delegates, you should set a shorter washing cycle.
Also, be sure to use fabric softener and this detergent when washing.
So complicated.
Okay.
What about this red wine stain?
How do I get it out?
Since this is a white t-shirt, you can just pour a little bit of bleach on it.
And it will do the trick.
Cool.
Then I can just throw everything in the dryer for an hour.
And it's all set, right?
No.
Since you're washing delegates and cotton, you should set the dryer to medium heat
and for 20 minutes.
You know what?
I'll just have everything dry clean.
So here at English Paw, we'd like to also provide you listeners with some phrases
that allow you to increase your fluency.
So that means sound more like a native English speaker.
And so today let's check out these phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Alright.
So on fluency builder, we're going to be looking at four words or four phrases.
So the first one was really easy when she was telling the guy
or instructing him how to do the laundry.
She said, let's go through this one more time.
Go through what?
The wall?
No, so it's not actually to go through an object like to pass.
So it's let's repeat or let's rehearse again.
Okay, so normally we say this when there are many different steps to do something.
So let's go through this again.
When you leave work, you go home, you unlock the door, you open the door,
and so it means that there's a process.
There are many steps.
So let's go through this again as a way for us to say let's think about and discuss this process.
Very good.
So we also use it maybe when we're studying.
So let's go through this subject one more time.
Can we go through chapter five again?
And exactly.
So you would reread a chapter five.
Alright, so why don't we listen to a couple of more examples of how we could use go through.
Example one.
I want to go through chapter five again before the exam tomorrow.
Example two.
David, do you have time this afternoon to go over the details of this new project?
Example three.
I went through my contract and it says that I am entitled to 15 vacation days a year.
Now this next phrase is very common when we're using sarcasm when we're trying to make jokes.
So we say so called right so she said this so called contraption.
It's like she doubts that it's really a washing machine.
So I could say her so called boyfriend wants to go out tonight.
So I say that because he doesn't really act like a boyfriend.
So you're being sarcastic.
It's a very good way in easy way of demonstrating sarcasm.
Yeah actually in 1990s in America there was a very famous TV show called my so called light.
And right so this is my so called life.
It's almost like it's not really like I have any control over it.
No or I don't really have a life because it's kind of boring.
Yeah so my so called life not bragging it's joke.
So you can say it my so called friends my so called job.
Basically you can almost be sarcastic with anything.
Yeah but be careful that you know that it's a joke because if you're trying to be serious you might make some people angry.
Right and now well she was explaining the whole process of how to do it and when she recommended using bleach she said that should do the trick trick.
So dogs do tricks right but to do the trick right what is going to be for meaning.
All right so she's saying this should work this should fix your problem.
Mm hmm so that should do the trick.
So Marco I've been having this itch on my foot and I and I just can't I can't seem just to figure out.
What to do with it do you have any suggestions?
Yeah you should maybe just put some ointment on it and I should do the trick.
All right cool thanks for this suggestion.
Yeah so very easy is just a way of saying that should solve your problem.
All right great so that should do the trick or it will do the trick.
Mm hmm and what we have one last phrase all set.
All set so this is another phrase that that has two words that always go together to mean.
Well we're finished we're done everything is ready everything is ready.
We're all set to go on vacation so my bags are packed I have my passport we are all set.
Or after meeting you can say are we all set here that means are we finished is it time to leave?
Very good so we are almost all set let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
Okay let's go through this one more time.
I don't want any more ruined or die blouses.
I know I know okay so I have to separate the colors from the whites and put them in this strange looking contraption so called washing machine.
Right you have to turn it on and program it depending on what type of clothes you're washing.
For example for delegates you should set a shorter washing cycle.
Also be sure to use fabric softener and this detergent when washing.
So complicated okay what about this red wine stain how do I get it out?
Since this is a white t-shirt you can just pour a little bit of bleach on it and it will do the trick.
Cool then I can just throw everything in the dryer for an hour and it's all set right?
No since you're washing delegates and cotton you should set the dryer to medium heat and for 20 minutes.
You know what I'll just have everything dry cleaned.
Have you ever had any laundry miss apps have you ever lost a sock died something?
Have I ever I hate doing the laundry?
Why?
So it's time consuming it takes a lot of time and I just I have no patience.
And so normally when I was in college I would take all of my laundry in a bag and I'd throw in the washing machine and I put it on cold.
You know because cold water it's okay for all colors but hot water makes the colors bleed.
I took out the clothes and put them in the dryer and afterwards I saw all my clothes were clean except for my three sweaters which were small enough for babies.
Oh you're so cute.
Yeah I shrunk three of brand new sweaters.
Oh that's too bad.
The problem that I have when doing laundry is that I forget that I started doing laundry so all of a sudden you know I'm doing laundry in the morning and then.
Closer or washed but they're still in the washing machine and I remember like the next day so then the clothes are like kind of smelling like kind of humid because they're moldy.
Yeah so I have to re wash them and it's just like a pain.
Yeah but doing laundry is sometimes so time consuming but let us know what you think.
Do you like doing laundry or have you ever lost a sock?
I think everyone has lost a sock or something in the washing right?
I think there's a secret home for socks somewhere.
Maybe it's an Australia or something.
So come to our website EnglishPod.com.
Give us all your feedback, question, comments or suggestions and we're always there.
Alright I hope to hear from you soon and until next time everyone.
Bye.