Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and this is our 300th lesson here at EnglishPod so it's a special lesson.
But today we're talking a little bit about dating.
That's right today we're going to talk about dating now in a little bit of a less conventional way,
a new type of dating, very modern with using technology.
Using technology that's right. So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
Oh, I can't have a date.
Really? Wow, with who?
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months.
She's really cool and she's driving over here this weekend.
Wait a minute.
You mean you met her online?
Yeah, I send up for a website called Match.com and it's great.
You fill in all your details and preferences like if you are a smoker or if you have any pets.
Then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them or chat.
That's kind of weird. What if she's a psycho or something like that?
It's the same as meeting people anywhere in dating them.
I'm just tired of going to bars being set up for dates by my friends.
I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy.
I guess it does seem logical. I'll have to check it out.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of these keywords
with that we've picked out for you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word is a word that you're going to hear English speakers say all the time,
especially if they're Americans. So cool is our first word.
Right, this guy described this girl that he is seeing as really cool.
She's really cool. So what does that mean if I describe someone as a cool person?
A cool person is someone who you like. It's a good thing. So someone who is cool,
I think of as relaxed and interesting and someone who maybe had lots of ideas or things to say.
Okay, so if you say that a person is cool, you're saying that you like that person.
Now what if you say something is cool, like Paris is really cool?
Paris is cool. It's a cool city. That means it's an interesting city. It's something that you like.
Maybe you're trying to recommend someone to go there. You can also say that movie was really cool.
So again, it means you liked it. Yeah. Okay. So talking about dating this friend, it was a bit
surprised when he said that he met this girl online. That's right. So online, where is this place online?
In cyberspace. All right. So online means on the internet. And we often use this
when describing things. So EnglishPod is an online English learning site.
That's right. So anything that is in the internet, in cyberspace, you say that is online.
So our website is online or maybe you have pictures online. I have many photographs online
or I like to meet people online. Okay. So continuing on, we talked about a website that obviously
that's online where you find people and talking about preferences, you mentioned that you can stay
to whether you are a smoker or if you have pets. So what is a person that's a smoker?
Well, many of you have probably heard the term to smoke before. I smoke cigarettes. I smoke.
But a smoker is a person who smokes cigarettes. And so I could say that I want a non-smoker
if I'm looking for a boyfriend. Right. Because I don't want someone who smokes. But maybe if you do
smoke, you can say I'm looking for a smoker. Someone who does smoke. Okay. So his friend was a little
bit concerned saying, well, that's weird. Why did this girl is a psycho or something like that?
All right. A psycho. Now maybe you've heard of the movie psycho. But psycho is something that we use
in English to say that someone is really crazy, almost scary, crazy. It comes from the word
psycho path, right? That's right. And a psychopath is someone who is crazy, but also very dangerous.
So obviously when we use this word, we're describing someone as being a little bit strange
or maybe even a little bit dangerous. That's right. So we don't want any psychos to come and
talk to us online, right? That's right. So he went on to explain how dating is just the same
online as it is offline and that he thinks it's a really cool alternative, even if you're shy.
So something is an alternative if you have different options, maybe dating by going to a bar
and meeting someone is what normal people do, but an alternative to that would be dating online.
That's right. I mean, it's another option. So the word alternative is a second option.
Another option. Right. For example, if I want to go have a Thai food tonight, but you don't want to,
I'd say, hey, Mark, what can you give me an alternative idea? That is the other option.
All right, great. So a lot of words in this very interesting dialogue. Stay with us. We'll be right back
where we'll take a look at Fluency Builder.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow? Oh, I can't have a date. Really? Wow, with who? This girl I've been
chatting with for the past couple of months. She's really cool and she's driving over here this weekend.
Wait a minute, you mean you met her online? Yeah, I send up for a website called match.com and
it's great. You fill in all your details and preferences, like if you're a smoker or if you have
any pets, then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them or chat.
That's kind of weird. What if she's a psycho or something like that? It's the same as meeting
people anywhere and dating them. I'm just tired of going to bars being set up for dates by my
friends. I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy. I guess it does
seem logical. I'll have to check it out.
All right, we're back and we've picked out five key phrases for you. Let's check those out on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. All right, the first phrase we've got here is one that we often use in English
spoken English to talk about seeing our friends. Okay, so the first person says,
do you want to hang out tomorrow to hang out? That's right. So let's hang out. We never hang out any
more. What does that mean? Well, it's hard to define because you can do many things when you're hanging
out. But basically it means friends being together. So watching a movie, listening to music,
chatting, these are all examples of hanging out. So maybe if you get together with your friend,
I just sit in the living room and talk your hanging out. That's right, or you could go drive a
car together in your hanging out. You're talking. So to hang out is to be social, it's to talk to
your friend. So spend time together. And you said, wait, oh, I can't because I have a date.
Okay, to have a date. So a date is a romantic appointment with someone that you want to go out with.
But you have a date. This is something you have. I have a date that night.
So this is actually a very important part because as you said, it's a romantic appointment. So
if you have to go to the doctor and he's not your boyfriend or anything like this, you don't
say I have a date with the doctor. No, you say I have an appointment with the doctor. Okay.
But if it's romantic, you say, oh, I want to get my hair done because I have a date tonight.
Right. I have a date. I want to look nice for my date. Okay. And then he goes on to explain that
this date that he has is with a girl that he has been chatting with. Okay. So the verb here is to chat
with chat. Chat just means talk to talk to, but in internet terms to chat with means to talk to
on the internet. So maybe you use a program like MSN or Google, G chat to talk to somebody online.
That's called chatting. That's right. So I think everyone has done this at one point or another
when you are online chatting via MSN messenger or any of these chat clients. So very, very
calming thing. But remember to add the chat with. I am chatting with my friends. Yeah. I don't like to
chat with people while I'm at work. They're excited. On the internet. Now this guy explained about
the website match.com and he said that he signed up for this website. Okay. Another really key
verb when you're talking about internet things. So for example, if you want to come to English
you can sign up for a free trial. That means provide your information. Right. Start to use.
That's right. So it applies for things online and offline. You, for example, in the real world
or offline, you can sign up for a cooking class. That's right. Or last week I signed up for a dance
class so I can learn how to dance. Very good. Okay. And then to finish off the guy explained that
he's tired of meeting people at bars or that his friends set up dates for him. Okay. So he doesn't
like to be set up. To be set up. Remember that B to be set up. That means someone else is doing this
to you. So Marco, I want to set you up with my friend. That means I want to take you and my friend
and make you have a date. Right. Exactly. So this is exactly what it means to set someone up or to
be set up is to have them go on a date with someone else. All right. So I don't like to be set up
because I like to know the person I will have a date with before we go out. But when you're set up,
someone else makes a decision for you. That's right. It's a little bit difficult. That's right.
Okay. So a lot of interesting things here. Why don't we take a look at our dialogue one last time
and we'll be right back.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow? Oh, I can't. I have a date. Really? Wow. With who?
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months. She's really cool and she's driving
over here this weekend. Wait a minute. You mean you met her online? Yeah. I send up for a website called
Match.com and it's great. You fill in all your details and preferences like if you are a smoker
or if you have any pets, then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email
them or chat. That's kind of weird. What if she's a psycho or something like that? It's the same
as meeting people anywhere in Dane, then. I'm just tired of going to bars being set up for dates
by my friends. I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy.
I guess it does seem logical. I'll have to check it out.
All right, so talking about setting up, this is another word that comes to mind when your
friends set you up for a date is a blind date. Okay, so a blind date is not a date with two blind
people. Right. A blind date is a date that you go to when you don't know who the other person is
before you go. That's right. So for example, my friend's mother loves to set people up
on blind dates. She's a match maker. She makes these makes couples. She will call one person
and call the other person and then she'll make them have a date. She sets them up and then they have
this date a blind date. A blind date. That's right. What you're doing with this technology now
that you can use a website to find and meet people who are also looking for romance. It's very
interesting. It's very modern obviously because now we have the technology to do it. And many
people actually have very successful or very great love stories of how they met online, chatting
or while playing a video game online or many different things like this. Well, the thing that I like
about it and I have to say I've never done it. So what I like from hearing about it is that like
mass.com you you save a lot of time. It seems that way because you get to tell the person hey,
I don't want I don't like people who smoke, I don't like who have pets, but I really like people
who play video games. And so you find people who are like that and then you can get to know that
person better. But I think it's hard when you're going on dates especially your friends they set you
up and you have nothing in common. You have no interests that are in common and that can be really
frustrating. So it seems like online dating is a new type of efficient way of dating because you
preliminary already filter out everyone or everything that you don't like about a person and you
find someone that has your same or similar likes. So it but that's that's modern date, right?
That's right. A lot of people I now have dated using these websites and have been very successful.
Really, it's been married. Very, very, very, very. Wow, it's amazing. So actually this is a great
thing. Let us know if you have any friend who's found their significant other husband or wife
of your online dating or if you've tried it, maybe you can let us know how it is.
Our website is EnglishPod.com. Don't forget to sign up if you don't have an account and we'll see you there.
All right, bye guys. Bye.