Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about fear.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about phobias. Different types of fears that that you have.
Many people that have many people are scared of different things and that's what we're going to talk about today.
Okay, so let's listen to today's dialogue and find out what the people in our dialogue are very, very afraid of.
Are you excited about your trip next month?
Yes, and no. I can't wait to go to Europe but at the same time I'm terrified.
Why?
Well, I have aerophobia. I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh really? I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying.
It's not that bad though. I mean, it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine
flying through the air in 700 miles per hour. I actually have a rack in phobia.
You're scared of spiders. I actually have two more phobias.
Acrophobia and glossophobia. I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying but
public speaking is not that bad. Are you kidding? When I get on stage my palms start to sweat.
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak.
Well, I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic. I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds.
We are such weirdos, right?
All right, we're back. So let's take a look at those phobias on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first phobia that we have is called arrow phobia.
That's right, arrow phobia. And that means that you are scared of flying.
Okay, so we can tell because phobia means a, you know, fear of something but it's not just a fear.
It means that if you go on an airplane, you get very, very upset.
Right. You think that you're going to die. That's right. Okay. And so phobia is a very serious fear.
But arrow, like arrow plane, is the prefix. So arrow phobia is a fear of going on airplane.
That's right. And another phobia that we have is a rack no phobia. So again, as you see in the prefix,
a rack no is related to a spider. That's right. So this comes from the origins of English.
Mm-hmm. I'm not sure if it's Greek or Latin but a rack no phobia, like a rack nid, has to do with
spiders. So I'm afraid of spiders if I'm, if I have a rack no phobia. That is right. And now taking
to look at two more types of phobias here, we have acro phobia and glosophobia. So let's take a look at
the first one. Acro phobia. So acro phobia, acro has to do with heights. So I don't like to be on
tall buildings. I don't like to maybe look down from heights. That means I'm afraid of heights.
That's right. You're afraid of being in a very high altitude acro phobia. Now glosophobia is an
interesting one because this one you are scared of public speaking or you get very nervous when
you're in front of a group of people. Right. So this is actually a very, very common fear.
But if it's a, if it's a serious fear, it's a phobia. So glosophobia means that when you go
in front of people, you get very anxious, upset, your stomach hurts. You have wet hands. So that's a
very serious fear. That's right. And for our last phobia, we have claustrophobia. I think is one of
the most common ones. If you have claustrophobia, you're afraid of smaller tight spaces. That's right.
So people who, so you heard the word claustrophobic. People who are claustrophobic or people who
suffer from claustrophobia don't like to be in small tight places like elevators for example.
tunnels. So now you brought up an interesting point. Our last phobia, we said claustrophobic.
And now we must make the difference between, for example, claustrophobia and being claustrophobic.
So phobia, you hear the word, I hear the ending eye eye phobia, claustrophobia is a noun.
Okay, that means I can talk about, I have it, I have this fear. But when you're talking
with the adjective, something that describes you, you have to use the iq ending. I'm claustrophobic.
He is acrophobic. They are arrow phobic. Okay, so that, that is the adjective form. So if I say,
I have a reccanophobia. It means I have this fear or I can say, I am a reccanophobic. Great.
So this can be used for all other kinds of phobias. So when you learn those words, remember that
there's two different kinds. There's the ia, phobia, which is the noun, and iq, which is the adjective.
All right, let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder.
Are you excited about your trip next month? Yes, and no, I can't wait to go to Europe. But
at the same time, I'm terrified. Why? Well, I have aerophobia. I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh, really? I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying. It's not that bad, though. I mean,
it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air in 700 miles per hour.
I actually have a reccanophobia. You're scared of spiders. I actually have two more phobias.
Acrophobia and glossophobia. I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying, but
public speaking is not that bad. Are you kidding? When I get on stage, my palm start to sweat.
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak. Well, I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds. We are such weirdos, right?
All right. So we've picked out a couple of different phrases today. Let's take a look at those now on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So in the beginning of today's dialogue, the character said, I cannot wait to go to
Europe, but at the same time, I'm terrified. So at the same time. So in this case, we're saying that we are
happy, but also we are scared. So two things at once at the same time. Right. So this is a little bit
different from when we talk about, I can do two things at the same time. I can walk and chew gum.
More talking about feelings or emotions. You say, you know, I'm happy, but at the same time, I'm also scared.
That means that I have these two feelings and actually they're opposite feelings. Right. Exactly.
Usually they are opposite feelings. So like you say, you're happy, but at the same time,
you're nervous. Like saying, on the other hand. Exactly. All right. Now, when we talked about all these
fears, we're afraid of flying. We are afraid of spiders. We describe them as a chronic fear.
Okay. So this adjective chronic is very important because it has to do with time. Okay. So I have a
chronic fear of heights. That means this is a fear I've always had. Okay. And I will always have.
You can also say she has chronic back pain. Mm-hmm. Okay. That means it comes back again and again.
It's not just one time. It's all it's it's some person's whole life maybe, not every day, but it
comes back. Right. Okay. So that's if you say you have a chronic something you are explaining that you've
had it for a while or you will always have it. Something usually very serious also.
And going back to one of the phobias, we mentioned Goloso phobia and the other person said, well,
you know, public speaking is not that bad. It's not it's not something to be so afraid of.
And the other person replied by saying, are you kidding? Are you kidding? So this is actually a
way of showing some sarcasm when you're talking because public speaking is not that bad.
The person wants to say, no, it is that bad. It is awful. So are you kidding is a way to say, no,
I totally disagree. Right. So you're being a little bit sarcastic, but at the same time,
you're also acting a bit surprise. Like I can't believe you said that or like I said,
I really like the Twilight movie of Marco. Are you kidding? Those were what was
terrible. All right. So Marco does not agree with my opinion. All right. Now, when we're talking
about public speaking, we mentioned that you get on stage. So this is very important because
this is the action to get on stage and speak. Okay. So if you have a stage or maybe even you don't
have a stage, but you're talking about performing in front of other people like a speech or play,
you say you get on stage. And it's important to remember this as a phrase. So whenever I get on stage,
I start to sweat. Now, you may want to add the, there you want to say to get on the stage.
But it's not necessary. It's not incorrect, but the usual or let's say more correct form would
just be used a phrase to get on stage. When I get on stage, I get very nervous. You don't have to
say when I get on the stage. Or she's normally very shy, but when she gets on stage, she opens up
and becomes very, very talkative. That's right. All right. So that's all the phrases we picked out
for you. Let's listen to her dialogue one last time and we'll be right back.
Are you excited about your trip next month? Yes. And no, I can't wait to go to Europe, but
at the same time, I'm terrified. Why? Well, I have Airophobia. I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh, really? I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying. It's not that bad, though. I mean,
it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air in 700 miles per hour.
I actually have a rack inophobia. You're scared of spiders. I actually have two more
phobias. Acrophobia and glossophobia. I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying, but
public speaking is not that bad. Are you kidding? When I get on stage, my palm start to sweat.
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak. Well, I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds. We are such weirdos, right?
All right, so talking about all these phobias. Now, one of these phobias was actually made into a
movie. I think in 1990, a rack no phobia. This very chronic fear of spiders. That's right. And
I remember when I was younger and this movie came out, everybody started talking about how they were
a rack no phobic. Had this horrible fear of spiders. Did you ever see that movie?
Of course, of course. They terrifying. It was supposedly some South American spider that made its way
into the United States in a box in a crater, something. Now, many people handle phobias differently.
Are you having any phobia? Are you claustrophobic? Are you a rack no phobic? I don't have any phobias,
and I'm not really afraid of anything. So I'm pretty lucky that way. But I know a number of people
who are afraid of heights and are afraid of phobic. And actually, if you look it up, you will find
in dictionary maybe hundreds of phobias. People who are afraid of open spaces, people who are afraid
of close spaces or people who are afraid of marriage, they even have a phobia determined for this
type of person. So it's very interesting. Now, this is going to be a challenge. Why don't you
look up a couple of different phobias and share it with us? Maybe some of the craziest ones or the
funniest ones or maybe the strangest ones you can find. That's right. So look them up. Share
them with us. Our website is EnglishPod.com. All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.