Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and here today we have almost almost the end of our series on giving a presentation in English.
This is part nine of 10 so this is near the end but we've got a lot of really great words and phrases for
discussing what you've talked about in the last, I don't know, 10 minutes or so. It's the summary of your speech and so that's what we're going to talk about today.
That's right. So let's take a look at what Mr. Ford is saying in his summary and we'll be back in a bit.
Right, everyone. I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign today but next week you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves.
And I have no doubt that you will be impressed. Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points. As I mentioned at the outset, 2010 represents a key year for alpha computers.
The recession is hopefully behind us. It is clear to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming, especially in the developing markets.
If we're to succeed in this ultra competitive field, then we really need to push forward and offer our customers products that meet their needs on all levels.
As I hope I've illustrated, the X420 represents the kind of computer that can really satisfy those needs.
I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue expected hit in 2010 with the new X420 range and believe me,
this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the X420 in the market, we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary and impressive products.
Alpha computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I really see no limit in our potential as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier.
Quality, excellence and service. Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with the quote that really sums up everything that we've discussed today.
And hopefully we'll provide you with the same inspiration that it gives me.
As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means doing it right when no one is looking. Well, in fact, our customers are looking.
They're looking for us to lead the way and to give them the quality that our competitors cannot. We cannot let them down.
Alright, we're back so now let's take a look at some language on language takeaway.
Some are quite the very beginning of today's monologue. We have a phrase that basically means the same thing as summarized. What was that phrase?
That's right at the last sentence of the first paragraph we've seen Mr Ford say, let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points. So the phrase there is wrap up.
That means to conclude to finish to end. This is the very end of his speech and so to wrap something up means to finish it.
That's right. So maybe if you're getting a speech and someone is telling you to wrap it up quickly.
I mean stop. That's right. He's find an ending point. So wrap it up. Let's go. Come on.
That's right. So he's wrapping it up by summarizing what he has talked about.
And so he goes back to the very beginning and he says as I mentioned at the outset.
Okay, the outset is an ounce of time and it means the beginning. So you might remember in parts one or two of this speech that he was talking about why 2010 is an important year for their company.
And so this is the outset. This is the beginning. You can also say, you know, at the outset things looked bad, but it turns out that they went well.
Okay. So outset means beginning the start of something. Mm-hmm. Okay. And he also talked about how the computer industry demand is booming.
All right. So booming is an interesting word because boom, the noun means boom.
So it's blown. Right. It's a sound that you hear when there's a storm. But booming means doing very well. That means that in this case demand is booming.
There is a lot of demand. That's right. So when you hear people say business is booming.
I mean, business is going very well. It's very successful. Okay. So it basically means that it's doing very well that it's growing quickly and rapidly.
So he went on to talk about the X420 and how the company has plans to keep expanding and keep coming out with ever more
revolutionary and impressive products. Okay. So something is a revolutionary if it changes a situation.
Okay. Because revolution basically means change. But not a small change. A really big change.
And so a product is revolutionary if it introduces something really new, really exciting.
Okay. So an example of a revolutionary product was the home computer.
Exactly. Because the home computer changed the way people typed and communicated and did all these different things.
And so it's revolutionary because it introduced a big change. That's right. Okay. So revolutionary towards the end of Mr. Ford's dialogue.
He said that they're going to have a Q&A section and he left us with a quote that according to him sums up everything we've discussed today.
Okay. To sum up, this is very related to the word to summarize. It means to say in fewer words.
Okay. So this quote says what he wants to say. But it says it in a very short space.
So if we read a book and I ask you to sum up the story, this is basically I'm asking for a summary.
That's right. So I could say, you know, the Harry Potter story is a story about a young boy who is a wizard
who loses his parents who goes to school with his friends and learns about his powers.
That's a perfect way to sum up the Harry Potter story. All right. Very good.
So that's about it for language takeaway today. But we have some great phrases coming up for you in fluency
filter. Let's listen to the dialogue again first and we'll be back in a moment.
Right, everyone. I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign today.
But next week, you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves. And I have no doubt that you will be impressed.
Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points. As I mentioned at the outset,
2010 represents a key year for alpha computers. The recession is hopefully behind us. It is clear
to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming, especially in the developing markets.
If we're to succeed in this ultra competitive field, then we really need to push forward and offer
our customers' products that meet their needs on all levels. As I hope I've illustrated,
the X420 represents the kind of computer that can really satisfy those needs.
I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue we expect to hit in 2010 with the new X420 range.
And believe me, this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the X420 in the market,
we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary and impressive products.
Alpha computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I really see no limit in our potential
as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier. Quality, excellence and service.
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with a quote that really sums up
everything that we've discussed today. And hopefully we'll provide you with the same inspiration that
it gives me. As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means doing it right when no one is looking.
Well, in fact, our customers are looking. They're looking for us to lead the way and to
give them the quality that our competitors cannot. We cannot let them down.
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at four key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So the first phrase we've got here in fluency builder is an interesting one. And I
think it's important to point out because we've got a verb and a noun that often go together.
Mr. Ford said this kind of computer can really satisfy those needs that users that customers have.
That's right. So the phrase there is to satisfy a need. And as you said this verb and this
noun usually go together, you want to satisfy your customers' needs.
Alright, so what do I need? I need a good computer that is fast that I can do my business on.
And this computer, the X420, satisfies that need. It does what I need it to do.
Okay, so we understand the verb to satisfy and but the phrase is a very powerful phrase,
especially if you use an in business where you're saying we are giving our customers what they need
and we are making them happy. Exactly. Okay. As he continued talking about the X420,
he said, this is just the beginning. Alright, so this is something we often say when
we have a long project or plan. You can say, you know, yes, things are good now,
but this is just the beginning. There are many good things to come. And this is something we
often say in a positive way. Yes, this is good, but expected better things in the future.
Very good. Okay, so this is just the beginning. And well as he continued talking about the company,
he said that the customers are looking for us to lead the way. Okay, so this is an interesting phrase
because he's making a comparison with other companies and he's saying listen, our customers
have many needs, but they want us to really be ahead of them and to innovate and to make new
things and new computers that will be ahead of the competition. So take the lead, be in the front.
So basically the phrase to lead the way is for you to be in the front and and give people a clear path.
Think of your saying bolts that runner in the Olympics. Everyone's running quickly, but all
the sudden he takes the lead. He leads the way. He is ahead of everyone else. All the other runners
are far, far behind him. That's right. Okay, so he's leading the way and he finishes his monologue
by saying we cannot let them down. We cannot let our customers down, basically. So the phrase here
is to let someone down. He let me down. We let them down. This is a great phrase and you can use
it about anybody and it's really important phrase because it means to disappoint someone.
So for example, Marco, when you forgot my birthday, you really let me down. Okay, so that means I
disappointed you because I've already read it. So to let someone down is to disappoint them, to not do
what you were expected to do. Exactly. And so a company can do this. For example, when a company
like Toyota makes a car that has many problems, that company lets down its customers. So you can
let someone down. Basically, you have to have the subject. You let someone down or the company
let down its customers. Exactly. Okay, a lot of great stuff here when we take one last listen
and boy back in a bit. Right, everyone. I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign
today, but next week you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves. And I have
no doubt that you will be impressed. Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points.
As I mentioned at the outset, 2010 represents a key year for alpha computers. The recession is
hopefully behind us. It is clear to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming,
especially in the developing markets. If we're to succeed in this ultra competitive field,
then we really need to push forward and offer our customers products that meet their needs on all
levels. As I hope I've illustrated, the X420 represents the kind of computer that can really satisfy
those needs. I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue we expect to hit in 2010 with the new X420
range and believe me, this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the X420 in the market,
we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary and impressive products.
Alpha computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I really see no limit in our potential
as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier. Quality, excellence and service.
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with a quote that really sums
up everything that we've discussed today. And hopefully we'll provide you with the same inspiration
that it gives me. As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means doing it right when no one is looking.
Well, in fact, our customers are looking. They're looking for us to lead the way and to give them
the quality that our competitors cannot. We cannot let them down.
All right guys, so this is the penultimate lesson about presentation skills. As you saw, we are
summarizing and concluding the presentation and there are actually a lot of great things here
to learn from, especially the vocab where you're saying, okay, let to some things up to wrap it up
to conclude to summarize the key points. Yeah. But there are also some important things coming
up next week. That's the very, very last part of this series because usually after presentation,
there is a section for questions and answers. That's called Q&A. And that's the topic of our next
show. So you guys should stay tuned for that. All right, so we'll see you guys next time. And of
course, if you have any questions or comments, you will always find us at EnglishPod.com.
See you guys there. Bye.