Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica
and today we're bringing you another great lesson for all of you who are interested in shopping
especially those of you who are interested in shopping for a car
a car exactly
so we're going to give you some great language about describing a car or characteristics of a car
and also some really interesting language for shopping
yes, especially buying something really big and expensive
yeah, like a car
so before we listen to our dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary preview
very vocabulary preview
I'm vocabulary preview today we're bringing you two words
the first one is vehicle
vehicle
so again, a vehicle is a machine right?
right, a machine that carries people from one place to another
so it's important to say that a vehicle can be an airplane
a car
car
boat, boat, even a bicycle
right, that's a vehicle
our second word is sedan
sedan
so a sedan is a type of car
exactly, it's a type of car with four doors that can fit five people inside
so to make it more clear, most taxis are sedan
exactly, right?
they have four doors, five people can fit in there including the driver
except taxis in Mexico
they're not sedan
they're little beetles
they're folks who are in beetles
so that's not a dance
but yeah, most countries have sedan's as taxis
to give you some examples like a Toyota Corolla or a Toyota Camry as a sedan
yeah, maybe like a Volkswagen jet-a
a jet-a jet-a-a sedan
now we can listen to our dialogue
and it's going to be at a normal speed the first time but you don't have to worry about it
we'll come back and teach you some of the important words from the dialogue
Hi there, can I help you folks?
I'm just browsing, seeing what's on the lot
my daughter wants a car for her birthday, you know how it is
Dad, I'm 16 already
and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car
she's right, you know, kids these days all have cars
let me show you something we just got in
I've seen 96 sedan, excellent gas mileage
it has dual airbags and anti-like brakes
a perfect vehicle for a young driver
Dad, I love it, it's awesome
can we get this one please?
I see, what can you tell me about this one?
oh, that's just an old World War II tank that we use for TV commercials
now about this today
oh, whoa, wait a minute, tell me more about this tank
Well sir, if you're looking for quality and safety then look no further
three inches of reinforced steel, protect your daughter from short range missile attacks
does the sedan protect her from missile attacks?
it does not
well, I don't know, let me sleep on it
did I mention the tank is a tank?
I'll take it
Dad
I think she's really lucky
really?
she's getting a tank to go to school
how awesome is that
I would be so embarrassed
to drive to school in a tank
like the coolest car
oh, you're such a boy
alright, a surprising ending to a
relatively easy shopping day
yeah
let's take a look at some language that we saw in our dialogue on language
take away
language take away
we have four words for you today
the first one is gas mileage
gas mileage
so gas mileage is how many miles you can travel on a gallon or
liter of gasoline
well you know what's interesting in some English speaking countries like Australia
New Zealand Canada we use kilometers to measure distance
but we still talk about gas mileage
hmm
yeah
I guess you can't say gas kilo mileage
no
or something
but yeah, it's
yeah, basically how many kilometers or how many miles you can travel on a tank or a
liter or gallon of gas
exactly
okay
the next word is
air bags
these are like big bags of air that fill up and come out of the car
when there's a crash
so that way you don't hit your head against steering wheel or something like that
so they protect you
right I've heard that Volvo has like 18 air bags now in their cars
they are very safe cars
like a big balloon
okay our third word today is
brakes
so what are brakes
brakes are little
what are brakes
brakes are what make your car stop
okay so the little machines maybe that stop your car
yeah they're on the wheels
yeah they make your car stop
you have brakes on your bike
yes
etc
our last word today on language
take away reinforced
reinforced
so we have some examples of how we use reinforced because it's a little bit weird
yeah these will help you understand the meaning
example one
so I reinforced all the walls there's no way they're going to fall down
example two
this plastic is reinforced with a glass so it's both light and strong
so basically anything that's reinforced is made stronger
perfect
reinforced steel reinforced table
okay great so now we could listen to our dialogue again
you can practice all these words that we just talked about and we'll come back shortly
hi there
can I help you folks
I'm just browsing
seeing what's on the lot
my daughter wants a car for her birthday
you know how it is
dad
I'm 16 already
and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car
she is right you know
kids these days all have cars
let me show you something we just got in
a 1996 Sudan
excellent gas mileage
it has dual airbags and anti lock brakes
a perfect vehicle for a young driver
dad I love it
it's awesome
can we get this one please
I see
what can you tell me about this one
oh
that's just an old world war two tank that we use for TV commercials
now about this Sudan
whoa wait a minute
tell me more about this tank
well sir
if you are looking for quality and safety
then look no further
three inches of reinforced steel
protect your daughter from short range missile attacks
does this the Dan protect her from missile attacks
it does not
well I don't know
let me sleep on it
did I mention the tank is a tank
I'll take it
dad
so we have a couple of interesting phrases to talk about
shopping
right
let's look at these influencey builder
fluency builder
the first one today is
I'm just browsing
this is a really useful phrase because usually
salespeople will come up to you and ask you can I help you
or you're just in something
and you're just looking
so yeah you maybe you don't really want to buy
right you're just just browsing
so then they'll just leave you alone
yeah they won't bother you as much
yeah it's a good good phrase
another good phrase
sleep on it
so we have some examples of how you sleep on it
example one
I don't know if we should buy that house
it's perfect for us but it's so expensive
I was sleep on it
example two
why don't you sleep on it and tell me tomorrow
example three
this is a bit more than what I can afford
let me sleep on it
to sleep on it means to
like to think about it overnight
to think about it
so maybe you want to buy this really expensive car
but you need to think about it
so you'll sleep on it
you go home sleep on it
think about it twice and then make a decision
exactly
okay great words and great dialogue
yeah I love this dialogue
yeah it was it's kind of funny
so we could listen to it again
and then we'll come back and talk a little bit about it
hi there can help you folks
I'm just browsing seeing what's on the lot
my daughter wants a car for her birthday
you know how it is
dad
I'm 16 already
and I'm like the only one at school who doesn't have a car
she's right you know
kids these days all have cars
let me show you something we just got in
a 1996 sedan excellent gas mileage
and it has dual airbags and anti-elect breaks
a perfect vehicle for a young driver
dad I love it
it's awesome
can we get this one please
I see
what can you tell me about this one
oh
that's just an old world war two tank
that we use for TV commercials
now about this today
whoa wait a minute
tell me more about this tank
well sir if you're looking for quality
and safety then look no further
three inches of reinforced steel
protect your daughter from short range missile attacks
does the sedan protect her from missile attacks
it does not
well I don't know let me sleep on it
did I mention the tank is a tank
I'll take it
dad
so Marco have you ever driven a tank
I mean I know you're in the army
yeah
yeah actually I did
I did drive a tank before
really yeah really old one kind of like a world war two
type tank
but yeah they're really fun
interesting you have it's not like driving a normal car
you have pedals and
but there's no steering wheel
no no you have levers
yeah
and what many people don't know is that
actually tanks are
manual transmissions you have to change gears
really
and it's really hard to change gears on those things
and what's the gas mileage like a tank
I don't know maybe like five miles
forgotten
they run on diesel which is a different type of fuel
right?
yep
okay well very cool I never knew that my podcast partner had driven a tank
that's pretty awesome
yeah well it was it was fun definitely
and I hope I get to do it again someday
all right well
guys have you ever driven a tank
or a submarine or any type of
armoured vehicle
yeah tell us about it at our website
englishpod.com
right we'll be there to answer all your questions
I'll also be there to maybe post some more crazy stories
or some pictures of the tank
yeah maybe
all right guys we'll see you there until then
goodbye