Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have a very painful lesson for you.
That's right. Today we're going to go to one of the worst places for me. We're going to go to the dentist.
Okay. So the person in this dialogue has a pain in their mouth in the tooth area. So let's take a
listen to this dialogue and we come back. We'll be talking a little bit more about it.
What seems to be the problem? I have a really bad toothache. My cheek is swollen and I can't eat anything.
Let's have a look. Hmm, this doesn't look too good. I think we may have to pull out your wisdom tooth.
It's pressing against your mullers and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing so much pain.
When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
First people take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with. I also noticed a small cavity up front here.
So you are going to need a feeling. I guess that's what I get for not
flossing or brushing my teeth through times a day. It could be that. Or maybe you're eating too many
sweets. In any case, I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
All right, we're back and obviously we're going to take a look at a lot of vocab related to going to
the dentist and experiencing a little bit of pain. So let's take a look at that in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay, first up in language takeaway today, we have the root of the problem.
It's a toothache. That's right. We have a really bad toothache. Okay, well, egg means pain or
soreness and tooth is your tooth. So I could say, oh gosh, I have a really bad toothache.
That's right. That means your tooth or your teeth hurt. And basically you can combine it like
a stomach ache or headache. Backache. Backache. That's right. So usually when you have a toothache,
you experience different symptoms, different things happen to you. What's one of these things, Marco?
Well, in this case, the girl had a swollen cheek. Her cheek is swollen.
Ouch. So the cheek is the side of the face. It's usually where it's a little bit pink.
And when your cheek is swollen, it looks puffy. It looks bigger than normal. That's right. So
for example, sometimes you fall and you hurt your finger and it'll get fat and it'll get puffy as you say.
It's swollen. That's right. So anything can be swollen, really. When you hit your toe on something
hard and your toe later gets bigger, it's swollen. That's right. So obviously her cheek is swollen
and she has a toothache because apparently her wisdom teeth or her wisdom tooth is coming out.
All right. So wisdom teeth are special teeth. I don't know if they actually have anything to do
with wisdom, which means being smart to be wise. Wise. But wisdom teeth are those four teeth
in the very, very, very back of your mouth. That's right. So these are the last teeth that come in
or the last teeth that grow in your mouth. So I think usually you're 18 or 20 when they come in.
That's right. A lot of people experience these when they're older. Maybe that's why they call them
wisdom teeth because you're older and you're wiser. I had them when I was about 14, 13. So I was
very young. But these come in in the very back. The furthest away from your lips. Okay. Very good.
So when they come in, sometimes there's not enough space. And so they start to press against the
other teeth in your mouth, specifically against your mullers. So mullers are other teeth. These are also
in the back of your mouth. You can tell which ones are mullers I believe because they're flat
on top. They look like a little square. Those are the ones that you used to chew your food with mostly.
Exactly. They're not pointy like your front teeth. And so mullers are in the back of your mouth.
Wisdom teeth are in the very back of your mouth. And mullers can be very sore when the wisdom
teeth push against them. And so in this case you'll have to take your teeth out or the dentist will
take your teeth out. But what's something we say when we talk about taking the whole tooth out?
Well, in this case he's going to extract the tooth. But also he's going to extract the nerve
and the root. Okay. So nerves are parts of our bodies. We can't see them. But they help us feel things.
So maybe when someone hits me, the nerves in my arm, they tell my brain that it hurts.
Well, we also have nerves in our teeth. And that's what we're talking about here. But what's this
other thing? You talked about the nerve and the root. It's very similar to a plant, for example.
You're a consider that your teeth are like plants. And they have little roots that go into your
gums. And this is how basically you get teeth stay alive. They are fed basically by your body.
All right. So root like with a tree or a plant is the very bottom of something. And in this case,
two extract means to take out or to take away. So the dentist will have to extract the root
and the nerve. That sounds pretty painful. It's painful, but they have to do it, right?
So when the dentist has to extract the tooth, in this case the nerve and the root and everything,
in order for you not to feel it, he gives you special drugs. What are these drugs called? These are
called anesthetics. Okay. So most people when they are having major surgery, they get anesthetics
so that they can't feel anything. Remember we were just talking about nerves. Well, anesthetics
make it so that you can't feel things through your nerves. That's right. So obviously you don't
want to feel the pain when somebody's pulling that tooth out of your mouth. So you get an anesthetic
and then you don't really feel anything. You kind of feel something but you don't really feel pain.
Exactly. So anesthetic basically makes you numb. Numb. That's right. That's the word numb.
Okay. So we're taking a look at a lot of vocab, mollers, whizz them teeth, etc. Why don't we
listen to the dialogue again and we're back in a bit with fluency builder?
What seems to be the problem? I have a really bad toothache. My cheek is swollen and I can't eat
anything. Let's have a look. This doesn't look too good. I think we may have to pull out your whizz
them tooth. It's pressing against your mollers and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing
so much pain. When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
First people take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with. I also noticed a small cavity up front
here so you are going to need a feeling. I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing
my teeth three times a day. It could be that or maybe you're eating too many sweets. In any case,
I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
All right. So the topic of today's lesson is toothache but it's also basically about learning
that you will have to have your tooth taken out. So to say this we say to pull out a tooth.
Okay, so that's what the dentist said. I think we may have to pull out your whizz them tooth.
It's not good news. Okay, so to pull out means to extract. So just remember here, this is a phrase
that has pull out to out would be the preposition here. We wouldn't say pull off or pull out.
We'd say pull out. Like for example, you can pull out a hair or your hair. Exactly. Okay,
so we're pulling out the whizz them tooth and the dentist first wants to take some x-rays to see
what we're dealing with. Okay, so to deal with something means to work on it or to
to have something to do with. And so in this case, an dentist wants to know, is this serious?
Mm-hmm. What are we dealing with here? That's right. And so he's trying to judge the situation.
So maybe what would be another scenario or another situation when you would say,
hmm, I have to see what we're dealing with? Well, in the case of the weather and the newsmen
who report about the weather, maybe they see that a storm is coming, but they have to look at the
radars and the computer screens to see what they're dealing with. Is it a serious storm or is it a
very weak storm? They have to evaluate. That's right. Okay, very good. And so we're going to see what we're
dealing with. And then the girl, I think, knows that she hasn't really taken good care of her teeth.
And so she says, I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing my teeth. So that's what you
get or that's what I get. Here, the pronoun changes. I, you, he, that's what I get for not taking care of
myself. This means that's my fault. I deserved it. I deserve this things. So I could say, Marco,
that's what you get for not doing your homework. You got a bad grade on your tests. That's right.
So it's basically a way of saying, that's what you deserve. That's the consequence for your action.
Exactly. Okay. And what about our last phrase? Well, this is something that I hate to hear from
doctors and dentists because usually it's a lie. A dentist will say before he gives you a shot or
before he takes your tooth out, you won't feel a thing. That's right. So he's basically saying,
you're not going to feel any pain. But why do we say you won't feel a thing instead of you won't
feel anything? Just to set phrase, it's something we say. I would remember it like this because
it's more likely to be said in this way. You won't feel a thing. I think it basically means
not even one little thing. You're not going to feel that. So for example, I'm about to
fix someone's back. You know, when you have to pull them and make their back feel better,
I say you won't feel a thing. You fix their back. Okay. So you won't feel a thing or you won't feel
anything. Both are correct, but I think it's more common to hear you won't feel a thing.
Okay. So why don't we go back? Let's take one last look at our dialogue and we're back in a bit.
What seems to be the problem? I have a really bad toothache. My cheek is swollen and I can't eat
anything. Let's have a look. Hmm, this doesn't look too good. I think we may have to pull out your wisdom
tooth. It's pressing against your mullers and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing so much pain.
When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
First, we will take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with. I also noticed a small cavity up
front here, so you are going to need a feeling. I guess that's what I get for not
flossing or brushing my teeth through times a day. It could be that or maybe you're eating too many
sweets. In any case, I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
Alright, so talking about dentists and talking about wisdom teeth, you say that you still have
all four wisdom teeth. I do. They're all still back there. So you didn't need to have them
taken out or pulled? No, as my dentist likes to say, I have a big mouth, which in English has two
meanings. If big mouth is not just a large mouth, but also it means you like to talk a lot.
Did you ever have braces for example when you were a kid? Yes.
You had braces. I had a retainer, which is a device that it looks like a line across your teeth
and you put it in usually at night, but sometimes during the day and it makes some space in your mouth.
But I also had braces after that. I hated braces. I had them for two years. Why did you hate
braces? Because they're uncomfortable. Well, they don't look very good. It's for someone you're 13
year old girl and you won't look cute and you have this big metal thing in your mouth. That's right.
Did you have braces? No, no. I never had braces. Actually it was kind of for a while. I think a
lot of people thought it was cool to have braces. I did not grow up with you. It was not cool.
I don't know. I think or it gets to a point where in certain parts, I guess my school was
filled with kids that had braces. So I guess everyone just had really bad teeth. So obviously,
the people that didn't have braces kind of were left aside. So you're like, oh, I want braces.
I want to be part of the group. Kind of like sometimes I wish I had glasses. Is that everyone I know
has glasses? Really. Yeah. If you have good vision though. Yeah, it sucks to be perfect, right?
Well, this is a really interesting topic and going to the dentists is always complicated. Maybe
some of our listeners are dentists themselves or they can have or they have some stories that
please let us know what you're thinking and share your dentist stories with us on EnglishPod.com.
We're waiting for you there. All right. We'll see you guys then. Bye.