Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you guys.
Now Marco what are we talking about today?
That's right today we're going to try to buy a new car. So we're going to the car dealer and we want
to try and see if we can get a new car. Okay so lots of great vocabulary for buying that car.
Let's check out today's dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
I see. You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale.
It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year. Perfect.
I like this one. That is the Ford Focus. A very light but powerful vehicle.
It comes with dual-site airbags, power steering and power windows.
Tinted windows and your choice of either automatic or manual transmission. Sounds like a good car.
How many miles to the gallon? It is a very fuel efficient vehicle.
Giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the highway. That is really convenient.
Especially now the fuel prices are so high. What's under the hood?
A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine.
Trust me. This car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question. What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest
for the first year. You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
Great. Let's do it.
All right. We're back. So now we're going to take a look at some of that Vokab, especially the one that
the salesmen used on language takeaway. Language takeaway.
All right. So at the beginning of this dialogue we hear a lot of features that this car has.
The first one is trade in. Actually this is something that the man says when he goes to the car
lot. That's right. He says he has an old car. He has a Ford Pinto and he wants to trade it in.
He wants to trade in his old car. So this is something that you do in America or
other places when you have a car already but you want a new car. And so the car
lot, the place where you can buy the cars, they usually give you some money for your old car
and you can spend that money on your new car. That's right. So basically you give them your old
car plus some extra cash and then you can get a new car. So that's basically what a trade-in is.
And well as you said we had a lot of features on this car of the Ford Focus.
First of all, dual-side airbags. Okay. So dual-side is pretty simple. It means that you have them on both sides.
The left and the right dual means two. But our airbags are what's important in this phrase.
Airbags do what exactly Marco? They protect you from hitting the front part of the car.
So maybe out of the steering wheel a bag will inflate if you crash. So it will prevent you from hitting
the steering wheel and getting hurt. It's like a big balloon and it protects you from damaging your body.
That's right. So it has two airbags with for the passenger and for the driver.
All right. So after that we also heard about a number of things that are power,
power steering power windows. So what is power steering do? Power steering or also called assisted
steering. It allows you to turn your car with less effort. So maybe you've driven a car that
didn't have power steering. And so you really have to struggle when you're turning the car,
especially if you're parking. So you have to turn the wheel and turn it turn it turn it to turn.
But a power steering steering makes it more automatic. That's right. So it's very easy to turn
left or right. That's right. And the same thing goes for power windows. So maybe your car
doesn't have electric windows. So you have to do it manually with a little lever. It's a turn
and around that around that around. But instead with power windows, you just push a button
and the window goes down or up. That's right. And actually as well, another feature for the windows,
we have tinted windows. Now these are sometimes very popular. I don't think I've ever had tinted
windows on my car. But tint means something is darker. It's protected from the sun. So tinted
sunglasses, for example, can be very dark. But tinted windows on a car are black. They don't let
much sunlight in. So you don't get blinded by the sun or so other people can't see you from outside.
Usually limousines. You will see all limousines have tinted windows. Politicians like to drive
around in cars with tinted windows. That's right. Okay. So a lot of features. There are a lot of
vocabre going in the car. Why don't we take a break? Let's listen to the dialogue again and
we'll be back to talk some more. Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford
Pinto that I would like to trade in. I see. You are in luck this month because all of our
2010 models are on sale. It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year.
Perfect. I like this one. That is the Ford Focus. A very light but powerful vehicle. It comes with
dual-site airbags, power steering and power windows. Tinted windows and your choice of either
automatic or manual transmission sounds like a good car. How many miles to the gallon? It is a very
fuel-efficient vehicle giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the highway. That is really
convenient. Especially now the fuel prices are so high. What's under the hood? A very powerful 2.5
liter turbocharged engine. Trust me. This car is fast. Now for the most difficult question. What
is the price tag for this lovely vehicle? Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this lot today
with zero-down payment and no interest for the first year. You can test drive it now and we can
sign the papers when we get back. Great. Let's do it. All right. We're back. So now let's start again
with language takeaway. Now let's take a look at part two. Language takeaway. All right. So a very,
very key phrase that we heard in the dialogue is automatic or sometimes manual transmission. So
automatic transmission, manual transmission. This is very important when we talk about cars.
That's right. So basically the car has a lot of gears and with an automatic transmission,
the car will basically change gears by itself. Right. So you can you start in park and you go to drive
and you can go to reverse park drive reverse. That's right. This controls kind of the way the car moves.
But with a manual transmission, this means you have to do it by yourself using your hand.
So we have what gears. We have 1, 2, 3, 4 and sometimes 5. That's right. So that's a manual transmission.
You have to change the gears manually. It's a lot of work. Yeah. Now talking about another feature of the
car, the client asked, well, how many miles to the gallon does the car get? And the salesman said that
the car is very fuel efficient. Okay. So this is a very important phrase right now as gas is very expensive
in some parts of the world. And we are concerned about the environment. Right. So a fuel efficient
car is a car that uses gas very well. That means that I can go very very far on one tank of gas.
I don't need to keep putting gas into my car. That's right. So usually for example,
sports cars are not fuel efficient. Hummers are not fuel efficient. That's right. So fuel efficient is
a key thing to look for these days. But the customer also wanted to know what's under the hood.
So this phrase under the hood is very, very common when we're talking about cars. That's right.
The person said what's under the hood? And basically what we're saying is what is under the hood,
which is that metal cover and the front part of the car. So you lift that in there. You can have
access to the engine. So basically that's the question. What kind of an engine does this car have?
Oftentimes when you're car stops or you have a problem like it's broken, someone like a mechanic will say,
hey, let's have a look. Let's look under the hood. He wants to know. Let's look at the engine so we can find the problem.
But in this case, it's not a problem. He just wants to know what kind of a car is this? Is it powerful?
Or is it not so powerful? That's right. That's exactly right. So that's why we want to know what's
under the hood and well, he goes on to explain all the features about the engine. But then when we
talk about the payment, how much the car costs, the salesman said, you know what? It's not expensive.
And on top of that, you can drive it out today with 0% down payment. Okay. This is important.
Down payments are payments that you often make with very, very big ticket items, a house, a car.
Things like this. So a down payment is what you have to pay to get the thing to begin using it.
But not all of the payment, right? So it's a percentage. So if the car is $10,000 and the man says,
there's a 0% down payment. How much do I have to pay? Mark 0? 0. I don't pay anything today. I pay in a month.
A little bit. And then next month a little bit. But if the payment is a 10% down payment,
then I have to pay $1,000. That's right. That's right. So as you said, it's usually about things that
have a big price tag that are very expensive. A house, a car, these types of things,
usually you need to give a down payment. That means that you're committing to buying it. That's right.
So a lot of interesting things going on in today's lesson. Why don't we listen to the dialogue
again? And we'll be back to talk some more.
Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade
in. I see. You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale.
It is a perfect time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year. Perfect. I like this one.
That is the Ford Focus. A very light but powerful vehicle. It comes with dual-site airbags,
power steering and power windows. Tinted windows and your choice of either automatic or manual
transmission. Sounds like a good car. How many miles to the gallon? It is a very fuel efficient vehicle
giving you about 34 miles in the city and 40 on the highway. That is really convenient,
especially now the fuel prices are so high. What's under the hood? A very powerful 2.5
liter turbocharged engine. Trust me, this car is fast. Now for the most difficult question,
what is the price tag for this lovely vehicle? Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this
lot today with zero down payment and no interest for the first year. You can test drive it now
and we can sign the papers when we get back. Great. Let's do it.
All right, so buying a new car can always be tricky. What do you prefer though for example in these
types of features of the car? For me, a car must be very fuel efficient. Because number one,
cars are all bad for the environment. So I want a car that's less bad for the environment.
But also I really like manual transmission because number one, manual transmission is
more fuel efficient than automatic. And also I like to have more control when I'm driving. I feel
safer in a manual transition car because when you do manual, you actually pay more attention to your
driving. You have to concentrate. But automatic, you can think about other things, listen to the music
and touch. So I think that that's a safety issue. What do you look for? I know you're really really
into cars. Yeah, I actually prefer manual transmissions as well. Most importantly because of
the way that the car drives, especially a sports car, it's definitely something for me is nice
to have a manual transmission. But also you know little nice features like in the exterior,
like the rims, I like nice rims, or maybe a nice paint job. Tinted windows, I'm not a very big fan
of tinted windows. But yeah, I don't know. Some cars nowadays even for, as you said, politicians,
they even sell them bulletproof. That's right. They have bulletproof glass. Very, very secure. Well,
for me, I don't think I need bulletproof glass, but a good stereo is a good sound. That's right.
Yeah, you want to have good speakers and the... Connect your iPod to the stereo now. Exactly. Exactly.
So a lot of great things with cars and actually the model that they mentioned, the Ford Pinto
is a very popular but very bad car. It was cheap. It was cheap, but it wasn't very good.
And the 1970s and 80s, this was a very common car and it's its famous for being a small cheap car.
That's right. That's right. Like the Volkswagen Beetle. Yes, exactly. So maybe you can come
to our website, EnglishPod.com and you can tell us if you have a car, what was your first car?
And did you buy a new car or a used car? That's right. Second hand cars. So let us know.
And of course, if you have any questions, we're always there on the website EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.