Hello English learners welcome back to English pot my name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today we're bringing you part four of our romantic series called I'm sorry I love you
Yeah and today we've got some drama I don't we we got a lot of drama and we got a lot of useful
language yeah we're gonna learn some phrases we can use to describe a mistake and we're also going to
learn how we can comfort someone we can make them feel better okay exactly so in our dialogue today
Veronica and her boyfriend are on a break right so what does it mean to be on a break well it means you
stop having a romantic relationship for a short time so you can say we are on a break so we're not dating
we're not dating oh we don't date all right all right all right all right all right we could say let's take a
break right so we've got the state on a break and the action take a break take a break okay let's take a break
okay so let's listen to our dialogue and it's gonna be a little bit fast and the girl I think she's
crying so it'll be a little bit difficult to understand but Marco and I will come back in a minute
and we'll talk about some of the difficult language here
so so I said let's take a break and since that night I've been waiting for him to call but I still
have it hurt from him you don't think he's seeing someone else do you come on don't be so dramatic
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine you think so oh no how could he do this to me
I'm sure he's cheating on me why else would me call but you two are on a break theoretically he can
do whatever he likes he's a love of my life I really mess this up come on hun pull your stuff together
it's going to be all right
but I I still love him and it's all my fault I can't believe how immature and
salvage I was being I mean he is a firefighter it's not like he can just leave someone in
the burning building and meet me for dinner I'm totally messed this up you know what Veronica
I think he should make the first step I'm sure he'll forgive you no this is not gonna happen
I I really the everything hey do you hear something
it's your lovely firefighter
Wow that's a romantic boyfriend singing in the street yeah yeah that's amazing have you have you ever
done that for a girl um no have you have you ever sung to a girl and KTV I've sung to a girl and KTV
and karaoke karaoke yeah so but not so much as an industry with all the neighbors coming out to see me
well okay well I don't blame you all right let's take a look at the language that we saw in
our dialogue on language takeaway language takeaway all right so let's take a look at our first word
seeing someone seeing someone seeing someone seeing someone so if I'm seeing someone
you're dating them I'm dating them yeah I'm frequently going out with that person right so
but it's not very serious no it is serious but not really it's more of a casual thing it's not very
exclusive so so if you are seeing someone then you can also see another person maybe hmm
well I think sometimes seeing someone can mean actually they're your boyfriend or girlfriend
like I'm seeing John he's my boyfriend okay yeah see this is the difficult thing about seeing
someone is that for some people it means it's really serious well for other people it means it's more
casual I guess it's important that you and your boyfriend or girlfriend share the same view on the
meaning of this word have to agree on what seeing someone means okay well what's our next word
Marco cheating on cheating on someone cheating on me cheating on someone okay so if you're
cheating on someone then you are like kissing or even having sex with someone who's not your boyfriend
or your husband or your girlfriend or your wife exactly so if I say she cheated on me that means that
my girlfriend kissed her head sex with another guy right but if I say she cheated me
yeah that's different that's different it's different maybe she sold you something for a really
high price she cheated me yeah or maybe she sold me something that was fake or yeah or broken or
broken yeah okay so cheated on is really different from cheated okay let's take a look at our next word
mess this up mess this up mess this up so Marco this is a phrasal verb and that means we
can sort of switch it around a little bit right exactly why don't we listen to some examples
and then we can come back and talk some more example one I messed up on the exam and now I won't
pass my class example two when I'm cooking I always mess up and burn the rice okay so messed up it's
pretty clear I think yeah all right let's take a look at our next word immature immature immature
so when someone is immature they're acting really young really young right but it's not a very good
thing to be immature no it has a negative meaning right it's normal for children to be immature
because our children right but not an adult yes okay so we've got some examples that will help you to
understand this word a little bit better example one your toilet jokes are not funny stop being sorry immature
example two genie acts like she's 16 she's so immature
example three god you and your friends always act so immature
all right so immature now let's take a look at our next word selfish selfish selfish selfish
so a selfish person is a person who only thinks about themselves okay so I only think about me
no one else yeah you don't care about other people's feelings okay so it's not a good thing to be a mature
or selfish exactly okay so I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again we're going to slow it
down a little bit and this will help you to understand these phrases a little bit more clearly
so I said let's take a break and since that night I've been waiting for him to call
but I still haven't heard from him you don't think he's seeing someone else do you
come on don't be so dramatic I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine
you think so oh no how can he do this to me I'm sure he's cheating on me
why else wouldn't he call but you two are on a break theoretically he can do whatever he likes
he's the love of my life I've really messed this up come on hunt pull yourself together it's going to be all right
but I I still love him and it's all my fault I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being
I mean he is a firefighter it's not like he can just leave someone in a burning building
and meet me for dinner I've totally messed this up you know what Veronica I think you should make
the first step I'm sure he'll forgive you no this is not gonna happen I I've ruined
everything hey do you hear something guess what it's your lovely firefighter
okay so we saw Veronica's friend trying to calm her down yeah trying to comfort her okay to make her
feel better let's take a look at some of the phrases she used in fluency builder fluency builder
okay so what was the first phrase that she said everything is going to work out just fine
everything is going to work out just fine everything is gonna work out just fine what does that mean
it's going to be okay it's going to be okay right yeah the problem will be solved okay so if somebody's
worried or somebody is crying you yep you can say I don't worry everything is going to
work out just fine okay okay let's look at the next one pull yourself together pull yourself together
pull yourself together pull yourself together so what does that mean exactly it sounds kind of weird
I know I guess it just means stop crying relax and you know take a deep breath okay just like calm
down yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so you can
think of maybe somebody who's got tears down their face and everything is sort of in a mess
if you pull it together they clean up and they sort of relax right okay pull yourself together
alright and the last phrase that we saw it's going to be all right it's going to be all right
it's going to be all right so it's going to be all right means everything is going to be okay
Yeah, it's going to be fine.
It's going to be fine.
The problem will go away.
You'll feel better.
Maybe you could even say it'll be alright.
Yeah.
It'll be alright.
These are three really helpful phrases that you can use when you want to say something nice to a friend or a colleague who has a problem.
Okay.
Exactly. Very useful language.
So let's listen to some more examples.
Example one.
Don't worry, everything's going to work out just fine.
I'm sure he still loves you.
Example two.
Everything's going to be alright.
We'll find you puppy. Don't worry.
Okay. Great examples and I think it's clear now.
So let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and talk some more.
So let's take a break.
And since that night I've been waiting for him to call but I still haven't heard from him.
You don't think he's seeing someone else do you?
Come on. Don't be so dramatic.
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine.
You think so?
Oh no. How could he do this to me? I'm sure he's cheating on me.
Why else would he call?
But you two are on a break.
He's theoretically. He can do whatever he likes.
He's a love of my life.
I really messes up.
Come on, hun. Pull your stuff together.
It's going to be alright.
But I...
I still love him and it's all my fault.
I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being.
I mean, he is a firefighter.
It's not like he can just leave someone in the burning building
and meet me for dinner.
I'm totally messed this up.
You know what Veronica? I think he should make the first step.
I'm sure he'll forgive you.
No.
This is not going to happen.
I really think everything.
Hey, do you hear something?
Just a little bit.
It's your lovely firefighter.
I'm so happy.
Okay, I really like this style.
It's so romantic.
Yeah.
It's drama, but at the same time romantic.
So we want to know what you think will happen next.
Yeah.
Will they get back together?
Well, they get married.
Well, they have a baby.
Maybe they'll break up forever.
Maybe she'll move halfway across the world.
Anything could happen.
So let us know what you think will happen.
Come to our website at EnglishPod.com
and leave your comments on the lesson page.
Exactly.
And maybe you'll be right.
Yeah.
You never know.
Okay.
So we're out of time for today.
I hope you guys had fun.
And we'll see you next time.
Until then, it's...
Goodbye.