Hello English learners, welcome back to English pot my name is Marco
I'm Erica and today we're at a party
Yeah this is a great exciting fun energetic lesson
We're at the biggest party in the world
Carnival in Rio
Okay so Rio this is this is the name of a city right?
Yeah this is a city in Brazil called Rio de Janeiro
So Rio de Janeiro
Yeah different pronunciation
Yeah it sounds a lot more
I don't know
I'll fend it in my
So for we sometimes refer to it as Rio just to make it shorter
Yeah I think that's actually the most common way it's referred to in Rio
Yeah Rio yeah it's just like if you would say Los Angeles you would say a la
Yeah or yeah if you're talking about qualal and poor you might say chaos
Yeah same idea
Okay so we have some words that we're going to preview before we listen to our dialogue
So let's start with vocabulary preview
Very vocabulary preview
Okay and vocabulary preview we have one word
Samba drone
This is actually a building
So it's it's a proper now not not a common now right?
No it's not really a common now and it's a proper now but it is a building
And what happens in this building?
Basically it's very similar to a stadium
But each end isn't closed off
So you have stands on one side
Yep and stands on the other and you have like a little street in the middle
Okay so you can sit down and you can watch people parade or
Walk by and you can see the dancers and everything
And so what is it used for?
The Samba drone is used so that the Samba schools can present their dances and their
dancers and their costumes to judges and all the people that want to watch them dance Samba
Okay so you've been using this word Samba
Samba
What is this?
Samba is a type of dance that Brazil is famous for okay?
It's um it's very fast dance a lot of hit movements a lot of uh
It's very fast but it's very very nice and the music is based uh with many different type of
Tropical instruments so it's really really fun.
Can you Samba?
I can Samba a little bit
It's kind of hard it's trickier than when it seems.
Okay well we're actually gonna hear some Samba music in the dialogue right?
Exactly we're gonna hear some Samba that is actually used during carnival so okay so let's go to Rio now and
Listen to some Samba
I can't believe we're here
Kind of a win Rio seriously
This is like a once in a lifetime opportunity can we believe it?
We're here at the biggest party in the world.
I know we're still lucky we found tickets for the Samba drum good thing we found that ticket scalper
Look it's starting wow this is amazing look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh
The costumes are so colorful this is so cool
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious Samba schools in Rio
No kidding look at them. They're amazing look at that girl on top of that float
She must be the carnival queen
Over there so I can get a picture of her okay hurry up take the picture
Really don't like it
I don't know how to dance
Honey I'll see you later
Patrick don't just leave me here
Woo
All right, what a lucky guy he got asked out to dance by a beautiful
Brazilian Samba dancer. I know
I don't think his wife was very happy though. Well we've got some language about
Carnival in Rio right exactly. So let's look at that now with language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right our first word on language takeaway today ticket scalper ticket scalper ticket scalper
This is actually a job title I think
Maybe not a totally legal job title but exactly so what is a ticket scalper do?
Basically this person will sell tickets at a higher price to people who don't have tickets
Okay, so he buys like hundred tickets right and goes and stands outside of the
Samba drone or the stadium any any sells them for like twice the price right yeah exactly
Yeah, that's a tickets scalper actually they they come in handy sometimes because you want to go to a concert or something and you don't have tickets
You gotta turn to them right right?
Okay our next word prestigious prestigious prestigious prestigious
This is a very nice word prestigious
Before we explain anything let's listen to some examples
Example one
Harvard University is one of the most prestigious schools in North America
Example two
The Academy Award is the most prestigious prize an actor can get in the film industry
Example three
He worked really hard and now is a very prestigious heart surgeon
I can see that when when something is prestigious it's really well respected right it's well known well respected and
You can and if you are part of this thing you can feel a sense of pride right prestige
Okay now let's take a look at our last word float float float float now it doesn't mean like to float in water right?
No, this is a now not a verb. It's kind of hard to describe actually yeah it's hard to describe
A float is something that you commonly see in parades right so it'd be like a car
But you can't really see the car no because it's covered with decoration but big decorations and it's made to look like a
Artificial island yeah or a tree maybe so you have people standing on there and dancing or or waving
Okay, we'll definitely post a picture of a float on our comment section so you could see what a float looks like
Okay, so now let's listen to our dialogue again. We're gonna slow it down a little bit so you can understand all of these words
We've just talked about
I
Can't believe we're here Carnival in Rio
Seriously this is like once in a lifetime opportunity
Can you believe it?
We're here at the biggest party in the world. I know we're so lucky that we found tickets for the soma drum
Good thing we found that ticket scalper look
It's starting
Wow, this is amazing look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh the costumes are so colorful
This is so cool
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious soma schools in Rio
No kidding look at them
They're amazing look at that girl on top of that float
She must be the carnival queen move over there so I can get a picture of you
Okay hurry up take the picture
Oh really no I can't no really I don't know how to dance
How do you uh I'll see you later
Patrick
Don't just leave me here
All right we're back so now I think we should take a look at some of the phrases
Yeah, let's go to fluency builder all right
Fluency builder
So we have this phrase once in a lifetime once in a lifetime once in a lifetime
So this is an expression you would use to say that it doesn't happen very often
Yeah, it's a really special event so like a once in a lifetime opportunity or a once in a lifetime chance
Okay, yeah once in a lifetime
Let's look at our next phrase good thing good thing good thing
So we have some examples for good thing what don't we listen to them and then we'll come back
Example one
Good thing I studied for my exam it was really hard
Example two
It's a good thing I brought my umbrella it rained the whole day
Example three
It's a good thing that I bought in my house before the prices went up
Good thing I had money in my wallet your happy you had money in your wallet
If you could also maybe use it as a negative right like good thing I didn't go
Right, I'm happy I didn't go because it was terrible. Okay good thing. Yeah
All right now let's take a look at our last word no kidding no kidding no kidding
Okay, so many of you probably already know this word kidding, right? Yeah, I mean joking
I'm joking just kidding. Yeah, okay, but if I would say no kidding
You're saying like yeah, I totally agree with you right I agree with you. I know you are I know you're being serious
I know you're being serious. I know it's true. Yeah, so I could say wow this restaurant is really expensive
No kidding. Yeah, so you would agree is like yeah for real. Yeah, all right
So this term no kidding is slang, right? It's a little bit informal. Yeah. Yeah, okay
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again for the third time and then we'll come back and talk about Brazil
I can't believe we're here
Kind of a win real
Seriously
This is like a once in a lifetime opportunity
Can we believe it?
We're here at the biggest party in the world. I know we're still lacking we found tickets for the soma drum
Good thing we found that ticket scalper look it's starting wow this is amazing
Look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh the costumes are so colorful
This is so cool. It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious
Samba schools in Rio no kidding look at them. They're amazing
Look at that girl on top of that float she must be the carnival queen
Over there so I can get a picture of her okay hurry up take the picture
Really, no I can't really I don't know how to dance honey. I'll see you later
Patrick don't just leave me here
All right Marco so um carnival it's a Brazilian celebration right it's a it's very popular in all Latin America
Oh really yeah, but Brazilian carnival is very very special okay, so what are they celebrating?
So basically it's the beginning of lint which is a this period of time in the Catholic religion right before Easter
Carnival in Brazil is very special because of all the dancing and all of this and costumes and everything
Yeah, well from the dialogue it sounds really wild and crazy so what happens?
Well it definitely is really amazing and it's just basically a lot of sambam music and partying and
It's really nice and especially to be able to see something so spectacular as like hundreds and thousands of dancers in the samba drum and
And they're parading down in their costumes and and in floats so it's a very very it's a very special event
All right, so it sounds like a lot of fun
Yeah, I want to hear from our listeners. Yeah, for sure we have a lot of listeners from Brazil and carnival is not only celebrating in Rio
It's also in São Paulo and Bernan Boco and Baia and it's a little bit different in each place
So so it's not just a thing of Rio. It's just more popular there is there a samba drum in each city
Yeah, there is a sambam really so Paulo. Yeah, yeah cool yeah
Let us know if you've ever been to carnival or how you
Celebrated in your hometown or in your city. Yeah, come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave us your comments all about carnival
Exactly and everyone be sure to come because we're gonna post some videos of what sambai is like and some photo
So you can get an idea of this really interesting Brazilian celebration
Okay, everyone. Thanks for listening and until next time. Bye