Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and it's the holiday season so that means more Christmas songs for you guys
That's right and today we're going to be taking a look at a very famous song, very relaxed
but very beautiful song called Silent Night
Yeah this is one of those songs that you hear everywhere but unlike jingle bells which is like
jingle bells, jingle bells, not you know very cheering and uplifting and shopping music
This is more as Marco said calm peaceful almost church music so right we're going to find out
what the words mean in this very classic song right it's classic and very religious because it has a
connotation towards the Catholic religion so why don't we listen to the song and then we'll be back to
explain it
Mostly
silence
only
always
With American words
Appeared with Bearγά
Like aANK
And Happy Christmas
Well,
it's a summer
second
I gave
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at this song line by line. So we're not
going to do the standard format of picking out words. We're going to do it line by line
to kind of get a good feel for this dialogue.
So first of all, some background. Okay, so the 24th the evening, Mary and Joseph are
looking for a place to stay. Mary, the virgin mother of God is going to give birth to a baby.
Right. And they need a place to stay. So finally they find a place. It's not a hotel. It's not a house.
It's like an inn. Yeah. Well, it's actually the stables for the inn. All the stables for the inn.
Yeah. And so what the song is celebrating is what happens afterwards after the baby Jesus is born.
So that's where we are. All right. So the first line says silent night, holy night. All right. You know,
it's holy. That means it's religiously special. It's important. Okay. All is calm. All is bright.
So we talk about bright light sometimes. Something is bright. If it gives a lot of light off.
And well, the next line is very interesting because it says round, young, virgin, mother and child. Now,
you see this first two words there. Round, young. What is round, the young? So round comes from
around. Okay. Yon means over there. So around over there. So over there we've got two people. Okay. We've
over there. We've got the virgin mother and her child. Okay. So the virgin mother is Mary. Right.
Right. And the child would be Jesus. Exactly. And this is holy infant. So tender and mild. Okay.
So what is an infant? An infant is a baby. Some some some baby that's just been born. So we can say that
infants are very, very delicate. You have to be very careful when you hold an infant. But in this case,
a holy infant is Jesus. He's special for religious reasons. Okay. And when they say that he's tender and
mild, what does he mean by that? Well, you talk about tender things when you're talking about things
that are soft. Okay. Delicate. Gentle or sweet. Mm-hmm. Okay. And something that is mild or
someone that is mild is very quiet and calm and gentle. So not making much noise. So the baby was
is very sweet, very tender and wasn't crying or making a big, you know, fuss. Exactly. And then we
have a sleep in heavenly peace, sleep in heavenly peace. Well, the baby's quiet because the baby's
sleeping. So you're saying sleep and heavenly peace. That means, you know, may the peace of heaven
because heaven is a very peaceful place. The most peaceful place may that peace be with you when you're
sleeping. Okay. Very good. Right. And moving on, we have Silent Night Holy Night again. But then they
say, shepherd's quake at the site. So what is this? Shepherds, we know that these are people
that take care of sheep. That's right. They make the sheep move from one place to another. And
but it says they quake at the site. So they quake at the site of what? Well, quake we often say
quiver in one's boots or to quake means to shake to another. Well, nervous. Okay. So you know,
when you're going to make a speech in front of many, many, many people, your hands start to shake.
That's called quaking. Okay. So to quake. All right. So shepherd's quake, they're nervous at the site.
Well, the site is the noun for seeing something. Mm-hmm. The site of Jesus. Oh, the baby. Okay.
Glories stream from heaven afar. So glories stream from heaven afar. Okay. The verb here,
the action word is too stream to stream. Okay. That means to come down. Okay. So to come down
and kind of big amounts. So we have glory glory. So happiness and joy and glory and good things
coming down from the heaven. So lots of positive, good things coming down from heaven.
And where is heaven afar? So the key part of this is the word far. It's far away, right? Yeah.
A far is an old word we used to describe something that's far away. So the heavens of far,
the heavens that are far away are giving us all of this joy and happiness. Okay. Glory. And then the
song says heavily hosts sing, hallelujah. So heavenly hosts, those are bodies or people or spirits,
angels, angels. They're singing hallelujah. So hallelujah is a word that we often use in the
Christian religion that comes from Greek, actually. Oh, really? Yeah. So hallelujah is a Greek word and it
means celebrate joy, amen. Okay. Hallelujah. It's something you're happy about.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah. And then they say Christ the Savior is born. Now we have this the Savior.
What is it? Who is the Savior? What is a Savior? It's a very good question. The Savior is
aware we only read well we don't hear that often but you've heard the word to save before. So for
example, I fell into the water and Marco jumped in and saved me. So I would be a Savior. Marco was
my Savior. He saved me. But in this case, Savior refers to the Bible and the things that Jesus did
later. So we say in Christianity, He saved people. This is even kind. So he is the Savior.
All right. Christ the Savior. All right. And then our next verse, it says,
Silent Night Holy Night. Son of God loves pure light. Radiant beams from thy holy face. So we have
radiant beams. And then we have this word thigh. So these beams, it's like a beam of light, right?
It's like a line of light, but you know how light is clear. So a beam of light is something that
comes down in a straight line. You can see it. You can see it. So for example, when I turn on a flashlight
and there's a line of light, that's a beam. Okay. And radiant means it's very bright. It's very
clear. Clear and it's strong and it's coming out from that one place. Okay. And what about this word
thigh? It's very popular like form old English, right? It's an old English form of saying,
you. You. Right. So in the olden days in English, we had different ways of saying the word you.
Mm-hmm. Okay. And so thigh is one of those words. And you hear this very often. And so in this
sentence, we're saying radiant beams from thy holy face. We're now starting to talk to Jesus
because we're referring to him. You radiant beams light is coming out of your face.
Your whole face. Now, I think you can probably see this thigh and thou in Shakespeare, for example,
right? Exactly. Shakespeare, the Bible, prayers, and all sorts of old books and poetry.
Okay. And then we say with the dawn of redeming grace. So what is two redeemed?
To redeem is to find value in something that didn't have value before. Okay. Okay. So maybe I
have a ticket for some, okay, I want a small lottery ticket, $5. I go to the store to redeem my money.
The paper is worthless. Right. But it's worth something when I redeem it. Okay. So Christ the Redeemer,
when he saves people, he redeems them. Okay. He gives them value again. Very good. So it's a very
profound song, right? And it talks about, as we say, about Jesus, about angels and it's very,
very religious. So it's a great song and it's well, it's a very popular song. And well, even if you
don't share the religious connotation that the song has, it still is very popular in North America,
many parts of the world. So why don't we have a listen to this song one last time?
So when I was a little girl at school, we had to sing this in German. So I know that there are
some other countries that have the same song with words. So it's the same rhythm and everything
but just in German. Is it this pretty much the same idea, the same words? Yeah, almost exactly the same
just in the translated form. So I'm maybe it came from German. I don't know that because it seems to
be pretty old, right? Right. But it is a very common song during Christmas. And even many times,
Christmas carolers will go around in an neighborhood and sing these songs in different places.
Exactly. And it's a really beautiful song, one of my favorites. And I'm not a religious person. So
I don't really like it for the religious perspective that it gave us. But I do think that it's just
one of those beautiful classic songs. Yeah, those the season very warm. The music is nice and
nice. All right. So an interesting song and I'm sure we're going to have a lot of questions and
comments about it. So we expect to see you guys on our website EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there.
Happy holidays and enjoy. Bye bye.