Hello English learners, welcome back to English pot my name is Marco
I'm Erica and today we're at a party
Yeah this is a great exciting fun energetic lesson
We're at the biggest party in the world carnival in Rio
Okay so Rio this is this is the name of a city right?
Yeah this is a city in Brazil called Rio de Janeiro
So Rio de Janeiro
Yeah different pronunciation right?
Sounds a lot more I don't know
I'll fendic the mind
So for we sometimes refer to it as Rio just to make it shorter
Yeah, I think that's actually the most common way it's referred to in Rio
Yeah, Rio yeah, it's just like if you would say Los Angeles you would say a lay
Yeah, or yeah if you're talking about qualal and poor you might say k-L
Yeah, same idea
Okay, so we have some words that we're gonna preview before we listen to our dialogue
So let's start with vocabulary preview
Very vocabulary preview
Okay, well vocabulary preview we have one word
Samba drone
Samba drone Samba drone
This is actually a building so it's it's a proper now not not a common now
No, it's not really a common now and it's a proper now, but it is a building
And what happens in this building basically it's very similar to a stadium
But each end isn't closed off
So you have stands on one side yep and stands on the other and you have like a little
Street in the middle okay, so you can sit down and you can watch people parade or
Walk by and you can see the dancers and everything and so what is it used for?
The Samba drone is used so that the Samba schools can present their their dances and their dancers and their costumes
To judges and all the people that want to watch them dance Samba
Okay, so you've been using this word Samba
What is the Samba is a type of dance that Brazil is famous for okay?
It's um, it's very fast dance a lot of hit movement a lot of
It's very fast, but it's very very nice and the music is based with many different type of tropical instruments
So it's really really fun can you Samba?
I can Samba a little bit
It's kind of hard it's triggered and when it seems okay
Well, we're actually gonna hear some Samba music in the dialogue right exactly
We're gonna hear some Samba that is actually used during carnival. So okay, so let's go to Rio now and
Listen to some Samba
I can't believe we're here
Kind of a win Rio
Seriously this is like a once in a lifetime opportunity
Can we believe it?
Here at the biggest party in the world. I know we're still lucky we found tickets for the Samba drum
Good thing we found that ticket scalper look it's starting Wow, this is amazing
Look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh the costumes are so colorful
So cool. It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious Samba schools in Rio
No kidding look at them. They're amazing
Look at that girl on top of that float she must be the carnival queen
Over there so I can get a picture of her okay hurry up change the picture
Oh, they look like a Jane too. Oh really don't like it
Really, I don't know how to dance
Honey, I'll see you later
Patrick don't just leave me here
All right, what a lucky guy he got asked out to dance by a beautiful Brazilian Samba dancer. I know
I don't think his wife was very happy though. Well, we've got some language about carnival in Rio, right?
Exactly. So let's look at that now with language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, our first word on language takeaway today ticket scalper ticket scalper ticket scalper
This is actually a job title I think
Maybe not a totally legal job title but exactly so what is a ticket scalper do?
Basically this person will sell tickets at a higher price to people who don't have tickets
Okay, so he buys like hundred tickets right and goes and stands outside of the
Samba drum or or the stadium any any sells them for like twice the price right yeah
Exactly. Yeah, that's a tickets scalper actually they they come in handy sometimes because you want to go to a concert or something and you don't have tickets
You gotta go turn to them right right?
Okay, our next word prestigious prestigious prestigious prestigious
This is a very nice word prestigious
Before we explain anything let's listen to some examples
Example one
Harvard University is one of the most prestigious schools in North America
Example two
The Academy Award is the most prestigious prize an actor can get in the film industry
Example three
He worked really hard and now is a very prestigious heart surgeon
I can see that when when something is prestigious it's really well respected right it's well known well respected and
You can and and if you are part of this thing you can feel a sense of pride right prestige
Okay, now let's take a look at our last word float float float
Now this doesn't mean like to float in water right no this is a now not a verb it's kind of hard to describe actually
Yeah, it's hard to describe a float is something that you commonly see in parades right
So it'd be like a car but you can't really see the car no because it's covered with decoration with big decorations and
It's made to look like a artificial island yeah or a tree maybe so you have people standing on there and dancing or or waving
Yeah, okay
We'll definitely post a picture of a float on our comment section so you could see what a float looks like
Okay, so now let's listen to our dialogue again. We're gonna slow it down a little bit so you can understand all of these words
We've just talked about
I can't believe we're here
Carnival in Rio
Seriously this is like once in a lifetime opportunity
Can you believe it we're here at the biggest party in the world? I know
We're so lucky that we found tickets for the soma drum
Good thing we found that ticket scalper
Look it's starting
Wow, this is amazing look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh
The costumes are so colorful this is so cool
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious soma schools in Rio
No kidding look at them
They're amazing look at that girl on top of that float
She must be the carnival queen
Move over there so I can get a picture of you
Okay, hurry up take the picture
Oh really no I can't no really I don't know how to dance
I'll see you later Patrick don't just leave me here
All right we're back so now I think we should take a look at some of the phrases
Yeah, let's go to fluency builder all right
fluency builder
So we have this phrase once in a lifetime once in a lifetime once in a lifetime
So this is an expression you would use to say that it doesn't happen very often
Yeah, it's a really special event so like a once in a lifetime opportunity or a once in a lifetime chance
Okay, yeah once in a lifetime
Let's look at our next phrase good thing
Good thing good thing good thing
So we have some examples for good thing. Why don't we listen to them and then we'll come back
example one
Good thing I studied for my exam it was really hard
Example two
It's a good thing I brought my umbrella it rained the whole day
Example three
It's a good thing that I bought in my house before the prices went up
Good thing I had money in my wallet your happy you had money in your wallet
If you could also maybe use it as a negative right like good thing I didn't go
Right, I'm happy I didn't go because it was terrible. Okay good thing. Yeah
All right now. Let's take a look at our last word no kidding no kidding no kidding no kidding
Okay, so many of you probably already know this word kidding, right? Yeah, I mean joking. Yeah, I'm joking just kidding. Yeah, okay
But if I would say no kidding
You're saying like yeah, I totally agree with you right I agree with you. I know you are I know you're being serious
I know you're being serious. I know it's true. Yeah, so I could say wow this restaurant is really expensive
No kidding. Yeah, so you would agree is like yeah for real. Yeah, all right, so this term no kidding is slang, right?
It's a little bit informal. Yeah, yeah, okay
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again for the third time and then we'll come back and talk about Brazil
I can't believe we're here
Kind of a win Rio
Seriously this is like a win once in a lifetime opportunity can we believe it?
We're here at the biggest party in the world. I know we're still lucky we found tickets for the song bedroom
Good thing we found that ticket scalper look it's starting wow this is amazing
Look at how many dancers there are oh my gosh the costumes are so colorful
This is so cool. It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious
Samba schools in Rio no kidding look at them. They're amazing look at that girl on top of that float
She must be the carnival queen
No over there so I can get a picture of her okay hurry up change the picture
Oh, I don't like a jane to oh
Really, no, I can't
Really, I don't know how to dance
Honey, I'll see you later
Patrick don't just leave me here
All right Marco so carnival it's a Brazilian celebration right it's a it's very popular in all Latin America
Oh really yeah, but Brazilian carnival is very very special
Okay, so what are they celebrating? So basically it's the beginning of lent which is a this period of time in the Catholic
Religion right before Easter right carnival in Brazil is very special because of all the dancing in all of this and costumes and everything
Yeah, well from the dialogue it sounds really wild and crazy so what happens? Well it definitely is really amazing and it's just
Basically a lot of sambam music and partying and and it's really nice and especially to be able to see something so spectacular
It's like hundreds and thousands of dancers in the sambadrome and and they're parading down in their costumes and and
In floats so it's a very very it's a very special event all right so it sounds like a lot of fun
Yeah, I want to hear from our listeners. Yeah, for sure
We have a lot of listeners from Brazil and carnival is not only celebrating in Rio
It's also in São Paulo and Bernambuco and Bahia and it's a little bit different in each place
So so it's not just a thing of Rio it's just more popular there. Is there a sambadrome in each city?
Yeah, there is a sambadrome in São Paulo. Yeah, yeah, yeah, cool. Yeah, let us know if you've ever been to carnival or how you
Celebrated in your hometown or in your city. Yeah, come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave us your comments all about carnival
Exactly and everyone be sure to come because we're gonna post some videos of what sambas like and some photos
So you can get an idea of this really interesting Brazilian celebration. Okay, everyone. Thanks for listening and until next time. Bye