Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be taking you to the airport
That's right. We're going to listen as a man, um, checks in at the airport and deals with his
luggage. That's right. So we're going to be looking at a lot of great stuff that can help you the next
time you are at the airport at the check in counter. So why don't we take a look at one word that we're
going to preview today in vocabulary preview? Very cablory preview. We're going to hear this guy say
I'd like to check three pieces. He's going to check three pieces of what?
Pieces of luggage. So when we talk about luggage we can say pieces of luggage. That's right.
luggage is a non-count noun. So you can't say one luggage, two luggage, three luggage is. That's wrong.
Right. So we use pieces of luggage. Okay. So three pieces of luggage. Very good. Let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time. We're going to see what happens with this guy at the airport and
with his pieces of luggage.
Next please. Hello sir. May I see your passport please?
Yes. Here you go. Will you be checking any bags today? Yes. I'd like to check three pieces.
I'm sorry sir. Airline policy only allows two pieces of check luggage at 20 kilograms each plus
one piece of carry on luggage. I will have to charge you extra for the additional suitcase. What?
Why? I'm taking an intercontinental flight. I'm flying 16,000 kilometers. How am I supposed to take
only two 20 kilo bags as absurd? I'm sorry sir. There's nothing I can do. You cannot board the flight
with that large bag either. Carry on bags must fit in the overhead compartment or under your seat.
That bag is clearly too big. Now I see. You charge next to nothing for an international ticket.
When it comes to charging for any other small thing you charge an arm in a leg. So tell me miss
how much will I have to pay for all of this? Let's see. 625 US dollars. That's more than my round trip ticket!
All right well that's a whole lot of money isn't it? Well I think it's a very common situation.
I'm sure many of our listeners can relate to this situation. Overweight charges are pretty expensive
very high. I know from personal experience but that's the what we want to talk about. Now we
want to talk about some really useful vocabulary in language takeaway. Language takeaway.
All right on language takeaway today we have five words. So why don't we start with the first one?
So the woman asked will you be checking any bags today? Will you be checking any bags today?
Two check bags. Right so the verb to check. It means to to give your bags to the airline to register them.
Okay so that's what happens with your luggage. You check them so basically they become responsible for your
bags. Right it reminds me of checking into a hotel. Right very similar when you go to a hotel
you register at the hotel you check in. In this case you just check your luggage. You don't check in
right okay so check luggage. So you wanted to check three pieces of luggage and he also had carry on
luggage carry on luggage carry on. So carry on luggage it's pretty simple. That's right you carry it
on yourself. Exactly you carry it on to the plane. Now we can we can talk about carry on luggage right
or carry on bag right or carry on suitcase. Mm-hmm. A very small suitcase that can fit on your seat.
Exactly. All right so carry on luggage. Now he was traveling on an intercontinental flight.
Intercontinental. Intercontinental. We have two words there. Inter between between right and
continental. So this sounds like continent. Okay so he's traveling maybe from Asia to North America.
Okay intercontinental. He's trying to board this intercontinental flight. So to board a flight
board a plane. Board a train. All right so basically it means to to get on to get on to get on to get
on a vehicle. Okay so I can say board the ship. Mm-hmm. Board the car. No. No. No. But board the train.
Board the train. Board the bus. All aboard. That's right that's why in movies you see that
somebody will yell all aboard. Yeah. And the train station right? Exactly. All aboard. Okay so
board a vehicle and our last a phrase for today. Overhead compartment. Overhead compartment.
Overhead compartment. All right let's break this phrase down. Um overhead. So that's on top of your
head right? Exactly. Yeah. Above you. Yeah and the compartment is a place where you can put something
and store it. Mm-hmm. Kind of like a box. Right. Yeah. So you have an overhead compartment that
big box where you put your bags and your purse or whatever on an airplane. Mm-hmm. Very similar
of two for example an overhead projector. Right so that's the machine that puts an image or a
picture on a wall like sometimes you see them in meetings. Right so because the image is over your head
in a big it's called an overhead projector. Okay so some great language why don't we hear again
in context by listening to the dialogue for the second time? Next please. Hello sir. May I see your
passport please? Yes here you go. Will you be checking any bags today? Yes I'd like to check
if three pieces. I'm sorry sir. Airline policy allows only two pieces of checked luggage
at 20 kilograms each plus one piece of carry on luggage. I will have to charge you extra for the
additional suitcase. What? Why? I'm taking an intercontinental flight. I'm flying 16,000 kilometers.
How am I supposed to take only two 20 kilo bags? That's absurd. I'm sorry sir. There's nothing I can do.
You cannot board the flight with that large bag either. Carry on bags must fit in the overhead
compartment or under your seat. That bag is clearly too big. Now I see. You charge next to nothing
for an international ticket but when it comes to charging for any other small thing you charge an
arm and a leg. So tell me miss how much will I have to pay for all this? Let's see.
625 U.S. Dollars. No that's more than my round trip ticket.
All right so I think it's a little bit more clear now and with this it's time for us to take a
look at some great phrases in putting it together. Let's see me together. So this guy was pretty
angry about this airline policy and he said how am I supposed to? How am I supposed to? How am I supposed
to? Okay so before we get into explaining this why don't we listen to a couple of examples so we can
try and understand what it means. Example one. How am I supposed to fit the dog in the car?
There are 10 people in there already. Example two. How is she supposed to get to work if a car's in the shop?
Example three. How are we supposed to know the answer to that? It's impossible.
Okay so I can understand that it means how can I do this? Right how do you expect me to do this?
How is it possible for me to do this? Very good. It's a phrase you use when you're frustrated right?
Yeah exactly you're maybe a little bit frustrated or you're maybe nervous of something that you can't
do or don't know how. Yeah this phrase it's not impolite but it sort of gives the idea that you're
challenging the other person a little bit. Maybe yeah okay so a good phrase that you can use
on different situations and you can try and mix it up with different verbs right? Right. All right
now let's take a look at our next phrase. I'm sorry sir there's nothing I can do. There's nothing I can do
there's nothing I can do. There's nothing I can do. So basically the woman can't help the man even though
he's insisting and he's pushing that he wants another solution. Yeah right so finally she says I'm sorry
there's nothing I can do. So we use this phrase when someone's pushing you too much right? Right and you
would use it only in that situation. Yeah. Yeah. Because it is a little bit it's it's strong.
It's not impolite but it's just you're saying you know what I'm sorry there's I can't do anything
about it. Now let's move on to our third phrase you charge next to nothing. Next to nothing.
Next to nothing. Next to nothing. All right so we're talking about charging we're talking about
money why don't we listen to some examples of what this next to nothing phrase means.
Example one. Do you like my new house? It was so cheap that I almost cost next to nothing.
Example two. Let's go to Thailand. Take it's cost next to nothing right now.
Example three. The real estate agent charged me next to nothing for his commission so I got a really good deal.
So when something costs next to nothing it's really cheap. Right. Right. Or you consider it to be cheap.
And now for our last phrase it's the complete opposite of next to nothing. Right. Charge an arm in a leg.
An arm and a leg. An arm and a leg. All right so this means it's really expensive.
It's so expensive it's like giving your arm and your leg. Right to pay for it. Yeah. Very good.
So next to nothing really cheap an arm and a leg really expensive. Can we look at the use here?
All right so when the dialogue we heard you charge an arm and a leg but we can also say it costs an arm
right because we are referring to money. Right. All right so some great phrases here. Now I think it's time we
listen to our dialogue one more time.
Next please. Hello sir may I see your passport please. Yes. Here you go. Will you be checking
any bags today? Yes I'd like to check three pieces. I'm sorry sir. Airline policy only allows
two pieces of check luggage at 20 kilograms each plus one piece of carry on luggage. I will have to
charge you extra for the additional suitcase. What? Why? I'm taking an intercontinental flight. I'm
flying 16,000 kilometers. How am I supposed to take only two 20 kilo bags that's absurd? I'm sorry sir.
There's nothing I can do. You cannot board the flight with that large bag either. Carry on bags must
fit in the overhead compartment or under your seat. That bag is clearly too big. Now I see. You
charge next to nothing for an international ticket. When it comes to charging for any other small
thing you charge an arm and a leg. So tell me miss how much will I have to pay for all of this?
Let's see. 625 US dollars. That's more than my round trip ticket!
Okay so airline policies, luggage, it's always a problem right? Most of the time you always
end up paying overweight when you travel. Yeah I know that this happened to me once and it was
really expensive. Really what happened? I was flying on an intercontinental flight from from India
back to Europe and I had too many extra bags but I really needed to bring them and so it cost me
$6,000. $6,000. Wow. So my credit card was pretty maxed out after that. That's incredible.
Well I'm sure many of our users probably suffered similar experiences like this so please come to
our website and share it with us at EnglishPod.com. That's right Marco and I are always around to
answer your questions so please check us out and thanks for downloading you guys until next time. Bye!