Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have part 7 of our series all about giving a presentation in English.
That's right so obviously not every presentation is going to go perfectly. Sometimes we do have some problems.
In this occasion we're going to take a look at tech problems and how to handle them.
That's right so you're going to learn some great ways to discuss and to explain technical problems.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert.
Please note that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over. Let's see if this
results the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael. There might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and start again.
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time don't they?
But it's not a huge problem. In the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that I can talk a little bit
more about the advertising concept and what we're looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
All right so we're back and now let's take a look at five keywords that we've picked out for you
on language takeaway. Language takeaway.
Okay so we have some phrasal verbs today the first one is to kick off. That's right Mr. Ford started out
by saying that we can kick off the first TV advert. So this phrasal verb to kick off what does it mean?
It means to start something okay so to kick it off means to start. So I can say tonight we're
kicking off the party at 8 o'clock. That's right or let's kick off this new product with a big party.
That's right okay so the phrasal verb to kick off you've probably also seen it in sports. I
think in soccer you have the kick off which is the same thing. That's right except it's in
now. So be careful with that one. The kick off is the very beginning of the game.
Okay very good. In that same paragraph towards the end we see Mr. Ford saying okay so I just
need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen. Pop. Right. I like this
of actually because it makes me think of that but when you're using a computer and you have these
little windows or these little icons, those little pictures. When something changes they appear
quickly and that means in computer talk it means to pop up. That's right you obviously maybe
heard of this already you have annoying pop ups maybe visit a website and all of a sudden these
new windows start to open. They're all advertisement. Do you buy this by this by this by this?
Those are pop ups but also you can have a pop up in a chat window for example.
And in this case we also use it as a verb. It should pop up so to pop up to appear to appear.
All right very good. Now obviously it didn't work. Something was happening with the projector
and Mr. Ford was going through maybe some of the problems and he said let me check the connection
a second. Well the connection seems okay. Okay connection is a very important now especially
we're talking about technical things like computers. You can have an internet connection. This
means how you are able to use the internet. But in this case we're talking about a projector
which makes things bigger and a computer. And so those things need to need to have a connection.
They need to have a cord or something that you plug into one and to the other so that they can
talk to each other. That's right. So as you notice we are using it as a noun. They need to have
the computer and the projector needs to have a connection. So you have the verb to connect but then you
have the noun a connection. All right and let's move on to another possible solution. Mr. Ford
suggests rebooting the system. Okay so the verb here to reboot is another special computer word that
means to turn off and turn on again to restart. So if I say reboot that I'm using the prefix
they re which means a repetition or to do it again. If I just say boot can I say just I need to boot
the computer? I need to boot up the computer. Okay boot up. That's right so in this case
you would be talking about a computer that is off and you want to turn it on. So I would say
hey Marco can you boot up the computer for me? Now about using the word reboot or to boot up
it's usually for electronic things electric things. You wouldn't say to reboot your car or to boot
up your car. No this is for for computer specifically likeronics for example. Oh man my iPhone just
froze. I need to reboot it. Okay very good. All right and for our last phrasal verb for today on
language take away we have the towards the end of the dialogue towards the end. Towards the end of the
dialogue Mr. Ford apologizes and says you know what I'm sorry but technical problems do crop up sometimes.
Okay so this verb to crop up means to appear or to happen but not all the time. So unexpectedly
or occasionally. That's right so these things do crop up sometimes it means every once in a while
this problem will happen. So can I use this for a person if you say oh you scared me you cropped up on me.
No the creeped up on me creeped up very good so we can't confuse those too but they sound very similar.
They do sound similar but to crop up is usually a problem or an event or a thing that happens
and it happens not very often. Okay very good so I think we've taken a look at a lot of words
here specifically phrasal verbs so let's review those let's listen to our dialogue again.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert.
Please note that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over. Let's see if this
resolves the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael there might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and
start again. I'll call IT support to come over right now. Okay guys unfortunately technical
problems do crop up from time to time don't they? But it's not a huge problem. In the meantime
while the IT guys get to work on that I can talk a little bit more about the advertising concept
and what we are looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first phrase we have is very important to especially when we're
using video or a projector in a presentation we say let's dim the lights. That's right so
we have the verb to dim. So to dim something is to make it darker. But not turn it off completely.
No it means it means maybe to lower the lights. We could actually see this on a computer also
when the screen is very very bright because it's too bright. I need you to dim it a little.
Make it a little bit darker. Okay so you can use this verb to dim to make it a little bit darker
or to make it lower in intensity. That's right. Dim the color. Dim the lights. All right very good.
Now Mr Ford when he was talking about the advert he said well it's new and it's not ready yet
completely so it might seem a bit rough around the edges. Okay this is a very very popular phrase
that means that something is incomplete. Maybe it's not perfect yet. It needs some work. Okay so
if maybe you're designing a new website and it's maybe 50% done. So you say the website is
almost finished but it's still rough around the edges. We need to make some changes to fix it.
That's right so rough around the edges is a phrase that is the opposite of the word polished.
Something is polished if it's perfect and ready to go. Okay and well when the technical problem
started Mr Ford was apologizing and said it looks so sorry and he also used this interesting phrase
bear with me bear with me a second. Okay so this is interesting because it's not the animal
the bear. Right right. This is different. This means you know excuse me please be patient.
I have to do something and you have to wait. So this is a very very polite way of asking some people
or some person to wait for you. To tolerate yes. So both the animal bear and to bear with me are
spelled the same way. It looks exactly like the animal but we're not talking about the animal.
No we're asking someone to tolerate something that's annoying or frustrating.
Okay. For example I'm trying to show you a file in my computer Marco. My
computer is not working. I say please bear with me a second. I have to reboot my computer.
We have to wait here. Okay very good. Now towards the end of the dialogue when we talked about
to crop up the second part of that Mr Ford said unfortunately technical problems do crop up
from time to time. So we already discussed cropped up what is time to time me from time to time.
Okay I think of this as a set phrase because we said already that you could also say sometimes.
So from time to time means every once in a while or occasionally. So it's an ad
verbal phrase. It's a it's a way of telling people how often something happens but in this case
it's not very common. So for example you can say I like to go to the movies from time to time.
That's right so maybe once or twice a month you like to go to the movies.
But what if I come to work every day do I come to work from time to time? No right I mean that's okay
from time to time is rarely or occasionally not very often. Exactly. All right very good.
So now let's listen to our dialogue one last time and review everything we've just learned.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert. Please note
that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see Jonathan could he lend a hand a second.
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over.
Let's see if this resolves the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael. There might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and
start again. I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time don't they?
But it's not a huge problem. In the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that I can talk a
little bit more about the advertising concept and what we're looking to achieve over all with this campaign.
All right so this was part seven of our presentation series and actually these type of
problems occur very very often specifically with with the laptop and the projector and
sometimes it doesn't work it doesn't recognize it and so this is a nice way of handling it.
This is and we hope that these are phrases that you can use in your daily life as well.
Maybe you're working with your colleagues and you're having some technical problems
or if you're having a problem and someone gives you instructions for how to solve that problem.
Like I often get this from my technical team. I say listen I have a problem and they say hey
just reboot your computer and it'll be okay so these are very very common
issues that I think that you can you can learn how to describe in English with today's lesson.
All right very good and of course if you guys have any questions or any doubts about this or any of our
lessons please come to our website EnglishPod.com on the lessons page you can leave your comments and
questions and we'll see you guys next time. Bye. Bye.
you