Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica. And today we're back bringing you another great lesson and an intermediate lesson.
That's right about one of my favorite subjects.
We're talking about food. Exactly. So on this occasion we're going to be talking about food.
So let's preview some words on vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. All right. We have three words for you today.
And the first word is head chef. Head chef. Head chef. So what is a head chef? Well in a
professional kitchen. This is the boss of the kitchen or the leader of the kitchen. Okay. So the head chef is the
the main cook. Yes, but he doesn't cook. He doesn't cook. Okay. All right. So if he doesn't cook,
who's the one that does the cooking? That brings us to our second word. Sushchef. Sushchef. Sushchef. S-O-U-S.
So the S is silent because it's like a French word. Yeah something like that. Okay. So the
Sushchef is the second in line to the head chef. Yeah. He's the number two. Number two. So he's basically
the one that's doing some of the work in the kitchen. Yeah. Now let's take a look at our last
word, cuisine. cuisine. cuisine. So this is an interesting word. What exactly does it mean?
Well it basically means cooking, right? Okay. Like the art of cooking. So for example I can say French food.
Yeah or French cuisine. Red cuisine which includes all the food. Yeah. And this is also the major
that people study in college to be how much chef. Yeah. You study cuisine. And cuisine is a noun, right?
It's a noun. Okay so I think we're ready to dive into our dialogue. What exactly is going on?
Well we're in a restaurant. And it's a really busy night. And so we're going to listen to
what is happening in the kitchen.
Gosh, oh my gosh. Your order would be ready shortly. Jean Pierre, we have another special for table
I'm working as fast as I can. We are willing to read where is my spaceship. Look, I need you to
peel more potatoes, marie, chop some onions and carrots for the stew.
From here, another special. We're really packed tonight. We're running low on wine. There's a
only left in the salon. Sorry I'm late everyone. Wow we're really doing well tonight.
Hi, top-to-king and get a very hot. I need some sauce to eat and the fish needs to be
but chilled and buttered. Okay, how about it? Jean Pierre, table saver has requested to see the chef.
I think they're full critics from cuisine, marie, and...
Okay so a busy night here at this restaurant. I know it sounds like there's a lot of pressure on this chef.
Yeah. Yeah you can you can tell in his voice that he's really stressed out. Yeah.
Okay let's take a look at some of this kitchen vocabulary that we found in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right well we've got five words for you today.
Uh in the first one is peel peel peel peel peel peel.
Pe-e-e-l. So this is a verb and it means to remove the outside skin.
Okay so for example when you're gonna eat a banana you must peel it first.
You must peel it you gotta take away the yellow skin. What else do you peel oranges?
Potatoes. Potatoes like in the dialogue. What else can you peel? I don't know carrots.
Carrots. Yeah. Some people peel their tomatoes I don't know why. Yeah it is kind of weird.
All right now let's take a look at our next word. Chop chop chop chop chop.
So again another verb and it means to it means to cut food into pieces.
Oh so if you're gonna eat carrots first you got to chop them. Exactly right you can put a whole
carrot in your suit and your suit in your rice. Yeah. Okay chop. Okay our next word stirred.
Yeah this is the past participle of the words stir. Okay so the verb stir stir.
So when you stir something imagine you have a big pot. Mm-hmm and you've got a long spoon.
You move the spoon around in circles. Okay. So you're stirring the pot. You're mixing. Mm-hmm.
To stir is very similar to mix. Yes. Okay. So you just move the food around.
Move the food around. Yeah. Okay our next word butchered. Again the past participle of the verb butchered.
Okay butchered. Butchered. Now this a verb to butcher something. Mm-hmm.
It's when you remove all the bones and all the organs from the meat. Exactly so you cut up the meat.
And this is interesting because it's also a noun. Right a butcher is a person who cuts up meat.
Okay so so it's really easy. A butcher butchered. Butchered.
Yes. All right our last word buttered. Buttered. Buttered. Buttered.
Buttered. Okay so buttered. This is weird. I know normally we all know the noun buttered but
here it's acting as a verb. Okay. So when you buttered something you spread or put buttered on it.
Okay so to put buttered on something so you can buttered a piece of bread. Exactly.
Or in this case the fish is being buttered. Mm-hmm sounds delicious.
Okay now we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the second time.
We're going to slow it down a little bit so it's easier to understand.
Right away sure your order will be ready shortly.
Jump here. We have another special for table 7.
I'm working as fast as I can. We are really in the weeds. Where is my sous chef?
Look I need you to peel more potatoes.
Marie. Chop some onions and carrots for this too.
Jump here on all special. We're really packed tonight. We're running raw on wine.
Is there any left in the salad? Oh sorry I'm late everyone. Wow we are really doing well tonight.
Marie. Stop talking and come over here. I need this so sturdy and the fish needs to be butchered and
buttered. Okay I'm on it. Jump here. Table 7 has requested to see the chef.
I think they are food critics from quasi-models rate.
Okay so that seems to be a little bit better. Mm-hmm and hey I noticed that there's a lot of
really great kitchen words and here are words that you commonly hear in a professional kitchen.
Okay so let's take a look at these kitchen words in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right we've got three phrases and the first one is in the weeds.
In the weeds. In the weeds. In the weeds. So when you're in the weeds you're so so busy
and you can't do all the work you need to do on time. Okay so in the weeds it means that you're
really busy. Yes and you can't finish everything. And you can't you have too much to do.
Yeah okay in the weeds. Okay our next word running low on running low on running low on.
Okay so before we get into explaining what running low on means let's listen to some examples.
Example 1. You better look for a gas station we're running low on fuel.
Example 2.
We're running low on beers. Can you go out and get some?
Example 3. My flashlight is running low on battery. Hurry up before it gets dark.
So basically running low means you don't have much of this left. You don't have much of
something left. So here they're running low on wine. So basically there's not much wine left.
So as we heard in the examples you could also be running low on fuel. For example on your car,
etc. Running low on. All right and now let's take a look at our last word doing really well.
Doing really well. We are doing really well. Doing really well. So this seems to be like a pretty
simple structure. I mean we know all these words, right? So why is it special? Well basically
if you say I am doing really well maybe it sounds a little bit difficult to understand. What are you
doing really well? So this is a great way of answering a question when somebody says how are you or
how are you doing? You can say oh I'm doing really well or I'm doing well. In your life everything is good.
In your life things are good and you're happy basically. Yeah but in this situation in the dialogue
what's doing really well? Well the restaurant is doing really well. The business is doing really well.
So when he says we're doing really well, business is good. Good. They're making lots of money. Exactly.
So you can use it with people. You can use it with businesses. You can say oh I'm doing really well
in my new job. Yep or my son is doing really well in school. Yep. Okay so you can use it in
those different ways. All right well let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be able
to hear all of these great words and phrases we just talked about.
Don't worry sure your order will be ready shortly. Jean Pierre we have another special for table
seven. I'm working as fast as I can. We're willing to read where is my spaceship? Look I need
you to film up with it or the marie. Chop someone yarns and cows for the stew.
Oh yeah we're really packed tonight. We're running low on wine. Is there any left in the
cello? Sorry I'm late everyone. We're really doing well tonight. Hi.
Top Turquin and get a very young. I need some so steered and the fish needs to be
but chilled and better. Okay how about it? Jean Pierre table saven has requested to see the chef.
I think there are food critics from Quercaine Magazine.
So Marco do you think this chef had a rat under his eyes? That was a really good movie.
Yeah I had a two-y that Disney Pixar where a rat is a cook. Yes it's interesting I love to cook
but I'm not very good at cooking. Really but it's good because for me it helps me relieve stress.
Me too actually you know if I'm in a bad mood I go home and cook something to eat
the world seems a happier place. And people don't understand it because they think cooking is
work but you know for some people it's fun. Yeah so what about you guys what do you like to cook?
Do you have any particular dish that you prepare very well? And if you do please send us the
rest of it. Exactly because we know that we have listeners from all over the world and of course
we want to know what type of food you prefer. So come to EnglishPod.com and post your questions,
your comments and your recipes in our community section and Erica and I will always be there.
Yes to test out your recipes as well as answer questions. For sure if a good recipe comes
along will prepare it and we'll let you know how it turned out. Yeah all right guys we're out of time
but we'll see you next time. Until then goodbye.