Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about going out for a drink.
That's right, we're going to a bar and we're going to order cocktails.
So we're going to learn all about the different types of cocktails and a little bit more language
that you can use at a bar.
Exactly. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
What can I get you?
I'll have a cosmo please.
Dude, you can't order a cosmo. That's a ladies drink. You're embarrassing me.
Why are you talking about it? It's a good drink.
It's too soft. Order something with a little more kick to it.
Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach.
You have got to be kidding me.
Come on, it's delicious. Especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it. I'm ordering for you. I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have
a Manhattan. Put it on my top. Here. Now this is a real drink.
It's strong. This is going to get me wasted.
That's the idea.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those drinks on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So in language takeaway today, we're going to focus on the names of drinks.
So we heard four of them in today's dialogue. What was that first one, Marco?
The first one was a cosmo or also called a cosmo palette.
Okay, so this is something if you watch the TV show sex in the city you will have heard before
because the girls always order cosmos. Now a cosmo palette is served in a martini glass, right?
Right. You've seen the martini glass. It kind of looks like a triangle.
And it's very easy to spill. Yeah. That's right. So so what does a cosmo have? Because obviously
a cocktail is a combination of different lickers or alcohol with maybe juices and stuff like that.
So what does a cosmo have? That's a good question. Cosmo is a vodka drink I believe and it's
served in a martini glass. Uh-huh. But it's generally considered a drink for ladies for women.
Why is that? Probably because it's a weaker drink but also because it's popular in the media and in
movies and stuff as a woman's drink. So that's how I got that every time I see. All right, very good. So that's
what a cosmo is now. If we move on to another very popular drink a little bit more tropical. I
think everyone always has it when the Caribbean or when they're on vacation at the beach.
It's called a sex on the beach. Okay, this name might make you laugh because the sex on the beach
it's very descriptive but it's actually a very common drink. Right. And in the dialogue he talks
about how he likes to have this drink served in a pineapple or a coconut. So that means it's very
fruity and I think the rum drink. Yeah, and it usually has either a coconut juice in it or maybe
some pineapple juice. Very fruity. Very fruity. I think even they I think they add a little bit of vanilla
or even ice cream like a milk or something like that. So it's very fruity. It's kind of like a milkshake
with liquor. Weird. Yeah, I don't know that I've ever had one but this is the part of the dialogue where
his friend says, come on, you need to buy something that's more manly. He orders a scotch on the rocks instead.
Okay, so a scotch is a type of liquor. It's a whiskey. That's right, Scotch whiskey comes from Scotland.
And it's a whiskey drink and basically scotch on the rocks means scotch poured over ice.
Ice. So in this case rocks means ice. And you'll hear this often. Do you want that on the rocks? Do
you want that on ice? Right. So you don't say I won't whiskey with ice or you don't say I
want scotch with ice. You can just say on the rocks. Scotch on the rocks. So it may be if you're ordering
a rum drink and you don't want it mixed with anything you can say rum on the rocks. On the rocks. Very
good. And not only are we ordering a scotch on the rocks but we're also ordering a manhattan.
So what does a manhattan have? All right, a manhattan is a very strong cocktail. It has
bourbon, which is a kind of whiskey. Mm-hmm. The American whiskey. It has vermouth,
which is also very strong ingredient. It has bidders. What is bidders? Bitter is another kind of ingredient
is often using cocktails to make things bitter. Ah, okay. So it's not a sweet drink. No, no,
it's not a sweet drink. Although they sometimes put a little bit of lemon or orange rind in the
drink and that's the skin. A huge orange. Okay. So both these drinks are pretty strong. They're
very interesting though. All the ones that we've seen, the Cosmo, the Sex on the Beach. They're all
called cocktails. And the cocktail has the characteristic that it usually has alcohol, right?
That's right. So cocktail is a mix of different ingredients, but it's an alcohol-based drink.
Okay. You can also get non-alcoholic cocktails. So there is that option. All right. Very good. So
when will we take a break? Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with
Fluency Builder.
What can I get you? I only have a Cosmo please. Dude, you can't order a Cosmo. That's a ladies drink.
You're embarrassing me. Why are you talking about? It's a good drink. It's too soft. Order something
with a little more kick to it. Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach. You have got to be kidding me. Come on.
It's delicious, especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut. Forget it. I'm ordering for you.
I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a man hat and put it on my tap.
Here. Now this is a real drink. It's strong. This is going to get me wasted. That's the idea.
All right. We're back. So now let's talk a little bit more about these drinks on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. So Marko, there are many different ways to talk about drinks, but the most important
ones that we often discuss, especially with cocktails is weak drinks versus strong drinks. That's right.
weak drinks versus strong drinks. Now, usually the the Cosmo or maybe the sex on the beach,
it's considered to be a weak drink. That's right. So it's not it's not very strong because there's
less alcohol. Like a Cosmo has fruit juice, like cranberry juice and the sex on the beach is very
fruity. So it makes it less less alcoholy. That's right. And actually those two also have one type of alcohol.
So it's not very strong whereas maybe a man hat and has all this mix of bourbon and other drinks.
As well. So it'll be strong a strong alcoholic drink. Yeah. And Scotch on the rocks is also very strong
because it's just Scotch. Right. You're not mixing it with anything. No, there's just some ice and some
Scotch. So that's a strong drink. Okay. So obviously his friend was saying that all those drinks are
too weak. He should order something with a little more kick to it. So in this context, kick means
strength. So alcohol. He wants a drink that's not weak, that's strong. So a strong drink has more kick
than a weak drink. So can we use this with food or with other situations? You can, but with food
that usually means spice. So Indian food tends to have a lot of kick to it. That means it's
very spicy. Okay. So with alcohol, it's strong with food. It's usually spicy. If this rice has a
kick to it, it means it's a little spicy. That's right. So just think about kick as meaning that
something is strong or has a strong flavor. Okay. Very good. Now when they were ordering,
they didn't pay immediately because she said, put it on my tab. All right. So to put something on a
tab, this is really important when you're going to a bar or a restaurant and you want to order
drinks. A tab is a bill that you don't pay immediately. Right. You, the bartender will write down
all the drinks that you have and all of their prices and you pay when you leave. Mm-hmm. Okay.
So if you put something on your tab, you'll pay it later or when you leave. That's right. So normally
it a bar in America. You say, I want to start a tab. That means I want to start a bill and you
give the bartender your credit card and he will keep your credit card until you leave. Oh, really.
So he keeps your credit card into it because obviously maybe you start a tab and then you want to leave
and you don't want to pay then it's poor. People get a little bit drunk and they forget they have to
pay. So bartenders now keep your credit card so that even if you forget to pay, they can charge you.
Oh, wow. Okay. Very interesting. And now for our last phrase, he was a little bit concerned because
this drink is so strong. He said, this is going to get me wasted. Okay. So to be wasted or to get
wasted means to get very, very drunk. So drink too much. So if you say, I'm wasted, it means I'm very drunk.
I'm very drunk. We could say, oh, look at those those boys over there. They're all wasted. They're all,
you know, being drunk and sick and yeah. Okay. So it's a very informal, very casual kind of a colloquial
way of saying being drunk or being intoxicated. That's right. So it's something we often use with friends
or as, you know, with young people, but it's not something you want to use in your English class because
it's not a good thing to be. It's not a good thing to be wasted. Okay. Very good. So now let's take a break
and listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
What can I get you? I want to have a cosmo please. Dude, you can't order a cosmo. That's a
ladies drink. You're embarrassing me. What are you talking about? It's a good drink. It's too soft.
Order something with a little more kick to it. Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach. You have
got to be kidding me. Come on, it's delicious, especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it. I'm ordering for you. I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a
man hat and put it on my tab. Here. Now this is a real drink. It's strong. This is going to get me
wasted. That's the idea. All right. So about cocktails, liakers. What is your favorite cocktail
when you go out? I almost always order gin and tonic. That's my cocktail. So gin is another type of
liquor. That's right. Gin is another type of liquor like vodka or whiskey. It has a very unique taste.
And tonic is a kind of water but it has a certain flavor to it. It has a flavor to it. So gin and tonic
usually has some gin, some tonic water and some lime. But the tonic water is kind of bubbly.
That's right. It's bubbly. So that's I like bubbly drinks.
It's a selection of pain and stuff like that. Yes. Exactly. I see. What's your favorite?
I am a whiskey guy and so I usually order something like this scotch on the rocks or so I never
like to mix it with anything else. And especially I really don't like mix having sweet drinks.
So you're a purist. Kind of it's just that you know when the sweet alcohol and things that
are sweet I don't really think go that well together. No I think I agree. Although there are some
sweet alcohols. Our Italian friends will be familiar with limon cello which is that it's a dessert
the core which tastes like lemon or also calua calua which is very sweet. It's kind of like
a coffee alcohol. Right. So many people like to put calua in their coffee to have Irish coffee.
That's right. So actually the alcoholic world is very vast and actually many people don't
drink alcohol. Many people may have it occasionally. But the other interesting thing is that
usually countries have a national alcoholic drink. So for example the Mexican national
alcoholic drink would be tequila. That's right. Or Russian or Eastern European. What got in
vodka. So in your country maybe you have a local or a national alcoholic drink. We would be
very interested to know about. That's right. Let us know our website is engoshpod.com. We'll see you
guys there. All right guys. Bye. Bye.