Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
And I'm Erica
And today we're going to be bringing you another great sports lesson
Yes, this one is for all our hockey fans
I know we have a lot of listeners from Russia
So this is a very popular sport in Russia, Czech Republic
Yes
So Canada
And Canada, right?
Very very popular in Canada
It's our national game
Well I guess because you guys have so much ice
I know there's nothing else to do
The skiing and hockey
All right, so it's going to be a really fun lesson
We're going to have a lot of great vocabularies
So before we start in the dialogue, let's take a look at vocabularie preview
Very vocabulary preview
Well we have three words for you now
The first one, really simple
Puck
Pue, C.K.
So it's almost like duck
But with the P
Yes
And this is actually kind of like the ball that you use in hockey
But it's not a ball
It's flat
And round
So it looks like a disk
Kind of like a mini-freeze B
Yes
And this is what the players do
This is what they chase this around
So in basketball you have a ball
And talk you have a ball
In hockey you have a puck
Yep
Okay our next word
Key game
A key game
So this word key
Important
It means important
Really important
Yeah so I can say a key game is a really important game
Exactly
You could also maybe say a key player
Key player is a really important player
Or even a key goal
Key goal
Okay
So let's take a look at our last word now
Finals
Final
The finals
So the finals are the last games
That's right
And the winner of the finals
wins the championship
Okay
For example in the World Cup in soccer
There's only one game played in the finals
So after everyone gets eliminated
There's one game where the winner is the champion
Yes
Okay
So now we're ready to listen to our dialogue
And it's going to be a little bit faster than usual
Because it's a sports commentator
And it's exciting
It's a lot of action
So don't worry about it
Listen to it
And then we'll come back and talk about some of the vocabulary
The game between Russia and Canada
As you know the winner will move on to the finals
That's right
And it looks like we're just about ready to start the match
The ref is calling the players for the face off
And here we go
The Russians win position and immediately start up their attack
Finarov gets checked hard into the boards
But he's got a shout has the puck now
And he passes it to center he shoots
Wow what a save by the golly
Alright the puck is back in play now
Level Bore is on a breakaway
He is flying down the ice
The defenders can't keep up
Slapshot
He scores
What an amazing goal
Alright so the Canadians versus the Russians huh?
It reminds me of a classic classic game
He's exactly the classic match
Yep
So let's take a look at some of the vocabulary that we heard in the dialogue
In language takeaway
Language takeaway
We have five phrases in language takeaway today
And the first one is face off
Face off
So Marco a face off here is a noun right?
It's a noun exactly
And it's so in the beginning of a match
The two players will stand face to face
That's why it's called kind of a face off
And the referee will drop the puck
Yes
And they'll try to get it
Exactly so that's the face off
It's the face off
Yep
Okay let's take a look at our next word
Check
To check
So an interesting verb here
Yeah it's really interesting because it's different from
The way that you would say check or revise
Yes
This is actually kind of a violent move
Yeah
So what do you do?
So basically in hockey you take your body
And you hit another person with it
Okay so to check someone is to hit them with your body
With your body right
You can't use your arms or your legs or your hands
You can only hit them like with your shoulder
Or your hip or hip check
Okay
So yeah
It's very cool
All right
Our next word
Golly
Golly is a person
Right
And probably the bravest
The hockey mat
No kidding
So why don't you tell us what the Golly does
The Golly prevents the puck from coming in the net
From going into the gold
Yeah so the Golly stops the other team from getting a gold
Golly
Okay so the Golly prevents the gold
All right very interesting
Now our fourth word is related to Golly
Yes
Save
A Save
It's a noun here
So the Golly makes saves
That's right
When he stops a goal
He makes a save
Makes a save
Yeah
Okay we have some examples
So we can understand this form of using save
Yes
Example one
That was an unbelievable save
Example two
The Golly didn't make the save
Example three
What a save
The Russians win
Yeah a little bit unusual here
That save is a noun
Instead of a verb
But I think those examples were helpful
Now let's take a look at our last word
Breakaway
A breakaway
Okay so you have two words there that we know already break
Yes
Right and away
So what are these two words together actually mean?
Well imagine a group of hockey players
All fighting to get the puck
Right
And then one player
Break's off
Break's out
Escape of the group
Yeah
And he skates down the ice
And he has the puck
And he's far away from the other players
Right
So he's going away from the other players by himself
Yeah
Okay so break away
All right
So we've looked at a lot of hockey language here
Yep
And I think it's time now to listen to our dialogue again
This time we're going to slow it down a little bit
Yeah I think this will help you
To understand these words a little bit better
Hello everyone
I'm Rick Fields
And here with me is Bob Copeland
Howdy folks
And welcome to today's game
You know Rick
Today is a key game between Russia and Canada
As you know
The winner will move on to the finals
That's right
And it looks like we're just about ready to start the match
The ref is calling the players for the face off
And here we go
The Russians win possession
And immediately set up their attack
Fender off gets checked hard into the boards
Moly Sly shot has the puck now
And passes it to the center
He shoots
Wow what a save by the goalie
All right
The puck is back in play now
Pavel Buray is on a break away
He is flying down the ice
The defenders can't keep up
Slap shot
He scores
What an amazing goal
Okay this dialogue is interesting because we have commentators narrating
Or describing what's happening
Yeah and that moment right
Yeah and they're using some interesting grammar aren't they?
Exactly they are because some actions are happening in that moment
But we noticed something a little bit strange
All right well let's look at it and grammar breakdown
Rama breakdown
Okay let's listen to this sentence that we previously heard in the dialogue
Moly Sly shot has the puck now
And passes it to the center
He shoots
Moly Sly shot has the puck now
And passes it to the center
He shoots
I noticed that he's using the present simple right?
Yeah
Even though the action is now
It's in present simple
Yes even though the action is happening in that moment
He's not using the present progressive
Yeah
Because in continuous
This is because if you notice the actions are very very brief
And fast
And fast and exciting
Exactly
So you don't really have enough time to say
For example
He is shooting
Yes
Because it's only one quick action
He shoots the puck very fast
Right
Or for example you wouldn't really say he is passing
Yeah he is passing the puck
Right
It's just one quick action he takes it and passes it
And the action is finished
Yes
I think we can see a few more examples of this
Let's listen again
The Russians win possession
And immediately set up their attack
Here we can hear that he is using the present simple again
Because these are very short actions that finish quickly right?
Exactly
And it's actually very very common
When you're describing something you see
That's happening now
That's really exciting
It's common to use present simple
Exactly
If you pay attention
Most sporting events are in the same way
Yep
They would describe the actions that are happening in the present simple
Yeah
But Marko you have an example of some present progressive here right?
Yes
Let's listen to this sentence
He is flying down the ice
Now we heard the sentence he is flying down the ice
Hmm
Right
Now this one is in progressive
Yeah, why is that?
Well, first of all when we say he's flying down the ice
It's not that he's literally flying
No, he's not an airplane
He's just skating really fast
Yep
Right, so we kind of exaggerate and we say oh he's flying down the ice
But he's actually skating
Hmm
So this is a progressive action
So he is doing it
It's happening for more than one second
Yeah, exactly
So that's why we would say he is flying down the ice
Instead of he flies down the ice
Yes
Right
And let's say it was like really really really fast
Okay
So here we see that sometimes in English
We do use present simple
To talk about what's happening now
Right
When it's happened really really quickly
Or when we want to show that it's really exciting
Exactly
Yep
Makes it much more exciting if we just use the present simple
Yeah
Okay, let's listen to this exciting dialogue
One more time
And we'll come back and talk a little bit more
Hello everyone
I'm Rick Fields and here with me is Bob Copeland
Howdy folks and welcome to today's game
You know Rick today's a key game between Russia and Canada
As you know the winner will move on to the finals
That's right
And it looks like we're just about ready to start the match
The ref is calling the players for the face-off
And here we go
The Russians win position and immediately start up their attack
Federal gets checked hard into the boards
The police wish out has the puck now
Any passes at the center he shoots?
Wow, what a save by the golly
Alright the puck is back and play now
Heavy Moore is on a breakaway
He is flying down the ice
The defenders can't keep up
Slapshot
He scores
What an amazing goal
Alright so hockey is the Canadian National sport
Well actually it isn't the National sport
Yeah
What is it?
La Crosse is our cross
But anyway we're not we don't have a lesson about real cross today
Not yet
No
But actually all Canadians love hockey
Like we start playing hockey when we're about two years old
Yeah I've heard that
Yeah I've heard that some Canadian children learn how to skate before they learn how to walk
It's totally common
Well it is a great sport
Very very exciting
It's very fast-paced
And it's very aggressive
That's what I like about it
I know
Not violent but very aggressive
Yeah but you know what I must tell you that I am not a good Canadian
You're not a hockey fan
No I'm really
Yeah I really hate hockey
Why
You know the puck is so small
It's hard to see where the hands on the ice
And it's cold
These guys are fighting and anyway
Have you ever been to a hockey game?
Yeah
Many times
And I just find that the puck is really small
Maybe you just need better sense
Maybe
Well what do you guys think about hockey
We'll post some some videos and some pictures of hockey on the comments section
So you can more or less see it a little bit more about this really interesting sport
And tell us what you think about it
Yeah so visit our website
EnglishPod.com
And you'll find some interesting stuff about hockey right?
Exactly
And also lots of other great lessons
I exactly
And also if you have any questions or doubts about the less you can leave your questions on the site
Mm-hmm
Alright we're out of time
We'll see you guys next time
Thanks for listening
And bye