Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and sometimes you're just tired of work, you're tired of everything you
want to go somewhere for a nice romantic weekend, you take a holiday or get away.
That's right. So why don't we take a look at this word on vocabulary preview?
Very cablory preview.
Okay. So Marco, the word I mentioned is getaway. It has a couple of different meanings
What are we talking about today? Well, to get away from someone would be to like leave, right,
to try and stay far away. But a getaway. So taking it as a noun, a romantic getaway is
actually to take a holiday or romantic escape from the city, escape from your daily normal
life. That's right. So it's usually kind of brief or sudden, almost like you're just going
to sneak out and then come back in a couple of days. Exactly. So many people refer to them as
island getaways. If you go to an island or a romantic getaway, if you have a romantic
two-day vacation or something like this. Right. And what are you getting away from? You're
getting away from work. You're getting away from the busyness of the city, you're getting away
from noise. It's a nice way to get into the country side. Or as you said, the islands. Exactly.
So I think we can take a look at our dialogue. We actually, we're going to a travel agency
called Getaway tours and we're going to try and see if we can book a nice romantic getaway.
Welcome to Perfect Getaway tours. How can I help you? I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife. Very well. We have a couple of different options such as beaches,
the wilderness, the countryside, or even going to a spa for the weekend. I think something
in the countryside would be nice. Perfect. This package includes round trip flights to New Hampshire.
A free airport pick-up is included. Our VIP limousine will pick you up and provide you with
complimentary champagne and finger food to soften the 30-minute ride to the countryside. Sounds good.
What is the hotel that will be staying at? That is the best part. Your hotel is actually an old
country villa that has been restored and refurbished to accommodate a maximum of 10 guests.
You will enjoy an intimate and private time in this very spacious and warm hotel.
Included in the price is 3 meals a day, excluding beverages. You can choose to eat at the
fabulous restaurant that offers a stunning view of the lush green garden. Or if you prefer,
your own private spotlar can arrange your meal to be served in your room or outside on our terrace.
Wow, this sounds like something my wife would really enjoy. Are there any outdoor activities we can
take part in? Of course. The hotel has a stable with beautiful salions for a very romantic horse
back ride along the country trail. You can also go fishing at the nearby lake or visit the local
vineyard. I'm sold. I want to book this trip. I don't care what it costs. Money is no object.
All right, we're back. I think this sounds pretty romantic, right? It sounds too good to be
true. It's perfect. They have buttlers and food and horseback riding. That's right. She actually
mentioned a couple of interesting words there describing where they're going to go or how they're
going to spend their time. So why don't we take a look at those now on language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay, so the first word has to do with where this couple is going. They're going
to the countryside. That's right. The countryside. So what exactly is the countryside? Well,
countryside or the country is the opposite of the city. So it's anywhere that is rural or less
developed than a city. Not big skyscrapers or businesses or big towns. It's actually pretty quiet.
Okay, so yeah, usually the countryside will have a lot of natural wildlife, trees, gardens or farms.
I think can be considered part of the countryside. Definitely. And so yeah, that's basically the
complete opposite from a city, right? Yes, and that's why a lot of people take getaways
to the countryside because it's as far away from the city as you can go. Okay, very good. And to get to
the countryside, they're actually taking a round trip flights to New Hampshire. All right, so round trip
is an important vocabulary item when we're talking about travel because you can use this for train tickets,
flight tickets, even boat tickets. It means that you're going there and you're coming back. It's basically
two tickets. Right. So the opposite would be if you buy one way ticket or a one way flight.
That's right. So many people dream of buying a one way ticket to the island. They never have to come
back. The round trip means you're going to come home at some point. Okay. So they're actually
going round trip to New Hampshire and also they're getting picked up at the airport where they're
going to have a nice limo that's going to offer them complimentary champagne and finger foods.
Okay. My favorite kind of champagne. Complimentary. That's right. This means that they're not
going to pay for it. Right. It's free. So it's the company is going to pay for it. You can have
complimentary food. You can have complimentary service. These are basically things that someone else
is providing for you. You don't have to pay for them. Yeah, even on a talking about flight,
sometimes people will get a complimentary upgrade to first class. That means they are getting
a better service for free. Not me. Hey, if you're working for an airline, I would love
complimentary complimentary bump to first class. And what about this finger foods? What about that?
That sounds kind of strange. Yeah, it might sound disgusting, but it's not actually fingers that you
eat. It's food that you can eat with your fingers. So they're like small little treats or snacks
they can have. Exactly. Usually if you go to a cocktail party or if you go to a party at a museum or
an event, they'll have these little little foods that you can pick up and eat. You don't need a fork
or a spoon. Okay. So they're very small convenient little snacks that you can just kind of pick
at and pop into your mouth. All right. And all of this they're doing because they have a 30 minute
ride to the countryside. So they want to soften the 30 minute ride. Okay. So to soften something
means to make it more enjoyable or more pleasurable. Because oh no, the 30 minute ride is so
rough. So boring. So this makes it better. Okay. So yeah, you can you can soften things
such as the ride to the countryside or you can even soften someone up so maybe give them some nice
compliments so they'll be nice to you. That's right. To soften. Okay. All right. So I don't
we take a break and listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with language takeaway part two.
Welcome to Perfect Getaway Toors. How can I help you? I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife. Very well. We have a couple of different options such as beaches,
the wilderness, the countryside or even going to a spa for the weekend. I think something in the
countryside would be nice. Perfect. This package includes round trip flights to New Hampshire.
A free airport pick up is included. Our VIP limousine will pick you up and provide you with
complimentary champagne and finger foods to soften this 30 minute ride to the countryside. Sounds good.
What is the hotel that will be staying at like? That is the best part. Your hotel is actually
an old country villa that has been restored and refurbished to accommodate a maximum of 10 guests.
You will enjoy an intimate and private time in this very spacious and warm hotel.
Included in the price is three meals a day, excluding beverages. You can choose to eat at
the fabulous restaurant that offers a stunning view of the lush green gardens. Or if you
prefer your own private Butler can arrange your meal to be served in your room or outside on our
terrace. Wow. This sounds like something my wife would really enjoy. Are there any
outdoor activities we can take part in? Of course. The hotel has a stable with beautiful
stallions for a very romantic horseback ride along the country trail. You can also go fishing at the
nearby lake or visit the local vineyard. I'm sold. I want to book this trip. I don't care what it
costs. Money is no object. All right we're back and now we are going to take a look at a good
group of adjectives that the travel agent used to describe how great this hotel is, how great the
place is. Language takeaway. Okay so the person on the telephone representing the company is
trying to sell something. So she is using these really, really great adjectives to make everything
sound awesome. And one of the first things she says is that you will enjoy an intimate and private
time in this great hotel. Okay so an intimate time if something is intimate it means it's very,
I don't know it usually means like romantic, right? romantic cozy but also private.
Private. So something that is intimate is usually between two people. Okay so if they're going to have
an intimate and private room that means it's a room only for them. Yes or if someone has an intimate
relationship that means that they're romantically involved. Okay and the travel agent went on to
describe how fabulous the restaurant is. So this adjective is really nice fabulous. I think you have to
say it like that fabulous. So this means it is just a wonderful restaurant and some people even say
totally fab. Okay can you describe someone as fabulous not really right? He is so fabulous. She is
fabulous. Really you can you can say. I love it. That's it all the time. Yeah so it also depends on I think
your personality this is a very very descriptive word. So sometimes it's a bit too strong. Okay.
You have to be careful but yeah you can describe a person you can describe a place you can describe
a thing with the word fabulous. All right apart from having this fabulous restaurant they also have
a stunning view of the gardens. All right stunning is similar to the word breath taking or
shocking in a good way. It makes you really really impressed because it's so beautiful or so
unique. Okay so for example the views of the of the beach is stunning right or even someone
you can say wow you look stunning. That's right so this is a really great compliment by the way.
Usually men say this to women. Okay. Women don't say this to men. Okay. You can describe someone's
clothes as stunning like her dress was stunning at the Oscars but if you're
man trying to give a woman a good compliment believe me this one works. You look stunning.
All right. Okay nice little tip there using the adjective stunning. Okay now lush we have lush
green gardens so we're looking we have a stunning view of the lush green gardens. This word lush.
lush usually describes things that are organic like plants and flowers. And we say this to
me that something is very green very healthy very full. Okay so an apple tree the full with apples
and you have a it just looks great you would say it's a lush apple tree. Right or I could even say
I've heard that the rainforests of Ecuador are very very lush. Okay. Very green. Yeah exactly.
All right so lush the very abundant very green very healthy. And apart from these adjectives
the sales agent also described that the country villa had recently been restored and refurbished.
So what about these two words restored and refurbished? Okay basically what she's saying is that
this house this big villa was recently completely remade on the inside. Okay. So the appearance the
look doesn't really change. It's still an old beautiful villa but maybe the insides were old or
needed to be updated. And so that means that the plumbing, the lights, the walls, the paint that
with all restore, maybe to look like the original very very beautiful and clean. But also it was refurbished
which means that the fittings and the carpet and the maybe the lights and all the furniture that
was also new again. Okay so we usually hear about this sometimes in the news when they are
restoring an old church or an old building. That means they're making it they're trying to save
it and make it look like it used to. They're not changing it right? They're not trying to make it look
new but they're trying to make it look like it used to look before it got old. Okay you know
how sometimes old things are worn and they're not they're not pretty anymore. Well what they're
trying to do is make it really shiny and beautiful. And refurbish is basically to give it as you said
new new carpet or sometimes new furniture or stuff like that. So many people refurbish their homes
right? That's right and it's a very very popular thing to do with with older houses you buy them,
you fix them, you restore them, you refurbish them so that you can want to live in them. Right okay
so a lot of great things from this dialogue I think we should listen to it one more time and
we'll be back in a little bit.
Welcome to Perfect Getaway Tour. How can I help you? I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife. Very well we have a couple of different options such as beaches,
the wilderness, the countryside or even going to a spa for the weekend. I think something in the
countryside would be nice. Perfect. This package includes round trip flights to New Hampshire.
A free airport pick-up is included. Our VIP limousine will pick you up and provide you with
complimentary champagne and finger foods to soften this 30 minute ride to the countryside. Sounds good.
What is the old towel that will be staying at like? That is the best part. Your hotel is actually
an old country villa that has been restored and refurbished to accommodate a maximum of 10
guests. You will enjoy an intimate and private time in this very spacious and warm hotel.
Included in the price is 3 meals a day, excluding beverages. You can choose to eat at the
fabulous restaurant that offers a stunning view of the lush green garden or if you prefer your
own private spotlar can arrange your meals to be served in your room or outside on our terrace.
Wow this sounds like something my wife would really enjoy. Are there any outdoor activities we can
Of course. The hotel has a stable with beautiful salions for a very romantic horseback ride
along the country trail. You can also go fishing at the nearby lake or visit the local vineyard.
I'm sold. I want to book this trip. I don't care what it costs. Money is no object.
All right so talking about getaways. Now the sales agent offered him options such as
beach, wilderness, countryside or even a spa. Which one do you prefer? Wilderness.
For sure. So you want to go into the forest, the jungle. Yes I hate to say it. I think beaches are boring.
Sorry mom I know. I love beaches. I like to do stuff when I'm away. So I love the desert too.
But the wilderness is somewhere where I'm outside. I live in a city. I don't want to go to a city.
So I like to go somewhere where I can walk around hike right a bike. Do things like that.
What about you? I actually I don't have a like a favorite actually. Sometimes it's nice for
me to go to the beach and relax. I do tend to get a little bit bored after maybe two days of doing
nothing on the beach. But it is that does give a good opportunity to do other things. Be checked
at a like snorkeling or scuba diving. Which can also be really fun. But definitely I do enjoy the
wilderness as well. The jungle and rafting or camping. Yeah it's good fun.
The insects can be a bit of a of a new sense at times. Or the rain. Or the rain.
Camping in the snow or the rain. Yeah. Oh horrible. But yeah it's great. I know not many people
enjoy these types of outdoor getaways. But of course you know that you have spas. I know
so many people enjoy going to a spa having a mud bath and nothing wrong with that getting your nails done.
Having such I mean getting the whole royal treatment like me say. So this is what we want to know now
is well when you go on vacation what do you like to do? Do you like to get away to the
tropical beaches? Do you like to go to the islands or the jungle? What do you like to do?
Let us know our website is englishpod.com. We hope to see you there. All right we'll see you guys next time. Bye.