Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson here with us at EnglishPod, my name is Maruko
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be in one of my favorite sporting events which is F1
F1 racing alright so yeah we're going to be talking about racing specifically F1 which is a very popular sport all over the world
yeah I think maybe it's like number two in popularity after soccer
yeah I think so I have no numbers to back that up now
well they do travel everywhere they have races all over the world and just people love it so
well it is kind of a cool thing it will going 300 kilometers per hour in a car is pretty cool
alright so let's not delay this any longer let's listen to our dialogue for the first time
back racing fans my name is Rick Field and as always I'm joined by my partner in crime Bob Copeland
we're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimmy Rikonan is leading the pack with only
full apps to go they're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Rikonan it's our close one
and oh no Hamilton hits the wall he came into fast jammed on the brakes and spun out we have yellow flag
and the pace car is making its way to the track the cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car
and the green flag drops right Kona is still in the lead with only two laps to go smoke is coming out of his car
he seems to be having edge of trouble he makes his way out of the pit and for none no one
on so takes the lead how unlucky for Rikonan and this race is over the ladies and gentlemen
for ones who takes the checkered flag
what an exciting race I always love a good crash when it comes to car racers I think many people
go to races expecting to see a crash they don't want to see people getting hurt no but a little bit
emotion of just car crashes yeah a little little explosion here all right so now we saw some really
exciting language related to racing so why don't we look at that now in language takeaway
language takeaway all right so we're talking about that crash and I think what led to the crash
was the driver jammed on the brakes right he jammed on the brakes to jam on the brakes okay now
if I jam on the brakes you push the brakes really really hard and really quickly and really suddenly
right so you jam on the brakes and you stop very quickly so Lewis Hamilton jammed on the brakes and
consequently spun out to spin out okay in the present it would be spin out spin out okay so
imagine yourselves driving your car on a very wet road and then you jam on the brakes right
so then the car you kind of lose control of the car and it starts to spin it goes in circles
that would be to spin out this is actually happened to me more than once really yeah were you okay
yeah I was fine I was fine okay so the car spun out now in racing you always see this really cool
car come out and be of head of everyone when there's an accident right that's called the pace car
the pace car pace car now why is it called the pace car because it sets the pace okay the pace or the
speed so pace means speed so this car comes out and no other car can pass it everyone must go
at the same speed right the pace car pace car all right so after there's an accident the clean up crew
must come out okay clean up crew all right so crew this is an interesting word hmm
when we talk about a crew we talk about a group of people who work together okay but for example in
office can I have a crew not really not commonly right yeah it's people who work together and they
use their hands to work they do manual labor okay so I can save for example a construction crew that's
right or maybe the ground crew at the airport okay or the flight crew also at the airport all right
well in the airplane so that's a crew so clean up crew clean up crew now they came out to take
that car away that broken or damaged vehicle so they were towing it tow okay the verb to tow to tow
so what does it mean when you tow something or you tow a car you pull something behind you so if you're
a truck that might pull a car behind you that's a tow truck a tow truck now this happens commonly
if you park your vehicle where you are not supposed to that's right and your car will get tow
your car gets towed yeah very good all right so we saw five really great words related to racing
and now why don't we listen to our dialogue again and then we'll look at some other interesting phrases
welcome back race fans my name is Rick Fields and as always I'm joined by my partner in crime Bob
we're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimi Rai Konen is leading the pack
with only four laps to go they are heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Rai Konen
it's a close one and oh no Hamilton hits the wall he came into fast jammed on the brakes and spun
out we have a yellow flag and the pace car is making its way onto the track the cleanup crew is towing
the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops Rai Konen is still in the lead with only two
laps to go smoke is coming out of his car he seems to be having engine trouble he makes his way
into the pit and Fernando Alonso takes the lead how unlucky for Rai Konen and this race is over ladies
and gentlemen Alonso takes the checkered flag okay so now we're back and I think it's
time for us to take a look at some phrases in fluency builder fluency builder well even though we're
talking about F1 racing a lot of the language can be used in many different situations so let's
look at some of those phrases now when Rick Fields introduced his co-host he said my partner in crime
partner in crime partner in crime now it's not that they are actually committing a crime no they're
not actually bank robbers but it's a very common and friendly way of saying my good friend or my
person I do everything what ride my coworker yeah but a coworker who's a really really good friend
who spend a lot of time with okay so that's your partnering crime it's just a metaphor right
so partner in crime now what about the next phrase the last stretch the last stretch last stretch
okay before we explain this word let's listen to some examples and then we'll come back and talk
about it example one we are finding the last stretch of a very long week I can't wait to go her
example two he's in the last stretch of his college years and soon peel graduate
okay so I understand that to mean like the final length of time right the last or final moments before
an ending all right so the last stretch the last stretch now when you're on the last stretch you just
have a few minutes to go to go yeah to go now this preposition two and the verb go is very easy right
but if you say five minutes to go what does that mean five minutes left left yeah it doesn't mean
it's five minutes to actually leave right right no it means you you must complete five minutes before you can
be finished okay so it's not about exiting right I have five days to go before I go on vacation so
it's not about you actually going on the vacation it's about you passing those five days can you give us another
example how about we have 45 minutes to go before the end of the day that's right so to go left exactly
to go all right now let's take a look at our last phrase close one a close one a close one
all right another interesting phrase made up of simple words so let's listen to some examples to help us
understand it example one that was a close one the teacher was called me cheating
example two it's a close one we are tied and the game is almost over
example three my girlfriend almost found the presence I hit under the bed it was a close one
okay so a close one it means a situation that is almost dangerous but wasn't but wasn't exactly that was a close one
mm-hmm okay so very good phrases I think we can take a lot from this and apply it outside of
that one right yeah all right so let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back
and talk about this great sport
welcome back racing fans might as a rickfield then as always I'm joined by my partner in
crime Bob Copeland we're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimmy Ryconin is
leading the pack with only four laps to go they're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass
Ryconin it's our close one and oh no Hamilton hits the wall he came into fast jammed on the
brakes and spun out we have yellow flag and the pace car is making its way to the track
the cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops
Ryconin is still in the lead with only two laps to go smoke is coming out of his car
he seems to be having edge of trouble he makes his way out of the pit and for none no one knows
what takes the lead how unlucky for Ryconin and this race is over the ladies and gentlemen
Alonzo takes the checkered flag
alright so F1 racing Erica do you like it do you watch it?
yeah F1's pretty pretty neat you know cars that drive fast that's pretty interesting
well for some people it is and I like why do I want to go to a race and just see fast cars
okay I would never go to a race but I think it's I would maybe watch the highlight on TV
well actually this year it's really exciting because again we're gonna have a night race I think
it's in Malaysia or somewhere in Asia that they're gonna race at night oh so that's pretty special
huh well it's like harder to see and you're going really fast all right so I hear you're going
to the F1 this year yes this year I'm gonna go to the Shanghai circuit to watch the F1 race so I'm
really excited about that I haven't ever been to one so it should be fun all right well I hope you
get to see some interesting things like car crashes and it's pace cars yeah yeah what about you guys
our listeners are you fans of F1 have you ever been to an F1 race exactly send us your questions
in comments and also your stories I think we have listeners from all over the world we have a lot
of listeners in Brazil and I know that there is a grand pre there so tell us how did you how did it go
do you like it you can visit us at englishpod.com where Marco and I are around to answer your
questions all right any Canadian race car drivers oh yeah there was one recently someone something
all right maybe that users know which one is the Canadian so we'll see you guys there thanks for listening bye