Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have an elementary level lesson in which we're going to talk about
small talk. That's right, today we're going to talk to an old friend and so we're going to give you
some of the words and phrases you need to talk about your past or talk about how you have been.
So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to discuss it.
I hate coming to a high school reunion. It'll be great honey. We will get to see your
old classmates and catch up to see how they've been doing.
Ah yeah I guess so. Oh look there's Robert Matthews. Rob. Hey Bill wow great to see you.
Likewise it's been a long time. This is my wife Dorothy.
But leisure to meet you. So Bill how have you been? Can't complain. We have two children who are in
college and my business is going well. How about you? Ah you know me I'm a dedicated bachelor.
I never married although I do have a beautiful daughter with Mary. You remember her?
We were a high school sweetheart. It didn't really work out between us but I really can't complain either.
That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping he would come tonight.
You didn't hear? Frank passed away last year. Are you serious?
Man just drinking your chain. He'll be here soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
All right we're back. So now let's get started with our language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The first phrase we have here in language takeaway is a very important one
because it is the setting for today's dialogue. We are at a high school reunion. That's right.
So everyone knows what high school is but a high school reunion is when you go back to your high school.
For a party maybe five years or ten years after you graduate. So then you meet all your old friends
from high school. You talk about you know how you have been and just meet up with everyone that maybe you
haven't seen in a very long time. Exactly. So a reunion usually happens every five years,
ten years or 20 years. It can happen at different times but this is important because you can have
many different kinds of reunions like a college reunion or high school reunion. I've even heard
of some people who had an elementary school reunion. Really. Wow. Imagine seeing your classmates
when you were maybe ten years old. I couldn't imagine. All right so we're at a high school reunion
and we are there because we're going to meet our old classmates and to catch up and see how they
have been. Okay so this is exactly what you do at a reunion. You catch up with people that you
maybe lost touch with. To catch up means to find out about what people have been doing since the
last time you talked. So maybe Marco and I were classmates in high school and we haven't talked in
ten years. As a Marco I want to catch up. I want to learn about what you do who you married,
where you work, things like that. Right so when two people get together the catch up,
maybe it doesn't even have to be a very long time. Maybe you haven't seen your friend for a week.
And so you want to get together have a cup of coffee and catch up and see how the relationship
has been going or how it's work. So you want to catch up. So you can say this in a very simple
way. Let's catch up or it's been nice to catch up. That's right. All right moving on to our next
word. This guy built meets up with Robert Matthews and they're saying hey wow great to see you.
And he answers by saying likewise. So it's good to see you likewise. Right. That means it's good to see
you too. So you don't have to repeat everything that person just said for example. If I just
meet someone new and I say it's a pleasure to meet you. You can say I could say likewise.
Because I don't want to say it's a pleasure to meet you too. That's so many words. So likewise
is a very short way to say all of those things. That's right. So we were finding out about Robert
Matthews and he says that well he is a dedicated bachelor. So a dedicated bachelor. What is a
bachelor Marco? So a bachelor is a person who is not married a person who is single. A man
a woman cannot be a bachelor. So a bachelor is specifically a man and he's not married and that we
often have a stereotype. That means we have an idea of what a bachelor lives like. Right. He has
only beer and his refrigerator and he has has many relationships and no wife. So that's right.
So a dedicated bachelor is a person who is not married and doesn't really seem to want to get
married or any of this. He wants to stay single. Exactly. Okay. And well to finish off this guy
Robert lied a little bit to Bill saying that a Frank had passed away. That's really mean. But this
phrase to pass away is very important and something we should talk about. So what does it mean to pass
away? It's another way of saying he died. So that's nicer. Yeah, it's a lot more subtle and nicer.
So instead of saying Frank died, you say Frank passed away. So you could say, you know, last year
my grandmother passed away. That's the way of saying that my grandmother died last year. But again,
it's a lot nicer way to say. Right. Because the word died can be a little bit too direct into harsh.
So maybe saying my grandmother passed away last year. It's a nicer way of saying it. Mm-hmm.
Okay. So that's all the language tickle you have. Let's take a look at our dialogue again and
we'll be back. I hate coming to a high school reunion. It'll be great, honey.
We will get to see your old classmates and catch up to see how they've been doing.
Yeah, I guess so. Oh, look. There's Robert Matthews. Rob. Hey, Bill. Wow.
Great to see you. Likewise. It's been a long time. This is my wife Dorothy.
Blasher to meet you. So Bill, how have you been? Can't complain. We have two children who are in college.
And my business is going well. How about you? You know me. I'm a dedicated bachelor.
I never married, although I do have a beautiful daughter with Mary. You remember her?
We were a high school sweetheart. It didn't really work out between us, but I really can't complain either.
That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping he would come tonight.
You didn't hear? Frank passed away last year. Are you serious?
Man, just drinking your chain. He'll be here soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
All right. Let's move on now to four key phrases on fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So the focus of today's fluency builder is small talk. These are phrases you can use when you're
at a reunion or dinner, especially with people you don't know very well. So let's jump in and
look at this first phrase. Great to see you. That's right. So he says, hey Bill, wow, great to see you.
So this is a nice little opening phrase saying, wow, I'm really excited to see you. I'm really happy to see you.
Exactly. I'm happy. Look at you. You know, great to see you. You say this at the beginning of a
conversation. That's right. And actually Bill responded by saying the likewise. So we talked about this.
He's saying, wow, great to see you too. Then he continues by saying, it's been a long time.
This means that these two people, they have not seen each other in a very long time. You can also
say, it's been so long or it's been a long time. That means it's been a long time since we last saw each other.
That's right. So Robert goes on to ask Bill. He says, well, you know, how have you been?
How how are things? Bill answers by saying, can't complain. Okay. So this is not grammatically
correct. Normally you need a subject. Right. I can't complain. But when we're speaking in English,
and we're having a conversation like this, it's okay to say just can't complain as a phrase.
So he's saying, how have you been? Well, I can't complain. Right. Can't complain. That means
nothing bad has happened. Things are okay. Right. You're saying that things are good. They're not
fantastic. But they're not bad either. So you can't really complain. So it's just a phrase where
very directly you can say, oh, can't complain. Everything's great. So you could even say this about
about other things. Like, you know, I asked John how his job was and he said, can't complain.
Right. It means not great, but it's not bad. Right. Exactly. Right. All right. And obviously we
saw how Robert lied to Bill by saying that they're good friend, that they're good friend,
a friend had passed away. And he said, are you serious? Now I'm just yanking your chain.
Okay. So this might sound very strange to to a lot of you because a chain is something that
that doesn't really seem to fit in this conversation. Right. Right. But yanking your chain,
remember this as a phrase, it means I'm just joking. Right. I'm not serious. Hitting. I'm lying to
you, I guess, right? So, but how can you use this in another context? Okay. I could say, you know,
Marco, I have something to tell you. And I say what? I'm leaving, which part I quit. Are you serious?
No. I'm just yanking your chain. Okay. Or no, I'm just kidding. Right. So you're kind of teasing
someone when you do this, right? I'm just yanking your chain. I'm just lying to you. I'm teasing you.
I'm making you believe something that isn't, that isn't true. Exactly. So this is something
that you can use after you tell someone that you were just joking. So, you know, I'm just yanking
your chain. I'm just joking with you. That's right. So don't try to translate it directly or
literally because it's not going to make sense. So just remember this as a phrase or a phrase in general.
Exactly. All right. Let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
I hate coming to a high school reunion. It'll be great, honey. We will get to see your old
classmates and catch up to see how they've been doing. Hi. Yeah. Guess so. Oh, look, there's Robert
Matthews. Rob. Hey, Bill. Wow. Great to see you. Likewise. It's been a long time. This is my wife,
but leisure to meet you. So Bill, how have you been? Can't complain. We have two children who are in
college and my business is going well. How about you? Ah, you know me. I'm a dedicated bachelor.
I never married, although I do have a beautiful daughter with Mary. You remember her. We were
high school sweetheart's. It didn't really work out between us, but I really can't complain either.
That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping he would come tonight. You didn't hear?
Frank passed away last year. Are you serious? Man, just drinking your chain. He'll be
yours soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
All right. So we're back and talking about high school reunions. These are very popular in the
United States, right? They are very popular and I think people often have them every five,
10, 15, 20 years. But most people don't go to the high school reunion until either 10 or 20 years
after their high school reunion. I think at five years is very soon. 10 years is nice because
you haven't seen people, but 20 years is really I think shocking because people can be completely
different or they could be the same. But it's been you know you were 18 when you graduated
high school. Now you're 38 years old. You have this whole life that you've had. And so I think it's
much more interesting. Yeah, it's very interesting. And I guess people go to these things
half because they do want to maybe meet up with old friends that they haven't kept in touch with.
I think especially this was very popular before the whole internet revolution. Now everyone's in
touch and Facebook and emails and it's just so much easier to keep in touch. But before you have to
remember that you know it was basically by telephone or by mail. So actually seeing a person
10 years or catching up with them was very difficult back then. Yeah, we all see photos and videos
now of our classmates. So it's not quite as surprising when we go into them later. But I think
it is still interesting though because at least on my social networking websites there are a lot of
people that I don't have connections to. And so I look forward to my high school reunion when I
get to see some of these people and kind of find out what they've been doing for the past 10 or 15 years.
It's actually very interesting I guess when you see how your classmates have changed,
how maybe the the one that used to be the nerd or maybe not to not very attractive all of a
sudden is really attractive and has like a super model as a wife or how these things work out.
Or the high school football captain is now kind of sad and you know fat. So yeah, these are the
types of surprises that people look forward to when they go to high school reunions. So a very
interesting subject. Let us know on our website English.com if you're high school and the place
where you live do they have high school reunions or maybe even elementary school reunions.
Yeah, let us know. We hope to find out more about you guys' experiences and until next time. Bye.