Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and as you've noticed on our website we have a number of lessons about giving
a presentation in English. So this is one of those lessons today we're talking about avoiding
questions. That's right today in part five or presentation series we're going to try and handle
some questions or avoid questions as Katherine said. So why don't we jump into the dialogue?
Let's see what Mr. Ford is talking about now and we'll be back in a bit.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia
in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners
but for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly the right
level. The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and secondly
what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop? Let's first of all tackle the first question.
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average income.
However as we mentioned before the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly and we need
to broaden our audience for this product. For example the X420 is also ideally suited to
younger student sector who might use laptops both for studying and gaming. There's no doubt that.
Mr. Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say that the computer is suitable for students
but you don't think the price of the X420 is just too much for most students?
Well that's a fair point. If you don't mind I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later
in the Q&A section is that okay? Yes sure. Okay so as I was saying we have an exciting campaign
planned for the X420. Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on
radio and also in many computer publications. We also intend to. I'm sorry to stop you Mr. Ford but
do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective? I mean how much is that going to cost?
Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with you after
the presentation. Okay let me just go on and talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in
store.
All right we're back and now we can get started with language takeaway. Language takeaway.
Okay so Marco a lot of the conversation today was about markets and a target consumer so
perhaps we should start talking a little bit about who Mr. Ford thinks this company's consumers are.
That's right he mentioned that the alpha laptop could also be aimed at the middle class.
We have different classes in society in especially America where we talk about people who are low
income they don't make very much money or people who make a lot of money they're rich they're on top.
That's the high class. Yeah high class but in the middle we have the middle class and this
is just average people they make money they have a car they're not rich but they're not poor.
Okay so they're in the middle so this is the middle class the computer is aimed at the middle
class market but he said that it's middle class white collar worker. Okay so I know this phrase
exists so many other languages but a white collar worker in English means refers to the color
of the shirt that you wear so white collar workers usually work in offices. So because they're usually
wearing suits. That's right they have to wear nice clothes like suits and buttoned down shirts but
we sometimes also talk about blue collar workers who are these guys. Blue collar workers are usually
are usually people that are in trades like for example a mechanic or a plumber because usually
you see them wearing those blue shirts. Yeah you uniform say they usually people who work with their hands
or who are not likely to work in the big office. So usually maybe these people are not middle
class maybe they are lower class. They can be both in America right now I think you can make quite
a bit of money if you're a plumber or construction worker. That's right but he also mentioned
middle class white collar worker within the above average income. Okay so an income is the amount
of money that a person earns usually in a year so we say $30,000 a year. That's your annual income.
That's right so when we talk about something that's average that means it's normal but in this
case we're not talking about something that's average or we're talking about. It's above average.
Above average so if the average income of a person in America is $36,000 a year
on above average income is $70,000 a year or $65,000 a year. Okay but for the middle class maybe
that's different. So in the middle class an average annual income is $70,000 and above average
income in the middle class is $120,000. Okay so the phrase there above average you're just referring
to something that's more than the normal. That's right so in this case more than the normal
income for a middle class worker you can also say below average so below average income is lower
than most people earn. Okay very good and well continuing on talking about markets and the
demographics who were selling the computer too we also talked about our target consumer.
Oh this is something that you often hear in meetings at work or in marketing departments.
A target is something you aim for. It's something you want to hit or achieve and so a target consumer
is the buyer is a customer that you aim to have. Okay so maybe you have some customers that
their students and you have some customers they're very old but your target consumer the people
that you really want to reach out to in this case the middle class white color worker. That's right so
in the case of our dialogue our target consumer is a middle class white color worker for example.
Okay so a lot of marketing stuff here talking about the computer and what Mr. Ford was saying
let's take a pause let's listen to the dialogue again and boy back with some phrases on how to
defer questions.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia in other developing
markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into. Now of course this represents
an enormous challenge within enormous rewards for the winners but for any new product we need
a great marketing message and marketing campaign it needs to be directed and focused at our target
consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly the right level. The question we must first address is of course
who is our target consumer and secondly what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop.
Let's first of all tackle the first question. Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle
class white color worker with an above average income. However as we mentioned before the total
number of computer owners is expanding rapidly and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
For example the X420 is also ideally suited to younger student sector who might use laptops both
for studying and gaming. There's no doubt that. Mr. Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say
that the computer is suitable for students but you don't think the price of the X420 is just too
much for most students. Well that's a fair point. If you don't mind I'd like to tackle your
question a little bit later in the Q&A section is that okay? Yes sure. Okay so as I was saying we have
an exciting campaign planned for the X420. Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as
well as advertising on radio and also in many computer publications. We also intend to. I'm sorry
to stop you, Mr. Ford but do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective?
I mean how much is that going to cost? Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to
discuss those figures with you after the presentation. Okay let me just go on and talk a little
more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at those phrases that we mentioned on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So Marko there was a phrase that I heard twice in today's dialogue
that I think we should talk about. The verb is to tackle so we heard to tackle a question.
Right so when Mr. Ford says I'll tackle that question a little bit later on. He's talking about
I'll answer the question or I'll talk about that question later on. All right but in this word to
tackle there's something kind of physical about it because you know in football we say that when someone
tries to hit the ball from someone else it's a slide tackle. Right and so to tackle a question
means to really to really jump into it and try and solve it and it's you know maybe not an easy
question so I'm going to tackle that later I'm going to tackle a challenge. Okay it's more than just
to solve a problem or to answer. So maybe you can also tackle a project a difficult project.
That's right so you know what I'm going to give us two weeks to tackle this project because it's
a very difficult one. All right very good and well actually when he was getting some questions from
the audience members specifically because he was kind of being interrupted he was very polite about it
and to kind of defer the question he said you know what that's a fair point but I'll tackle
that question later on. Okay and so this is a really great phrase if you want to if you want to
flatter someone make them feel good before you tell them that you're not going to answer their question
or maybe you disagree with someone so I could say you know Marco talk about cake is the only cake
in the entire world that people should eat. Okay and I could say something like that's a fair
point but in my opinion vanilla cake is better. All right so see what Marco did he made me feel good
he said you know fair point that's a good idea but I disagree or but you know in this in the
case of the today's dialogue but we'll talk about that later. Right and actually he did another
smart thing or in the way that he used his language skills here when he was interrupted again he said
hey you know what I'd be happy to answer your questions at a later time or in the Q&A session.
Okay so this phrase I'd be happy to I'd be happy to talk about that at a later time but
right now I'm trying to explain something else. Exactly so these are two really really key phrases
for trying to in a nice way change the the topic or change the conversation. So yeah I guess you can
say yeah I'd be happy to talk about that later on or I'll tackle that question in a little bit
or that's a fair point but we'll talk about it later on. Okay so a lot of great language there
why don't we take a last listen to our dialogue and review everything we've just learned.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia
in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners
but for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly
the right level. The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and
secondly what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop. Let's first of all tackle the first
question. Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above
average income. However as we mentioned before the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly
and we need to broaden our audience for this product. For example the X420 is also ideally suited to
younger student sector who might use laptops both for studying and gaming. There's no doubt that.
Mr Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say that the computer is suitable for students but
you don't think the price of the X420 is just too much for most students?
Well that's a fair point. If you don't mind I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later
in the Q&A section is that okay? Yes sure. Okay so as I was saying we have an exciting campaign
plan for the X420. Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on
radio and also in many computer publications. We also intend to. I'm sorry to stop you Mr Ford but
do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective? I mean how much is that going to cost?
Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with you after the
presentation. Okay let me just go on and talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
All right so this was part five of our presentation series we're halfway done with it and so
far we've seen a lot of interesting things and as you notice it's an intermediate lesson so it is a
little bit more challenging and a little bit longer than your previous lessons. That's right these
are longer and some of the phrases that you've learned these words are very difficult but
you know as a reminder some of the words repeat so for example in today's dialogue we heard a lot
about developing markets and campaigns but we also heard about these last week in an episode four so
you know if you're confused or you want some extra practice I would recommend listening to some of
the older lessons again just to review because you're going to hear a lot of these words and phrases
over and over again. That's right and of course if you have any questions about this or any
suggestions you can also come to our website englishpod.com where we'll see everyone there.
That's right so until next week bye everyone bye