Hello English learners. Welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today we're bringing you again the great series. I'm sorry. I love you. Part six.
The newest installment in the EnglishPod soap opera. Drama romance. Love tragedy.
All of it here at EnglishPod and and in our series. So today we have a really great dialogue.
I just can't believe what's happening here. But before we get into it, we need to preview one word.
That's right. So let's take a look at it in vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview.
Well, we're going to preview this word. Sleeping with. Sleeping with someone. Sleeping with him.
Yes. So it seems pretty easy. I mean, sleeping with. It just sounds like you are in bed with somebody.
Yeah, but you are doing a little bit more and sleeping. All right. So so in English, this phrase actually means that you are involved with someone and have an intimate sexual relationship.
Yes. You are in a relationship with someone and you are having sex.
Exactly. So be careful how you use it because I know that sometimes you want to translate and just say, well, they are in the same bed together, but it's not that they're having sex.
So most of the time in English, the phrase sleeping with means.
That's right. Okay. Sleeping with. Be careful.
Okay. Well, let's find out. Why are we talking about sleeping with?
Well, obviously somebody is sleeping with somebody. So let's listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and talk about.
This is ridiculous. I can't believe you've been sleeping with someone else. How could you do this? You know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible? I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess. I'm sorry Veronica. I lied.
Wait. What do you mean?
I lied. You aren't even pregnant. There's no body in the oven. I was just so overwhelmed with jealousy that I couldn't help myself.
Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about? Who are you?
It's me, Daniel. Don't you remember me from high school. I sat behind you in science class.
I used to go to every football game and watch you in the cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even spoke. Why did you lie like that to my boyfriend?
Because Veronica, it's not fair. I love you. I have since the first day we met. Everything was going fine until that jerk came into the picture and ruined everything.
I went to Mad School and became a doctor for you. You always said, are you wanted to marry a doctor?
You will be mine now. One way or another.
I heard everything you lie in, bastard. Get your hands off of her.
You're crazy.
Scandal again.
This poor Veronica and Steven, I don't know how the relationship could get more complicated.
It's amazing. They're having an amazing adventure in their love life.
I'm sure I'm my love life. Nothing like this.
We saw some really great words. Let's take a look at them in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The words we're looking at now are about feelings.
Let's take a look at the first one. Confess.
Confess.
Confess. What does that mean?
When you confess something, you tell a secret that you've been hiding.
That's pretty easy. You have a secret and you want to tell someone you are confessing.
It's usually something negative.
Marko, I confess that I stole $5 from you.
You did. I don't know. I know one or my wallet is lighter.
So, confess. I shall not forgive you for this.
Let's take a look at our next word. Overwhelmed.
Overwhelmed. I am overwhelmed.
When I am overwhelmed, I am filled with emotion.
It can be good emotions and bad emotions, right?
You feel too much. It's like you're going to explode.
Okay. I am overwhelmed with joy.
Yes. Or I am overwhelmed with work.
And I am overwhelmed with jealousy.
Like this guy.
Right? And that's our third word.
Jellacy.
Jellacy. So, this is interesting because jealousy is the noun.
That's right. It's the feeling of being jealous.
Which is the adjective.
So, what does it mean when you are jealous?
It means that you see somebody and you want what they have.
Okay. You want what they have.
In this case, the doctor is jealous of Veronica's boyfriend
because the doctor wants Veronica.
Okay. Jellacy.
So, Erica, are you a jealous wife?
I don't know maybe a little bit.
But I've never gone to the extent of telling someone that they are pregnant.
I don't know.
All right. Jellacy.
Okay.
And let's take a look at our next two words,
which are actually kind of insults, right?
Yeah. They're not very kind words at all.
Okay.
But you got to learn them anyway.
Yes.
Okay. Let's take a look at this one.
Jurk.
Jurk. He's a jerk.
J.E.R.K.
Jurk.
So, what does it mean if someone is a jerk?
A stupid and mean person?
Plain as simple as that.
Yeah.
Stupid and mean.
So, can a woman be a jerk?
It's mostly male, but now it's becoming more common to use with women as well.
Okay. So, I can say he is a jerk or she is a jerk.
Yeah. But it is more common for men.
Okay.
And now let's take a look at our last word.
You line bastard.
Bastard.
Wow. This is a pretty strong as well.
Yeah. You got to be careful about this one.
This one is almost a swear word.
Almost.
Yeah.
So, what does it mean if you call someone a bastard?
Well, literally it means your mother and father were not married when you were born.
When you were born exactly.
So, it is a pretty big insult.
Yes.
A little bit, I guess.
But it doesn't really really mean that your mother and father weren't married.
Right.
It means that you are a jerk.
You're a really big jerk.
You're a mean person, a really mean person.
So, jerk isn't as strong as a bastard, right?
Yes.
Bastard is stronger.
Okay. So, you got to be careful when you throw that word in there or how you would use it.
And again, it's for men, right? Not for women.
Yeah. You can't use this word with women.
Oh, okay.
That's another one out there.
But that will have to wait for another English pod.
Well, apparently all of these words are just for men. What did we do wrong?
I, Marco, I can't be getting to tell you.
Okay. Okay. So, let's listen to our dialogue again.
And then we'll come back and look at some great phrases.
This is ridiculous.
I can't, but we've you've been sleeping with someone else.
How could you do this? You know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible?
I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess. I'm sorry for Anika.
I lied.
Wait. What? What do you mean?
I lied. You aren't even pregnant.
There's no body in the oven. I was just so overwhelmed with jealousy
that I couldn't help myself. Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about? Who, who are you?
It's me, Daniel. Don't you remember me from high school?
I sat behind you in science class. I used to go to every football game
and watch you in the cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even spoke.
Why did you lie like that to my boyfriend?
Because Veronica, it's not fair. I love you.
I have since the first day we met. Everything was going fine.
Until that jerk came into the picture and ruined everything.
I went to Mads School and became a doctor for you.
You always said, are you wanted to marry a doctor?
You will be mine. No. One way or another.
I heard everything you lying bastard. Get your hands off of her.
All right. So great stuff. Jerk bastards. All that good words going around.
But we've also got some amazing phrases.
So why don't we take a look at those now in fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right. So in fluency builder today we have three great phrases.
Let's take a look at the first one.
Bun in the oven.
A bun in the oven.
Okay. This is obviously an idiomatic phrase.
It could be literal as well.
You could actually have a piece of bread in your oven.
Right. Bun is a piece of bread in the oven.
But in this context, we're not using it.
No. It means your pregnant.
Your pregnant. So the baby is the bun.
Yeah. And the oven is your stomach.
Right. So you say she has a bun in the oven.
Yes. She's pregnant. She's pregnant.
Okay. It could be difficult to understand if you don't really have the explanation.
Yes. You were to say what? She has bread in the oven.
Okay. Now let's take a look at the second one.
Couldn't help myself.
I couldn't help myself. I couldn't help myself.
So when you can't help yourself, you can't control yourself.
Right. You did something, but you couldn't control it.
You couldn't stop it. You couldn't stop it.
Okay. So let's listen to some examples of how you would use.
I couldn't help myself because it's a phrase that you can use in many different ways.
Right. That's right. Let's listen.
Example one.
I just couldn't help myself. When I saw your car, I just had to buy it.
Example two.
I'm sorry. I couldn't help myself. I just started laughing.
Example three.
The cake was so good. I couldn't help myself. I ate it all.
All right. Perfect. Can't help myself. Easy.
Now the doctor, you couldn't help himself from lying to Veronica because he was angry
that her boyfriend Stephen came into the picture.
Came into the picture.
To come into the picture.
Okay. So what does it mean when somebody comes into the picture?
Well, basically you appear in somebody's life.
You come into somebody's life.
So imagine that your life is a picture.
And somebody all of a sudden comes into it.
So they come into the picture. They come into your life.
Come into your life. Yes. So he's angry that Stephen appeared into Veronica's life
and they're in love and all that stuff.
All right. Well, these are some great phrases.
And why don't we listen to them again in contact?
So let's listen to the dialogue.
This is ridiculous. I can't believe you've been sleeping with someone else.
How could you do this? You know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible?
I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess. I'm sorry Veronica. I lied.
Wait. What? What do you mean?
I lied. You aren't even pregnant. There's no body in the oven.
I was just so overwhelmed with jealousy that I couldn't help myself.
Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about? Who are you?
It's me, Daniel. Don't you remember me from high school?
I sat behind you in science class.
I used to go to every football game and watch you in a cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even spoke.
Why did you lie like that to my boyfriend?
Because Veronica, it's not fair. I love you!
I have since the first day we met. Everything was going fine.
Until that jerk came into the picture and ruined everything.
I went to medical school and became a doctor for you.
You always said, are you wanted to marry a doctor?
You will be mine. Now, one way or another.
I heard everything you lying bastard. Get your hands off of her.
You're a doctor.
Veronica is not pregnant. That was a close one.
She's a very controversial topic.
Being knocked up.
Nice phrase.
There's a lot of interesting phrases and ways you can talk about pregnancy.
If you're knocked up, you're a pregnant.
You can hear that in movies.
It's not really a proper way of saying it.
It's not that polite. It gives you the idea that it was a mistake.
You would say she got knocked up.
Yes. Another common phrase is,
Pregars.
This is a more Australian.
She's pregnant.
It's actually a pretty interesting topic.
I know that for example, in Latin America,
if a girl that's maybe in her early 20s gets pregnant accidentally by her boyfriend,
usually the families expect them to get married.
Really?
It's kind of like, should they get married?
There's a lot of pressure.
A lot of pressure.
But it's different in other countries, right?
I don't know.
For you guys, what's it like in your country where you live?
Is there pressure on the guy in the girl to get married?
I mean, should Steven and Veronica get married in this situation?
Or what about just living together?
Or as they say, living in sin, right?
Living in sin.
Living together, living in sin.
Yeah. So is it okay to just live together with your girlfriend or should you get married before?
This is a controversial topic, so we'll have a lot of different opinions.
But it should be interesting.
So visit our website and tell us what you think. EnglishPod.com.
Alright guys, we'll see you there.