Hello English learners, welcome back to English pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another great lesson about sports part of our
sports series. That's right and in this lesson we are talking about maybe the world's most favorite
sports. Right one of the most popular sports in the world soccer or also known as football in
other countries. Yes. Okay so before we get started with this great lesson let's take a look
at some of the words we'll find in the dialogue in vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview.
We're going to look at three words here. The first word is wingman. wingman. A wingman.
Now wingman isn't really related to soccer in any way. Okay but it's a way of referring to somebody
as your right hand. So your helper. Your helper. Your number one guy. Okay. Right.
So a wingman is someone who helps you a lot. Uh-huh. Exactly. Okay. Our next word,
tie the tie. They are tied. They are tied. Now this is an interesting word because
tie can be a noun verb and an adjective right? Exactly. So in this case they are tied.
It's an adjective meaning they have the same score. Okay and a tie is a game that has ended with
no winner or loser. Both of them have the same score. Exactly. And so obviously the verb
two tie is to reach the same score as your other team. Exactly. All right well our third word
can also be used as a noun and a verb and it is foul. Fowl. Fowl. Okay so two foul somebody.
Is to do something to them that is not allowed in the sport. Okay and so when you do this you have
committed a foul. Exactly. Okay so use it in the same way two foul or a foul. Interesting.
Well we're going to hear these three words in context now. So why don't we listen to our
soccer dialogue?
Welcome back soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and as always I am joined by my
commentating weekman Bob Copeland and we are in the break of soccer history today as Ecuador
and Brazil are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 world cup.
The rough calls the players for the kickoff and here we go Ecuador quickly passes the ball
into the midfield but oh it's out of bounds. That will be a throw in for Brazil.
I do kind of know how to the ball and makes a long pass to Hauinio and the ref is called the
question about it he was off side by a mile. We have a goal kick recordor.
Edison Mendez heads a turbulence yell he shoots deflected by the defender and we have a corner
kick. Then Gallo takes the corner we have a foul. Oh no. D to the goalkeeper has foul
Ecuador in player. He gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick. This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world champions. He gets ready for the kick.
He shoots and he.
Okay so Ecuador tied with Brazil in the 2022 world cup. Wow Marko I'm really happy to see that
you are able to see so far into the future. Well I called it so in 2022 if we do win the world cup
you know who said it first. All right you have money on that? Uh yes. All right so apart from this we
saw some really great vocabulary in this lesson so let's take a look at it now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right you've got a lot of soccer words for you but they're all important.
So let's take a look at the first one kick off kick off kick off. So a kick off. This is how you
start a soccer game right? Right so it's the very beginning the referee blows the whistle and you
kick the ball to another player that's the kick off. Okay so our next phrase out of bounds.
Out of bounds. Out of bounds. Okay out of bounds this is a great word. Hmm so in soccer when the ball
goes out of bounds it goes outside the white lines right? Outside of the playing field. Okay and you
can use it on all other sports you can use it in basketball you can use it in tennis or football or anything.
Right so any part that is not for playing out of bounds. What's our next word? Throw in.
A throw in. A throw in. Okay so a throw in. The ball goes out of bounds. Uh huh. How do you put it back
into play? Obviously a throw in. Okay so you throw in the ball. That's the only time where a soccer
player will actually grab the ball with his hands. All right now another soccer term we have here
off side. Off side. Off sides. Okay so this is a little bit difficult to explain but just imagine
you're on the soccer field. Uh huh. And you are trying to score a goal. Now you have some defenders
right? Right? So the people who are trying to take the ball away and you pass the ball to somebody who is
behind the defenders. Oh and that person is off side. Exactly so you must be at all times
in the same position as the defenders or in front of them but you can't be all the way in the back.
Okay so is this a noun or a verb or an adjective? So this is an adjective he is off side.
That's his condition. Okay great. Excellent explanation Markle thank you. Right. Now we're going to
look at three different phrases for three types of kicks in soccer. Okay so let's take a look at this.
The first one is goal kick. A goal kick. Okay goal kick. So who does the goal kick? It's usually the
goalie or the goalkeeper. All right. Who takes the goal kick? Okay so when the goalie kicks the ball.
Now what about a corner kick? Okay so if the team is attacking and the ball goes out of bounds
in the back area near the goal then they get a corner kick. They got a kick the ball from the corner
of the field. This is a great chance to score a goal isn't it? Exactly yes. Okay and our final kick
a penalty kick. Penalty kick. Penalty kick. So if a player gets fouled while he is in the area near
the goal. Okay he gets a penalty kick. So basically it's just him. I think it's 13 or 15 steps away from
the goalie and he gets the opportunity to score or to kick the ball. So there are no defenders or
other players in the way. Wow another great chance to score a goal. All right well these are all
great soccer words. I think we should hear them again in context. So let's listen this time a little bit slower.
Welcome back soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and as always I am joined by my
commentating wingman Bob Copeland and we're on the brink of soccer history today as Ecuador and Brazil
are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 World Cup.
The ref calls the players for the kick off and here we go. Ecuador quickly passes the ball to
the midfield but oh it's out of bounds. That will be a throw in for Brazil.
Adriano has the ball and makes a long past to Rubinio and the ref has called him upside.
No question about it. He was off side by a mile. We have a goal kick for Ecuador.
Edison Mendez heads it to Valencia. He shoots deflected by the defender and we have a corner kick.
The El Gado takes the corner and we have a foul. Oh no. The the goalkeeper has fouled the
Ecuadorian player. He gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick. This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become World Champions. He gets ready for the
kick. He shoots and he. All right so we heard these words that we were talking about in context
and now some really interesting phrases came up and this would be a good time to take a look at them
in fluency builder. Fluency builder. Well Marco there are three great phrases in this dialogue
that I want to look at. The first one on the brink of we are on the brink of. We're on the brink of
soccer history. Okay so on the brink of what exactly does that mean? Well why don't we hear some
examples to help us understand the meaning? Example one. Look we don't have any money. We're on the
brink of going bankrupt. Example two. The two countries are on the brink of war. Example three.
We're on the brink of an important discovery. All right so great examples on the brink of
a critical point. Exactly means you're almost there right? Okay yeah very good and what about
this next phrase that I saw and it was really interesting? No question about it. No question about it.
No question about it. No question about it. All right so this is a statement that doesn't really
make much sense but what am I saying when I say oh no question about it? You're saying I agree there
is no doubts you're right. You're right. Okay well let's give some examples. I could say
there's no question about it. Ecuador is a great soccer team. There is no question about that.
All right so or you can say no question about it. Our company makes the best products on the market.
Okay so really useful phrase that you can use in sports or anywhere else. Okay and now let's take a
look at our last phrase for Fluency Builder and it's a really good one too. Exaggerate a little bit.
Okay by a mile. By a mile. By a mile. So he was off side by a mile. Right so the commentator is saying
that he was very off side. That it was really obvious. Right. So you can use that also in different
contexts maybe not in sports. Okay so maybe we can say our company is ahead of all the others by a
mile. Right or if you tell somebody to guess your age and they say oh I think you are 42.
Oh you could say you're off by a mile. Right so you're really really wrong. Exactly. Yeah so it's
a way of exaggerating a little bit. Yes and thing is really obvious. Right. Well it's three awesome phrases
and I think it will help us to hear them one more time. So let's listen to the dialogue.
Welcome Max soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and as always I am joined by my
commentating wingman Bob Copeland and we are in the break of soccer history today as Ecuador
and Brazil are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 World Cup. The ref calls the players
for the kickoff and here we go Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the midfield but oh it's out of
bow that will be a throw in for Brazil. I do kind of know how to the ball and makes a long past of a
wienio and the ref is called a mobside. No question about it he was off side by a mile. We have a
goal kick record or Edison Mendez heads a turbo Lachio he shoots deflected by the defender and we have a
corner kick. Then Galot takes the corner we have a foul. Oh no be that the goalkeeper has foul
Ecuador in player he gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick. This is the perfect
opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become World Champion. He gets ready for the kick
he shoots and he
will be a winner.
Okay well as you all may know soccer is a very popular sport especially in Latin America. That's right
and your favorite team Ecuador are they are they really this good in soccer they're really going to win
the 2022 Cup. Well maybe not well actually Ecuador has has improved with time but usually it's
the strong teams like Argentina in Brazil who dominate the region right. Right. But yeah hopefully we'll
make it next time. Okay well I have my money on Ecuador and for 2022. But yeah not on Canada there's
no hope for us. Well Canada is doing really well now they actually beat Mexico if on that mistaken.
Oh actually that sort of yeah I kind of remember that now but there's I think there's no hope for us
to be Brazil or Argentina one of these big countries. We have the next World Cup coming up so it's
really exciting and I don't know who's going to win. All right well um listeners who do you think
is going to win who is the best soccer team out there? Right they're really good soccer teams although
some of our some countries aren't really known for their soccer like Russia you don't really
hear too much soccer from Russia really or from China is for them. I wonder how popular it is in these
so let us know come to our website englishpod.com tell us how popular soccer is in your country
or what team you are a fan of. I know many people like the European cups and their fans of
Barcelona or the Italian teams. Well come to the website Marco and I are always around to
answer your questions and until next time goodbye.