Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking a little bit about small talk.
That's right we are getting towards the end of our series. Actually this is the last podcast
that we will have all about small talk and we're just going to be following Mr. Campbell and Michelle
and Melissa and they're just going to talk very briefly about the weather about traveling,
very casual things. That's right. So let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a
moment to discuss what's going on.
Hi ladies, thanks for picking me up. It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely. It's been raining for hours. How are you Melissa? Are you okay?
I'm great thanks, Mr. Campbell. Do you have any business trips, Fancy and Mr. Campbell?
Of course I'm always traveling. I'll leave for London next Monday and then I'll fly
to Boston from there. It's going to be a busy month. How about you Michelle? Do you have any vacation
plans? Yes, Megan, I will travel to Beijing to see my experience for the Spring Festival and
hopefully next year we will visit London. I hear it's a wonderful city. I couldn't agree more.
London is really fantastic. It's my favorite city. I'm sure you'll have a great time.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, we don't have that much today. Language takeaway. We do have a couple of really
important words and phrases. The first one comes from the very first line. Mr. Campbell says
Hi ladies, thanks for picking me up. That's right. Now this is a phrasal verb to pick someone up.
Means to get them right to. Yeah, to gather them to collect them. You can do this with a car.
Like I will pick you up at the airport. But you can also do it in person by just walking to a place
and meeting somebody and then taking them somewhere else. That's the important part. You take them somewhere else.
So maybe if you go pick your kids up from school, you just walk there. You get them and you walk
back home. That's right. And so the key here is that you remember that the verb goes first,
I will pick and then you have the person. I will pick you up. I will pick them up. He will pick us up.
That's right. So the subject goes between pick and up. That's right. All right. So we're going to pick
someone up. And then Mr. Campbell comments on the weather. He says it's awful weather out there.
It's awful. All right. So awful. You listen to the tone. You automatically think that this is
probably a bad thing in your right. It is a bad thing. But what's another way to say,
awful. It's terrible. It's bad. It's horrible. So awful is a way to say something's really bad.
And we use it very often with the weather. This weather is awful. But we can also use it about
other things like food for example. So if you have something to eat and it doesn't taste good,
you can say this is awful. What is this? Or what's that awful smell? Oh, Marco took his shoes off.
Right. An awful smell. All right. And well, Mr. Campbell went on to tell them that he's taking
another trip soon, but a specific kind of trip. All right. So you know that there are many different
kinds of trips. But the one that he's taking is a business trip. So normally we could just say,
I'm going on a trip next year. But out here, we specify. We say it's a business trip. So what are we
doing on this trip, Marco? That's right. So we're basically working. We're going because our
company needs us to go to a meeting or to do some work abroad. All right. So you know on a business
trip that you'll be doing work things, you'll be having meetings. You will not be going to Disney
world. You will not be meeting with friends and going to movies probably. Right. Exactly. So it's
very different from a vacation of vacation. You go with the objective of going to these fun places.
So can I say, I'm going on a business vacation? No. Do you either going on vacation or you're
taking a business trip? All right. Business trip. So now let's take a break and let's review our dialogue.
Hi, ladies. Thanks for picking me up. It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely. It's been raining for hours. How are you, Melissa? Are you okay? I'm great. Thanks,
Mr. Campbell. Do you have any business trips plans in Mr. Campbell? Of course. I'm always traveling.
I'll leave for London next Monday and then I'll fly to Boston from there. It's going to be a busy
month. How about you, Michelle? Do you have any vacation plans? Yes. Make it. I will travel to Beijing
to see my experience for the Spring Festival. And hopefully next year we will visit London.
I hear it's a wonderful city. I couldn't agree more. London is really fantastic. It's my favorite
city. I'm sure you'll have a great time.
All right. So now let's take a look at four key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right. Now we have a great phrase for everybody here in fluency builder.
Melissa is talking to Mr. Campbell and he asks her how she is. Are you okay? And she says,
I'm great thanks. Now, Mark, or why would we use this phrase instead of, I'm fine. Thank you.
Well, it's basically the same thing. It's just another way of answering this
common question. How are you? You can say, I'm fine. Thank you. I'm well. But this is just another way
of saying, I'm okay. All right. But I think it's important to remember that this is also very
casual, like the rest of the conversation. And pretty enthusiastic. She's great. So it's important
to remember that I'm fine. Thanks is standard. It's very normal. But I'm great. It's a nice way
to change it and do something different. That's right. Okay. And now we wanted to ask if we have
any plans, but we wanted to know if we have any vacation plans. And the interesting thing
about this question was that Mr. Campbell said any vacation plans. So that's how he's, that's the
whole sentence. Well, first he says, how about you Michelle? Any vacation plans? So what we think
here is that maybe it's wrong. Do you have any vacation plans? Is something that we, we want to
hear, right? Right. But here we don't actually need to say, do you have any vacation plans? Because
it's pretty clear who we're talking to. We're talking to Michelle, right? Right. And we're talking
about traveling and we're talking about plans. So it's overstated that we don't really need to say,
do you have any vacation plans? We're already talking about the subject. Now this is a great way to
transition. One person is talking about himself or herself. And then you want to talk about the other
person. So you say, what about you? Any vacation plans or any dinner plans or any ideas?
Exactly. So it's a great way to, uh, he's a transition from one idea or from one person to another.
Now to the next phrase, a very common one, specifically when you are not really sure about something,
but somebody told you, specifically in this case, Michelle says, I hear it's a wonderful city
when talking about London. So what does she mean by, I hear it's a wonderful city? Well basically
Michelle is saying she's never been to London, but she's read or she's heard from friends or
from a TV show that London's a wonderful city. So she can't say, it is a wonderful city because she's
never been there. But she can say, listen, you know, I have, I have heard this from other people
or from magazines. So it's, it's not even clear where she heard it, but that's not really important.
So basically the idea is that we don't know personally, but we have friends that told us
or we have read in a magazine or a TV show, we've seen it that it's great. So you can use it
with many things like a restaurant. That's right. I hear the food is delicious. Or I could say,
hey, Marco, I'm going to Hong Kong Disneyland next year. Right, and I can say, oh, I hear that
it's a very fun place. So, Marco, you've never been there, right? No, I've never been there. Okay.
All right. And to finish off Mr. Campbell agrees completely about London being such a wonderful
city and he says, I couldn't agree more. I couldn't agree more. So he agrees. We understand that.
But I couldn't agree more is like saying, I really, really agree. Right. Like you are completely right.
Yeah. So this is a way to exaggerate. You know, you want to say I agree. It's a little boring. So you
say, I couldn't agree more. I'm agreeing the most I can. That's right. And then we can also use the
opposite, which would be if you disagree with someone. I couldn't disagree more. So you just
changed that one word. I couldn't disagree more. So maybe I don't like London. Maybe it's too rainy
or too dark for me. So I say, I couldn't disagree more. I think London is terrible. Oh, right.
Maybe not the right thing to say in a small talk situation, but we can talk about that in a minute.
Exactly. All right. So let's review everything one last time.
Hi, ladies. Thanks for picking me up. It's awful weather out there.
Absolutely. It's been raining for hours. How are you, Melissa? Are you okay?
I'm great. Thanks, Mr. Campbell. Do you have any business trips, plans in Mr. Campbell?
Of course. I'm always traveling. I'll leave for London next Monday and then I'll fly to Boston
from there. It's going to be a busy month. How about you, Michelle? Do you have any vacation plans?
Yes. Megan, I will travel to Beijing to see my experience for the Spring Festival. And hopefully
next year we will visit London. I hear it's a wonderful city. I couldn't agree more. London is really
fantastic. It's my favorite city. I'm sure you'll have a great time.
All right. So this is our last podcast all about small talk. And well, I hope it's been
useful. We've gotten some great feedback about the different topics and small conversations you
can have with a stranger, a coworker, a friend, to kind of not have that awkward silence.
That's right. We've gone over a lot of different situations. We've had situations with stranger
situations with work friends. But I think what's really important is that in all these situations,
we're very polite. We say nice things. There are these transitions like I hear or
I couldn't agree more. These are wonderful ways of really being nice to the person you're talking to.
That's right. And we're going to come out with a new series soon. So we would really like your
feedback, any topics or any specific subject you want us to talk. You can let us know at English
pod.com and also your questions and comments can be left there. That's right. So please get in touch
with us. English pod.com. We'll see you guys there. Bye.