Hello everyone, welcome back to another podcast here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica. And today we're looking at another one of our lessons for English of the past
decades and this time it's the 1990s. Well you know the 1990s is a little easier for most of us to
remember. Yeah I guess it's a little bit more recent we're going to be looking at a lot of language that
is still used today. Most of these words and phrases are still used today so they're going to be
very useful and you're going to sound a lot more native. Mm-hmm a lot cooler as well.
Huh? Right so before we get started with this lesson why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very cablory preview. We have two words we're going to hear in the dialogue. Now the first one is
a mall. A mall. M-A-L-L mall. All right so a mall is basically short for shopping mall.
And a shopping mall is a big building with many stores inside. Right so it's like a shopping center.
And our last word for vocabulary preview is gain. The gang. The gang. Okay so a gang is a group of people right?
Yeah it's a group of people. You can call your friends the gang. We're going to go out with the
gang tonight. Yeah. Now we sometimes hear this word to have and it has a negative meaning right?
Right like street gangs. Yeah so people who are who fight and deal drugs and all that sort of stuff.
Right so it can have a negative and a positive meaning so but it just depends on how you use it.
Yeah but in the dialogue we'll hear it with the positive meaning. Right so that's all the words we
have for vocabulary preview. Let's listen to this cool and hip dialogue from the 1990s and we'll
come back later and explain some words.
music
Hey, for eyes. What's up man? How have you been? Not bad. Just went to the mall and picked up some
check out my new adidas. Those are dope. You are going to be getting mad drops from the gang man.
Anyways have you seen Betty lately dude? Don't even go there. That girl started tripping because
I went to the movies with Veronica the other day. I was like look you knew how I was before you got with
that's right. You're such a player man. Dude there's mad max. Let's go say hi.
Max was a are you okay? You look like you just saw ghost. I got an effort English class.
My life is over. Dude you're over it. You need to lay off the books for a while and have some fun.
Come on let's bounce. Where are we going? Oh crap. My dad doesn't go postally.
He finds out about this. I'm going to open the can of what's best on you if you don't come with me right now.
Okay okay. G
Oh
Well it sounds like this guy's got some problems at school huh? Yeah he got an F on his paper but
you always can count on your friends to try and cheer you up by doing something. Yeah but they
use some really great phrases and vocabulary words so why don't we look at those now in language
takeaway. Language takeaway. All right on language takeaway we're going to be looking at
five words and well let's start with the first one. So the guy was talking about his really cool
new shoes his new Adidas right and his friend said those are dope dope dope okay so it's
pretty easy to understand when something is dope it's really awesome. It's cool. Yeah it's great.
Right it's great so that's dope. And it's an adjective right? Mm-hmm. So his friend said those are dope
and he said you're going to be getting mad props from the gang. Okay so mad props.
Mad props. We can divide this word into so let's take a look at the first part mad.
Mad. So we understand that mad is angry right? Yeah but it can also mean a lot. Right. Amazing.
Really. So if I say you have mad skills you're really good at something or you can say
she has a mad amount of shoes. All right so he's going to get mad props. Now props is like
respect or compliments. Yeah so so his shoes are so cool that he's going to get a lot of respect
or a lot of compliments from his friends. Exactly mad props. Mad props. So they started talking
about girls and he mentioned that this girl started tripping tripping. So two tripping. Right as you
notice it's tripping. It doesn't have the G at the end which isn't really grammatically correct but
that's kind of the way it's pronounced. Yeah we would never say the G. Right so if somebody is tripping
they're they're getting really upset. They're getting really angry. Right they're causing trouble.
So why don't we listen to a couple of examples of how we could use tripping for different situations?
Example one. Leanne was tripping because I got dirt on her car.
Example two. Even though I apologize for calling her fat,
Jenny was tripping all night. Example three. He sent me 43 text messages and call me about 20 times.
That guy is tripping over me. Okay so that's pretty clear. Tripping. All right now moving on to
our next word. They wanted to go somewhere and he said come on let's bounce. Let's bounce. Let's bounce.
I'm gonna bounce. Now bounce basically means it's leave. Yeah let's get out of here.
But we might be more familiar with this word as in like a ball right? A ball bounces off the floor.
Exactly. So I guess it's kind of the same. You kind of bounce off the floor and leave that place.
Yeah let's bounce. Okay so for a final word now this guy who got a bad mark on his paper
he was nervous about what his dad would say right? Right? Because his dad was going to go postal.
He said my dad is gonna go postal. To go postal. Now if you go postal it means you go crazy.
Yeah you really freak out. You go you get very angry. Yeah like really angry. This word comes from
the 90s because during a time it was very common in the United States that postal workers
melman were going a little bit crazy and they started shooting people and delivering some strange
packages. Well I guess so people who work in the post office maybe don't have the most exciting
jobs and that drive them a little crazy. Exactly that's what. But now they have a term named after them.
All right so why don't we listen to our dialogue for the second time? We're gonna slow it down a little
and then we'll come back. Hey for eyes what's up man how have you been? Not bad just went to
the mall and picked up some junk. Check out my new adidas. Those are dope. You are gonna be getting
mad props from the gang man. Anyways have you seen Betty lately dude don't even go there
that girl started tripping because I went to the movies with Veronica the other day. I was like look
you knew how I was before you got with me. That's right you are such a playman dude there's mad
Max let's go say hi. Max was a are you okay? You look like you just saw ghost.
I got an effort in this class my life is over. Dude you're over it. You need to lay off the
books for a while and have some fun. Come on let's bounce. Where are we going? Oh crap my dad's
gonna go post when he finds out about this. I'm gonna open the can of what best on you if you don't
come with me right now. Okay okay geez. Okay so I think that was a little easier to
understand you know we've got a lot of pretty strange words and phrases some interesting slang.
Yeah and I want to take a look at this slang now so let's get started with fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay so the guy with the new shoes he asked his friends have you seen
Betty lately right? Right and the his friend replied don't even go there. Right he was like dude don't
even go there. Don't even go there. So what does he mean when he says don't even go there. He means
don't talk about it. I don't want to talk about it. Right don't even touch that subject. Don't even
mention it. Right so if somebody wants to talk about a topic that you think is sensitive or you don't
want to talk about us to say hey don't don't even go there. So Marko what do you think about the new
tax law? Don't even go there. I don't even want to talk about politics. Okay so I think that's
that's a really actually quite helpful phrase to avoid talking about an uncomfortable subject.
Right so he said don't even go there and he started talking about the girl and she was tripping
and then he said something interesting. He said I was like look you knew how I was before you got
yeah I really like this phrase. Now I want to focus on the first part. I was like I was like
I was like now you might hear a lot of native English speakers use these three words before they
start telling you what they said. So it's like saying I said or I told him yep so this actually
is really common especially with people under the age of 30. So why don't we hear a few more
examples of how it's used now. Example one. This guy caused a car accident I was like you
idiot you can kill people by driving like that. Example two. And then I was like I hate you and she
was all like I hate you more. Example three. I told the teacher that I didn't finish my homework
and he was like I'll see you after school. So if you're telling a story or you're maybe talking
to somebody and you want to explain what you said you can say I was like hey what are you doing
and she was like what so you can have an entire dialogue based with I was like she was like
we were like huh okay so I was like it's super super useful so now our next word now they saw
their friend who got the bad marking in school and the guy said dude get over it. Get over it.
Get over it. So if somebody tells you to get over it stop worrying about it okay or stop thinking about
it. All right so if somebody is sad because maybe his girlfriend broke up with him you would say
get over it. Yeah stop thinking about that it go. Yeah and you you commonly use this for
when somebody is upset about a small thing something they shouldn't worry about. Get over it.
Yeah now what are we going to our final word at the end of the dialogue they said
I'm gonna open a can of Wabass. Okay so to open a can of Wabass on somebody. To open a can of Wabass.
So again let's break this down before we explain it. Okay I think we have to take one step back here.
To whoop someone's ass is to beat them up right. To punch them and hurt them.
Right so to whoop somebody's ass. So if I open a can of Wabass what does that mean?
It means you're gonna beat them up so it's just a funny very informal way of saying like in this
can I'm gonna open it and I'm gonna start hitting you or something like that. Some sort of small
man it's gonna jump out of the can and start hitting you. Exactly but it's never literal. It's not like
you're actually gonna beat somebody up. It's just kind of like a joke. Yeah it's an empty threat. Yeah.
All right so some really interesting words and phrases in this dialogue I think we should listen
to it for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this great decade.
Hey, for eyes what's up man how have you been? Not bad just went to the wall and picked up some
jump. Check out my new adidas. Those are dope. You are gonna be getting mad props from the gang man.
Anyways have you seen Betty lately dude don't even go there. That girl started tripping because
I went to the movies with Veronica the other day. I was like look you knew how I was before you got with
you. That's right you are such a play man dude there's mad max let's go say hi
Max was a are you okay? You look like you just saw ghost. I got an effort English class my life is over
Dude you're over it you need to lay off the books for a while and have some fun. Come on let's bounce
Where are we going oh crap my dad's gonna go post when he finds out about this. I'm gonna open the can of
what best on you if you don't come with me right now okay okay G
Well Marco in the dialogue I heard one of the guys say what's up but he said it in a really strange way
didn't he? Yeah exactly he said what's up okay so what what's up with that?
So in the 90s it was popular instead of saying what's up you would just kind of double
BS and just say what's up and then it became very famous with a TV commercial for a certain beer and actually
I remember this commercial during the the Super Bowl they had this big commercial where
everyone was saying what's up in this really strange way right? It's still used today in
formally between friends you'll go hey hey what's up and why's that yeah and oh you'll use it. Yeah
so that commercial made it actually quite cool and in famous to talk like that actually in
Spanish pod they have a show called Getbasa which is like the translation of what's up and they start each
show with like saying getbasa but it's exactly the same so maybe it will become popular in Spanish
maybe but I guess only time will tell yeah that's right all right so really cool stuff and as we
heard typical music from the 90s and another interesting thing was the nicknames for eyes mad max
very popular among young kids. So remember if you have any questions about this language or anything
else about this lesson come to our website at englishpod.com. Right you can leave all your questions
in comments there and we hope to see you guys there. So thanks for listening and until next time. Goodbye. Bye.