Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got a very nerve-wracking situation for you.
That's right. We are going to meet the in-laws.
Meeting the in-laws. So who are in-laws? These are the parents of your husband or wife.
Right. So in this case you have the mother-in-law and your father-in-law.
That's right. So we're meeting these people for the very first time. You can imagine how nervous
the man is who's meeting his future wife's parents. Let's learn all about what they talk about in today's dialogue.
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce you to my fiance, Bob.
Hello, Bob. Welcome. Thanks for having me. Nice to meet the both of you. I've heard so much.
So Cindy told you about bringing home her last boyfriend then.
That idiot. Shhh! First-in! You're going to scare the poor boy. Come in and have a drink.
Dinner will be on in just a bit. What will you be having? Whiskey, bourbon, pick your poison.
If you have a lemonade that'd be great. Let me make sure there's some in the fridge. Mother makes her
own lemonade from scratch. It's the best. So what are your hobbies, son? If you want we can do
some hunting tomorrow, I've just picked up a new rifle I've been meaning to try out. Should be a real
hoot. I'm not really, uh, I don't really hunt. You don't hunt. Well, I'll beat there.
Bob is an animal rights activist. He doesn't believe in harming animals.
Dinner's ready. Let's go out to the patio where the pig is roasting.
Roast pig? I'm a vegetarian.
All right, we're back. So a very awkward situation. I think they might have a little bit of
a problem in the future. Yeah, there's there are a lot of cultural differences between the
characters, the son and law and the new parents. The father and all. Yeah. So that it's really
interesting. Why don't we start off by looking at a couple of different words on language take away?
Language take away. So first of all, we have the two characters, Cindy and Bob, who are getting
married. So we call them, uh, we call Bob's and he's fiance. Right. So my fiance and it's, uh,
it comes from French and it means to the person that you're going to get married to. That's right.
The person you've decided to get married to. So we say fiance, we can say the same word for a
man or a woman. So he is my fiance. She is my fiance. Okay. My fiance. Very good. So Cindy introduces
her fiance, Bob, to her parents. And they start talking a little bit and her dad, Thurston,
invites him to go do some hunting tomorrow. That's right. So hunting is a sport in America.
A lot of places in the world where you shoot animals. Okay. So you go in the woods, you wear brown
and green colors and you shoot animals to take them home and skin them and eat them. All right.
To keep them as trophies. All right. So you go hunting and well, the way that you shoot these animals
is you need to have a rifle. A rifle. So you could also call it a hunting rifle. This case.
A rifle is a gun, but it's a very long gun. Right. So it's not a little gun that you just hold
in your hand. It's a very long. It'll be maybe like half a meter a meter long. That's right. And so
oftentimes people when they're hunting, they lie on the ground and they wait for the animals to
pass and they hide themselves and then they shoot from a long distance. Right. So he's talking about
hunting. He's got a new rifle and he says, yeah, we should definitely go. It should be a real
should be a real hoot. This is a very fun spoken English phrase. It's said more by older people than
my younger people. So this is why the father says it in the dialogue. A hoot should be a real good
time real fun hoot. So how can you can use this like the party last night was a real hoot? Yep. You can
say that. You can say or she's a real hoot. She's really funny. Okay. It's a really enjoyable. This is a
little bit more like a spoken and used by maybe older people. My mother would say this. I wouldn't say
this. Oh my goodness. It was a real hoot. All right. So he's talking about hunting how much fun they
would have and fortunately. Bob is an animal rights activist. What does this mean? An animal rights
activist is someone who's very concerned with protecting the rights of animals. So for example,
if I'm an animal rights activist, maybe I will protest people who wear fur or perhaps I will also
try and secure land for a natural wildlife preserve so that animals can live in the wild. There's
not houses or cars. So animal rights activists are people who try to make sure that animals are
protected from human beings. Okay. Very good. And this is what Bob is. So obviously Bob is not really
into hunting. I'm guessing no. These are two opposites. You have people who like to kill animals and
people who want to protect the lives of animals. Right. Okay. Well and to finish off our language
takeaway dinner is ready. So let's go out to the patio. Okay. A patio is a space outside the house
usually in the back that's paved. So there's like cement or brick or some kind of tile. Not
three have a table and chairs or some place to sit and rest. This is where you have a grill. So it's
an outdoor area but it's not grass. Okay. So it's not your backyard. Oh, it could be in your backyard.
The patio could be in the backyard. That's right. But the ground in the patio is not grass. It's
some kind of material like cement or brick or wood. Okay. Very good. So great words there. Why don't
we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder. Fluency builder.
All right. We're back. So we have three great phrases here on fluency builder. Why don't we
start off with the first one? So the first one we have to go back to the very beginning of this
dialogue and think about these people who are introducing each other for the very first time.
Cindy says I want to introduce you to my fiance Bob. Bob says to Cindy's parents,
I've heard so much. I've heard so much. Okay. So this phrase that you can usually use it when you
meet somebody for the first time. I've heard so much about you. That's right. So the longer version
is I've heard so much about you. Basically you're saying listen, Cindy talks about you a lot.
I've heard really nice things. Sometimes people like to joke. You say I've heard so much about you.
They say, I hope only good things. No, I hope not too much. I hope not too much. So this is a very
polite way to respond when someone introduces themselves. Okay. I've heard so much about you. It's a
pleasure to finally meet you. Exactly. Okay. So they started talking and actually thirst and
offer some a drink. He says, well what do you want? Whiskey, bourbon, pick your poison. All right.
This is one of my very favorite phrases in English. The father-in-law wants to give the new
son-in-law drink and there are many different options. So pick your poison means pick your drink.
You might hear this at a bar. What do you want to drink? Well, pick your poison. Right. You
could have whiskey, rum. So usually we're just talking about alcohol like drinks. Okay. So you
wouldn't you wouldn't really use this for juices or some water or some like that? Okay. So if you
say pick your poison, that's for alcohol, right? Or maybe you can ask somebody what they're drinking.
You would say what's your poison? Yeah. What's your poison? Okay. So poison in this case is a
slang term for alcohol. Very good. And finally, when Cindy was talking about lemonade,
that her mother makes, she said, she makes it from scratch to make something from scratch.
You could say, my mother makes chocolate chip cookies from scratch. This means to not, not to buy
something in the store, but to make it all yourself from nothing. So making lemonade from scratch
means taking lemons, cutting them, taking the juice, adding some sugar. So you're making it from
nothing. Okay. You're not using some kind of kit or some kind of, you know, can't drink from the store.
Okay. So for example, maybe some Italians and Italy make their spaghetti from scratch with
flour and they need it and they make everything from scratch. Wow. So you don't buy a box of
spaghetti, but you actually have to cut the spaghetti and pull it and exactly. Very, very hard work.
To make something from scratch and usually you can add the something goes in between, right?
To make lemonade from scratch, make bread from scratch. Make ice cream from scratch. Okay. So those
are three phrases for today. Let's listen to the dialogue for one last time and we'll be back
to talk about this very, very interesting topic.
Music
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce you to my fiance Bob. Hello Bob. Welcome.
Thanks for having me. Nice to meet the both of you. I've heard so much.
So, Sydney told you about bringing home her last boyfriend then. That idiot.
First, you're going to scare the poor boy. Come in and have a drink.
Dinner will be on in just a bit. What do you be having? Whiskey, bourbon, pick your poison.
If you have a lemonade that'd be great. Lemonade. I sure, there's some in the fridge. Mother makes
her own lemonade from scratch. It's the best. So what are your hobbies, son? If you want we can do
some hunting tomorrow, I've just picked up a new rifle I've been meaning to try out. Should be a real
hoot. I'm not really, I don't really hunt. You don't hunt. Well, I'll beat there.
Bob is an animal rights activist. He doesn't believe in harming animals.
Dinner's ready. Let's go out to the patio where the pig is roasting.
Roast pig, I'm a vegetarian.
This is a very scary topic for a lot of people. I think they get very nervous introducing
themselves because in this case, Bob is going to be marrying Cindy. So these are going to be his
in-laws forever. Yeah, and it seems interesting. The differences, as you mentioned before,
between the father-in-law who's very much into hunting and drinks and likes roast pig,
whereas this guy is more of animal rights activist, doesn't drink. He's a vegetarian. He does
it in me. So I think it would be very complicated. And I think this happens a lot also with people
from different cultures, right? Maybe your age and your marrying an American or something like this.
Yeah, that's right. I think it can be very, very difficult. I recently went to a wedding
between a Chinese girl and an American guy. And it was amazing to see all these people getting together
because the families were so different. But they all got along really well. It was really fun.
They were all very supportive. They were just excited for their kids. Yeah, but I think it can be a
little bit difficult, right? I mean, being in a family where the culture is so different
under the traditions and the customs are strange to you. But it's exciting because then as a
family, the young people who are getting married, they can pick the traditions they want and make
new traditions. So this is very interesting topic. We want to know maybe if you are married,
how did it go when you met your in laws? Are you very different? Or did you get along very well?
Or how is it in your country? Yeah, please do let us know. Our website is engoshpod.com. We
hope to see you there. All right, everyone. Bye. Bye.