Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
Hi everyone. My name is Katherine and today Marco we're talking about money.
That's right. We're going to take a look at another lesson about money, but this time
we're going to learn a little bit more about coins in the United States.
That's right. Different coins, so different sizes and shapes. They have different names because
they represent different amounts of money. So today we're going to learn the names of those coins
and we're also going to learn a little bit about British money. So let's check out the dialogue.
How many organized these coins? That's a lot of money. What do you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to go to the bank and change it for bills. But first I have to separate them into
little piles. Okay. I'll find all the quarters and dimes while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great. Then we can add everything up and take it to the bank. I found some coins that are not from here.
Oh yeah, those are from a trip to the London. I have like 90 pens, but it all
it won't add up to one pound. Are you sure the bank will change these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right. We're back. So let's take a look at some of this language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So first up, Marco, we have this funny phrase. Break the piggy bank. What is a piggy bank?
That's right. A piggy bank. Now you may have seen this. It has the shape of a little pig.
It's usually made out of plastic or ceramic. And it has a little hole at the top where you can
put in coins that just basically save your money there. All right. So this is a big shaped bank.
Right. But it's a bank you keep in your room. Mostly children have these, right?
Yeah. So if you want to save your change or you want to save some of your coins that you have
teach your children about saving money, then usually they have a little piggy bank where they can
store their their money. So when you break the piggy bank, usually these were made of ceramic. So
to spend the money, you have to decide when it's very, very special or important. So you have to break
the entire bank. And that's when you take all the coins you've been saving. Exactly because they didn't
really have a little hole where you could take it out from. So when you wanted to take your money out,
literally had a break it. All right. So that's a piggy bank. But what do we store inside a piggy
bank? We don't store bills, do we? That's right. No. We sort of coin. So this is an interesting word
bill. You know, like the name bill, Bill Clinton. For example, bills are the paper money that we use.
All right. But not capitalized like a name because this is a normal common noun.
bills represent all paper money. So I could get, I could ask for change. Could I have the
change in bills, please? That's right. And if I'm at a store, they'll give me bills. Maybe a $5
bill, $10 bill. And there's also accounts for other currencies. So if I'm in China, I might get my
reminbee, my UN in bills. That's just a general name for paper money. That's right. So
what we store in the piggy bank are coins. Now talking specifically about the types of coins
are the different amounts that these represent. Let's take a look at those more in detail.
All right. So first up, we've got quarters. Now, this should be pretty easy if you know your time.
Mm-hmm. Because a quarter is one fourth of something. So if we're talking about money, it's a quarter
of a dollar or 25 cents. That's right. So 25 cents or a quarter of a dollar or one fourth of a
dollar, we just call it a quarter. So, you know, most machines or payphones, you need to insert
quarters. That's right. So you can recognize the quarter because it's the biggest coin and it
has a big eagle on one side. And on the other side, it has George Washington. George Washington. That's
right. Now the next in line or the next coin that we're going to take a look at are
dimes. Dimes. Now these are also recognizable because they're the smallest coins, but that does not
mean they're the smallest amount. Right. Dimes are actually the second largest. They're 10 cents.
They're 10 cents or one tenth of a dollar. And so you can say they're 10 cents or you can say
dime. So do you have, I don't know if you have a 10 dimes that means you get a dollar. That's right.
10 dimes equal one dollar. And the face on the dime is, oh, Jennifer Salix and their handle is in.
I don't know. Now he was the first, well, he created basically the Department of the
Treasury. But Thomas Jefferson is on another coin and that's what we're going to look at next.
That's right. The nickel. The nickel is like the metal, you know, nickel. And yeah, so this one is a
little bit bigger than the dime, but not as big as the quarter. I think it's a little bit thicker,
maybe. It is thicker, but it's not as much money. A nickel is five cents. Five cents. So one
20th of a dollar. That's right. One 20th of a dollar. So this is what we call a nickel. So you would
call this coin. You would say, do you have any nickels, dimes and nickels usually go together? I don't know
what. Nickels and dimes. Nickels and dimes. He's counting his nickels and dimes. Me and he doesn't have
very much money. That's right. So yeah. And then on this coin, you have the face of Thomas Jefferson.
That's right. Okay. And finally, we have the only coin that's not silver colored. It's actually
more of a copper color. That would be the penny. The penny. That's right. One cent or one penny
is the smallest of the coins. And actually you need one hundred of these to make one dollar. That's
right. So this is very unique because it's a different color. It's the smallest amount. And the face
on this coin. Do you know this one? Yes. This one is Abraham Lincoln. Correct. All right. So we've got
all these important people. All of them were presidents actually except for Alexander Hamilton.
That's right. And actually I think Alexander Hamilton looks good better than the rest.
He was a pretty handsome. Yeah. Actually, now he was had to be very funny looking. Yeah.
So actually, all of these coins, you can you can call them by these names and everyone will
recognize them, especially in the US. Now, I don't really think they apply to any other country
as we saw later on, for example, money in England or the United Kingdom. But usually in the
US, if you say, hey, do you know, do you have any spare change or do you have any nickels and dimes?
Then can I borrow a penny? Can I borrow a penny? Actually in the US, they have these little things
called take a penny. Leave a penny, right? Or give a penny take a penny. Yeah.
You see these because pennies are not worth very much money. And oftentimes people will leave a
penny. And if you have it may something costs 26 cents, but you only have a quarter, you can take a
penny and then spend that. So they're basically free pennies. You might see in a store. And then also,
if you get change, you maybe you don't want to carry those pennies around or that change. So you just
leave that there. And then, you know, it's kind of a way of recycling this small amount of money,
which is very interesting. It is very interesting. But we're going to actually take a look at some
British currency. So let's take another listen to the dialogue and when we come back, we'll explore that.
How do you organize these coins? That's a lot of money. What do you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to the bank and change it for bills. But first, I have to separate them into little
piles. Okay. All find all the quarters and dimes while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great. Then we can add everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins that are not from here. Oh, yeah. Those are from a trip to the London.
I have like 90 pens, but it all I won't add up to one pound. Are you sure the bank will
change these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right. We're back. So let's take a look at these British words on language takeaway part two.
So here we've got British currency. The pound right is the name of the currency. So in America,
we have the dollar and Britain, we have the pound. Is it the sterling pound? Yeah.
The pound sterling. The pound sterling. I think that has to do with weight. I'm sure.
But here we've got to divide it into small and large quantities. So where we have coins, we might have
pens. Sounds like sense. Right. Exactly. And I think actually the penny might come from from the British
term pens. I'm sure it does. They're very similar and the meaning is basically one hundredth of
a pound. Right. Exactly. And the pound is basically what you would say in the US dollar.
A pound is the currency of England. But actually, you know, how in the United States people would say,
a hundred bucks, which would be a hundred dollars. Over there, they say one hundred quid.
Quid. So yeah, this is actually important slang. In America, I would spend five bucks
at the movies in Britain. I would spend five quid. And now that's a slang term for one pound.
That's right. And actually I've heard also like 50 p, which I think means 50 cents. Yeah,
pens sense. Yeah. So 50 p. So you could say this stick of or this pack of gum costs 50 p.
So 50 p. That's right. Half of a pound. So as you can see, obviously the currencies are different.
But also it is interesting to learn the way that you would say locally. So, you know, next time
if you were in Britain or you're talking to an English person, then you'd know if they say, you know,
50 quid, you understand they're talking about 50 pounds. Exactly. So, but they don't use the
euro over there. No, they don't not in Great Britain. They do use the euro on the continent. So France,
Italy, and the euro is the name of that currency. Okay. All right. So a lot of great stuff. And
now lastly, although we saw at the beginning of the dialogue, let's talk about what this person wants
to do. He wants to change these coins into bills. That's right. So the verb when you need to
exchange money is to change money. So let's say if I go to England and all I have is dollars,
I would say I want to change money. Okay. You could also say exchange. But when we're speaking to
one another, we normally just say change. Right. Right. Because even the places are sometimes
called like money changes. You know, they say that or something like that. Exactly. And so if I want
to change money, that means I want to maybe change dollars for euros or dollars for pounds. But this
also can mean I want to change a dollar for some quarters. Right. Right. Because I need quarters for
like a laundry machine or telephone. Right. And I've heard also the term is to break. So if maybe you
have a $10 bill and you need maybe a $5 bill, but you don't have like you ask the person to break
that money. So you say can you break this bill? Yeah, that actually makes sense because it bill
normally you break something that's big into smaller pieces. So if you think about it, if I break
a glass, it becomes many pieces. Well, if I break a $5 bill, I want maybe $1. I get five of those.
There's one piece and then it breaks into many pieces. So to break means to ask for smaller change.
That's right. So maybe next time you guys need change, you can go up to someone and say excuse me,
can you change this $5 bill for me or can you break this $5 bill? That's right. All right. So
a lot of interesting language, very useful stuff. Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
How'd we organize these coins? That's a lot of money. What'd you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to go to the bank and change it for bills. But first, I have to separate them into
the little piles. Okay. I'll find all the quarters and dimes while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great. Then we can add everything up and take it to the bank. I found some coins that are not from
Oh yeah, those are from a trip to the London. I have like 90 pens, but it all I won't add up to one
pound. Are you sure the bank will change these coins for you? Hopefully.
All right. Coming back to the topic now, you seem to know a lot about this stuff. Let's test your knowledge
here. On the $100 bill, who do we find? But president or one person? Benjamin Franklin,
that's right. But he wasn't a president, right? He was not. He was a very important figure in
American history. Many people are familiar with the story of Benjamin Franklin and the
kite with the key item. He discovered electricity. He was a very important inventor and also an
important person when it comes to the creation of America. That's right. Now, the smaller of the bills
would be the $1 bill. And actually now you have a $1 coin as well. But on the $1 bill, do you know
who's on there? I think George Washington, I think so. Yeah. Yeah. So he's like the quarter and on the
one. We like to recycle our presidents. The $20 bill, then would be Abraham Lincoln, right?
Oh, that's right. So he's there actually on, that's sort of unfair though. Favorite president
in the United States. But they haven't changed over time. Like in other countries, you see that
that they change according to the important person that's in government or maybe you know like
for example in China, you know you have a German mal on there, which before you did into or
in England you have Queen Elizabeth before was the previous ruler, which I think was King George
the sixth. So, but in the US, guys flat out, 100 years ago, these guys haven't changed them since then.
Well, I think what's America likes to celebrate its creation.
And so that's a very young country, right? Right. 1776, so it's only been what 240 years. So yeah,
the idea is basically that we celebrate the founding, so the beginning of the Republic. And the
men who were involved in that, they're called the founders, George Washington, James Madison,
Alexander Hamilton, all of the Benjamin Franklin. These people are very important in the history of
America. And that's why we celebrate them on our money. The one exception of course is Abraham Lincoln.
Right. He was from the 1860s. Right. So he was president. Yeah. He was, he was very important
because of the civil war. And a lot of the changes that later happened to our constitution. And so
he's another person who's maybe added on. So he's basically the last guy you guys kind of
celebrate because you don't have Franklin Delano, Rosa, or Bill Clinton or something like this.
Not yet. Right. So I guess we got a way to wild. But that's very interesting. The history aspect of
current season is actually very, very interesting. It is. And one thing I like to add about quarters
is that in the 2000s, so from 2000, I think on the United States started to make state quarters.
So you'll see oftentimes these quarters with the picture of a state, New Hampshire, Maryland,
Illinois, California, and a special symbol of that state. And so these are special quarters from the
last maybe 10 years or so. Yeah. I remember seeing these because usually on the other side of the
quarter one, once that you had George Washington. On the other side, you had the the eagle, the the
emblem of the flag, I guess. Not the flag, but the national word or the Republic. But now you have
these states and it says Delaware and it has a little maybe an upflower or something that's represented
to the states. So that was actually very nice. It was a collector's type thing as well, right? People
were collecting. That's right. You can collect all 50. Some people did that and you still see them
in use. So those are the state quarters. And those generally are in our new work quarters. Okay,
all right guys. So we're at a time. But if you guys have any questions or doubts, you could find us
at EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there. Bye.