Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be going to one of the least favorite places
of many, many people. So it must be the dentist.
Exactly, that place where you have to go every six months, but you probably don't go.
You probably don't. I know I don't go every six months. So yeah, we're going to be going
to the dentist and of course we're going to be looking at a lot of great book
have related to teeth and all that crazy stuff that does do. Yes, and we'll also learn
some really interesting phrases. So Marco, let's get started with our vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview. Okay, I'm vocabulary preview. Today we have two words. Let's
look at the first one. tooth ache tooth ache tooth ache tooth ache. Okay, so we've seen
before this this ending ache, right? Right. It means it hurts. Exactly. So again, a tooth
ache would be hurting tooth. We can also say stomach ache. Yeah, pretty much everything can
ache. Okay. So our next word x-ray x-ray x-ray x-ray x-ray x-hifin are a y. Okay, pretty easy word.
So when you go to the doctor many times you'll get an x-ray. It is a picture of your bones.
Right. So that's an x-ray. All right, well we're going to hear both of these words in the dialogue.
So why don't we listen as Gary visits his dentist?
Hey Gary, great to see you again. Please have a seat. So tell me what seems to be the problem.
Thanks Doc. I've got a really bad tooth ache. I can't eat anything and look my face is also
all in. I think it might be my wisdom teeth. Well let's have a look open wide.
Uh-huh.
This doesn't look good. Well it looks like you have a cavity and your crown is loose. So we'll need
to put in a filling before it gets any worse and the crown probably needs to be refitted.
I'm going to order some x-rays. Is it going to hurt? No, not at all. Just lay back and relax.
Okay, spit.
Okay, that always happens. The dentist says no, it's not going to hurt. Don't worry about it.
But it always hurts much more than he says. Exactly. So in this dialogue we saw some
interesting words when the dentist was describing what problems Gary had. Yes. So why don't we look at
those now in language takeaway? Language takeaway. All right, let's take a look at our first word.
So Gary said that his face was all swollen swollen swollen swollen. So swollen is an adjective,
right Marco? Right. So his face is or was swollen. It was bigger. Yeah, his face was bigger than normal.
Yes. Often when you hurt yourself, that part of your body becomes swollen.
Right. So you have to put some ice on it usually and then the swelling will go down.
And that's the noun, the swelling. Right. The swelling and well the verb to swell.
All right, three words for the price of one. So let's listen to some examples of how we would use
the swelling swollen and to swell. Example one.
My nose is swollen. It's the size of a football.
Example two.
Puss some ice on your foot and the swelling will go down. Example three.
I got bitten by a spider and my hand is swelling up.
All right, so Gary's face was swollen and he thought that it was his wisdom teeth.
Wisdom teeth. Wisdom teeth. Okay, so this is interesting. Wisdom is like wise.
Yeah, knowledge. So these teeth, they're not knowledgeable, but they're called wisdom teeth.
They're the teeth that grow last in your mouth, right? Right. They are the last
teeth at the very end of your mouth. Yes. And usually you get them when you're about 20.
And since they come out at this age, sometimes they interfere. They hurt a little bit. So you
have to get them taken out. Yes. All right. Wisdom teeth. Wisdom teeth. Okay.
Now for our next word and something that we all got as children cavity cavity a cavity a cavity.
A cavity. It's a hole in your tooth. A hole in your tooth. And it's caused by too much sugar.
Too much sugar, right? Or not brushing your teeth enough. Yeah. So that's why
everyone had it. I think as children cavities. I never had a cavity. Really? Yeah.
Wow, didn't have much sugar. I guess I was a bit of a health nut when I was a kid. No, no, I wasn't my
mum was. No, I guess not. All right. But enough about my eating habits. Let's talk about our next word
Crown Crown. A crown. So a crown. This is interesting. We're not talking kings and
glad. That's the first thing that comes to mind, right? Yeah. No, a crown is actually the visible
part of your teeth. Okay. So there's one part of your tooth that's inside that you can't see, right?
That's called the root. Yes. So when he said your crown is loose. What's he talking really about the
actual tooth? So sometimes people will lose a tooth or have a really bad cavity. So the dentist
needs to make a new crown or a new visible part of the tooth for you. So sometimes it'll be made of
gold. Yep. Or porcelain. Or saline. Yeah. Exactly. So crown. It's like a really, really,
big filling. Yeah. Crown. So his crown needed to be refitted or put back into place. Yes.
Now our final word filling. Filling. A filling. A filling. So I just said this word previously.
Now when you have a cavity, you need to fill it in. Right. You need to fill it with something.
Yes. It's usually some sort of paste. And it gets really hard. And it's like your tooth. Exactly.
So then it covers up this cavity. Filling. A filling. I have many feelings. I wasn't very healthy as a kid.
All right. Not a good tooth pressure. Exactly. So why don't we listen to this dialogue again?
And then we'll come back and talk a little bit about some of the interesting phrases that the doctor
used. Hey Gary. Great to see you again. Please have a seat. So tell me what seems to be the problem.
Thanks Doc. I've got a really bad toothache. I can't eat anything. Look, my face is also
well and I think it might be my wisdom teeth. Well, let's have a look. Open wide.
This doesn't look good. Well, it looks like you have a cavity and your crown is loose.
We'll need to put in a filling before it gets any worse. And the crown probably needs to be refitted.
I'm going to order some x-rays. Is it going to hurt? No, not at all. Just lay back and relax.
Okay, spit.
Well, the dentist used three really interesting phrases. And I want to look at the first one.
What seems to be the problem? What seems to be the problem? What seems to be the problem?
Okay. Very easy. Little sentence to ask somebody what's wrong. Exactly. Right. And I mean,
these are small, easy words, but when you put them together, they sound really natural and really
fluent. So if you ask somebody what seems to be the problem, it's very polite. Yep. And it's a very
good way of asking what's wrong. Yes. All right. Our next phrase also made up of simple words.
Let's have a look. Let's have a look. Let's have a look. So this is a phrase that maybe you're
mechanic or your dentist or your doctor will say. Or anyone. Right. Let's have a look. Let's look at it
and see what the problem is. Okay. Let's have a look. Okay. And our final phrase. It doesn't look good.
It doesn't look good. It doesn't look good. So I can use this phrase for an object, right? Yeah. Like
this house doesn't look good. Yes. But here it's used a little bit differently. So why don't we
listen to some examples to help us understand the meaning? Example one.
John told me it doesn't look good for me. I probably won't get the job. Example two.
It doesn't look good for Michael Jackson. He's in a lot of debt. Example three.
You know, the economy doesn't look very good. Okay. So in the examples we can see that they are
using it for the situation. Yeah. It looks maybe problematic. Yeah. So when you say it doesn't
look good, you basically mean there are going to be problems. All right. It doesn't look good. Yeah.
Okay. So great phrases. Great words. Let's listen to our Gary at the dentist one more time.
Then we'll come back and talk a little bit more. Hey Gary, great to see you again. Please have a
seat. So tell me what seems to be the problem. Thanks Doc. I've got a really bad toothache.
I can't eat anything. It looked my face is all swollen. I think it might be my Worcestershire teeth.
Well, let's have a look. Open wide.
This doesn't look good. Well, it looks like you have a cavity and your crown is loose.
We'll need to put in a filling before it gets any worse. And the crown probably needs to be refitted.
I'm going to order some extra. Is it going to hurt? No, not at all. Just lay back and relax.
Okay, spit. Well, Marco, speaking of dentists, have you ever had an experience like this
where you've spat out a tooth of dentists? Well, nothing so serious is this, but
actually recently when I was in Cambodia, all right. You called that. It's been Cambodia.
Well, our taxi driver offered us to have some local food. And he said, well, we're going to have
dog. So that's interesting. Actually, it wasn't that bad. It was pretty good. But, you know,
if you get around the fact that it's a dog. So what does this have to do with your teeth? I was eating it
and I bit a bone that was hidden and I chipped my tooth. So you broke part of your tooth?
Yeah, like half of it. Which I had already chipped before. So I had to go to the dentist and so the
dentist created a new crown with not with gold or porcelain and actually with a paste. Oh,
and then it becomes hard and it just looks normal. It doesn't even look like I have a fake crown.
So to say. But dentists can be really expensive. So how much did this cost?
Well, this was for the bargain price of $10. $10.
$10. That's how much it cost. So we should all go to Cambodia for dentistry.
Yeah, because actually he was pretty good. He looked really young though. I was kind of scared because
when he walked in, he looked like he was 19. But I asked him his age and he was like 30.
Okay, well, you're very trusting. Yeah, so I imagine that you guys maybe have some dental experiences.
So why don't you come to our website and tell us all about it? Yeah, visit us at EnglishPod.com
and you can find lots more resources for learning English there. Well, guys, thanks for listening
and until next time. Bye. Bye.