Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about buying clothes.
That's right, we're going to go and get some clothes, but on this occasion we are going to get a suit
and we're going to have it made especially for us. So before we get started why don't we take a look at
one keyword that we have in vocabulary preview? Very cablory preview. Okay, this word makes me think of things
that are very rich and soft. It's a fabric, right? That's right. It's a kind of text style. It's called
cashmere. Cashmere. So maybe you've heard of cashmere wool. It's a special kind of wool that comes from animals.
So this is a text-dollar fabric that is commonly used to make pants, nice pants or suits for men.
Or scars or sweaters. You've ever had a cashmere sweater. You know it's very luxurious, very soft.
So it can be a little bit expensive depending on the quality and that's what we're going to be looking at.
Now we're going to be making a suit out of cashmere. So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time?
Welcome to Bill's Fabric world. What can I do for you today? I was wondering if you guys
also tailored clothes. Sure we do. We have the best tailors in the country. What is it that you need?
Well, I'm looking to get a custom made suit. Excellent. We have the finest cashmere that a
affordable price is. How about we get you measured? Let's start off by measuring the width of your shoulders.
Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar? My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your pants. Let me just measure your waist and the inseam.
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area. I tend to gain a few
pounds over the holidays. Okay. Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design. Please follow me.
So this reminds me of something that people used to do a lot more often. So you go to the
tailor and you'd have some clothes made. Most people don't do this anymore. Yeah. Well, it's actually
really interesting. Maybe because it's more expensive nowadays or tailors are harder to find.
That's right. So let's learn about the words first and what they mean and then maybe we can
talk about this at the end of today's show. Language takeaway. All right. So today on language
takeaway, we have a word that is a noun and a verb. So as you mentioned, the person that makes suits
is a tailor. That's right. You can say my uncle is a tailor. He makes clothes for famous people.
But this word is also a verb. That means it's an action word. We can say my uncle the tailor.
He tailors clothes. Okay. So two tailor clothes and what does it mean when you say to tailor? Well,
it can have two meanings. The first is what we learn about in today's dialogue. It means to make clothes.
So to make a shirt or to make a pair of pants. But these days we often say to tailor,
which means to fix something. So for example, Markov, you buy a pair of pants and they're too long.
Right. You can have them tailor. It has them tailored and that means that I am going to have them
fixed so they fit me properly. Exactly. This is a lot more common right now. Okay. So we're going to be
tailoring clothes. Now if any of you have ever been to the tailor, what they do is they measure you.
And what do they measure? Well, in this case, they get the width of your shoulders. What's really
great about these upcoming words is that they're useful in math as well, math and
basic measurements. So width is how big something is across. Across how wide something is. Exactly.
Wide width. Okay. So that's the width. Now your shoulders, they are wide and well your legs on the
other hand, your legs and arms. You don't measure the width. Usually you measure the length. How long
they are. Okay. So width and length. Now just to throw it in there, this wasn't in the dialogue,
but would be the other measure word. So the third word would be height. So you think of a rectangle.
You have the width. How wide something is? The length. How long it is and the height. How tall
it is. That's tall it is right. So width length and height. All right. Now that we've measured
our arms and legs, now we want to measure our waist. Okay. This is the important one. This is also
the sensitive one. If you find that you've gained some weight, we measure the waist. Okay. That's how
big you are around your stomach. And so usually we measure this in a circle. Okay. Okay. So you've
heard of a 26 inch waist or a 32 inch waist. This is the size of your stomach. Okay. So it's just above
your hips, right? As you say it's your stomach. And well we've measured the waist and now in men,
especially they measure the in seam. Now this is very particular for tailors and having suits made.
What is the in seam of your pants? Well think of the word in inside. This is the inside of your pants.
So from your foot to the middle of your pants where your zipper starts. Okay. So that's not the
outside length. It's the inside length. Okay. Now for example skirts. They don't have in seams, right?
No because there's no inside. There's no middle, right? So it's just like a circle. Okay. But in pants
or shorts, you have an in seam. That's where it's connected in the middle. All right. So also in shorts,
very interesting. So you can measure the in seam of pants or shorts. All right. So very interesting and
particular words for tailors. Why don't we listen to our dialogue again? And we'll be back shortly.
Welcome to Bill's fabric world. What can I do for you today? I was wondering if you guys also
tailored clothes. Sure we do. We have the best tailors in the country. What is it that you need exactly?
Well I'm looking to get a custom made suit. Excellent. We have the finest cashmere at affordable prices.
How about we get you measured? Let's start off by measuring the width of your shoulders.
Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar? My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your pants. Let me just measure your waist and the in seam.
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area. I tend to gain a few
pounds over the holidays. Okay. Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design. Please follow me.
All right. We're back. So now we have three key phrases that we found in this dialogue. So let's
take a look at them now in fluency builder. Fluency builder. This first phrase is the topic of today's lesson.
What we talked a little bit about measurements for a suit. But in particular we're getting a custom made suits.
So this word custom made. Well custom is important. It means special or unique. There's no
other like it. So we could talk about custom cars. That means a car that has been fixed especially for you.
Okay. So a custom made suit would be a suit that was made specifically for your height
for how big your waist is, et cetera, specifically for you. Right. So a suit that I buy at the
department store is just a normal suit. But a suit that I have made for me is a custom made suit.
Okay. And as you said, you can use it for cars, a custom made car, or maybe for example a custom
made custom made kitchen. That means that you get to pick every single part of the kitchen that you
want. Many people do that, right? They have custom built or custom made homes. Yeah. That's
that's why something I wanted to do. But I hear that it's much more expensive than getting a normal
home made. All right. So that's the first key phrase. Now moving on, when we talk about measuring,
we say I measured, I measured the length of this street. Right. Or let's measure use so we can see how big
you are. But if you noticed in the dialogue, we use the passive voice. He says, let's get you measured.
Okay. I got measured or it got measured to get measured, as you say, is the is the passive voice.
Now what's the difference between passive and active? All right. So basically what happens here is
we are concentrating on the person and the action falling upon you, for example. So I got measured.
What happened to me? I got measured. Who did it? Who measured you? We don't know. We don't know. We don't
care. Right. All right. The point, the important part is that you were measured. You got measured.
But we could have a different phrase. We say, for example, I will measure this table or he measures
the height of the door. And we know he measures. I will measure. We know who the actor is. That
means it's active voice because the focus is on who's doing this action. But in passive voice,
the important thing is who is receiving the action. Right. Now it's a little bit complicated because
as you can see, measured is in the past, but we're not really talking about the past. So it may
get a little bit complicated. We can take a more in-depth look at that in the community
section. You can ask a couple of questions. We'll place a couple of examples, but it's kind of
hard to get into the grammar over an audio podcast. That's true. So that's what we have the practice
space on the website. All right. Now moving on, we have our last phrase. And when he was talking
about the waste and how he should leave a little bit of extra room, it's because he tens,
he tensed to gain a few pounds. Okay. So to gain a few pounds is like gaining a kilo. It
means to gain weight over the holidays. And in this case, to tend to, I tend to,
means I normally, or I usually. So for example, Marco, what do you tend to eat for breakfast?
I tend to eat scrambled eggs and a glass of yogurt. That's healthy. Do you tend to run late in the
morning? Uh, yes. True. All right. So tend to its tendency is what usually happens.
It's normal. It's normal. All right. So very interesting phrase is very interesting words.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time?
Welcome to Bill's Fabric world. What can I do for you today? I was wondering if you guys also
tailored clothes. Sure we do. We have the best tailors in the country. What does it that you need?
Exactly. Well, I'm looking to get a custom-made suit. Excellent. We have the finest cash
mirrors at affordable prices. How about we get you measured? Let's start off by measuring the
width of your shoulders. Now let's measure the length of your arms and this bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave a little extra space in the collar? My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your pants. Let me just measure your waist and the in-sim.
You might also want to leave a little extra room in the waist area. I tend to gain a few
pounds over the holidays. Okay. Now you can pick your fabric and pattern design. Please follow me.
All right. So we talked earlier about how most people buy their clothes at a department store
or a clothing store. Have you seen much of this? Maybe back in Ecuador. It's more common than
in America. Yeah. Usually people just go to a department store and get suits for example.
But it's actually very common as well because it's kind of in their artisans to be like a shoemaker,
to be a tailor. So actually people like it more and go to tailor because they kind of become
renowned. All he used to make suits for the president. People really, really like to get suits made
there. And obviously they fit much better. You feel more comfortable. And you look better.
Yeah. As I've said before, you know, I see people who buy all these suits. My brother, for example,
they never quite fit right. You can tell it's a little too big in the shoulders. My brother's tall.
So his pants are a little bit too short. But when you come to a place like China and those people
can get these these suits made for them. They just look fabulous. It looks very, very nice.
Yeah. So maybe you guys can tell us if you've ever had anything tailor made. Not only guys,
suits, but girls also get tailor made dresses, tailor made blouses. I always get coats made actually
because my shoulders are broad. And so it's hard for me to find coats that fit right. But if I get
one custom made, it looks really good. Right. So come to our website, englishpod.com, leave your questions
and comments there and we'll see you guys later. Until next time, guys. Bye.