Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson here with us at EnglishPod.
My name is Maruko.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're going to be in one of my favorite sporting events, which is F1.
F1 racing.
Alright, so yeah, we're going to be talking about racing specifically F1, which is a very popular
sport all over the world.
Yeah, I think maybe it's like number two in popularity after soccer.
Yeah, I think so.
I have no numbers to back that up now.
Well, they do travel everywhere.
They have races all over the world and just people love it.
So, well, it is kind of a cool thing.
It will going 300 kilometers per hour in a car is pretty cool.
Alright, so let's not delay this any longer.
Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
Welcome back racing fans, my name is Rick Field and as always I'm joined by my partner
in crime Bob Copeland.
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimi Rikonan is leading the
pack with only four laps to go.
They're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Rikonan.
It's our close one and oh no!
Hamilton hits the wall.
He came into fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
We have yellow flag and the pace car is making its way to the track.
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
Rickonan is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Smoke is coming out of his car.
He seems to be having edge and trouble he makes his way out of the pit and for none, no one
wants to take the lead.
How unlucky for Rikonan and this race is over the ladies and gentlemen, Alonzo takes the
checkered flag.
What an exciting race.
I always love a good crash when it comes to car racers.
I think many people go to races expecting to see a crash.
They don't want to see people getting hurt.
No, but a little bit of emotion of just car crashes.
Yeah, a little explosion here and there.
So now we saw some really exciting language related to racing.
So why don't we look at that now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
All right.
So we're talking about that crash.
And I think what led to the crash was the driver jammed on the brakes.
Right.
He jammed on the brakes to jam on the brakes.
Okay.
Now, if I jam on the brakes, you push the brakes really, really
hard and really quickly and really suddenly.
Right.
So you jam on the brakes and you stop very quickly.
So Louis Hamilton jammed on the brakes and consequently spun out to spin out.
Okay.
In the present, it would be spin out spin out.
So imagine yourselves driving your car on a very wet road.
And then you jam on the brakes.
Right.
So then the car, you kind of lose control of the car and it starts to spin.
It goes in circles.
Uh-huh.
That would be to spin out.
Hmm.
This is actually happened to me more than once.
Really.
Yeah.
Were you okay?
Yeah, I was fine.
I was fine.
So the car spun out.
Now, in racing, you always see this really cool car come out and be of head of
everyone when there's an accident.
Right.
That's called the pace car.
The pace car.
pace car.
Now, why is it called the pace car?
Because it sets the pace.
Okay.
The pace or the speed.
So pace means speed.
Uh-huh.
So this car comes out and no other car can pass it.
Everyone must go at the same speed.
Right.
The pace car.
All right.
So after there's an accident, the clean up crew must come out.
Okay.
Clean up crew.
All right.
So crew.
This is an interesting word.
Hmm.
When we talk about a crew, we talk about a group of people who work together.
Okay.
But for example, in an office, can I have a crew?
Not really.
Not a commonly right.
Yeah.
It's people who work together and they use their hands to work.
They do manual labor.
Okay.
So I can save, for example, a construction crew.
That's right.
Or maybe the ground crew at the airport.
Okay.
Or the flight crew.
Also at the airport.
All right.
Well, in the airplane.
So that's a crew.
So clean up crew.
Clean up crew.
Now they came out to take that car away that broke in or damaged vehicle.
So they were towing it.
To.
Okay.
The verb to toe.
To toe.
So what does it mean when you toe something or you toe a car?
You pull something behind you.
So if you're a truck that might pull a car behind you, that's a tow truck.
A tow truck.
Now this happens commonly if you park your vehicle where you are not supposed to.
That's right.
And your car will get towed.
Your car gets towed.
Yeah.
Very good.
All right.
So we saw five really great words related to racing.
And now why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
And then we'll look at some other interesting phrases.
Welcome back, race fans.
My name is Rick Fields.
And as always, I'm joined by my partner in crime.
Bob Copeland.
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race.
And Kimmy Raccoonen is leading the pack with only four laps to go.
They are heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Raccoonen.
It's a close one and oh no, Hamilton hits the wall.
He came in too fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
We have a yellow flag and the pace car is making its way onto the track.
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
Raccoonen is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Smoke is coming out of his car.
He seems to be having engine trouble.
He makes his way into the pit.
And Fernando Alonso takes the lead.
How unlucky for Raccoonen.
And this race is over, ladies and gentlemen.
Alonso takes the checkered flag.
Now we're back and I think it's time for us to take a look at some phrases in fluency
builder.
Fluency builder.
Well even though we're talking about F1 racing, a lot of the language can be used in many
different situations.
So let's look at some of those phrases now.
When Rick Fields introduced his co-host, he said, my partner in crime.
Partner in crime.
Now it's not that they are actually committing a crime.
No, they're not actually bank robbers.
But it's a very common and friendly way of saying my good friend or my...
The person I do everything what?
Right, my co-worker.
Yeah, I'm born right.
But a co-worker who's a really, really good friend.
Who's spend a lot of time with.
Okay, so that's your partnering crime.
It's just a metaphor, right?
So partner in crime.
Now what about the next phrase?
The last stretch.
Last stretch.
Okay.
Before we explain this word, let's listen to some examples and then we'll come back
and talk about it.
Example one.
We have finally in the last stretch of a very long week.
I can't wait to go home.
Example two.
He's in the last stretch of his college years and soon, peel graduate.
Okay, so I understand that to mean like the final length of time, right?
The last or final moments before an ending.
All right, so the last stretch.
The last stretch.
Now when you're on the last stretch,
you just have a few minutes to go.
To go.
Yeah, to go.
Now this preposition two and the verb go is very easy, right?
Right.
But if you say five minutes to go, what does that mean?
Five minutes left.
Left.
It doesn't mean it's five minutes to actually leave, right?
Right.
That means you must complete five minutes before you can be finished.
Okay.
So it's not about exiting.
Right.
I have five days to go before I go on vacation.
So it's not about you actually going on the vacation.
It's about you passing those five days.
Can you give us another example?
How about we have 45 minutes to go before the end of the day?
That's right.
So to go left.
Exactly to go.
All right.
Now let's take a look at our last phrase.
Close one.
A close one.
All right.
Another interesting phrase made up of simple words.
So let's listen to some examples to help us understand it.
Example one.
That was a close one.
The teacher will miss quote me cheating.
Example two.
It's a close one.
We are tied.
Example three.
My girlfriend almost found the presence I hit under the bed.
It was a close one.
Okay.
So a close one.
It means a situation that is almost dangerous.
But wasn't.
But wasn't exactly.
That was a close one.
Okay.
So very good phrases.
I think we can take a lot from this and apply it outside of F1.
Right.
So let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk
about this great sport.
Welcome back racing fans.
My name is Rick Field and as always I'm joined by my partner in crime Bob Copeland.
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimmy Rikonin is leading the
pack with only four laps to go.
They're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Rikonin.
It's their close one and oh no.
Hamilton hits the wall.
He came into fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
We have yellow flag and the pace car is making its way to the track.
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
Right, Conan is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Small kids coming out of his car.
He seems to be having edge and trouble.
He makes his way out of the pit and for none no one knows what takes to lead.
How unlucky for Rikonin and this race is over the ladies and gentlemen.
Our ones don't take the checkered flag.
Alright, so F1 Racing Erica, do you like it?
Do you like it?
Yeah, F1 is pretty neat.
Cars that drive fast.
That's pretty interesting.
Well for some people it is.
Why do I want to go to a race and just see fast cars?
I would never go to a race but I think it's, I would maybe watch the highlights on TV.
Well actually this year it's really exciting because again we're going to have a night race.
I think it's in Malaysia or somewhere in Asia.
They're going to race at night.
So that's pretty special.
Well it's like harder to see and you're going really fast.
Alright, so I hear you're going to the F1 this year.
Yes, this year I'm going to go to the Shanghai Circuit to watch the F1 race.
So I'm really excited about that.
I haven't ever been to one so it should be fun.
Alright, well I hope you get to see some interesting things like car crashes and
pasted cars.
Yeah.
What about you guys?
Our listeners.
Are you fans of F1?
Have you ever been to an F1 race?
Exactly.
Send us your questions in comments and also your stories.
I think we have listeners from all over the world.
We have a lot of listeners in Brazil and I know that there is a grand pre there.
So tell us how did it go?
Do you like it?
You can visit us at EnglishPod.com where Marko and I are around to answer your questions.
Alright, any Canadian race car drivers?
Oh, yeah, there was one recently.
Someone's something.
Alright, maybe that user's know which one is the Canadian.
So we'll see you guys there.
Thanks for listening.
Bye.