Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're back in the office.
We have a lesson that's talking about something that goes wrong in the office.
Yes, something that I can really understand well.
But we'll talk about that later.
So this lesson is about a photocopier.
A photocopier.
So let's take a look at this word in vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview.
All right, so a photocopier makes copies.
Yeah, it makes copies of documents.
We often call it a copier or a copy machine.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, so you can call it a photocopier, copy machine or copyer.
Yes.
Or a zerox machine as well.
Zerox machine.
Yeah, we can talk about that a little bit later.
Because that's an interesting story.
Okay.
All right, let's take a look at our next word.
Toner.
So toner is what the copy machine uses to make copies.
It's like the ink.
Right.
It's a very fine black powder.
Oh.
Yeah, yeah.
It's not an ink.
No, it's actually dry.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, it's dry.
It's a powder.
So you don't want to get that all over you.
All right.
We'll get advice, Marco.
And our last word in vocabulary preview.
Mal function.
Let's break down this word.
All right.
Function.
To work.
Uh-huh.
All right.
Mal.
I guess Mal maybe comes from Latin or something.
Because in Spanish, we say Mal, which is something evil or not good.
Okay.
So I think we can understand.
Mal function is not good working.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
More or less.
It's not working properly.
Not working properly.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, why don't we listen to the dialogue and find out what isn't working properly.
Hey, Carl.
Can you make a copy of this contract for me, please?
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
Sure.
Yeah.
I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
Yeah.
Sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
And your way up, can you facts this while I try and fix this thing?
Sure.
Damn it.
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
I'll send this stupid facts later.
Oh, great.
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
The elevator has some sort of malfunction to take the stairs.
What's all right?
You're going to it.
I have to go up 15 floors.
Never mind.
Made it.
There's a copier.
No!
Okay.
So this copy machine is definitely not working properly.
A serious malfunction.
I think the whole building exploded.
Yeah.
All right.
Very dramatic.
Here at English Pod, but we have fun, right?
Exactly.
Okay.
Let's take a look at some of the great language that we saw in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right.
So this guy needs to get a copy.
A sap.
Or A S A P.
Yes.
Meaning as soon as possible.
So really, really fast.
Really fast.
Yep.
This is a very, very common phrase.
Right?
So it's an acronym.
And you can say it like A sap.
Or A S A P.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Usually people say that they're not going to be a copy.
A S A P.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Usually people say like that because it's too long, I guess, to say, as soon as possible.
So yeah.
Hey, I need this document A sap.
Yes.
Or A S A P.
Exactly.
Okay.
Let's look at our next word.
A practical joke.
Practical joke.
Okay.
So a practical joke.
I'm sure we have all played a practical joke on some of our friends, right?
Yes.
What we do is you do something funny on purpose to someone.
Yeah.
But something crazy.
Crazy.
Yeah.
For example, when I was in university, there was this guy in our building.
And we took all of his bedroom furniture.
So his bed, his desk, everything.
And put it down on the football field.
Nice.
Yeah.
That was a practical joke.
That is a very good and elaborate practical joke.
Yep.
Okay.
And now let's look at our last word.
Never mind.
Okay.
So if you say never mind, it means.
Don't worry about it.
Forget it.
Yeah.
Never mind.
Yep.
This is so common.
And I think it would be helpful to understand how it's used.
So let's hear some examples.
Example one.
Someone's going to be a little bit more difficult.
So let's see.
Example one.
Someone stole my wallet.
Oh wait.
Never mind.
Here it is.
Example two.
Can you get some milk on your way home?
Oh, never mind.
We still have some.
Example three.
The printers broken.
Never mind.
I'll do this later.
Okay.
Great examples.
And I think our language takeaway is clear.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the second time.
And then we'll come back and talk about putting it together.
Hey Carl.
Can you make a copy of this contract for me please?
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
Sure.
I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
Yeah, sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
And your way up, can you fix this while I try and fix this thing?
Sure.
Damn it.
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
I'll send this stupid facts later.
Oh great.
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
The elevator has some sort of mouth function to stick to stairs to you.
Well, sorry.
Are you going to?
I have to go up 15 floors.
Never mind.
Made it.
There's a copy here.
No!
In this dialogue, there's some great language that can be used in many different patterns or in many different ways.
So, in today's putting it together, we're going to show you how to use three of these patterns.
Put it in it together.
Okay.
The first pattern that we can look at is out of toner.
Out of toner.
Right.
So, we already talked about toner.
Yep.
Let's talk about out of.
Okay.
So, when you are out of you, you have none.
Right.
So, let's change a little bit.
So, I can say, I am out of milk.
Uh-huh.
I'm out of time.
Out of time, right?
Yep.
If you're driving, I'm out of gas gasoline.
So, out of plus noun.
Mm-hmm.
Perfect.
It means you don't have none.
You don't have none.
I think it's pod.com.
Yeah.
You ain't gotten none.
You bonnick, stop.
All right.
Out of time.
Let's take a look at our second one.
On your way up.
Yeah.
On your way, right?
Mm-hmm.
So, this is a great way when you are talking to someone and they're going somewhere.
Yes.
Right.
So, on your way up.
Can you bring this to HR?
Okay.
On your way to the store.
Can you mail this letter?
Mm-hmm.
Or maybe on your way home.
Can you buy me some flowers?
Mm-hmm.
Nice.
All right.
So, on your way, it means...
It means while you are going there.
Right.
Yeah.
Taking advantage of the fact that you are going somewhere.
Yes.
Okay.
Now, let's take a look at our last one.
And this is a really great phrase.
Mm-hmm.
Break down.
In our dialogue, we heard breaking down.
Yes.
Right.
Everything in the office seems to be breaking down.
So, when something breaks down, it stops working.
It stops working.
It stops working exactly.
Yeah.
So, we can change it a little bit.
What happens if we say break up?
Ooh, boyfriend and girlfriend.
Right.
They end their relationship.
Okay.
So, we can maybe think about it as their relationships stops working.
Ah, nice one.
Right.
Okay.
What about break in?
Mm.
Enter a place using force.
Right.
You enter a house that's not yours.
Yeah.
So, if you break into a house, maybe you break the window and climb in.
Okay.
Mm.
What about break out?
So, opposites.
Right.
So, for example, you might break out of jail.
Break out of prison.
Yeah.
So, this is a great phrase.
You can change the, you can change the last word from break down, break up, break in.
Yeah.
And it means different things.
So, use different prepositions for different meanings.
Perfect.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So, now let's listen to our dialogue for the last time.
And then, Erica and I will be back and talk a little bit more about malfunctioning
office supplies.
Okay.
Hey, Carl.
Can you make a copy of this contract for me, please?
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
Sure.
Mm.
I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
Yeah.
Sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
When you're way up, can you fax this while I try and fix this thing?
Sure.
Damn it.
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
I'll send this stupid fax later.
Oh, great.
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
The elevator has some sort of malfunction.
Just take this to here.
What's all right?
You're going to.
I have to go up 15 floors.
Never mind.
Made it.
There's a copier.
No!
All right.
So Erica, everything that you touch that's electronic seems to malfunction, right?
This is absolutely true.
I don't know what it is, but you know what?
If I turn on a computer, it will suddenly get a virus.
And even if I'm very careful, it still breaks.
Right.
Yeah, it happens sometimes.
I can relate to that.
But you are much better at computers and technology than I am.
Well, I really really like them.
And well, I guess even I know a little bit about copy machines or
copyers because my uncles are like copy technicians.
Really?
Yeah, so, you know, they fix copiers that broke down or they replace
toner and, you know, they do all that stuff.
So that's why you know a little bit about it.
But actually the original term is a zerox machine.
Yes, why is that from the brand, right?
There's a brand called zerox and zerox invented and patented
this technology of making copies.
All right, well, the next time my photocopier explodes.
I'll call you.
You call it, come on, uncle, right?
All right.
And well, let us know how things in your office break down or
if you have any stories of like Erica that breaks everything.
Yeah, it's true.
All right.
So come to our website, come to our comments section and
leave your opinions and we'll be there to also answer any doubts or
questions you might have.
That's right.
You can find us at EnglishPod.com and Markoneye.
Our O is around.
All right.
So we'll see you guys there.
Yeah, we will.
Okay, guys.
Thanks for listening and until next time.
Bye.