Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have the continuation of our series about giving a presentation.
That's right today it's part six and on this occasion we're going to address the audience.
So we're going to talk to the audience and explain a couple of things.
All right so let's take a listen to today's speech and we back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia,
in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners.
But for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly the right level.
The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and secondly what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop?
Let's first of all tackle the first question.
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average income.
However as we mentioned before the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
For example the X420 is also ideally suited to younger student sector who might use laptops both for studying and gaming.
There's no doubt that.
Mr Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say that the computer is suitable for students, but you don't think the price of the X420 is just too much for most students.
Well that's a fair point.
If you don't mind I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section is that okay?
Yes sure.
Okay so as I was saying we have an exciting campaign planned for the X420.
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and also in many computer publications.
We also intend to.
I'm sorry to stop you Mr Ford but do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective?
I mean how much is that going to cost?
Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with you after the presentation.
Okay let me just go on and talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
Alright we're back and now let's take a look at five keywords on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright so first up Marko we have a verb the verb is to devise.
That's right so we devise the A campaign.
Okay so to devise in this case means to create or to come up with.
That's right I think in many movies you will hear that someone will devise a plan to destroy the world for example.
Right or to devise a scheme.
So that's to create or to come up with a plan or come up with something.
And talking about the computers he mentioned a couple of words that describe it especially the affordability of the laptop computer.
Okay so yeah there's this string of nouns that Mr Ford thinks are very important relating to the perfect laptop.
And in this case affordability is the first one.
So something that is affordable is something that you can have the money to buy it's not too expensive.
Let's see adjective affordable affordability means whether or not something is expensive.
That's right so if you think of the if you think of the adjective affordable.
The noun would be affordability so this is just the way that you can transform an adjective into a noun.
Right so this is something that comes up a lot when we're talking about buying things for example Marko.
I could say what do you look for when you're buying a car?
Right so I can say affordability.
And you could also say our next one which is reliability.
That's right so if you look for a car you are also looking for reliability and this comes from the adjective reliable.
All right so something is reliable if you can depend on it.
It means you know in the case of a laptop or a car it won't break easily.
That's right so a person can also be reliable you can trust that person to help you for example.
Or I could trust that he will never be late or never forget that we have an appointment.
That's exactly right.
Well moving on to the next part of Mr. Ford's speech he talked about the television campaign and how he really hopes to reach out to a huge audience with this television advert.
All right so the reason we've chosen this is because it's important to remember this as a phrase to reach out to.
That means to connect with and I think your example of television is a really great one because television allows people to reach out to many many many people.
That's right.
Also for example with internet you are able to reach out to many people all over the world.
So to reach out to is to connect with.
Okay and for our last word when he was about to show everyone the TV advert he said that tonight for the first time we will unveil the first of these advertisements.
All right so to unveil something is actually very exciting because to unveil something is to show it for the very first time.
That's right so maybe you've seen in car shows where they have a car under a big white sheet and on that night they're going to unveil the new model of the.
I don't know the Ford car so that's what it means to unveil to take away this veil and show everyone to unveil.
All right so a lot of good key words there when we go back and listen to Mr. Ford again and when we return we'll talk about fluency builder.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners but for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly the right level.
The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and secondly what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop.
Let's first of all tackle the first question. Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average income.
However as we mentioned before the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
For example the X420 is also ideally suited to younger student sector who might use laptops both for studying and gaming.
There's no doubt that.
Mr Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say that the computer is suitable for students but you don't think the price of the X420 is just too much for most students.
Well that's a fair point if you don't mind I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section is that okay.
Yes sure.
Okay so as I was saying we have an exciting campaign plan for the X420.
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and also in many computer publications.
We also intend to.
I'm sorry to stop you Mr Ford but do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective?
I mean how much is that going to cost?
Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with you after the presentation.
Okay let me just go on and talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at these four key phrases we've picked out for you today.
Fluency Builder.
So in the beginning Mr Ford is talking about this exciting X420 and he says that you know he would like to say that without the help of each and every one of you the campaign could not have been created.
So each and every one of you.
That's right this is just a phrase where you emphasize that everyone helped you or that you are thanking everyone.
So in the speech you can say I want to thank each and every one of you so I want to thank everyone is basically what you're saying.
And it's it's interesting because it's kind of like you're saying every single person was important.
Right.
It's not just like hey guys thank you it's like no thank you and you and you and you so each and everyone.
If you really emphasize is that each person has helped that's right and it's a really nice way of for example thanking someone saying I want to thank each and every one of you it sounds a lot more personal.
Definitely.
Okay and he also used another very interesting phrase when he said I'd like to take my hat off and really thank you all for your wonderful work.
So this makes me think of a person actually back when people used to wear hats every day taking his hat off and maybe bowing.
This is this is something that used to be very polite because you know when you meet someone or you want to thank someone you take your hat off as a sign of respect.
Well we don't wear hats anymore so it seems a little funny but we still say this I want to take my hat off to you Marco that means I want to thank you.
That's right so you're showing respect and you're also showing admiration maybe for someone so maybe if you meet somebody who saved someone's life you would say I really want to take my hat off and thank you for the work that you've done.
Yes you're impressed you respect that person who saved that life and you want to thank them for their good deed.
That's right.
Well moving on when he continued to talk about alpha computers and the marketing efforts he said there's no doubt in my mind.
That we have a great workforce.
All right so another way to say this is I definitely think we have a great workforce.
But you know maybe not it's not as interesting right so we're making this more interesting by using a very colorful phrase and to say there's no doubt that you're a great workforce is good.
But there's no doubt in my mind means there's there's absolutely no way that I could doubt this I absolutely believe that you are the best workforce.
So and you can use it with anything you can say yeah there's no doubt in my mind IBM computers are the best computers out there for example.
Or there's no doubt in my mind that the Yankees will win the world series next year.
That's right okay so that's the way that you can use it you're basically telling people that you are very very sure.
And what about our last phrase a very interesting one when he says our campaign will really hammer home the point.
Okay well you can make a point you can say listen our computers are state of the art and they're the best for your needs.
But to hammer home the point means to really emphasize this one important point and to say listen.
You will never forget this okay you will not forget what I'm going to say to you so you really emphasize it and restate it.
This is something that can be frustrating when you're a consumer when you're watching it an advertisement because you hear them say this is the best product you shouldn't buy other products this is the best product and they're hammering home the point they're repeating this message.
So it's a colloquial phrase that you can use to really again put your point across.
Okay so a lot of interesting phrases there one we take a break and let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Now as we've already discussed there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners but for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at exactly the right level.
The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and secondly what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop.
Let's first of all tackle the first question.
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average income.
However as we mentioned before the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
For example the X420 is also ideally suited to younger student sector who might use laptops both for studying and gaming.
There's no doubt that.
Mr Ford if I could just interrupt a moment you say that the computer is suitable for students but you don't think the price of the X420 is just too much for most students.
Well that's a fair point if you don't mind I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section is that okay.
Yes sure.
Okay so as I was saying we have an exciting campaign plan for the X420.
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and also in many computer publications.
We also intend to.
I'm sorry to stop you, Mr Ford but do you really think that a television campaign is cost effective?
I mean how much is that going to cost?
Well I don't have the figures to hand but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with you after the presentation.
Okay let me just go on and talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
All right so this was part six of our presentations series we still have four more lessons to go all about this and they're going to get a little bit more complicated and we're going to continue talking.
And the next couple of lessons are actually answering questions from the public and many things like this.
Yeah I think they're really useful because sometimes you prepare your presentation you feel really good about it but those questions at the end can be scary because you don't really know how to answer question properly and English or you don't know how to anticipate a question that you might get from the crowd.
So those are things that we would like to talk about in the next couple of episodes.
That's right and remember that these phrases and how you see him presenting this laptop computer.
You can still take a lot of the words a lot of the vocal.
A lot of the phrases and kind of put it into your speech or your presentation. You're going to sound great.
Absolutely.
State of the art. Save that one.
But that's about it for us here today at English.
Probably hope you've enjoyed this lesson and we'll see you next time.
All right bye.