Hello English learners. Welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today we're bringing you the next part of our suspense series, the new guy in town.
That's right. So we know that our mod wasn't really a vampire that he was just acting.
And the women aren't quite what they see in this dialogue.
In the last one, something happened and she transformed into some sort of, I don't know, creature, right?
Monster. Right. So now let's see what happens. So we're not going to preview any vocabulary this time.
Let's just listen to the dialogue and see what happens.
But take a look is going on. Did you see that? What was that thing?
I don't know. I'm just how we made it up.
Look, there's a police car. Help! Help! Please, please stop!
How do you, man? What seems to be the problem? Is this man bothering your officer?
Officer. There is like a witch creature back there. We tied her up, but she broke me.
And she was about to have us for dinner. Okay, come down, come down.
Let me see your eyes, please. Have you been drinking tonight's son?
We're telling the truth. She's in there. We suspected her being a kidnapper or a rapist, but turns out
she's an alien or something. Okay, calm down, calm down. Let me see your eyes, please.
Seriously, are you going to help us out or not? Okay, let's go have a look, shall we?
YES!
Hello? Has anyone in there?
Be careful, she might be hiding.
That's perfectly safe.
There isn't anyone.
Well, I don't think things are turning out very well for our housewives and our
people.
The police officer is not going to make it the next episode.
We're going to look at five words and phrases here.
The first one, they described this woman as a creature.
What exactly is a creature?
A bird to an insect or a bug.
There's a creature under my bed.
A creature can be any living thing.
What about our next one?
A creature broke free from some ropes.
When you break free, you escape from something that stops you moving.
That's quite interesting the way we can use this in different ways.
An example one.
We tied up the dog, but he is trying to break free.
Example two.
I'm glad I broke free from that horrible relationship.
Example three.
I want to break free from all my daily responsibilities.
Okay, so break free it's clear now.
So why don't we move on to our next word?
They thought that maybe this creature was a kidnapper.
Kidnapper.
Okay, so this is a criminal.
So a kidnapper is a criminal.
Yep.
What exactly does a kidnapper do?
A kidnapper takes someone to a place and keeps them there against their will.
Against their will.
With force or violence.
All right, so I guess that makes sense, right?
Because the word has kid in it.
Yeah, so to take children.
Yes.
But it can be also you can kidnap in the adult.
Yes, that's true.
So this word can actually be used in three different ways.
So we saw a kidnapper, right?
Okay, that is the person.
Yeah, and the verb to kidnap.
Okay.
Or a noun describing an action.
Kidnapping.
A kidnapping.
Very good.
Yeah, a kidnapping took place today.
Okay, so very interesting word.
And of course, it's illegal to be a kid never.
Yes.
So our next word is also very serious and it's also a crime, right?
That's right.
A rapist.
Okay, so that is a person that who forces someone to have sex.
Okay, so again, against their will.
Right.
Exactly.
Okay, and the verb would be to rape to rape someone.
Okay, so on the lighter side, we heard the police officer say something in a very strange way.
He said, let me see your eyes, please.
Okay, so this is an interesting phrase.
It's a sound made from pushing two words together.
Right, so let me.
Why don't we hear a few more examples of this and see if we can figure out what are the two words?
Example one.
Let me have a look inside the car.
Example two.
Let me go out tonight, dad.
Please.
Example three.
Let me think about it and I'll give you an answer tomorrow.
So basically, let me is let me let me.
Yeah, let me have that pan.
Okay, let me see.
Now we do this also with other words, right?
Yeah, another example would be, give me, give me.
Yeah, so that is give me exactly.
Okay, so an interesting thing, it's not proper English, right?
No, you wouldn't really write it this way, but it's fine in an dictionary.
But it's really common when people speak.
And actually it's more likely that you'll say, let me give me, give me, give me.
Okay, very good.
So I think now it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the second time.
And then we'll come back and look at some other phrases that we saw in our dialogue.
What the heck is going on?
Did you see that? What was that thing?
I don't know. I'm just glad we made it out.
Look, there's a police car. Help, help, please stop.
Howdy, man. What seems to be the problem?
Is this man bothering you?
Officer, Officer, there is like a witch creature back there.
We tied her up, but she broke free.
And she was about to have us for dinner.
Okay, calm down, calm down.
Let me see your eyes, please. Have you been drinking tonight, son?
We are telling the truth. She's in there.
We suspected her of being a kidnapper or rapist, but it turns out she's an alien or something.
Okay, calm down, calm down. Let me see your eyes, please.
Oh, seriously. Are you going to help us or not?
Okay, let's go have a look, shall we?
Hello? Is anyone in here?
Be careful. She might be hiding.
It's perfectly safe. There isn't anyone.
We're going to look at two phrases now in Fluency Builder that you might hear when you're talking about a crime.
Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase that we're going to look at is what the heck is going on?
What the heck is going on?
Okay, so this is just asking what's happening, right?
Right, but it's a very strong way of saying what's happening.
Yeah, what really is happening?
Uh-huh. Now, why did they say what the heck?
What is heck?
Well, heck is sort of a polite way of saying hell.
Okay, so instead of saying what the hell is going on?
What the heck is going on?
Now, why do you do this?
Um, because in, especially in American English, we don't like to talk about religious words.
So like hell and God and Jesus, these things are, um, impolite and American people.
Right, you don't want to offend anyone.
Right.
So that's why we would have other words like, oh, my gosh.
For, oh, my God.
Or, geez.
Instead of Jesus.
Right.
Okay, so that is an interesting thing.
Of course, it is a little bit of a sensitive topic among some people.
So that's why it's better to just use these synonyms.
Yes.
Okay.
And what about our next phrase?
So they suspected her of being a kidnapper.
Okay.
So suspected her of being a kidnapper.
Yeah.
Suspect someone of being something.
Something.
So I suspect she is an alien.
Right.
So I suspect she is a suspect him of being a liar.
Okay.
So what about to suspect?
What does that mean, exactly?
To think something that is true, but not be a hundred percent sure.
So you can say, I think she is a kidnapper.
Yep.
Oh, I suspect her of being a kidnapper.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Why don't we hear a few more examples?
Example one.
The police suspected him of being a bank robber.
Example two.
We suspect our dog is responsible for this mess.
Example three.
The neighborhood suspected that our neighbor was selling drugs.
All right.
Very good.
So we've seen a lot of vocab.
We've seen these phrases.
So I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue for the last time.
And then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
But to take us going on, did you see that?
What was that thing?
I don't know.
I'm just how we made it up.
Look, there's a police car.
Help! Help! Please, please stop!
How do you, man?
What seems to be the problem?
Is this man bothering you?
Officer.
There is like a witch creature back there.
We tied her up, but she broke me.
And she was about to have us for dinner.
Okay.
Calm down.
Let me see your eyes.
Please.
Have you been drinking tonight's son?
We're telling the truth.
She's in there.
We suspected her being a kidnapper or a rapist.
But turns out she's an alien or something.
Okay. Calm down. Calm down.
Let me see your eyes.
Please.
Seriously.
Are you going to help us out or not?
Okay.
Let's go have a look, shall we?
You.
Hello?
Is anyone in there?
Be careful. She might be hiding.
That's perfectly safe.
There isn't anyone.
Okay.
Well, Mark, we're coming near the end of this series, aren't we?
Yes, exactly.
It's a short series.
But what do you think happens or how do you think the series ends?
What is really going on?
A mystery here at English Pod.
So we want you to hear from you.
What do you think is going to happen?
Exactly.
Come to our website at EnglishPod.com where you can leave us your questions.
Your comments or even maybe your ideas.
Don't be too much to be able to do this.
But for any lesson that you would like to hear.
That's right.
Well, guys, we're happy that you downloaded this lesson and remember to check out our website.
But until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye.