Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have part two of a very important and very valuable series
about giving presentations.
That's right. As you well know, we started this series. It's a ten-part series and today
we're going to talk about sales and charts and graphs and more or less explaining maybe
a PowerPoint presentation. That's right. So you're going to learn some wonderful ways of
talking about changes in markets and marketing. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what you've heard.
As all of you are well aware, competition and laptop computer sector is intense. We
continue to fight with our competitors for market share and this is the case both in the
developed markets and the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa.
You may ask yourself why is this market so cut-throat? Well the answer is simple. There's
a huge, untapped potential market out there with a huge, untapped potential for profit.
If I bring up the first graph here, it shows the increase in terms of number of computer
owners across the globe. As you can see in the 1980s computer ownership amounted to around
0.5% of the total world population. Since the 1990s computer ownership has risen dramatically.
In the new millennium, we saw an even larger explosion in computer owners with figures rising
to around 4% to 5%. In increase of 1,000% compared with the 1980s.
If we move on to discuss the figures for China specifically, we can see in chart B that the
overall figure for computer ownership stands at around 60 million, which represents a huge
increase in a very short time period. Now of course, 60 million is just a drop in the ocean
if you compare the total population of China. And this is a key reason why the personal
computer market is such a hot market. For us at Alpha and of course for all of our competitors
as well, we have millions of potential customers who are looking to join the internet generation.
If we do this right, we really can repude rewards in a very short time frame. I now like
to move on to discuss the X420 brand itself and compare and contrast with some of our key competitors.
All right, we're back. So now let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay. So in the first part of what Mr. Ford is saying, he mentioned something
called market share. Now, Markle, what is market share? That's right. Everyone is competing
for market share. And this is basically a small portion of your available market. So, for
example, if you sell perfumes, women's perfume, then your market share is maybe women who are
18 to 35 years old in your city or in your town or in your country. I see. Right. So when we're
talking about market share because we're sharing a piece of this big pie, we're going to
talk about that in terms of a percentage. So 30% or 15%. That's right. I think maybe one of
the clearest examples is Coca-Cola has I think maybe a 60% market share of the carbonated
beverages market. Interesting. So you could say that Apple has a 50% market share of the personal
computing industry. That's right. Very good. So this is what we refer to as market share.
Now, now as we continue to talk about markets, we have two very interesting words when we
refer to a developed market and a developing market. Okay. So a developed market is something
that has been polished and grown over time. Perhaps we talk about the developed world being
Western Europe and America. But then we have developing markets and those are markets that are
still trying to figure out kind of what's going on. They're growing. They're usually growing
much faster than a developed market. That's right. So again, when we're talking about maybe
computers, we consider, for example, the United States a developed market. Many people already
have a computer or expressed a desire by one. And so maybe a developing market are some of the
African countries where they're still growing. And so now they're beginning to purchase more and more
computers. Okay. So developed and developing two different ways to describe markets. That's right.
Now after that, we hear this phrase cut throat. So someone asks, why is this market so cut throat?
What does this mean? A cut throat business or a cut throat industry. It means that it's very,
very competitive. Okay. So cut throat. We're actually talking about maybe having a knife and
cutting someone else's throat. But it's just a metaphor. It's a way of saying, yes, this is very
competitive. So you're not actually cutting someone's throat. Everyone is fighting for that market
share. So it's very cut throat. Everyone is fighting very, very hard. But you're not literally
killing someone or cutting their throats. And you could even use this to talk about a sporting event.
You could say, you know, it was a cut throat game. That's right. That's right. So anything that's
very competitive or very close. So to finish off language takeaway when Mr. Ford was
towards the end of his presentation, he said that the rewards could be very, very big in a very
short timeframe. So when we say the word timeframe, we mean period of time. It's not like,
you know, two PM. It's like from from May to June. We have this short timeframe. It's only two
months long. That's right. So timeframe is a window or a period. That's right. So this is what he is
referring to is that in the very short period or in this period of time, they could make a lot of
many a time frame. Right. But how long would a long time frame be? Maybe a couple of years. All right.
So you can have a short timeframe and a long time frame. That's right. Okay. Why don't we take a look at
our dialogue again? And we'll be back shortly with fluency builder.
As all of you are well aware, competition in the laptop computer sector is intense. We continue
to fight with our competitors for market share. And this is the case both in the developed markets
in the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa. You may ask yourself,
why is this market so cut throat? Well, the answer is simple. There is a huge, untapped
potential market out there with a huge, untapped potential for profit. If I bring up the first
graph here, it shows the increase in terms of number of computer owners across the globe. As you can
see in the 1980s computer ownership amounted to around 0.5% of the total world population. Since the
1990s, computer ownership has risen dramatically. In the new millennium, we saw an even larger
explosion in computer owners with figures rising to around 4% to 5%. In increase of 1,000%
compared with the 1980s. If we move on to discuss the figures for China specifically, we can see
in chart B that the overall figure for computer ownership stands at around 60 million,
which represents a huge increase in a very short time period. Now of course, 60 million is just
to drop in the ocean if you compare the total population of China. And this is a key reason why
the personal computer market is such a hot market. For us at Alpha and of course for all of our
competitors as well, we have millions of potential customers who are looking to join the internet
generation. If we do this right, we really can repude rewards in a very short time frame.
I now like to move on to discuss the X420 brand itself and compare and contrast with some of our
key competitors. All right, we're back. So now we've picked out a couple of different phrases for you.
Let's check those out now on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. So in today's dialogue, we heard
Mr. Ford talk about some numbers. He's talking about growth and change in the market.
And he says with figures to around 4 to 5 percent, we've got an overall increase of 1,000 percent.
That's right. So this phrase and increase of very, very common when you're talking about growth
of maybe revenue or when you're talking about the growth of a company or sales, for example.
So it's important to remember here that this is a fixed phrase. We say an increase of 10 percent
increase of 30 percent. But you can use the same phrase with drops in percentages or money.
So you can say a decrease of 10 percent. That means that you go down 10 percent or a decrease of 100 percent.
That's right. So a very useful phrase when talking about incrementing someone or as you said,
decreasing a decrease of 5 percent. Now Mr. Ford used a very interesting phrase when referring to the
Chinese market. Obviously it's a very big market and he says that the computer ownership stands
at around 60 million. But of course 60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you compare it to the
population of China. That's right. So what does this mean? It's a big percentage or a small
percentage. Very, very small. All right. So what he's saying here is it's like a drop of water in an ocean.
So a drop of water is so small. You don't even notice it. You don't even see it because the
ocean is so big. And so you can use this in many different ways. You can say hey,
you know, $5 is just a drop in the ocean. Right. It's not really important because it's very
little money. That's right. That's right. So it's sort of like a metaphor saying, you know what?
It's very insignificant. It's just a drop of water in an ocean. It's not really something you can notice.
That's right. Just a drop in the ocean. And now at the very end of today's speech, we heard
the phrase to compare and contrast. So we're talking about the X420 computer brand itself.
Now what is what is Mr Ford mean when he says to compare and contrast? So when we mentioned the word
compare, we are basically trying to determine how they are similar in many ways. The characteristics
of how they are similar. And to contrast is how they are different, right? That's right. So let's
use an example, perhaps we could say Pepsi and Coca-Cola. Let's compare and contrast.
So they're both carbonated beverages. They are both sweet. And they're both, they're the
pretty much the same color. That's right. And they're also fairly cheap. They have about the same price.
But I would say that Coca-Cola is tastes more like prune. So that would be a contrast in
characteristic of Coca-Cola is that maybe it tastes a little bit sweeter. It does. And you could also
say it's easier to find Coca-Cola. Pepsi is less easy to find sometimes. That's right.
Another way that they're different. So basically to compare and contrast is to point out how
two things are similar and how they're different. That's right. So we've had a lot of interesting
phrases there. I think very useful if you're talking about business and marketing and sales.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue one last time?
As all of you are well aware, competition and laptop computer sector is intense. We continue
to fight with our competitors from MarketShare. And this is the case both in the developed markets
in the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa. You may ask yourself,
why is this market so cut throat? Well, the answer is simple. There's a huge, untapped
potential market out there with a huge, untapped potential for profit. If I bring up the first
graph here, it shows the increase in terms of number of computer owners across the globe.
As you can see in the 1980s computer ownership amounted to around 0.5% of the total world
population. Since the 1990s computer ownership has risen dramatically. In the new millennium,
we saw an even larger explosion in computer owners with figures rising to around 4% to 5%.
In an increase of 1,000% compared with the 1980s. If we move on to discuss the figures for
China specifically, we can see in chart B that the overall figure for computer ownership stands
at around 60 million, which represents a huge increase in a very short time period. Now of course,
60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you compare the total population of China.
And this is a key reason why the personal computer market is such a hot market.
For us at Alpha and of course for all of our competitors as well, we have millions of
potential customers who are looking to join the internet generation. If we do this right,
we really can reap huge rewards in a very short time frame. I now like to move on to discuss the
X420 brand itself and compare and contrast with some of our key competitors.
All right, we're back. So as we mentioned, this is just a part of our presentation series.
We're going to keep on talking with Mr. Ford as he discusses business and a lot of other
very interesting and useful skills for talking in public. That's right. So the goal of this series
is to help you feel better when you're giving a presentation in English. We all know it's very,
very hard to talk in English when you're still learning, but it's even harder to talk alone to give
us speech or presentation. And so the point of this series is to really give you those skills
and to help teach you some of the key phrases and words that you'll be using in your presentations
in the future. That's right. So if you have any questions or any doubts, we are always available
at English.com. And we'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.