EnglishPod.com
Yeah, I just moved here and I'd like to activate my cell phone and I'm not sure if I should go with a pre-paid plan or a monthly rate plan
I see. Well, can I have a look at your phone?
And fortunately this phone can't be using the US. It's not compatible with our 3G network
What? Really? I don't really want to have to buy a new phone
Well, you're in luck. You see, if you sign up for our 3-year plan, we'll throw in a hand set for free
Really? What's the cat? There's no catch. You just choose a plan, sign a 3-year contract, and that's it
Actually, we're running a special promotion right now, and we're giving away a blackberry curve with our special mega-value 40-dollar plan
So, what is this plan include? Well, you get 900 anytime minutes, and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile calling to other tell-mobile clients
A thousand text messages per month and unlimited evening and we can minutes
Oh, and we also offer a roll-over option. Wow, all this for $40 per month
That's right. Plus the activation fee and the emergency services fee the monthly service fee and oh, and any charges for extra minutes and