Hello English learners, welcome back to English pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're bringing you another great lesson about sports part of our
sports series. That's right and in this lesson we are talking about maybe the world's most favorite
sports. Right one of the most popular sports in the world soccer or also known as football in
other countries. Yes, okay so before we get started with this great lesson let's take a look
at some of the words we'll find in the dialogue in vocabulary preview. Very vocabulary preview.
We're going to look at three words here. The first word is wingman. wingman. A wingman.
Now wingman isn't really related to soccer in any way. Okay but it's a way of referring to somebody
as your right hand. So your helper. Your helper, your number one guy. Okay, right.
So a wingman is someone who helps you a lot. Uh-huh. Exactly. Okay, our next word,
tied. Tide. They are tied. They are tied. Now this is an interesting word because
tie can be a noun verb and an adjective right? Exactly. So in this case they are tied.
It's an adjective meaning they have the same score. Okay and a tie is a game that has ended with no
winner or loser. Both of them have the same score. Exactly. And so obviously the verb
two tie is to reach the same score as your other team. Exactly. All right well our third word
can also be used as a noun and a verb and it is foul. Fowl. Fowl. Okay so two foul somebody.
Is to do something to them that is not allowed in the sport. Okay and so when you do this you have
committed a foul. Exactly. Okay so use it in the same way two foul or a foul.
Interesting. Well we're going to hear these three words in context now. So why don't we listen to our
soccer dialogue?
Welcome back soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and as always I am joined by my
commentating weekman Bob Copeland and we are in the break of soccer history today as Ecuador
and Brazil are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 world cup. The
rough calls the players for the kickoff and here we go Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the
midfield but oh it's out of bounds. That will be a throw in for Brazil. I do kind of know how to
the ball and makes a long pass to Hauinio and the ref is called the mobside. No question about it
he was off side by a mile. We have a goal kick record or Edison Mendez heads a turbulence yell
he shoots deflected by the defender and we have a corner kick. Then Galot takes the corner we have a foul.
Oh no. D to the goalkeeper has foul the Ecuador player he gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick.
This is the perfect opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world champions.
He gets ready for the kick he shoots and he
Okay so Ecuador tied with Brazil in the 2022 world cup. Wow Marko I'm really happy to see that you are
able to see so far into the future. Well I called it so in 2022 if we do win the world cup
you know who said it first. All right you have money on that? Yes. All right so apart from this we saw
some really great vocabulary in this lesson so let's take a look at it now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right you've got a lot of soccer words for you but they're all important.
So let's take a look at the first one kick off kick off. So a kick off. This is how you start
soccer game right. Right so it's the very beginning the referee blows the whistle and you kick the ball to
another player that's the kick off. Okay so our next phrase out of bounds out of bounds.
Out of bounds. Okay out of bounds this is a great word. Hmm so in soccer when the ball goes out of
bounds it goes outside the white lines right. Outside of the playing field. Okay and you can use it
on all other sports you can use it in basketball you can use it in tennis or football or anything.
Right so any part that is not for playing out of bounds what's our next word? Throw in.
A throw in. A throw in. Okay so A throw in. The ball goes out of bounds.
Uh-huh how do you put it back into play? Obviously a throw in. Okay so you throw in the ball.
That's the only time where a soccer player will actually grab the ball with his hands.
All right now another soccer term we have here off side. Off side. Off side.
Okay so this is a little bit difficult to explain but just imagine you're on the soccer field.
Uh-huh and you are trying to score a goal. Now you have some defenders right?
Right so the people who are trying to take the ball away and you pass the ball to somebody who is
behind the defenders. Oh and that person is off side. Exactly so you must be at all times
in the same position as the defenders or in front of them but you can't be all the way in the back.
Okay so is this a noun or a verb or an adjective? So this is an adjective he is off side.
That's his condition. Okay great excellent explanation Marko thank you. Right. Now we're going to
look at three different phrases for three types of kicks in soccer. Okay so let's take a look at this.
The first one is goal kick. A goal kick. Okay goal kick. So who does the goal kick?
It's usually the goalie or the goalkeeper. All right. Who takes the goal kick? Okay so when the goalie
kicks the ball. Now what about a corner kick? Okay so if the team is attacking and the ball goes
out of bounds in the back area near the goal then they get a corner kick. They got to kick the ball
from the corner of the field. This is a great chance to score a goal isn't it? Exactly yes. Okay and
our final kick a penalty kick. Penalty kick. Penalty kick. So if a player gets fouled while he is in the
area near the goal. Okay he gets a penalty kick so basically it's just him. I think it's 13 or 15
steps away from the goalie and he gets the opportunity to score or to kick the ball. So there are no
defenders or other players in the way. Wow another great chance to score a goal. All right well these
are all great soccer words. I think we should hear them again in context. So let's listen this time
a little bit slower. Welcome back soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and
as always I am joined by my commentating wingman Bob Copeland and we're on the brink of soccer
history today as Ecuador and Brazil are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 world cup.
The rough calls the players for the kick off and here we go. Ecuador quickly passes the ball to
the midfield but oh it's out of bounds. That will be a throw in for Brazil. Adriano has the ball
and makes a long pass to Rubiniu and the rough has called him upside. No question about it.
He was off side by a mile. We have a goal kick for Ecuador. Edison Mendez heads it to Valencia.
He shoots deflected by the defender and we have a corner kick.
The Elgato takes the corner and we have a foul. Oh no. The the goalkeeper has fouled the Ecuadorian
player. He gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick. This is the perfect opportunity for
Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world champions. He gets ready for the kick.
He shoots and he. All right so we heard these words that we were talking about in context
and now some really interesting phrases came up and this would be a good time to take a look at them
in fluency builder fluency builder. Well Marco there are three great phrases in this dialogue
that I want to look at. The first one on the brink of we are on the brink of
we're on the brink of soccer history. Okay so on the brink of what exactly does that mean?
Well why don't we hear some examples to help us understand the meaning?
Example one. Look we don't have any money. We're on the brink of going bankrupt.
Example two. The two countries are on the brink of war. Example three.
We're on the brink of an important discovery. All right so great examples on the brink of
at a critical point. Exactly means you're almost there right? Okay yeah very good.
And what about this next phrase that I saw and it was really interesting? No question about it.
No question about it. No question about it. No question about it. All right so
this is a statement that doesn't really make much sense but what am I saying when I say oh no
question about it? You're saying I agree there is no doubts you're right. You're right.
Okay well let's give some examples. I could say there's no question about it.
Ecuador is a great soccer team. There is no question about that. All right so
or you can say no question about it. Our company makes the best products on the market.
Okay so really useful phrase that you can use in sports or anywhere else. Okay and now let's
take a look at our last phrase for fluency builder and it's a really good one too.
Exaggerate a little bit. Okay by a mile. By a mile. By a mile. So he was off side by a mile.
Right so the commentator is saying that he was very off side. That it was really obvious.
Right. So you can use that also in different contexts maybe not in sports. Okay so maybe we can say
our company is ahead of all the others by a mile. Right or if you tell somebody to guess your
age and they say oh I think you are 42. Oh you could say you're off by a mile. Right so you're
really really wrong. Right exactly. Yeah so it's a way of exaggerating a little bit. Yes and
thing is really obvious. Right. Well three awesome phrases and I think it will help us to hear them
one more time. So let's listen to the dialogue.
Welcome Max soccer fans. My name is Rick Fields and as always I am joined by my
commentating wingman Bob Copeland and we are in the break of soccer history today as Ecuador
and Brazil are tied one one as we begin the second half of the 2022 World Cup.
The rough calls to players for the kickoff and here we go Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the
midfield but oh it's out of bounds. That will be a throw in for Brazil. I do kind of do a
has the ball and makes a long pass to Hohenio and the ref is called a mob side. No question about it
he was off side by a mile. We have a goal kick recorder Edison Mendez heads a total of
two years. He shoots deflected by the defender and we have a corner kick. Then Galot takes the corner
we have a foul. Oh no. D to the goalkeeper has foul the Ecuador player he gets a yellow card and
that will be a penalty kick. This is the perfect opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match
and become World Champion. He gets ready for the kick he shoots and he
is ready.
Okay well as you all may know soccer is a very popular sport especially in Latin America. That's right
and your favorite team Ecuador are they are they really this good in soccer they're really going to win
the 2022 Cup. Well maybe not well actually Ecuador has improved with time but usually it's
the strong teams like Argentina and Brazil who dominate the region right. Right but yeah hopefully
we'll make it next time. Okay well I have my money on Ecuador and for 2022. But yeah not on Canada
there's no hope for us. Well Canada is doing really well now they actually beat Mexico with Hohenio
mistaken. Oh actually that sort of yeah I kind of remember that now but there's I think there's no
hope for us to be Brazil or Argentina one of these big countries. We have the next World Cup
coming up so it's really exciting and I don't know who's going to win. All right well um listeners
who do you think is going to win who is the best soccer team out there? Right they're really good
soccer teams although some of our some countries aren't really known for their soccer they're like
Russia you don't really hear too much soccer from Russia really or from China is for that. I wonder
how popular it is in these countries. So let us know come to our website englishpod.com
tell us how popular soccer is in your country or what team you are a fan of. I know many people
like the European cups and their fans of Barcelona or the Italian teams. Well come to the website
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions and until next time goodbye.