Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
And I'm Erica
And today we're going to be bringing you another great sports lesson
Yes, this one is for all our hockey fans
I know we have a lot of listeners from Russia, so this is a very popular sport in Russia, Czech Republic
Yes
So Canada
And Canada, right?
Very very popular in Canada
It's our national game
Well I guess because you guys have so much ice
I know there's nothing else to do
The skiing and hockey
All right, so it's going to be a really fun lesson
We're going to have a lot of great vocabularies
So before we start in the dialogue, let's take a look at vocabularie preview
Very cabularie preview
Well we have three words for you now
The first one, really simple
Puck
Puh, Puh, C-K
So it's almost like duck
But with the P
Yes
And this is actually kind of like the ball that you use in hockey
But it's not a ball
It's flat
And round
So it looks like a disk
Mm-hmm
Kind of like a mini-free-zbee
Yes
And this is what the players do
This is what they
They chase this around
Yeah
So in basketball you have a ball and talk you have a ball
In hockey you have a puck
Yep
Okay our next word
Key game
A key game
So this word key
Important
It means important
Really important
Yeah
So I can say a key game is a really important game
Exactly
You could also maybe say a key player
Key player is a really important player
Mm-hmm
Or even a key goal
A key goal
Okay
So let's take a look at our last word now
Finals
The Finals
So the finals are the last games
That's right
Um and the winner of the finals
wins the championship
Okay
For example in the world cup in soccer
There's only one game played in the finals
So after everyone gets eliminated there's one game where the winner is the champion
Yes
Okay
So now we're ready to
Listen to our dialogue
And it's gonna be a little bit faster than usual
Mm-hmm
Because it's a sports commentator
And it's excited
And it's exciting and there's a lot of action
So don't worry about it
Listen to it and then we'll come back and talk about some of the local players
You
Hello everyone
I'm Rick Fields and here with me is Bob Copeland
Howdy folks and welcome to today's game
You know Rick today's a key game between Russia and Canada as you know
The winner will move on to the finals
That's right and it looks like we're just about ready to start the match
The ref is calling the players for the face off
And here we go
The Russians win position and immediately start up their attack
Fender Ove gets checked hard into the boards
But he's gonna shout has the puck now
And he passes it to center he shoots
Wow, what a save by the golly
All right the puck is back in play now
Pvel Bore is on a breakaway. He is flying down the ice the defenders can't keep up
Slapshot he scores what an amazing goal
All right, so the Canadians versus the Russians, huh?
It reminds me of a classic classic game
He's exactly the classic match. Yep, so let's take a look at some of the vocabulary that we heard in the dialogue in
Language takeaway
We have five phrases in language takeaway today and the first one is face off face off face off face off
face off
So Marco a face off here is a noun, right? It's a noun exactly and it's so in the beginning of a match
The two players will stand face to face, right? That's why it's called kind of a face off
And the referee will drop the puck and they'll try to get it exactly so that's the face off the face off. Yeah, okay
Let's take a look at our next word
Check check
To check to check
So an interesting verb here, right? Yeah, it's really interesting because it's different from
The way that you would say check or revise, right? Yes, yep. This is actually
Kind of a violent
Move yeah, so what do you do? So basically in hockey you take your body and you hit another person with it
Okay, so to check someone is to hit them with your body with your body, right? You can't use your arms or your legs or your hands
You can only hit them like with your shoulder or your or your hip
Yeah, hip check. Okay, so yeah, it's very cool. All right
Our next word golly golly golly golly golly
A golly is a person right and probably the bravest of the hockey mat no kidding
So why don't you tell us what the golly does? The golly prevents the puck from coming in the net
From going into the gold, right? So the golly stops the other team from getting a gold a
Goal, yeah, okay, so the golly prevents the goals all right, very interesting
Now our fourth word is related to golly. Yes save save save save save
A save yeah, it's a noun here. It's a noun here. So the golly makes saves that's right when he stops a goall he
Makes a save makes a save, right? Yeah, okay. We have some example so we can understand this form of using save
Example one
That was an unbelievable save
Example two
The golly didn't make the save
Example three
What a save the Russians win
Yeah a little bit unusual here that save is a noun instead of a verb, but I think those examples were helpful
Now let's take a look at our last word
Breakaway breakaway breakaway breakaway a breakaway
Okay, so you have two words there that we know already break
And away yeah, so what are these two words together actually mean well imagine a group of hockey players all fighting to get the puck right and then
One player breaks off
breaks out escape the group yeah, yeah, and he's he skates down the ice and he has the puck
And he's far away from the other player right, right? So he's going away from the other players by himself. Yeah, okay
So breakaway
All right, so we've looked at a lot of hockey language here. Yep, and I think it's time now to listen to our dialogue again
This time we're gonna slow it down a little bit. Yeah, I think this will help you to understand these words a little bit better
Hello everyone. I'm Rick Fields and here with me is Bob Copeland
Howdy folks and welcome to today's game
You know Rick today is a key game between Russia and Canada as you know the winner will move on to the finals
That's right, and it looks like we're just about ready to start the match
The ref is calling the players for the face off and here we go the Russians win possession and immediately set up their attack
Federal of gets checked hard into the boards
Moly Sly shot has the puck now and passes it to the center he shoots
Wow, what a save by the goalie
All right the puck is back in play now
Pavel Buray is on a breakaway
He is flying down the ice the defenders can't keep up slap shot. He scores what an amazing goal
Okay, this dialogue is interesting because we have commentators narrating or describing what's happening
Yeah, and that moment, right? Yeah, and they're using some interesting grammar aren't they?
Exactly they are because some actions are happening in that moment, but we noticed something a little bit strange
All right, well, let's look at it and grammar breakdown
Raman breakdown
Okay, let's listen to this sentence that we previously heard in the dialogue
Moly Sly shot has the puck now and passes it to the center he shoots
Moly Sly shot has the puck now and passes it to the center
He shoots
I noticed that he's using the present simple, right? Yeah, yeah, even though the action is now
It's in present simple. Yes, even though the action is happening in that moment
He's not using the present progressive. Yeah, doesn't continuous. Yeah
This is because if you notice the actions are very very brief and fast and fast and exciting exactly
So you don't really have enough time to say for example, he is shooting
Yes, because it's only one quick action. He shoots the puck very fast
Right or for example, you wouldn't really say he is passing yeah, he is passing the puck
Right, it's just one quick action. He takes it and passes it and the action is finished. Yes, I think we can see a few more
Examples of this let's listen again
The Russians win possession and immediately set up their attack
Here we can hear that he is using the present simple again because these are very short actions that finish quickly, right?
Exactly and it's actually very very common when you're describing something you see
That's happening now. That's really exciting. It's common to use present simple
Exactly if you pay attention most
Sporting events are in the same way. Yep, they would describe the actions that are happening in the present simple
Yeah, present progressive. Yeah, but Marko you have an example of some present progressive here, right?
Yes, let's listen to this sentence
He is flying down the ice
Now we heard the sentence he is flying down the ice
Right now this one is in progressive. Yeah. Why is that? Well, first of all when we say he's flying down the ice
It's not that he's literally flying. No, he's not an airplane. He's just skating really fast. Yeah, right?
So we kind of exaggerate and we say oh he's flying down the ice
But he's actually skating. So this is a progressive action. So he is doing it. It's happening for more than one second
Yeah, yeah exactly. So that's why we would say he is flying down the ice instead of he flies down the ice
Right, yep, and less it was like really really really fast
Okay, okay, so here we see that sometimes in English we do use present simple to talk about what's happening now
When it happens really really quickly or when we want to show that it's really exciting
Exactly. Yeah, makes it much more exciting if we just use the present simple. Yeah, okay
Let's listen to this exciting dialogue one more time and we'll come back and talk a little bit more
You
Hello everyone. I'm Rick Fields and here with me is Bob Copeland howdy folks and welcome to today's game
You know Rick today's a key game between Russia and Canada as you know the winner will move on to the finals
That's right and it looks like we're just about ready to start the match the ref is calling the players for the face off
And here we go the Russians win position and immediately start up their attack
Federal gets checked hard into the boards
But he's wish out has the puck now and he passes it to center. He shoots wow. What is saved by the golly?
All right the puck is back in play now. Have a bull boor is on a breakaway
He is flying down the ice the defenders can't keep up
Slept shot he scores what an amazing goal
All right, so hockey is the Canadian national sport
Well, actually it isn't the business for yeah, what is it lacrosse is our cross?
Yeah, but anyway, we're not we don't have a lesson about real cross today not yet no
But actually all Canadians love hockey
Like we start playing hockey when we're about two years old. Yeah, I've heard that yeah
I've heard that some Canadian children learn how to skate before they learn how to walk. It's totally comment
Well, it is a great sport very very exciting. It's very fast past and it's very aggressive
That's what I like about it. I know not violent but very aggressive. Yeah, but you know what I
Must tell you that I am not a good Canadian
You're not a hockey fan. No, I'm really yeah, I really I really hate hockey why
You know the puck is so small it's hard to see where it is on the ice and it's cold and
These guys are fighting and anyway have you ever been to a hockey game? Yeah
Many times and I just find that the puck is really small
Maybe you just need better sense
Well, what do you guys think about hockey? We'll post some some videos and some pictures of hockey on on the comments section
So you can more or less see it a little bit more about this really interesting sport and tell us what you think about it
Yeah, so visit our website EnglishPod.com and you'll find some interesting stuff about hockey, right?
Exactly and also lots of other great lessons
I exactly and also if you have any questions or doubts about the less you can leave your questions on the site
All right, we're out of time. We'll see you guys next time. Thanks for listening and bye