Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson.
That's right. We're going to go and buy shoes.
Okay. This is very fun. I like buying shoes. Although I have a hard time finding shoes in my
size sometimes, but we're here talking about men's shoes specifically.
That's right. We've actually decided to talk about this topic buying shoes separately between men
and women's shoes because I think each type of shoe has its own type of vocab and that
could be very useful for men or women. That's right. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue
and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about the specifics of men's shoes styles.
Hi. I'm looking for a pair of shoes for my son.
Sure thing. Here we are. If you're looking for dress shoes, we have several different styles of
Oxford for boys. We also carry athletic shoes, hiking boots.
Oh Jacob, how about these sneakers? Mom, they've got Velcro.
Well, then how about these? What is this style called? They're tennis shoes. They're very
popular with teens and young adults. Oh, mom, can I get these? What are those? They're
Chuck Taylor's. Everyone has them. Can I please? I don't know. Would they go with your clothes?
The backs are really high and the way the tongue just sticks up, they're almost like a boot
and the sole doesn't look like it would have a very good grip. They're only $45.
And if you're like cool for us and orange shoes, it's mom, mom. Okay, try them on.
What size are your feet? Here's the size nine. We'll try a size 43 on you first and see how that fits.
Oh, what? They come in European sizes. He should be a size 43. I'll be right back.
All right, we're back. So as you saw, we have a lot of different shoe styles. And so we're
going to take a look at these on language takeaway. Language takeaway. Okay, first up, we have a very
popular style of shoe. This is called an athletic shoe. Okay, athletic shoe. Now, I imagine that
athletes wear these shoes. Good, yes, Marco. So athletic athletes. This is actually for sports in
general. So this is sports shoes. But in English, we say athletic shoes. Okay, so it's not specifically
for any type of sport, but they're just comfortable shoes that you can do most sports in. Right,
like running shoes and basketball shoes and soccer shoes. These are all kinds of athletic shoes. Very good.
These types of athletic shoes. They're usually, they're kind of low, right? They don't have
a lot of support around the ankle. No, but they do have a lot of support in the heel. The bottom of
your foot, right? Because you're running, you need that extra support. Exactly. Now, on the opposite
if you're going hiking, if you're maybe tracking, then you need a special type of shoe that
that's going to give more ankle support. And these are called hiking boots. Okay, hiking boots.
So like you were saying, you get a lot of support in your ankle. That's the bank of your foot
and the area around your leg. So these shoes tend to come higher on your leg. They're taller on your
leg. And they're usually pretty heavy. Yeah, yeah. And I think they are more weather resistant. So
if it rains or if it's wet, these shoes will respond better. You're not going to get wet feet.
You're not here. And so hiking boots. And now we have another interesting word. I never really
understood it. Why they're called this way. But we have sneakers. Snickers. Snickers.
Okay, I love sneakers. I always wear sneakers. A very common brand that you see with sneakers is
Puma. Also, a deetus. Right. So, converses and other brand sneakers are shoes that are not fancy.
They're not leather or work shoes. But they're also not athletic shoes because you don't necessarily
use them when you're playing sports. They're basically very simple shoes for, you know, normal
daily stuff. Normal walking. Young people wear them usually. Okay, sneakers. Now, I never understood
why they're called sneakers. Because I think if you sneak maybe on someone, I guess these shoes
are good for sneaking up. Perhaps. I don't know. They're less noisy than other shoes. Yeah, that's right.
Okay, so we have sneakers. And now another type of shoe that is can be a little bit confusing.
They're called tennis shoes. Okay, tennis shoes can be considered a kind of sneaker. Again,
it's not the kind of shoe that you would normally wear to work. It's not leather. It's not a hiking
boot. They're low shoes. So, low angles generally. And they have, they tie up, you know. Right.
But it's, you would think that you use these shoes to play tennis. Not necessarily, right? I mean,
you don't have to play tennis. Well, they're not specifically designed to play tennis.
Now, perhaps originally, they were tennis shoes for the game tennis. But nowadays, they're very
very common. They're like sneakers. Right. They're their shoes that most young people wear to
school or to play around in. Okay, so they're kind of like you say a sneaker. And now moving on,
these might seem a little bit strange. But we call them Chuck Taylor's. Chuck Taylor's. Well,
basically Chuck Taylor is a brand. Okay. Convers. Chuck Taylor's. We also call them Chuck's. And this
is a style of shoe that this brand made very famous. They're very, very thin canvas shoes. So,
the fabric is not leather. It's canvas. Okay. And they come in bright red or black or green. Yeah.
And some of them are very low. And some of them have an ankle, a piece of the ankle that comes up.
So it almost looks like a, like a, like a boot to a certain extent. But it's not like a hiking boot.
It's not very hard. It doesn't support your ankle as much as just the style is higher. It's
exactly. And so because these are made of fabric, they're very thin. They're very light. They're
not very good for hiking. Right. Right. So these are called Chuck Taylor's. They're very, very popular
with teenagers. Right. That's right. Teenagers all over the world. Where Chuck Taylor's. And I think
they're very old. This style, these Chuck Taylor's have been around for like 30 years. Yeah. I think
since the 1960s or 70s. But they're still popular. Yeah. And they haven't changed. They haven't changed.
Right. So these are the five types or styles of shoes that we're going to take a look at.
Why don't we move on now to more specific of vocab related to the parts of the shoe on language
takeaway part two. Language takeaway. Okay. So Jacob is talking to his mother and his mom wants
to know, hey, how about these sneakers? What do you think? And Jacob says, mom, they've got Velcro.
Okay. So Mark, or what's this Velcro? Jacob speaks of. Well, as you can see, Velcro is
capitalized. Right. And so that means this is a proper noun. And it's actually a brand.
Okay. It's like Chuck Taylor's. Like Chuck Taylor's. So Velcro is supposed kind of like a
like a zipper, right? I'm fastener. But instead of zipping it up, you just put two pieces of cloth
together and they stick. Okay. And when you pull them apart, they make that sound. Yeah. They make a
loud sound. And so sometimes with baby shoes or young children's shoes, we don't want to tie them
because that's too hard. So we have Velcro. This is a kind of fabric like you said that sticks
together. We don't have to spend all this time tying things. So you see Velcro on hats, on gloves,
on jackets, on shoes. It's a very popular way to make things close things or to keep things
secure. In a very easy way, right? You just push them together and that's it. There's their seal.
Exactly. So the next time you see it, now you know that it's called Velcro, I imagine in
other languages it's probably called the same thing. Well it's the brand name. Yeah. Yeah.
So okay. And well now moving on to the parts of the shoe, we have the tongue. Okay. Well think
about the body part, the tongue, right? When you look at your tongue, it's straight and it's flat
and it kind of curves at the bottom. Right. Well on a shoe, when you're putting your shoe on,
you know, in the front of the shoe, you can make it stuck. You have to pull the tongue. Right.
It's a piece of fabric or piece of the shoe where the top of your foot is.
Yeah, very good. So that's called the tongue. Now some shoes have a very small tongue or a low one.
In other, have a very high one. Like for example, Chuck Taylor, they have a big tongue. That's
right, very long tongue. And so the tongue is the part that rests on top of your foot and usually
the shoe laces are over the tongue. Exactly. And then moving on to the bottom part of the shoe,
that's called the sole. Okay. S-O-L-E, sole. This is a really important part of shoes. I always
look at the sole before I buy a pair of shoes because this is the part that you use the most
because you're walking on the ground. Right. So in so for example, hiking boots, they will have
a very high sole and they will have kind of like a pattern so that you don't slip if you're walking
on dirt, right? That's right. Sometimes rubber, rubber sole. But other times like Chuck Taylor's
also have a rubber sole, but it's very thin. It's very thin. And some shoes, for example, they have
plastic sole, maybe because they're used for other purposes. So they might be a little bit slippery
if you go onto a smooth surface. Exactly. So the sole, that's the bottom part of the shoe.
And the last part of the shoe that we're going to take a look at, and probably the most important
are the shoe laces. Shoes laces. So shoe laces are basically long pieces of string that you
use to tie your shoes closed because you want your shoes to be tight on your foot. You don't want
to be too loose otherwise it might fall off. Right. And Chuck Taylor's and some other shoes are
very famous for having crazy colored laces or for people using crazy colored laces to tie them up.
Right. So that's the part they used to tie or tighten the shoe with. So on the opposite if
a shoe doesn't have shoe laces, it's probably going to have Velcro. That's right, Velcro or
shoe laces. Okay. So those are all the words that we have for you today. Why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue for the last time?
Hi. I'm looking for a pair of shoes for my son. Sure thing. Here we are. If you're looking for
dress shoes, we have several different styles of Oxford for boys. We also carry athletic shoes,
hiking boots. Oh Jacob, how about these sneakers? Mom, they've got Velcro. Well, then how about these?
What is this style called? They're tennis shoes. They're very popular with teens and young adults.
Oh, Mom, can I get these? What are those? They're Chuck Taylor's. Everyone has them. Can I please?
I don't know. Would they go with your clothes? The backs are really high and the way the tongue just
sticks up. They're almost like a boot and the sold doesn't look like it would have a very good grip.
They're only $45. Maybe I'd call for as an orange shoe laces. Mom, Mom! Okay, try them on.
What size are your feet? Here's the size nine. We'll try a size 43 on you first and see how that fits.
Oh, what? They come in European sizes. He should be a size 43. I'll be right back.
All right, so talking about shoes, you say that you always take a look at the sole. Why is this?
Because I'm always afraid that my shoes are going to wear out and I don't buy shoes very often.
I love sneakers. I love my pumas and I love flat shoes. And so when you buy a pair of shoes,
you really like you don't want to buy another pair in six months. You want to get a pair that has a
really good sole so that will last for a long time. Right, right. Yeah, that's true. I think for me,
yeah, that's probably one of the most important parts is the sole as long as it's comfortable.
Because some souls of some shoes can be very rigid. So it's a little bit uncomfortable to walk with.
And, but I don't know, I don't really have that many pairs of shoes if I think about it.
Well, most people have one fancy pair of shoes for special occasions and then a pair of
work shoes that are leather and then maybe a couple pairs of sneakers and some sandals. Sandals.
The summer. So what you have sandals and you have flip flops or are they the same?
Well, sandals is basically a kind of shoe. It's an open shoe that you wear in the summer.
Flip flops are a kind of sandal. So they usually have a V in the front and that's where you put your
your big toe and the second toe. Yeah, so you wear them in the shower or at the beach.
They're usually made of plastic or rubber so that you can get them wet. Right. But their
sandals are flip flops are a kind of sandal. Yeah, very good. It's very interesting. How many
styles and types of shoes? And actually for men, I think it's not that complicated. But when we get into
women's shoes, then we'll see a lot of different things. There are too many styles. I can't keep track.
All right, so that's all the time we have for today. But we'll see you guys on the website.
If you have any questions, any doubts or if you just want to chat with us, we'll see you at
EnglishPod.com. See you guys there. All right. Bye.