Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco and my name is Catherine
and today we're going to be visiting one of my favorite places I must say.
Really, see you're a big meat eater.
I am. I have to have meat every day so that's why I usually go to the butcher.
Alright so vegetarians be warned today's dialogue is all about eating meat and where to go to
get meat so as Marco said that place is called the butcher's.
So we're going to be visiting the butcher and we're going to learn all the different types of meat
you can find there. Great so we don't have anything to preview but before we get started just
like to mention that you're going to hear a lot of different kinds of words and we're back
in a minute to talk about what they mean.
I'd like half pound of ground beef please.
Good choice. Our ground beef is extra lean if you know what I mean.
Could I also have half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of boneless chicken breast?
No, no, no chicken breasts at the moment but we have some nice chicken dines.
No, that won't do. I'll take this smoked ham you have here.
Okay, is there anything else?
Is this salami and bologna you have here?
Yes, it's very fine meat. Made it myself.
Sounds good. Okay that's it.
Wait, we have tea bowl, ribeye, and sirloin sticks. They are very fresh.
Just came from the slaughterhouse.
No, that's okay really. I think that's all for today.
Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back so this butcher was kind of creepy in the beginning.
Very creepy in the beginning.
I think that's usually the conception that you have of butcher's because they always have a knife
and they're always covered in blood, but it's not human blood.
Right like the movies, we need Todd.
Yeah like we need Todd.
What's your own elite street?
So, but we actually took a look at a lot of different types of meat that the woman was ordering.
So why don't we take a look at these now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay so the first is a classic cut. This is something that we had at my house about once we
growing up. It's called a pork chop. Pork chop.
So a pork chop comes from the animal, the pork or pig.
Yeah we actually don't say pork to me the animal. Pork just means the kind of meat that comes from a pig.
So big difference there when we're talking about food we say pork.
Oh wow and what about a pork chop? So what exactly is that?
Chop is usually just on the bone and oftentimes it's fried.
More baked I guess but it's just a piece of pork on the bone and a chop.
You just imagine a knife chopping something.
Alright so a pork chop very good.
And after pork chops we were ordering some ground beef.
Alright so ground beef is another important one. Ground beef is beef that's been chopped up
and pushed through a machine that kind of pushes it out in very very small bits.
Okay there's no bone. So ground comes from the verb to grind.
Mm-hmm. So to grind up meat to make it very very small pieces.
Right so if you want to make a spaghetti bowl on Yaze the kind of beef you use is ground beef or even
hamburgers. What are you exactly? So ground beef you ground up beef. What are the things
would you grind? Oh you could grind your teeth.
You can grind. Some people do that when they're sleeping and grind their teeth.
You can grind pepper grinders you know pepper sometimes come in balls.
You have to grind them to make them smaller and broken down.
Very good so that's ground beef and from the verb to grind.
Now we are buying some boneless chicken breasts.
Alright so boneless as you have guests means without bones and chicken breasts are usually just
a really nice juicy kind of tender cut of meat from the chicken from the kind of underside
of the chicken where obviously uh yeah they have it. It's not a wing it's not a leg it's just a chicken breast.
Alright so bone this chicken breast. Now usually it is boneless right when you buy it at the
supermarket. Yeah yeah. Next up we've got some classic deli counter favorites. These are our
cold cuts. Alright so cold cuts. Now this means that they are cold. Oh well yeah they're cold
but I think cold cuts the most important thing to remember here is that they're mostly like
kinds of salami or cured meats so these are salt cured or um they're dried meats and you
usually have them on sandwiches so like a salami sandwich. So like cured meat you mean that meat has
it hasn't been cooked. Oh no it's not been cooked but it's treated in a way that allows it to last
for a very long time. Alright so they look like long, long tubes of meat.
They look very dry. So they look very dry like a jerky for example. Alright so cured meat.
Now for example we have salami and uh baloney. Baloney. Now it's interesting because baloney
is actually spelled BOLOG and A so you would say balona balona or something like that.
Well I think comes from the Italian balonia. Right. But it's definitely a change that happened
in the English language when it came over from Italy but baloney is a kind of meat that's
yeah it's got a very funny looking name. Yeah see you're more sophisticated than I am that's why
you know this dude. I just speak Italian. Alright so you have salami baloney and uh bestrami
strami. What about ham is that? Is that considered a cold cut? You can have ham in the
cold cut section because ham sometimes comes in tubes that you slice but ham is also just a normal
kind of pork but ham is cured you know like a smoked ham. Exactly. We're smoked turkey one of my
favorite. Very good and well now moving on from the cold cuts we're going to concentrate on
steaks. Ooh steak so there are a thousand kinds of steaks in this world and every city seems to
have its own kinds but here we're only looking at three the first of which is the T-bone.
Alright the T-bone steak I think is one of the most popular ones definitely. Um it's a steak
it's pretty big right? Yeah well yeah I can't be and it has a bone inside that looks like a T.
Alright so um you're saying Marco that the T-bone is named after the shape and the look of this
steak. Yeah. T-bone steak. Alright and as well as our next one is also a rib eye. Okay so the rib eye
I think actually has a piece of the rib in it so the rib is the bone and there's a circle which is kind
of a it's it's a piece of meat is sliced off the rib and the circle is actually part of that rib
so there's a little bit of bone in it but it's not as bone as the T-bone. Right so it does have
one small bone that kind of looks like a knife because you can see through it and our next
steak has no bone and is the most tender and the best steak you can have sirloin steak.
So I think the sirloin is definitely the most expensive if you're in a restaurant definitely the most
tender I think of all those delicious and usually you can have like a big sirloin steak like a half
a kilo like a 400 grams sirloin steak. At a friend of eight a full kilo really sirloin steak
yeah for is it a competition or no there's a kind of steak called the best steak. I love
your antenna and it'll eat it's the the Florentine beef steak and it is it can be about a kilo of meat.
Wow. Yeah I bet you can't even move after that. No you're you fall asleep with your head
in your soup on the table. All right so that's all the the meat related words that we have for you today
so why don't we move on now to Fluency Builder where we're going to take a look at some of the phrases
in this dialogue. Fluency Builder we're going to look at the phrases if you know it
if you know what I mean. Now I love this phrase if you know what I mean. I do know what you mean.
Well it's I like it too. So you can use it for sarcasm. Yeah. Right or you can use it to kind of
insinuate something right. Exactly. Yeah so you're saying you're saying there's a double meaning
in what I want to say. So there's two things I could say and I'm not going to say it outright but
you know this thing that we can't really say. So for example we can say she likes to go out
if you know what I mean. All right so you're insinuating that not only does she like to go out
but maybe maybe she goes out a lot a lot or maybe she gets drunk or something like that. Yeah so
it's kind of like a double meaning but you're trying to be subtle. Yeah but it's not so subtle
because you're actually saying like this is that what I mean or um she's eating for too if you know
there we go. So you're insinuating that well you're not really insinuating you're telling me that.
She's pregnant. Eating for too is a common idiom and English that means that a person a woman
has a well it's going to have a baby. So here I'm saying hey do you know this idiom? She's eating for
too if you know what I mean. Yeah. I mean, wink wink wink. I'm really great. So now why don't we take
a look at some other examples of how we could use if you know what I mean in different circumstances
when you're trying to insinuate something. Example one. She's eating for too now if you know what I mean.
Example two. Tim hit a home run today if you know what I mean. Example three.
Jim and Laura are going their separate ways if you know what I mean.
All right we're back so um now that that's clear why don't we move on to our next phrase.
So this one is accounting phrase and for those of you who have heard the word doesn't before it
might not be so new the phrase is half a dozen. Half a dozen. So that means half a 12. 12. So it
doesn't is 12. And it's I'm not really sure when this started being used in English but a
dozen is 12 and half a dozen is then six. Now there's another phrase or another saying that's very
common a dime a dozen. He's a dime a dozen. So that means you can get 12 of the same type of guys for
10 cents. Right so they're easy to find. They're easy to find. Yeah. The dime it doesn't. All right very
good and moving on to our last one. When they were talking they said something about the meat being
lean extra lean. Okay lean this is not mean a lean on a door. Right. This is not like resting on
something. This is actually a kind of way to describe food. And so food is lean if it's not got
much fat. It's not fatty. Okay so if it's lean it doesn't have much fat. Exactly so I prefer to eat
lean meats so I often eat birds and poultry so chicken I like it pre-lean and if it's got fat on it
I'll cut the fat off. Okay like the skin the skin is fat right? Yeah. All right so you can have lean beef
it doesn't have much fat around it. Yeah and in America actually on the the packages at the supermarket
it often says the percentage of meat that you have so it's 95% lean or 98% lean. So that means you have
3% fat in there. Exactly. My math skills are amazing. All right so now that we've finished with all of
these words on fluency billet let's take a look at a dialogue for the last time.
Hi. What can I get for you? I'd like half pound of ground beef please.
Good choice. Our ground beef is extra lean. If you know what I mean.
Could I also have half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of boneless chicken breast? No no no
chicken breasts at the moment but we have some nice chicken thighs. No that won't do.
I'll take this smoked ham you have here. Okay is there anything else? Is this salami and bologna you have here?
Yes it's very fine meat made it myself. Sounds good. Okay that's it. Wait we have
tea room, ribeye and sirloin sticks. They are very fresh. Just came from the slaughterhouse.
No that's okay really I think that's all for today.
Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back so Catherine are you a big beef or meat eater? Definitely am. It helps
that my partner and crime is from Kansas City and they have the best among the best sticks in our
entire country in Kansas City. Wow I actually miss there was a back in California we had the
$6 burger from Carl's Jr it was just basically beef bacon cheese it was just like this huge
burger with full of meat and obviously a lot of calories. Okay but it was delicious I'm in Ego
or we are very used to having some meat product every day with our food. Yeah well it was the same
in the Midwest actually from where we're from. It's the same in the Midwest because people in the
Midwest generally think that if you're not eating meat then what are you eating bread?
Corn so meat is considered a healthy part of the day and you definitely eat it with your meals.
Yeah and I'm sure our vegetarian listeners might not appreciate this but you know it's just
kind of different diet some people eat for example rice every day. So we're in other countries you
wouldn't really have rice every day or for example when I was in Chile had a lot of potatoes.
Really? A lot of potato. Have you ever had an Argentine steak I hear they have the best beef in the
world? They are not only delicious but they are very inexpensive and it's amazing you can have a
like a complete steak buffet for like I don't know like it can't even remember but it was just I sat there
for three hours and couldn't move and kept eating. Yeah was it is it true you can eat it with a spoon?
It's so soft. Some of the meat is very very tender and not if it's grilled you can't really do that
but in other preparations it's almost like that. With a nice butter sauce herbs. All right so
you're making me hungry. You've made me hungry I think we're gonna take off and have some burgers.
All right so if you have any questions any comments please come to our website at EnglishPod.com
and we're there to answer any doubts. And we'd love to know what your favorite foods are meat or
otherwise so post something on our website. Hope to see you there soon. Bye bye.