Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we are going to be teaching you a very important technique, especially
for the guys if you want to have good look with the ladies right?
Well today's lesson is called that's flattering.
Right so we are going to be teaching you how to flatter someone.
Okay so what does it mean to flatter someone?
Well basically you're going to be giving compliments and you're going to make that person
feel good about themselves.
That's right.
Okay so flattering.
Now before we get on with this flattering lesson we need to look at some vocabulary
in vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
Alright, on vocabulary preview today we have two small words so the first one is bar exam.
The bar exam.
So the bar exam is that formal test that lawyers must do to become official lawyers.
Right so it's that final exam in order to finally become a lawyer.
Okay and what about our next word?
Well we're also going to hear in the dialogue obnoxious obnoxious.
obnoxious.
Okay so this is an adjective.
Yes and it means something that is really really annoying.
So something can be obnoxious or someone.
Okay very good.
So now we have these two words that we're going to listen to in the dialogue and now let's
listen to two people as they flatter each other in our dialogue.
Valerie.
Hi.
How have you been?
It's been such a long time.
To our lean.
Indeed it's been a while.
How have you been?
How you look amazing.
I love what you've done with your hair.
Really?
Things.
I went to that hair salon you told me about but enough about me.
Okay you got your having it today.
What is your secret?
Come on.
I've been watching what I eat and I work out three times a week.
By the way I heard your son recently graduated.
Yes my little Paul is finally a doctor.
They grew up so fast you know.
He is such a handsome guy.
He gets his looks from his mother of course.
Thank you.
What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
Oh yes she had a beautiful wedding in Cosmol Mexico and we all attended.
Such a lovely girl.
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday.
It's cool.
Well it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
Same here.
We'll catch up soon maybe over coffee.
That would be great.
Give me a cool.
See you soon.
Bye.
Oh I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
All right so this is your typical normal everyday behavior that women show to each other.
I think it's very common.
It's very hard to argue against this because I think everyone does it or at least you've heard maybe your mother or someone to talk to her friends like this right?
So pretend you like a person who you actually hate.
Right you have to be courteous.
Is that what you're doing to me now?
All right no I'm not but we can take a look at some of this great language.
Very rich language that we found in this dialogue in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right we're doing things a little bit different in this lesson.
So we're going to do two fluency builders and in the first one we're going to focus on language you can use to flatter someone.
Right so let's get started.
In the very first part of the dialogue we heard Valerie say,
I love what you've done with your hair.
I love what you've done with.
Okay so if somebody says this basically they're saying,
I like the change you made.
Okay and change not only to your hair right?
It could be anything so I love what you've done with your new house.
Okay or I can say I love what you've done with your garden.
It looks so beautiful.
So something that you've changed you can use this phrase for.
Okay and in this case it's her hair so she is complimenting her on her hair.
We also heard Darlene say you haven't aged a day.
You haven't aged a day.
Okay so now she is saying that she hasn't gotten any older.
That's right.
Two age is to get older.
Okay so this is a very common way of telling somebody you look great.
That's right.
You look young.
You look great.
You haven't aged a day.
All right so then they talk about their kids and they're talking about the sign and they
and Valerie says he's such a handsome guy.
He is such a handsome guy.
Okay so this structure is important because now I can change the adjective.
And I am saying he is very intelligent.
He is such an intelligent guy.
That's right or even this is such a good day.
All right very good.
So now why don't we combine the two phrases that we've just heard.
I love what you've done with and he is such a and let's listen to some examples.
Example one.
We love what you've done with this place.
Such a beautiful room.
Example two.
I love what you've done with your hair.
Such a nice color on you.
Example three.
I love what you've done with this space.
Such a wonderful garden.
Okay I really like how those two phrases can fit together.
Yeah they are very good and now you can use them together or separately like in the dialogue.
That's right.
Now let's move to our final flattering phrase.
Valerie says that Darlin's son gets his looks from the same place.
His looks from his mother.
Right he says he gets his looks from his mother of course.
He gets his looks from.
Okay so when she says he gets his looks from she is saying his appearance.
His positive appearance is good appearance.
Right his good looks.
Okay so now we can change the noun and I can say he gets his intelligence from his father.
Right or even he gets his beautiful singing voice from his mother.
Okay so now typically you would say his mother his father or maybe one of the grandparents.
Maybe yeah but you wouldn't say he gets his good looks from his brother.
No no no no mother father grandma grandpa.
All right so now that we've covered four great ways of flattering someone.
Let's listen to this dialogue again but we're going to slow it down a little bit so you can pick up on these phrases.
Valerie hi wow how have you been it's been such a long time.
Darling indeed it's been a while how have you been how you look amazing.
I love what you've done with your hair really.
Thanks I went to that hair salon you told me about but enough about me look at you got you
you have an interest a day what is your secret.
Come on well I've been watching what I eat and I work out three times a week by the way I heard you're
suddenly graduated.
Yes my little Paul is finally a doctor.
They grew up so fast you know.
He is such a handsome guy he gets his looks from his mother of course.
Thank you.
What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
Oh yes she had a beautiful wedding in Cosimale Mexico and we all attended.
Such a lovely girl.
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday but it's a course well it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
Same here we'll catch up soon maybe over coffee.
That would be great giving me a cool see you soon bye.
I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
Okay so we see a lot of great flattering language in the dialogue but we also have some really good language and phrases you can use in small talk in any situation.
Right so maybe if you talk to a friend that you haven't seen in a while we have some really great phrases for as you say small talk.
So let's look at those now in Fluency Builder part two.
Fluency Builder.
Okay so let's start with the first phrase.
She says Valerie hi wow how are you?
It's been such a long time.
So basically here she's saying we haven't seen each other in a long time.
Right but it kind of gives you that idea that she regrets not talking her for such a long time.
Yes she wishes she could have talked to her.
It's been such a long time how are you?
So a wonderful way to start a conversation.
So when they start talking about their kids Valerie says by the way I heard your son recently graduated.
Right by the way I heard your son recently graduated.
So this phrase by the way I heard blah blah blah blah is really really useful.
Right let's take a look at the first part by the way.
So this is a way to to connect to different ideas or to start a new topic.
Exactly and now when she says I heard your son recently graduated.
So we use this phrase I heard when we've got information that we're not sure about.
Right or also you are demonstrating interest about a certain topic or a news event that you would like to know about.
Right and so basically you're asking the other person tell me about this.
Right so I can say hey by the way I heard you got married.
So then I tell you all about my wedding.
Exactly.
Okay so this is a very common way of talking to someone or getting some more information from a person.
So let's listen to some more examples of by the way.
Example one.
By the way I heard you recently been promoted.
Example two.
I heard your daughter just had a baby. Congratulations.
Example three.
Oh I had you just go back from holiday and France.
All right now since these two ladies don't like each other very much.
They want to end the conversation right?
Right they want to end the conversation and well you want to end it in a polite way right?
So they use a really great phrase here.
They said it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
So it's like well it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
So it's been great talking to you.
I've enjoyed talking to you.
Right so this is a very polite very subtle way of saying hey I have to go or
Yeah by I can't talk anymore.
Yeah when you say that you know that the conversation is ending.
Exactly.
Now she says I have to get going.
What does it mean get going that doesn't make much sense?
Basically it just means leave.
Okay I have to leave.
I have to get going.
You should get going you're going to be late.
Exactly.
Okay.
So really good small talk phrases that are useful in any situation.
So why don't we hear them again one more time by listening to the dialogue.
Valerie.
Hi.
Wow how have you been?
It's been such a long time.
It's a lean indeed it's been a while.
How are you being?
How are you look amazing?
I love what you've done with your hair.
Really?
Thanks.
I went to that hair salon you told me about but enough about me.
Okay you got you haven't either today.
What is your secret?
Come on.
Well I've been watching what I eat and I work out three times a week.
By the way I had your son recently graduated.
Yes my little Paul is finally a doctor.
They grew up so fast you know.
He is such a handsome guy.
He gets his looks from his mother of course.
Thank you.
What about your daughter Pamela?
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
Oh yes she had a beautiful wedding in Cosmol Mexico.
I mean all attended.
Such a lovely girl.
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday.
It's really cool.
Well it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
Same here.
We'll catch up soon maybe over coffee.
That would be great.
Give me a cool.
See you soon.
Bye.
Oh I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
All right very good.
Now you have a couple of phrases that you can use to flatter someone, be it your friend or
somebody that you know or anyone.
Well they are very, very useful and if you use them correctly of course.
And these phrases sound really honest and really natural.
Very native like.
Okay so if you have any other questions or comments or if you want to share some other phrases
that you use to flatter people come to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave them in
our comments section.
So Marco and I have to get going but we're looking forward to seeing you on the website.
Thanks for listening and until next time.
Bye.