Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine. Welcome back everyone. So what are we talking about today, Marco?
We are going to the flower shop.
Okay, so this is an intermediate level lesson and we're going to be learning about the different kinds of flowers you can buy at a flower shop.
And so we've got a guy here who's probably trying to say something to someone he loves.
Yeah, I think he did something to his girlfriend or wife.
And well, that's the typical thing, right? You do something wrong so you got to get her flowers.
And that's why women are often very nervous when their husband or boyfriend gives them flowers because she's thinking,
what did he do? What did he do wrong?
Alright, so let's listen to the dialogue and move to the action.
Hello sir, how may I help you? I would like to buy some flowers, please. Something really nice.
I see. May I ask what the occasion is?
It's not really an occasion, it's more like I'm sorry.
Very well. This arrangement here is very popular among
web-grateful husbands and boyfriends. It has a dozen long stem red roses with a couple of
some flowers and a single orchid that stands out. It includes a small teddy bear to achieve the
effect of immediate forgiveness. I think I'm going to need more than just a dozen red roses in a bear.
What else do you recommend? Well, this is our, I'm sorry I cheated on you package.
Two dozen red roses lined with tulips, carnations and lilies. The fragrance and beauty of this
flower arrangement is sure to make her forgive you. I don't think that's going to cut it. I need
something bigger and better. I'm sorry sir, but what exactly did you do? Well, I may have
accidentally insinuated that she is getting chubby. Get out of my store you jerk.
All right we're back so what do you think is this really like a bad thing to do?
Heck yeah. No really? Well no one wants to hear that someone thinks they're fat. Okay and
chubby is maybe not as bad as fat, but the guy could have been a little bit nicer. All right so we'll
we'll give our listeners some advice towards the end of the lesson. So now why don't we take a
look at all the flower names in language takeaway? Language takeaway. Okay this first flower is a
beautiful one and it has delicious seeds that people like to eat that's called a sunflower. A sunflower.
All right so that's a yellow flower right? It's bright yellow and in the middle is orange and the
stems are very very long and thick so it's a tall flower. Okay sunflower and yeah as you mentioned
some people eat sunflower seeds they're like the little salty one that's right they're really good.
All right next is an orchid. Okay an orchid is a beautiful flower and they're often grown just one
at a time and people collect orchids so these can be very very expensive. They're very expensive.
And they come in all shapes, sizes and colors. Okay an orchid. Now what about a tulip?
A tulip is another pretty flower and I think they're most famous in Holland for their tulips
because this actually used to be the kind of money that they would use. This was their currency
for many years. So they used to use tulips. They used tulips and the tulip flower is kind of like a
it's like a champagne glass. It's tall and it's kind of empty in the middle. Oh that's interesting
so next time somebody says do you think money grows on trees and Holland it literally did?
Well yeah almost almost. All right what about a carnation? Okay carnation is another pretty
flower and they come I think in red pink and white. Yeah I mostly seen white carnations. Yeah and
um you know flower giving there's a whole definition. Not to it right so yeah every flower is
symbolic of something red roses are for love and carnations I think are generally
friendship or either friendship or like when someone die I'm not sure.
Well you can give them somebody's past away. Really. I'm not sure I have to look it up but
carnation is another very very common flower that you'll see in many different colors. Okay and the
next flower is also really common it's a lily. All right a lily is a beautiful flower and usually
you see these on water so water lilies for examples is another name you might hear. Okay a water
lily or just a regular lily and next we have the most common of all the flowers but we've had a little twist
to it it's a long stem rose. Right so rose everyone knows rose by any other name with smell
a sweet Shakespeare wrote a lot about roses but in this case uh which I'm a long stem roses and we
talked about this with sunflowers. The stem is the green part that grows out of the ground and you
think of the flower as the head and so the stem is actually the connector between the ground
and the flower. Okay so these types of roses have a really long stem so they're very nice to like
maybe give them you've one of them away. That's right and you see for example at the opera you see
singers people throw these roses at them and they pick them up and they're so long the stems are
so long and they collect them in their arms and so that's a long stem rose. All right interesting
okay why don't we listen to our dialogue for the second time let's keep a look out for these
flower names and their pronunciation and we'll come back in a little bit.
Hello sir how may I help you? I would like to buy some flowers please something really nice.
I see may I ask what the occasion is? It's not really an occasion it's more like I'm sorry.
Very well this arrangement here is very popular among were gretsful husbands and boyfriends
it has a dozen long stem red roses with a couple of sunflowers and a single orchid that stems out
includes a small teddy bear to achieve the effect of immediate forgiveness. I think I'm going to need
more than just a dozen red roses and a bear what else do you recommend? Well this is our I'm sorry
I cheated on new package two dozen red roses lined with tulips, carnations and lilies the fragrance
and beauty of this flower arrangement is sure to make her forgive you. I don't think that's going to
cut it I need something bigger and better. I'm sorry sir but what exactly did you do?
Well I may have accidentally insinuated that she is getting chubbier. Get out of my store you jack.
All right we're back so in this dialogue we had a lot of interesting phrases so let's look at them now
in fluency builder fluency builder. A lot of these phrases Marco have to do with well what the guy
did wrong. Get to the dialogue and so the first one is to cheat on. So the woman offered him the I'm
sorry I cheated on you package right so it's like an arrangement of flowers that usually people buy
when they cheated on their boyfriend or girlfriend. Right and so in this case to cheat on means to
see another person so if you're married to a woman seeing someone else you know having a date
or romantic encounter with another person is cheating on your wife. So you're cheating on your wife.
And you used it like this cheat on right. Cheat on so he cheated on her or they were both
cheating on each other. Okay so it's a cheat on not a good thing. Not a good thing. All right so he was
explains to her that wasn't enough the arrangement wasn't enough and he said I don't think that's
going to cut it. Well okay you've probably heard the word cut before but in this case Marco
we're talking about to be able to cut something to cut it so that's not going to cut it or it's
not going to cut it. It's not going to be enough. Exactly so that's not quite what I'm looking
for it's not enough. He wants bigger and better. He wants more. And so for example we could say
you know what this dessert's not going to cut it we need something much fancier.
Okay so to be good enough for. Okay so to be good enough for. All right very good and then he
was explaining to the shop lady what happened and he said well I accidentally insinuated.
Okay to insinuate is to suggest so I could say hey you're really chubby that's not an insinuate
and that's a statement but I could say well you're looking a little bit round the side that's an
insinuation because I'm suggesting without saying something indirectly right exactly and he was
insinuating that his girlfriend was getting chubby. Chubby so chubby chubby yes. In this case
we're talking about being round or a little bit overweight. Right so it's not really saying fat.
No if that is rude. Chubby you know it's just a little bit extra pounds. Yeah like maybe you
had a little bit too much ice cream over the past couple months. All right very good so why don't we
listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be back.
Hello sir how may I help you? I would like to buy some flowers please something really nice. I see
may I ask what the occasion is? It's not really an occasion it's more like I'm sorry. Very well
this arrangement here is very popular among regretful husbands and boyfriends. It has a
dozen long stem red roses with a couple of some flowers and a single orchid that stands out.
Includes a small teddy bear to achieve the effect of immediate forgiveness. I think I'm going to
need more than just a dozen red roses and a bear. What else do you recommend? Well this is our
I'm sorry I cheated on you package. Two dozen red roses lined with tulips,
connations and lilies. The fragrance and beauty of this flower arrangement is sure to make her
a gift for you. I don't think that's going to cut it. I need something bigger and better.
I'm sorry sir but what exactly did you do? Well I may have accidentally insinuated that she is
getting chubby or get out of my store you jack.
All right so if you make a mistake like as a guy you could flowers here girlfriend. What about women
giving flowers to guys is that common? Do you think that's possible? Can you do that?
I'm sure you can do it but I don't know if it's as common. I think as a guy I wouldn't really
feel comfortable receiving flowers. Really? I mean I would be touched by the gesture and I would
be like oh that's really sweet but like flowers is a little bit too feminine I think. Generally I think
it's one-sided thing so you can get flowers for your mother or you can get flowers for a friend or
if someone you know passed away you can get flowers for their family. Right but in a romantic
situation rarely do you get flowers to a guy? So if you want to say I'm sorry to a guy what do you give him?
Season tickets to his favorite football. Man that works.
Or a game for his playstation or
offering a new coat of paint on his car. I don't know. Have you never given a gift to somebody like
saying I'm sorry? No. No. You don't make mistakes. I like to use my words.
Ah that's good. Yeah this is kind of interesting. Why don't we do this? So why don't we give
gifts to people as a token or as a demonstration of our our our regretfulness? Well can I get personal
for a second? I was just thinking about this in terms of engagement so why do people give a ring
when they get engaged? So it's like it's because people like things that glitter you know it's like
distract the woman and she'll say yes. And so it's the similar thing with with flowers and
for giving it forgiveness you say oh gosh these flowers are so beautiful. Of course I forgive you.
Oh they're so pretty and they smell so you know it's like it's like distraction from the matter at hand.
Right. Oh maybe that's it. I don't know if you disagree with me please. It was the very
wise man who invented this. Absolutely. All right so if you have any questions doubts or comments
please come to our website englishpod.com and we'll see you guys there. Bye everyone. Bye.