Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very dangerous lesson for you guys.
That's right today we're going to talk about guns or specifically about weapons.
So yeah we're talking about kinds of guns. There are more than I think I ever knew and we're
going to discuss about six today but before we get going, Mark we've got a phrase in a vocabulary preview.
That's right so today on vocabulary preview we're going to take a look at shooting range.
Have you ever been to one of these places? Yes a shooting range. It's a place like you say
and it's a place where you can fire your weapons or you can use guns safely. So you don't
kill anyone or you don't hurt someone. Now basically yeah it's a place to practice shooting.
So maybe for example if you want to practice how to shoot guns you go to this place and they have
special things to help you improve your shooting abilities. Usually these are very very secure.
They have guards and things because you don't want to give the guns out to anybody. That's right.
But let's listen to today's dialogue about a shooting range and find out what kinds of guns they have.
Hey Nick, what are you up to? Not much. Just had no over to the shooting range. You want to come?
Seriously? You mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man.
Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's
really fun too. They have big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim.
Yeah that would be cool. Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a
shotgun. Maybe even a rocket launcher or an anti-tag missile. Or what about a flame thrower?
Whoa take it easy there Rambo. Don't get carried away. These weapons are not toys and you must
first learn how to handle them properly. There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe.
For example never handle a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure there isn't
anything in the chamber and never put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot.
Wow I didn't know. It always looks so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know
running and firing a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
All right we're back so obviously this guy was very excited about using these weapons and
you may have heard that we're using this word weapons. It's basically all of these things. I guess
anything that can be used in defense or hurt someone. Yes anything that can be used to hurt someone
as a weapon. So a knife can be a weapon not just guns. Guns are kind of weapon. That's right so
taking a look at our first type of gun or our first type of weapon we have a 9mm pistol.
Okay so the weapon is the pistol and the pistol is basically a handgun but it comes in
different sizes so that's what the 9mm refers to. That's right that's the size of the projectile
that will come out of the weapon and a pistol as you say it's a handgun it's usually small and
it can fit in your hands so you can use just one hand to use this weapon. Okay so there's a
similar handgun that's a little bit bigger that's called a revolver. That's right a revolver so
this one has a revolving chamber so you kind of see this in the old Western movies when
they have six bullets right? I like swing their guns into their side holsters. Yeah.
Well yeah that's right the revolver refers to the well to revolve it means to move around to spin
that's right. And so the the place with the bullet basically spins after you shoot the gun.
That's right so that's why it's called a revolver unlike the pistol the pistol will usually
not really have a revolver will have a magazine. Okay now moving on to our next type of weapon
we have the very famous machine gun. That's the one that shoots off really fast so basically it's
called a machine gun because it's it's automatically releasing all of these bullets at one to just
pull the trigger and many many many bullets come out. That's right so in a pistol or in a revolver
usually you have to press the trigger and once and it shoots only once but in the machine gun you can
keep it pressed and all of these bullets will start flying out. Very very dangerous. Very dangerous okay
so now moving on to the next one we also took a look at a shotgun. Okay this is well this is not
the biggest gun we're going to talk about today but it's a very large gun very long and you have
to use two hands to hold it. This is what you usually use when you go hunting right? That's right so
as you say it's very long and it's very loud and it doesn't really shoot bullets, it shoots
little pellets, little cartridges that are filled with little rocks for example and that's what it
shoots and this is why it's not very precise like a like a machine gun or a handgun but it does a
lot of damage. Absolutely and what's something else that does a lot of damage? Our next gun will
do that. Well this guy got a little bit excited and he said he wanted to use a rocket launcher.
Okay so you know what a rocket is? A rocket is something that's basically a projectile that goes into
the sky and can basically blow up big buildings or cars. That's right and that's what a rocket
launcher is. Now maybe you've heard of the word bazooka. A bazooka is a type of rocket launcher.
The one it's very very wide and it's circular and you usually see it in movies like Rambo we talked
about where the Rambo will hold it on one shoulder. It's so big and the rocket shoots out and
can destroy huge buildings. That's exactly right so that's why it's called a rocket launcher.
Now for our last type of weapon we have a flame thrower. Okay well a flame refers to fire so
fire has flames those are the parts that kind of come up on a fire that read and orange.
And a flame thrower is a device is a weapon that will shoot flames not bullets. Exactly.
It was very popular back in in World War II to actually shoot the flame thrower into bunkers
or into holes because then you know this is how you can get people out of there and I think
flame throwers are used now to some sort of degree like to fumigate sometimes or to burn
weeds when you're in a field. Right they're not really used as weapons anymore. Although I think
I've seen a number of them in action movies. Really yeah in action movies of course. So we have a lot
of guns a lot well a lot of different types of weapons. Why don't we go back to the dialogue?
Let's listen to it again and we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
Hey Nick what are you up to? Not much just had no over the shooting range you want to come?
Seriously you mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man. Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol
that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's really fun too. They have big targets
of the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim. Yeah that would be cool.
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun. Maybe even a rocket
launcher or an anti-tag missile or what about a flame thrower? Whoa take it easy there Rambo.
Don't get carried away. These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them
properly. There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe. For example never handle
a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber
and never put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot. Wow I didn't know.
It always looks so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know running and firing
a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at our phrases that we've picked out for you on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So this first phrase comes from the beginning of today's dialogue when
Nick is saying well I'm not doing much I'm just heading over to the shooting range. That's right
so we know what shooting range is but when he says I'm heading over to the shooting range.
Well this can be confusing because to head over has nothing to do with the head on your body.
Right. It means I'm going towards some place. I'm going to this place.
So it's just another way of saying going to right. So for example you can say I'm heading over to
my friend's house this afternoon. That's right so I'm going to my friend's house this afternoon.
But remember that this is a pretty relaxed, pretty informal way of saying something so you wouldn't
say I'm heading over to work. Do you say hey I'm heading over to his house to hang out
I'm heading over to the pizza restaurant to grab a bite to eat. That's right okay so now obviously
we saw that one of the guys got very excited about the idea of using all these cool weapons
and this friend said whoa take it easy their rambo don't get carried away. I love this phrase
uh this phrase is something you say to someone who is maybe too excited about something.
That's right. It means don't go crazy. Don't exaggerate. Right so maybe at the shooting range
they'll have a revolver and they'll have a pistol but they're probably not going to have a rocket
launcher or as he said an anti tank missile. These are crazy weapons from movies and so the
friend is saying no you're you're exaggerating don't get carried away. Now for example maybe you
go to the mall and you go shopping and maybe you got a little bit carried away and you spent
too much money. That always happens to me doing holidays like a carried away and I buy way too much
stuff. That's right so that's the way that you would use carried away and now for our last phrase
uh he was actually explaining a couple of rules of weapon weapon handling and he said that there
are some rules that he has to abide by. Okay so this is a fixed phrase we use the the verb to abide
with word like the rules so to abide by the rules or we must all abide by the rules. This is a
fancy way of saying to follow the rules or to recognize the rules and that's right so you have to
abide by the rules of your school or maybe you have to everyone has to abide by the law.
Right or some people can say there are rules in the Bible that other people abide by. That's right.
Okay so a lot of great stuff um I think we've taken a look at a lot of different types of weapons and
phrases so pretty interesting stuff why don't we listen to it for the last time.
Hey Nick what are you up to? Not much just had no over to the shooting range you want to come?
Seriously you mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man. Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol
that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's really fun too. They have big targets
that the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim. Yeah that would be cool.
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun. Maybe even a rocket
launcher or an anti-tag missile or what about a flame thrower? Whoa take it easy there Rambo.
Don't get carried away these weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them properly.
There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe. For example never handle a weapon
that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber and
never put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot. Wow I didn't know it always
looks so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know running and firing a weapon
is a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
Alright we're back so I'm talking about weapons and pistols and all this has
have you ever used one of these? Have you ever? I have. I have been to a couple of shooting
ranges and have fired a couple of guns. I've never fired a shotgun. They don't usually
well sometimes they have guns. I've shot pistols before and did you like it?
I like it. It's an interesting activity. I don't know how I feel about
using guns on people but I understand why hunting is an enjoyable sport because
there is a sport aspect to it you really have to control your body and
you can improve you can get better like darts but with loud guns.
It's very hard to aim actually to hit something people think it's very easy
like in the movies. Well and I think it's particularly hard with handguns because
there's a kick. You don't realize it the first time you shoot a gun you're like oh
that was way harder than it looks. I bet you're a good shot right?
Yeah yeah I've always really enjoyed weapons and my aim is alright although my
eyesight kind of I need to use glasses so it can be a little bit tricky sometimes.
Especially when you shoot a weapon sometimes it's very you just cleaned it so it has a lot of
oil and it'll kick out into your face and get your glasses wet. Well that's why we use goggles
at the shooting ranges but I'm curious to know have you guys ever shot a gun before have you ever
been to a shooting range or shooting ranges legal in your country? Yeah some places are not.
Yeah so let us know our website is englishpod.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.