Hello English learners, welcome back to another podcast with us here at English Pod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're going to be looking at a very popular topic something that everyone
has to do at least once in their life. That's right, we're talking about mobile phones and getting
a mobile phone plan. Right, so you have a mobile phone, you need to get a plan or you need to do something
in order to make it work, right? Yes, and in this lesson we're going to learn some language
to help you do that. Alright, so let's start with the language on vocabulary preview.
Very cablory preview. In the dialogue, we're going to compare two types of mobile phone
plans, the prepaid plan and the monthly rate plan. Okay, so we have two types of plans,
prepaid. prepaid plan. Okay, prepaid plan. Well, a prepaid plan, basically, just like the
name suggests, you pay before you use the minutes. So you maybe you have to buy a card and then
you can use maybe 20 minutes or 30 minutes or 100 minutes. Exactly. And then when you run
out of money or you use all your minutes, you can buy another card and like that. Yeah, but
the monthly rate plan is different. So the monthly rate plan you have to pay each month. Right,
at the end of each month. At the end of each month. And what do you pay? You pay for everything
you used. You get a bill at the end of the month. Exactly. Okay, so very interesting. These are
the ways that mobile phone plans usually work. And well, now it's time for us to listen
to this dialogue for the first time. We are going to be listening as a shopper is looking
to buy maybe a mobile phone or get a mobile phone plan.
Yeah, I just moved here and I'd like to activate my cell phone. And I'm not sure if I should
go with a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan. I see. Well, can I have a look at your phone?
And fortunately, this phone can't be using the US. It's not compatible with our 3G network.
What? Really? I don't really want to have to buy a new phone. Well, you're a look. You see,
if you sign up for our 3-year plan, we'll throw in a hand set for free. Really? What's the
cat? There's no catch. You just choose a plan, sign a 3-year contract, and that's it. Actually,
we're running a special promotion right now. And we're giving away a blackberry curve
with our special mega value for it all our plan. So what is this plan include? Well, you
get 900 anytime minutes and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile calling to other
tell-mobile clients, a thousand text messages per month and unlimited evening and we can
minutes. Oh, and we also offer a roll-over option. Wow, all this for $40 per month. That's right.
Plus the activation fee and the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee and oh, and any
charges for extra minutes. And...
Well, it sounds like a lot more than $40 doesn't it? This is very common. They always say
that it's a very low price and they always have these hidden charges. Right? Yeah, you're right.
So why don't we look at some of the language they were using in the dialogue now in language
takeaway? Language takeaway. All right, a language takeaway today. We're going to be looking
at for very basic words that are used in this whole mobile phone context and the first
one is activate. To activate my cell phone. All right, so you have to activate your cell
phone. That's right. You have to make the cell phone work. So basically you make it work.
Now can you only apply this to mobile phones? No, there's many things that you must activate
to make work. For example, you must activate your computer software. Okay, or maybe you
have to activate your credit card. Or activate your bank account. So usually you do this for the
first time before you start using it. Yeah, like imagine your mobile phone is sleeping, right?
And you need to activate it to make it start working. But you only do it once. Right. Only
what? Okay. We talk about mobile phone or we say the cell phone, but this also has a specific
name, right? That's right. A hand set. Hand set. A hand set. So the device, the phone,
you can call it a hand set. Exactly. All right, a very easy word, but it's kind of a little
bit more technical. Yeah. Now, one of the things they were talking about with this monthly
rate plan was a roll over option. Roll over. A roll over option. So what is this roll over
option about? Well, okay. I'll give you an example. Let's say you have 500 minutes each
month. And you only use four of them in this month. 100 of those minutes can roll over.
It can move over to the next month. So now you have 600 minutes. So basically the minutes
that you don't use, you can still use the following month. Right. Okay. So that's a roll
over plan. And we might recognize the verb to roll over, right? Right. So it's very similar
to physically move from one place to another. Yeah. All right. Roll over. And now in the end,
we talked about many types of fees. That's right. Activation fee. Okay. Or we also had
emergency services fee. So what is a fee? A fee is the amount of money you must pay
for a service. Okay. So this is important. It's for a service. Yeah. You can't pay a fee
for something you can touch. Okay. So if I go to the store, I don't say what is the fee of
this bottle of water. Right. What's the fee for filling this bottle of water? Okay. So
for a service. Yes. We're in action. All right. Very good. So I think it's time for us
to listen to this dialogue again. We're going to slow it down because it was a little
bit fast. And then we'll come back and look at some great phrases. Hi there. Can I help you?
Yeah. I've just moved here. And I'd like to activate my cell phone. And I'm not sure if
I should go with a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan. I see. Well, can I have a look
at your phone? Unfortunately, this phone can't be used in the US. It's not compatible
with our 3G network. What? Really? I don't really want to have to buy a new phone. Well,
you're in luck. You see, if you sign up for our three year plan, we'll throw in a handset
for free. Really? What's the catch? There's no catch. You just choose a plan. Sign a three-year
contract. And that's it. Actually, we're running a special promotion right now. And we're
giving away a blackberry curve with our special mega value $40 plan. So what does this plan include?
Well, you get 900 anytime minutes. And you can also enjoy free mobile and mobile calling to
other tell mobile clients. 1000 text messages per month. And unlimited evening and weekend minutes.
Oh, and we also offer a roll-over option. Wow. All this for $40 per month. That's right.
Plus the activation fee, the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee. Oh, and any charges for
extra minutes. And... Well, you know, there are some interesting phrases in this dialogue. And,
you know, a lot of them can be used when you're talking about an negotiation or a contract or a deal.
All right, great. So let's take a look at these phrases in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. The first phrase that we have on fluency builder today was the problem
that she had with her mobile phone was that it wasn't compatible with a three-g network. Okay.
To be compatible with. To be compatible with. To be compatible with. Now, this word compatible
means that it works well with something else. Exactly. Now, there's a lot of things that you can use
this phrase compatible with together with. You know, people, things. So why don't we hear a few examples now?
Example one. Our application is compatible with most smartphones.
Example two. My roommate and I are just not compatible. All she ever does is study. And I like to
say a blatant party. Example three. I'm sorry. Your computer is not compatible with our software. It's too old.
Okay. Great example. So compatible with very clear end. It's very useful. That's right.
Now, what about the next phrase? Well, you know, the the girl was hearing about all of these great
things that are included in the contract. And she asked what's the catch? What's the catch? What's the catch?
So she was asking for the catch. What is the catch? Well, good thing you ask. A catch is something
negative. Something that's hidden that makes the deal seem not so great. Okay. So if somebody
offers me a new car, that's that you can have this new for free. Okay. Well, that seems too good to be
true. So what is the catch? The catch is that I can only drive it at night. Okay. That's kind of annoying.
Right. Yeah. So that's the catch. There's like a condition. Yep. Now, she asked about the catch.
And well, she said, well, there's no catch. You know, it's you just signed the contract. And then the
salesman told the lady that she is in luck. You're in luck to be in luck. Well, okay. I think that I think
we can really understand the meaning. Right. When you're in luck, something lucky has happened. Right.
You're having good fortune. But how do we use it? So maybe you're looking for a very special
bottle of wine for dinner tonight. Yep. It's very rare. Okay. And you go into this little store
and all of a sudden, you're in luck. You found it there. Exactly. Okay. This phrase is actually
most commonly used in the second person. Your in luck. You are in luck. You are in luck. You
are in luck tonight. Yeah. And it usually when someone asks you for something, then you say,
you're in luck. You're in luck. I have it. Or you're in luck. I have the very last one. Exactly.
All right. And now to end a fluency builder, we have one more phrase. And so it was when the salesman
said, we'll throw in a handset for free. All right. To throw something in. So if you sign the contract,
he will throw in a free handset. It means to include something for free. Okay. So you can say,
if you buy this house, I'll throw in the dog. The dog for free. Right. So to throw into
include for free. Right. Okay. All right. So great phrases. And I think we understand them now. So
let's listen to this dialogue for the very last time.
Yeah. I just moved here and I'd like to activate my cell phone. And I'm not sure if I should go with a
prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan. I see. Well, can I have a look at your phone?
Unfortunately, this phone can't be using the US. It's not compatible with our 3G network.
What? Really? I don't really want to have to buy a new phone. Well, you're luck. You see,
if you sign up for our 3-year plan, we'll throw in a handset for free. Really? What's the cash?
There's no cash. You just choose a plan, sign a 3-year contract. And that's it. Actually,
we're running a special promotion right now. And we're giving away a blackberry curve with
our special mega value, $40 plan. So what does this plan include? Well, you get 900 any time
minutes and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile calling to other tell-mobile clients.
A thousand text messages per month and unlimited evening and weekend minutes. Oh, and we also
offer a roll-over option. Wow. All this for $40 per month. That's right. Plus the activation fee
and the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee and oh, and any charges for extra minutes
and mobile phones. This is very common in the United States, right? These monthly plans.
Yeah, most places where I have lived. It's much more common to pay as you go, right, to have a prepaid
plan. But in the States, almost everyone goes with the monthly plan. Maybe it's because,
in order to have a monthly plan, you need to have a credit card. You might be on to something.
Right? Yeah. So if you don't have a credit card or maybe you're 18, you can't get a monthly plan.
So you got to do this prepaid plan. Yeah. You know, another interesting thing that I've noticed
when living in different countries and seeing mobile phone habits. Americans and North Americans
respond very differently to a ringing mobile phone and other people do. How so?
For example, if I was in a meeting in America and my phone rang and I answered it,
people might think that I was very rude to answer the phone in a meeting. But you know, here
when we're living in China, it's totally normal. It's, you know, everyone does it. That's the
polite thing to do. Answer your phone. Right. And I think that's absolutely true and maybe it's
because in North America, you have this voicemail option for your mobile phone. Yeah, and everyone has it.
Everyone has it. So if it's something very important, then the person will leave you a voicemail
message and then you will know what it's about or you can call them back. But here, I guess,
or in other countries, maybe they don't have that option. So they need to answer every call.
Yeah. It's, it's interesting. An interesting sort of cultural difference in the way we use our phones.
But what about listeners in your country? Do you answer the phone immediately or do you let it ring?
Right. Or maybe do you see who's calling and maybe just not answering? Yeah. Screen your calls.
Screen a call. So come to our website, englishpod.com. Let us know what your mobile phone
habits are and also if you have any questions or doubts. Yeah. Marco and I are always there to
answer your questions. So until next time, thanks for listening and goodbye. Bye.