Hello English learners, welcome back to another great lesson here at EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we are going to have a lesson that is going to be very useful when you arrive late
Yes, well we all have arrived late to something and we need a good way of saying sorry and saying why we were late
So today we're not only going to be looking at vocabulary used to explain why you are late but also some
typical excuses of why people are late Right so some normal reasons for saying why you're late
Well why don't we get started with the dialogue now we're going to hear five people in the dialogue
So at the beginning we'll hear the boss and the assistant and then we'll hear three people who are arriving late
Where is everyone we're supposed to start 15 minutes ago
Joe Colton said she'd be here in a sec she said she got tied up with a client
Sorry I'm late everyone oh there was a huge traffic jam on the highway this morning
morning everyone were you stuck in traffic as well Jess there was a huge pile up on the highway
And traffic was backed up for miles
Scotch is called and said that he's running late his last meeting ran over but he's on his way now
Guys, this is not acceptable if I say the means starts at 10 the meeting starts at 10 not 10 01 and
Definitely not 10 20 all right, let's get started
So the first thing I want to talk about is I'm sorry everyone I know him late, but really it's not my fault
I was in a coffee at Starbucks and the line was way way too long. I was waiting for 20 minutes to get my coffee
All right, so well good excuses in general except the last one I don't think that's such a good excuse of
Why you're late right? Yeah, I don't really think if I was the boss
I would be very happy with this employee. Yeah, I don't think coffee is that important
But some of the excuses were good and some of the language they used to describe the excuses was really great
So let's look at that now in in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right on language takeaway today we have four words that we're gonna be looking at and while let's get started with the first one
So Joe called the office assistant and explained that she will be late because she got
Tied up with a client to get tied up so I got to tie up with a client. All right, this is a really common reason for being late
But why don't we listen to some examples to help us understand what it means
Example one
Sorry, I'm late honey. I got tied up at the office
Example two
I
Was tied up on the phone all afternoon and didn't get any work done
Example three
I got tied up and traffic on the way here
All right, so if you get tied up it means that you get busy with something that you can't avoid
Right, you're busy with something that's so important. It's like you are tied by a rope to that thing
Okay, I got tied up. I'm sorry. I got tied up. Yep, all right now the first person that arrived to the office will explain that
There was a huge traffic jam on the highway a traffic jam a traffic jam a
A huge traffic jam now we understand traffic right cars a lot of cars. Yeah, so a jam
It means that it was like block it was stopped. It was stopped. Yeah, there were a lot of cars on the highway and they weren't moving
So a huge traffic jam is a very very big stopping of cars now our next word explains why sometimes there is a traffic jam
We found out that there was a huge pile up a pile up a huge pile up. Okay a huge pile up now if a pile up is another way of saying an accident right?
Yeah, an accident with many cars and they all get piled on top of each other all right, so
Many cars got into an accident. Yep, so this could be a reason of why there was a traffic jam
And also a reason for why you were late
All right now the other person Scott also called and he said that he's running late. He's running late. He's running late. I'm running late
Now if I'm running late, it might actually running somewhere. What what am I doing? What's happening?
You are going to be late and you know you're going to be late. Okay, I know I'm going to be it
So I'll call you and I'll say hey, I'm running a little bit late. Yeah, actually this is the most common thing I say when I'm gonna be late
And I think it's really important to know how to use this phrase. So let's hear some more examples
Example one
Jane is running late. She'll be here in 10 minutes
Example two
Traffic is really bad. So I'm running late
Example three
I'm running a bit late, so please start without me
All right
Perfect so running late a very common way of explaining that you're going to be late and well it makes you sound very native
Yeah, it's a great phrase now our last phrase what we heard the reason why Scott was running late was because his last meeting ran over
Okay to run over my meeting ran over now ran over my meeting ran over it means at point two far
Well when something runs over it goes longer. Okay longer than expected. Yeah, so a meeting can run over or
An appointment can run over so I can say my meeting ran over 15 minutes. I'm going to be a little bit late. That's right a great excuse
Very good five great words and well I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue and
Understand these words as they were used in the dialogue and then we'll come back and take a look at more phrases
Where is everyone you were supposed to start 15 minutes ago?
Joe called and said she'd be here in a sack. She said she got tied up with a client
Sorry I'm late everyone. There was a huge traffic jam on the highway this morning
morning everyone were you stuck in traffic as well Jess? There was a huge pile up on the highway and traffic was backed up for miles
Scotch is called and said that he's running late his last meeting ran over but he's on his way now
Guys, this is not acceptable if I say the meeting starts at 10 they're meeting starts at 10 not 1001 and
Definitely not 1020 all right
Let's get started. So the first thing I want to talk about is are I'm really sorry everyone
I know him late, but really it's not my fault. I was getting a coffee at Starbucks and the line was way too long
I was waiting for 20 minutes to get my coffee
Okay, we got some some more great phrases for describing being late. Let's look at them now in fluency builder
Fluency builder
When Joe called she said she'd be there in a sack. I'll be here in a sack. I'll be here in a sack
So when someone will be here in a sack it means they'll be here very soon. Okay, I'll be here in a sack
I'll be there in a sack. But what about this word sec? It's a short way of saying second
So SEC now it's an exaggeration obviously because you won't be there in in one second
But you're just explaining that you'll be there very very soon
What about the difference between I'll be here in a sack and I'll be here in a minute
Well if you say I'll be there in a sack it means like I'll be there in one minute, right?
But if you say I'll be there in a minute it could be a minute or more like three or four or five minutes
Yeah, I think that's true now again going back to this traffic issue we saw that somebody was stuck in traffic
To be stuck in traffic. I got stuck in traffic now when you're stuck in traffic you can't drive
Because there are too many cars stopped on the highway so you are actually in the traffic
Yeah, yeah, you're stopped there for like 20 minutes. You can't move. Okay. I'm stuck in traffic
I'm going to be late. Mm-hmm really great excuse and the reason they were stuck in traffic was because traffic was
Backed up for miles. Okay traffic is backed up for miles
To be backed up for miles now if I say the traffic is backed up for miles it means that it's very long
Or how it how does that work? Well, okay, imagine there is an accident and that has caused a traffic jam
And the cars are lined up for for many miles behind you. Okay, so it's backed up from that point
There are many miles of cars waiting to pass. Yep, so it's backed up for miles. Very good. So great phrases
And I think it's appropriate for us to listen to the dialogue for the very last time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this being on time issue
Where's everyone we're supposed to start 15 minutes ago
Joe called and said she'd be here in a sec. She said she got tied up with a client
Sorry I'm late everyone. Oh, there was a huge traffic jam on the highway this morning
Morning everyone. Are you stuck in traffic as well, Jess? There was a huge pile up on the highway
And traffic was backed up for miles
Scotch is called and said that he's running late. His last meeting ran over, but he's on his way now
Guys, this is not acceptable if I say the means starts at 10. The meeting starts at 10 not 1001 and
Definitely not 1020. All right, let's get started. So the first thing I want to talk about is
Sorry everyone. I know I'm late, but really it's not my fault. I was doing a coffee at Starbucks and the line was way way too long
I was waiting for 20 minutes to get my coffee
Oh
Marco, I know that ideas about time and ideas about being late are different in different countries
Yeah in different countries people treat time or being on time in different ways
Yeah, like I'm from Canada and I look at being on time really different than you do, right?
Yes, because for example if you call for a meeting at nine o'clock
Usually people will be there at nine o'clock because the meeting will start in America
Right in America now for example Latin America we do have this what we call sometimes the Latino time or a
Fanning time which is like nine o'clock is like the time that everyone should be there, but
Until people get there get their coffee and whatever then it'll be nine 15 maybe up to nine 30 and I think it's a little bit even more
Noticable when when we're talking about social events like if you go to someone's house for for dinner in Canada
If they say come to my house at six o'clock for dinner you'll be there at six o'clock right?
Okay, yeah, yeah, usually it'll be there only a couple of minutes
After the time that was specified just to you know
Give the house owner a little bit of time. Yeah, but if we have a dinner invitation for six we know that it's not really going to begin eating at six
So people will get there at six 30 or seven and of course food isn't ready until like maybe eight or nine
Hmm, but in German countries from what I know
You've got to be if they say be there at six you're there at six
00 right not six a one and also I think it's about
When people start work right yeah, I'll on time you have to begin work
Sometimes is acceptable to be 10 or 15 minutes so called late, but in other places, you know
Yeah, North America if you're supposed to start work at nine you have to be at your desk working at nine
Yeah, see that in in in other countries people get there at nine get their coffee
Maybe take a quick glance at their email got the newspaper and then you know start working it around nine 30 or 10
So I guess the important thing is to know
What the tradition is in the country where you are exactly so come to our website English pod.com
And let us know how it works in your countries. I know that many different countries have a different way of treating time
So share it with us. Yes, and remember if you have any questions
Please ask them at the website as well. We're out of time today, but until next time. Thanks for listening and goodbye. Bye. Bye