Hello English learners, welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we're back bringing you another great lesson and an intermediate lesson
That's right about one of my favorite subjects
We're talking about food exactly
So on this occasion we're gonna be talking about food
So let's preview some words on vocabulary preview
Very vocabulary preview
Alright, we have three words for you today
And the first word is head chef head chef head chef head chef
So what is a head chef? Well in a professional kitchen
This is the boss of the kitchen or the leader of the kitchen okay so the head chef is the
The main cook yes, but he doesn't cook he but he doesn't cook okay all right
So if he doesn't cook who's one that does the cooking that brings us to our second word
Souschef
Souschef S-O-U-S
So the S is silent because it's like a French word. Yeah, something like that. Okay, so the sous chef is the second in line to the head
Yeah, he's the number two number two
So he's basically the one that's doing some of the work yeah in the kitchen. Yeah
Now let's take a look at our last word cuisine cuisine cuisine
So this is an interesting word. What exactly does it mean? Well it basically means cooking right okay
Like the art of cooking so for example I can say French food yeah or French cuisine
French cuisine which includes all the food yeah and this is also the major that people study in college to be how much chef
Yep, you study cuisine and cuisine is a noun right it's a noun. Okay, so I think we're ready to dive into our dialogue
What exactly is going on? Well we're in a restaurant and it's a really busy night and so we're going to listen to what is happening in the kitchen
God wait sure your order will be ready shortly
Jean Pierre we have another special for table saver. I'm working as fast as I can we're willing to eat
Where is my ship look I need you to peel more potatoes marie
Chop someone yarns and cows for the stew
From here another special we're really packed tonight we're running low on wine
There's already left in the salon
Oh sorry I'm late everyone. Wow we're really doing well tonight. Hi
Top-to-king and get a very yeah I need some so steered and the fish needs to be butchered and butterde
Okay, how money? Jean Pierre table saver has requested to see the chef. I think there are food critics from cuisine magazine
Okay, so a busy night here at this restaurant. I know it sounds like there's a lot of pressure on this chef
Yeah, yeah, you can you can tell in his voice that he's really stressed out. Yeah, okay. Let's take a look at some of this kitchen vocabulary that we found in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right well we've got five words for you today
In the first one is peel peel peel
Peel
E-e-l
So this is a verb and it means to remove the outside skin
Okay, so for example when you're gonna eat a banana you must peel it first you must peel it
You gotta take away the yellow skin
What else do you peel oranges potatoes potatoes like in the dialogue?
What else can you peel? I don't know carrots
Carrots some people peel their tomatoes. I don't know why yeah, it is kind of weird
All right now let's take a look at our next word chop chop chop chop chop
So again another verb and it means two it means to cut food into pieces
So if you're gonna eat carrots first you got a chop the exactly right you can put a whole carrot in in your suit and your suit
in your rice. Yeah, okay chop
Okay our next word
Sturd yeah, this is the past participle of the words stir
Okay, so the verb stir stir
So when you stir something imagine you have a big pot
And you've got a long spoon you move the spoon around in circles
Okay, so you're stirring the pot you're mixing
Hmm to stir is very similar to mix. Yes, okay. So you just move the food around move the food around
Okay, our next word butchard again the past participle of the verb butcher okay butcher butcher
Now
This a verb to butcher something
It's when you remove all the bones and all the organs from the meat exactly so you cut up the meat
And this is interesting because it's also a noun right a butcher is a person who cuts up meat. Okay, so so it's really easy a butcher
Butcher's meat. Yes, all right our last word butter butter
Butter butter
Okay, so butter this is weird. I know
Normally we all know the the noun butter, but here it's acting as a verb. Okay, so when you butter something you spread or put butter on it
Okay, so to put butter on something so you can butter a piece of bread exactly or in this case the fish is being buttered
Sounds delicious
Okay, now we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the second time
We're gonna slow it down a little bit so it's easier to understand
Right away, sure your order will be ready shortly
Jean Pierre, we have another special for table seven
I'm working as fast as I can we are really in the weeds
Where is my sushi if look I need you to peel more potatoes
Marie
Chaps of onions and carrots for the stew
I said I'm a table as a name I'm a
Jean Pierre, an awesome special we're really packed tonight. We're running low on wine. Is there any left in the salad?
Whoa, sorry. I'm late everyone. Wow. We are really doing well tonight
Ari, stop talking and come over here. I need to so stir the end of fish needs to be buttered and buttered
Okay, I'm on it
Jean Pierre, table seven has requested to see the chef. I think they are food critics from quasi-models rate
Okay, so that seems to be a little bit better and hey, I noticed that there's a lot of really great kitchen words
And here are like words that you commonly hear in a professional kitchen. Okay, so let's take a look at these kitchen words in fluency builder
Fluency builder
All right, we've got three phrases and the first one is in the weeds in the weeds in the weeds
In the weeds so when you're in the weeds you're so so busy and you can't do all the work you need to do on time
Okay, so in the weeds it means that you're really busy. Yes, and you can't finish everything and you can't you have too much to do
Okay in the weeds. Okay, our next word running low on running low on
Running low on running low on
Okay, so before we get into explaining what running low on means let's listen to some examples
Example one
You better look for a gas station. We're running low on fuel
Example two
We're running low up beers can you go out and get some?
Example three
My flashlight is running low on battery hurry up before it gets dark
So basically running low means
You don't have much of this left you don't have much of something left. Yeah, so here they're running low on wine so basically
There's not much wine left right so as we heard in the examples you could also be running low on fuel for example in your car
etc running low on all right and now let's take a look at our last word doing really well doing really well
We are doing really well doing really well so the seems to be like a pretty simple
Structure I mean me know all these words, right? So why is it special? Well basically if you say I am doing really well
Maybe it sounds a little bit difficult to understand what are you doing really well
So this is a great way of answering a question when somebody says how are you or how are you doing you can say
I'm doing really well
Or I'm doing well in your life everything is good in your life things are good and you're happy basically
But in this situation in the dialogue what's doing really well? Well the restaurant is doing really well
The business is doing really well so when he says we're doing really well
Business is good good. They're making lots of money exactly
So you can use it with people you can use it with businesses you can say oh I'm doing really well in my new job
Yeah, or my son is doing really well in school. Yep, okay, so you can use it in in those different ways
All right, well let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be able to hear all of these great words and phrases
We'll be ready shortly
Don't worry sure your order will be ready shortly
John pair we have another special for table seven I'm working as fast as I can we're willing the weeds
Where is my ship look I need you to peel more potatoes
Marie chop someone yarns and cows for the stew
What's your business?
From here another special we're really patched tonight. We're running low on wine. Is there any left in the salon?
Sorry, I'm late everyone who are we're really doing well tonight. I
Tupter King and get a very yeah, I need some so steered and the fish needs to be butchered and butter
Okay, how money?
John pair table seven has requested to see the chef. I think there are food critics from cuisine magazine
So Marco do you think this chef had a rat under his house?
That was a really good movie. Yeah, I had a two-year that Disney picks our um where a rat is a cook
It's interesting. I love to cook but I'm not very good at cooking really
But it's good because for me it helps me relieve stress
Me too actually, you know if I'm in a bad mood
I go home and cook something to eat and the world seems a happier place
And people don't understand it because they think cooking is work. Yeah, but you know for some people it's fun
So what about you guys what do you like to cook? Do you have any particular dish that you prepare very well?
And if you do please send us the rest of it
Exactly because we know that we have listeners from all over the world and of course we want to know what type of food you prefer
So come to EnglishPod.com and post your questions your comments and your recipes
In our community section and Erica and I will always be there
Yes, to test out your recipes as well as answer questions for sure if a good recipe comes along
We'll prepare it and we'll let you know how it turned out. Yeah, all right guys we're out of time
But we'll see you next time until then goodbye