Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod, my name is Marco
and I'm Erica
and today we're bringing you the second part of Christmas Chronicles
Another Christmas lesson to get you in the Christmas spirit
Christmas and useful language for all of our listeners today
That's right, in today's lesson we'll be learning some great Christmas vocabulary
and police-related vocabulary as well
Now Christmas, police vocabulary how exactly does that fit together?
Well, they don't
But here at EnglishPod we can make anything happen
So that's why we have done this to be creative, to be creative
So let's take a look at our vocabulary preview for this lesson
The vocabulary preview
In today's vocabulary preview we've got two words from our dialogue
that you will need to know to understand this dialogue
The first one is elves elves elves elves and this is the plural of the word elf right
So elves are little people little people with pointy hats with pointy hats
Sense is helpers
Okay, so elves elves are next word is candy cane candy cane candy cane candy cane
So a candy cane is a traditional Christmas candy right?
Yes, it's red and white and kind of shaped like a like a jay like a jay
Okay, so like very traditional yeah, you hang them on the tree and you eat the Merry Christmas time
He's like peppermint. Okay, well, I guess we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the first time
And it's gonna be kind of fast, but don't worry if you don't understand everything because we'll come back and talk about some of the language later
It's gonna stay
Really, thoughts you can't take me to jail don't you know who I am Chris Kringle, you know
Pop in the world, per no-one Bob in the toilet, shung that all right, yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before haven't we Joe
Yeah last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy. Can you believe that?
That's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit? What will happen? We're all children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts on their stockings
Sorry buddy, you're part in a no-pocking zone you were speeding and you have no ID
Side's at even if we let you go now your slaves been impounded and those reindeer were taken to the city zoo
What this is unbelievable
What's this world coming to Christmas is ruined?
What's that up ahead? It looks like
Ells
Whoa there are shooting candycains
Mate, hey, mate, we're under heavy attack we need backup
Okay, so Santa has escaped from the police car a thank God
It's like a war over there. They were really firing everything. I know I mean those elves are
Aggressive very aggressive
Okay, well we can take a look at some great vocabulary from this dialogue why don't we start with our language take away for today
Language take away
In today's language take away we have five really important words that we hope you will take away from the lesson
Exactly and the first word that we have today is book
Booked booked booked booked booked is another way of saying arrested arrested yet the slang word, hey
It's kind of slang. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's a slang word. Okay next word
Speedings speeding speeding
speeding so Santa was speeding because he was
Going too fast driving too fast. Yeah, going over the speed limit exactly
Third word today is
Impounded
Impounded that's when your car gets arrested your car gets arrested
Yeah, they take your car to car jail
Okay, so my car is in car jail. I think I understand it's impounded
Okay, so the police take my car and I have to
Pay to get it out. Okay, let's move to our next word
ruined
We have a few examples for us to listen to to understand the meaning of this word
Example one
It's been raining for five days
Alfocation is ruined
Example two
Look at this hole you've ruined my favorite pair of jeans
Example three
Sam you've been called stealing from the company your chances for a promotion are ruined
Okay great examples and basically ruined of means destroyed destroyed yeah messed up messed up okay
Now for our last word
Back up
So now for our last word
Okay, so now for our last word and language takeaway
Back up back up back up back up
So backup is help help yeah, right? So when you call for backup you call for help
Yeah, you see it all the time and war movies police call for backup. Yeah, right? I think though
It's important to point out that here the pronunciation and stress of this phrase is really important, hey
Yes, yes, you have to say backup backup backup yeah, so both words are stressed at about the same level, hey
Back up because if you were to stay back up that means to move back exactly. Yeah, it's different so backup
Back up yes the stress is important. All right well, you know what? I think with those words in mind
It's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time
Really fellows, you can't take me to jail
Don't you know who I am
Chris Kringle, you know
Papnawell, Pernawell
Bob and the Tully, Shandana, right?
Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before having we Joe
Yeah last week we booked this guy who claimed to be the truth fairy can you believe that
Ha ha ha
It's Christmas Eve and I have all these presence to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen when all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts in their stockings?
Side buddy you will parked in a no parking zone you were speeding and you have no ID
Besides that even if we let you go now
Your sleigh has been impounded and those reindeer were taken to the city zoo
What this is unbelievable what's the world coming to Christmas is ruined?
What's that up ahead? He looks like elves
There's shooting candy kings
Mayday mayday we are under heavy attack we need backup
Okay, so without the sound effects and without any noise
I think it's much more clear now, right a little less dramatic a less dramatic but good language yes
Speaking of good language there's some great phrases I want to look at in this dialogue and so let's do that in putting it together
Put your hands together
We have two phrases in putting it together that we want to show you how you can use in many different situations
In the dialogue we heard this
Last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy
So when you claim to be something you're saying that you are something but it might not be true, right?
Right so for example you can say this woman claimed to be your wife
But she's not but she's not okay. We have a few other examples of how you can use the phrase claim to
Example one
Daniel claimed to be the son of a government minister, but later we found out that he was lying
Example two
The criminals came to have a gun
Example three
This man here just claiming to know your father
That's such a great phrase just by putting it together with another verb
Mean something different but still expresses that same idea right claim to have
She claimed to have a baby or something. Yeah, okay, okay, so let's move to our next phrase
Under heavy
Under heavy so when the dialogue they said we're
Under heavy attack right you can also use this phrase in a couple of other ways
Example one
We're in the heavy attack
Example two
We're under heavy fire
Example three
The prime minister isn't the heavy security
So if you're under heavy fire means that there's a lot of fire like gun fire gun fire
Yeah, not like fire fire
Yeah, okay, and if you're under heavy
Security it means that you have a lot of security a lot of body guards or a lot of
Right like a prime minister a president will be under heavy secure exactly okay
Couple of great phrases really good phrases and with this we can listen to our dialogue a third time
You
Really thoughts you can't take me to jail don't you know who I am Chris Crangle you know pop in the world
Perino well Bob of no taller sure not all right. Yeah. Yeah. We've heard that one before haven't we Joe?
Yeah last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy. Can you believe that?
Haha
It's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen? We're all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts on their stockies
Sorry buddy your partner no parking zone you were speeding and you have no ID
Besides that even if we let you go now your sleighs been impounded and those reindeer were taken to the city Zoo
what
unbelievable. Once this world coming to Christmas is ruined.
What's that up ahead? It looks like...
Ells! Whoa, there are shooting candycains!
Mayday, mayday, we're in her heavy attack! We need backup!
So, Marco, the police mentioned something about the tooth fairy.
The tooth fairy. I don't know. Maybe some of our listeners don't know the story about the tooth fairy.
So, can I go ahead and say it?
Yes, go ahead. Okay, well, when you're small and you lose the tooth.
Your baby teeth. Yeah, you put it underneath your pillow.
Uh-huh. And then you go to sleep. And then in the night, the tooth fairy comes into the house.
Flies into the house, sneaks under your pillow, takes the tooth and puts money there.
Ah, I see. So, this is a story that parents tell their kids about what happens to their baby teeth.
And they get money exchange for it. Right, so it gets it takes away the sadness of losing that tooth.
Yeah, yeah. But in South America, for example, we have the tooth mouse.
The tooth mouse. Yes. Okay, mouse.
What is it called in Spanish?
Well, in some places it's called ratoncito peris.
Uh-huh. Like, it has a last name, peris.
Oh, really?
Uh, in other places it's just called ratoncito, raton, which means mouse.
Okay, so it'd be like tooth fairy Smith.
To be a tooth fairy Smith.
And it's the same thing. It's the little mouse that comes in and steals a little tooth from you.
And leaves money in exchange.
Cool, very cool. Yeah.
So we go from Santa Claus to Guns and Wars to the tooth fairy.
Only yet English pod. Exactly.
All right, guys. I hope you enjoyed today's lesson.
If you have any questions or comments about the lesson, please visit our website, EnglishPod.com.
All right, well, we're out of time. We got to go. We've got some Christmas shopping to do.
Yes, Christmas shopping. So, we'll see you guys later.
And until then, it's goodbye.