Hello everyone and welcome to English Park. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have another episode in our series all about small talk.
That's right. Today we're going to take a look at a work setting where two colleagues may be
run into each other and they talk very briefly about something.
Alright, so let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Hi Michelle. Do you need to use the photo cover here?
Oh hi, Jeremy. No, please go ahead. So how are you Jeremy?
I was talking to Linda about you only last week.
Oh, I'm fine. Thanks. I'm super busy with work actually.
Did you hear about the loss in contract?
No, tell me more. Well, I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the
head of loss in last week. And, and hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday
fingers crossed. That's great news, Jeremy. Congratulations.
Anyway, I must get back, but give my regards to your wife Monica.
I will, Michelle. Speak to you soon.
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at some vocab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word for you guys today is photo copier. Now this is something that's very
common in offices. That's right. A photo copier also known as a copy machine or just a copier.
Yeah, this is something that you use to print on paper or to copy paper. So if I have a document,
but I want another copy of it, I put it on this machine and through it will copy it and print it out.
That's right. So those are the ways that you know this machine by this name either photo
copier, copy machine or just copier. All right, but after that we have a very interesting
adjective. This is something that we use very often in spoken English. The phrase here Marco was,
I'm super busy, but what does it mean to say you're super something? That's right. So when we
add the word super to an adjective, we mean that we're very, very, very busy. Super busy.
All right, so I'm super hungry. That means you're very, very, very hungry. All right, or I'm super
woman. Also, it means that you are a very much a great woman. All right, like superman is very good
it going fast and doing things. And so he's super, means great or exceptional. So in this case,
I'm exceptionally busy. That's right. And moving on to the next line where Jeremy says that he was
discussing the contract with Bill. So a contract, we know what this means. Yeah, what is this?
So a contract is a document and it's something that you have to have two or more groups for
or two or more parties. So Marco between you and me, we could have a contract, says that
when we come to record you will be respectful of me. That's right. And then we will both sign.
So it's kind of an agreement between two, as you said, or more people and
but you are promising to respect the contract and to do what the contract says.
And if you don't do what the contract says, we have a special verb. We say you broke the contract.
So to break a contract. That's right. Well, Jeremy was discussing the contract with Bill and
they said they met the head of Losins. Now Losins is a company that we're just using for the
dialogue. But what does it mean the head of this company? Okay, if you think about the company as a body,
the head is the top. And in this case, that would be the president or the manager or the leader.
It's the most important person. Okay. So we can also use this in our offices, for example,
the person in charge of marketing, the director of marketing. We also call him the head of marketing.
Or the head of the head of the sales division would be the manager of the sales team,
or whoever's most important in sales. Another very common example I think is the president,
many times they call him the head of state. Yeah, the head of state. So you can have a dinner with
many heads of state. And those could be kings or queens or presidents. Very good. All right.
So that's all the vocab for language. Take away when we take a short break and listen to the dialogue again.
Hi, Michelle. Do you need to use the photo copy here? Oh, hi, Jeremy. No, please. Go ahead.
So how are you, Jeremy? I was talking to Linda about you only last week. Oh, I'm fine. Thanks.
I'm super busy with work, actually. Did you hear about the Lawson contract? No, tell me more. Well,
I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the head of Lawson's last week.
And, and hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday, fingers crossed. That's great.
News, Jeremy. Congratulations. Anyway, I must get back, but give my regards to your wife, Monica.
I will, Michelle. Speak to you soon.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So there's a great phrase here in fluency builder that we use more trying to be
polite in English. Michelle says, oh, hi, Jeremy. Please go ahead. Okay. So, Jeremy asks if
she needs to use the cop the photo copy or he said, no, Jeremy, it's okay. Go ahead.
Please go ahead. Okay. This literally means you go ahead of me, but in reality, she's basically saying,
I can wait. You go first. So if you're going into a building and somebody opens the door before you,
and they say, please go ahead. That means they'll hold the door and you can go inside first.
So please go ahead. This is a very polite thing to do. And if you're in line and you see someone
is in a hurry, you can say this to them. Please go ahead. All right. Very good.
Please go ahead. And we also going back to the contract discussed about confirming the deal.
Okay. All right. So you have a deal or an agreement or a contract. But the thing you do to make sure
that you all agree is you confirm. So this means you want to make sure it is actually going to happen.
And you can actually combine confirm with many different things like you can confirm your tickets
to go to Italy. Or can we confirm those holidays before I make my my bookings? Because I want to go to Italy.
Exactly. So you confirm something and then Jeremy said a very strange phrase here.
Fingers crossed after talking about the deal. Okay. So fingers crossed is an interesting phrase.
It doesn't mean okay. Now go cross your fingers. But it's something we save to be superstitious
because it means basically I hope so or hopefully. Because fingers crossed when you cross your fingers
in many Anglo-American cultures, you are saying that you hope something will happen. It's to bring
good luck. All right. So oh gosh. I really hope it doesn't rain today. And then I say fingers crossed.
Yeah. Well, fingers crossed it doesn't. That means that we hope it doesn't. But now that you said
that maybe it will. Right. So it's kind of a superstitious belief that people have that if you cross
your fingers it will bring good luck or what you say will happen. Will happen or won't happen.
That's right. fingers crossed. All right. So let's take a break now and listen to our dialogue one last time.
Hi Michelle. Do you need to use the photo copy here? Oh hi Jeremy. No please. Go
ahead. So how are you Jeremy? I was talking to Linda about you only last week. Oh I'm fine. Thanks.
I'm super busy with work actually. Did you hear about the Lawson contract? No. Tell me more.
Well, I was discussing the contract with Bill and he said that they met the head of Lawson's last week.
And and hopefully they're going to confirm the deal on Wednesday fingers crossed. That's great
news Jeremy. Congratulations. Anyway, I must get back but give my regards to your wife Monica.
I will Michelle speak to you soon. So this is a very common scenario in a very in an office in
a normal office setting where maybe you meet your friend at in the kitchen or the water cooler,
the photo copy. And you have very small brief conversations. That's right. And you're often going
to hear this called water cooler talk because you don't want to have a long conversation about
something really deep at the water cooler. But you do want to talk about basic things things that
you have in common or work stuff, you know, how's that paper coming along or how's that?
I heard you had great sales last week. And so these are great short things you can talk about with
your colleagues. Right. Very good. And as we say, it's some of the phrases in the vocab are key
things that you can use to start up a small conversation, very brief to talk about, you know,
small things with your colleagues. That's right. So we hope that you'll tune into our future lessons
about small talk. And if you have any questions or comments, you're welcome to find us on EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.