Hello everyone, welcome back to another podcast here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica. And today we're looking at another one of our lessons for English of the past
decades and this time it's the 1990s. Well you know the 1990s is a little easier for most of us to
remember. Yeah I guess it's a little bit more recent we're going to be looking at a lot of language that
is still used today. Most of these words and phrases are still used today so they're going to be
very useful and you're going to sound a lot more native. Mm-hmm a lot cooler as well.
Huh? Right so before we get started with this lesson why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview?
Very cablory preview. We have two words we're going to hear in the dialogue. Now the first one is
a mall. A mall. M-A-L-L mall. All right so a mall is basically short for shopping mall.
And a shopping mall is a big building with many stores inside. Right so it's like a shopping center.
And our last word for vocabulary preview is gain. The gain. The gain. Okay so a gain is a group of people right?
Yeah it's a group of people you can call your friends the gain. We're going to go out with the
gain tonight. Yeah. Now we sometimes hear this word to have and it has a negative meaning right?
Right like street gain. Yeah so people who are who fight and deal drugs and all that sort of stuff.
Right so it can have a negative and a positive meaning so but it just depends on how you use it.
Yeah but in the dialogue we'll hear it with the positive meaning. Right so that's all the words we
have for vocabulary preview. Let's listen to this cool and hip dialogue from the 1990s and we'll
come back later and explain some words.
Hey, for eyes. What's up man? How have you been? Not bad. Just went to the mall and picked up some
check out my new adidas. Those are dope. You are going to be getting mad drops from the gang man.
Anyways have you seen Betty lately dude don't even go there. That girl started tripping because I
went to the movies with Veronica the other day. I was like look you knew how I was before you got with
that's right you're such a play man dude there's mad max let's go say hi
Max was I are you okay you look like you just saw ghost I got an effort English class my life is over
dude you're over it you need to lay off the books for a while and have some fun come on let's bounce
where are we going oh crap my dad's gonna go post when he finds out about this. I'm gonna open
the can of what's on you if you don't come with me right now okay okay G.
Well it sounds like this guy's got some problems at school huh yeah he got an F on his paper but
you always can count on your friends to try and cheer you up by doing something yeah but they use
some really great phrases and vocabulary words so why don't we look at those now in language takeaway
language takeaway all right on language takeaway we're gonna be looking at five words and
well let's start with the first one so the guy was talking about his really cool new shoes his new
adidas right and his friend said those are dope dope dope okay so it's pretty easy to understand
when something is dope it's really awesome it's cool yeah it's great right it's great so that's dope
and it's an adjective right so his friend said those are dope and he said you're gonna be getting
mad props from the gang okay so mad props we can divide this word into so let's take a look at
the first part mad mad so we understand that mad is angry right yeah but it can also mean a lot right
amazing or really so if I say you have mad skills you're really good at something or you can say
she has a mad amount of shoes all right so he's going to get mad props now props is like
respect or compliments yeah so so his shoes are so cool that he's gonna get a lot of respect
or a lot of compliments from his friends exactly mad props so they started talking about girls
and he mentioned that this girl started tripping tripping tripping so two tripping right as you
notice it's tripping it doesn't have the G at the end which isn't really grammatically correct but
that's kind of the way it's pronounced yeah we we would never say the G right so if somebody is tripping
they're they're getting really upset they're getting really angry right they're causing trouble
so why don't we listen to a couple of examples of how we could use tripping for different situations
example one Lian was tripping because I got dirt on her car
example two even though I apologize for calling her fat Gini was tripping all night
example three he sent me 43 text messages and call me about 20 times that guy is tripping over me
okay so that's pretty clear tripping all right now moving on to our next word
they wanted to go somewhere and he said come on let's bounce let's bounce let's bounce I'm gonna bounce
now uh bounce basically means it's leave yeah let's get out of here but we might be more familiar
with this this word as in like a ball right a ball bounces off the floor exactly so I guess it's
kind of the same you kind of bounce off the floor and leave that place yeah let's bounce okay so
for a final word now this guy who got a bad mark on his his paper he was nervous about what
his dad would say right right because his dad was going to go postal he said my dad is going to
go postal to go postal now if you go postal it means you go crazy yeah you really freak out
you go you get very angry yeah like really angry this word comes from the 90s because during
a time it was very common in the United States that postal workers melman were going a little bit
crazy and you know they started shooting people and delivering some strange packages well I guess
so people who work in the post office maybe don't have the most exciting jobs and that drive them a
little crazy exactly that's what and but now they have a term named after them all right so why don't
we listen to our dialogue for the second time we're gonna slow it down a little bit and then we'll come back
to surprise what's up man how have you been not bad just went to the mall and picked up some joke
check out my new adidas those are dope you are gonna be getting mad props from the gang man
anyways have you seen Betty lately dude don't even go there that girl started tripping because I went to
the movies with Veronica the other day I was like look you knew how I was before you got with me
that's right you are such a play man dude there's mad max let's go say hi
max was ah are you okay you look like you just saw ghost I got an F and English class my life is over
dude you're over it you need to lay off the books for a while and have some fun come on let's bounce
where are we going oh crap my dad's gonna go post when he finds out about this I'm gonna open
the can of what best on you if you don't come with me right now okay okay geez
okay so I think that was a little easier to understand you know we've got a lot of pretty strange words and
phrases some interesting slang yeah and I want to take a look at this slang now so let's get started with
fluency builder fluency builder okay so the guy with the new shoes he asked his friends have you
seen Betty lately right right and the his friend replied don't even go there right he was like
dude don't even go there don't even go there so what does he mean when he says don't even go there
he means don't talk about it I I don't want to talk about it right don't even touch that subject don't
even mention it right so if somebody wants to talk about a topic that you think is sensitive or
you don't want to talk about us to say hey don't don't even go there so Marko what do you think
about the new tax law don't even go there I don't even want to talk about politics okay so I
think that's that's a really actually quite helpful phrase to avoid talking about an uncomfortable
subject right so he said don't even go there and he started talking about the girl and she was
tripping and then he said something interesting he said I was like look you knew how I was before
you got with me yeah I really like this phrase now I want to focus on the first part I was like
I was like I was like now you might hear a lot of native English speakers use these three words
before they start telling you what they said so it's like saying I said or I told him yep so
this actually is really common especially with people under the age of 30 so why don't we
hear a few more examples of how it's used now example one this guy caused a car accident I was like
you idiot you can kill people by driving like that example two and then I was like I hate you
and she was all like I hate you more example three I told a teacher that I didn't finish my
homework and he was like I'll see you after school so if you're telling a story or you're maybe
talking to somebody and you want to explain what you said you can say I was like hey what are you
doing and she was like what so you can have an entire dialogue based with I was like she was like
we were like huh okay so I was like it's super super useful so now our next word now they saw
their friend who got the bad marking in school and the guy said dude get over it get over it get over it
so if somebody tells you to get over it stop worrying about it okay or stop thinking about it all right
so if somebody is sad because maybe his girlfriend broke up with him you would say get over it
and stop thinking about that it go it's in the past yeah and you you commonly use this for
when somebody is upset about a small thing something they shouldn't worry about get over it yeah
now what are you going to our final word at the end of the dialogue they said I'm going to open
a can of what pass okay so to open a can of what pass on somebody to open a can of what pass
so again let's break this down before we explain it okay I think we have to take one step back here
to whoop someone's ass is to beat them up right to to punch them and hurt them right so to
whoop somebody's ass so if I open a can of what pass what does that mean it means you're going to
beat them up so it's just a funny very informal way of saying like in this can I'm going to
open it and I'm going to start hitting you or something like that some sort of small man it's going
to jump out of the can and start hitting you exactly but it's never literal it's not like you're
actually going to beat somebody up it's just kind of like a joke yeah empty threat yeah all right so
some really interesting words and phrases in this dialogue I think we should listen to it for the last
time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more about this great decade
hey for eyes what's up man how have you been not bad just went to the wall and picked up some
joke check out my new adidas those are dope you are going to be getting mad props from the
gang man anyways have you seen Betty lately dude don't even go there that girl started tripping
because I went to the movies with Veronica the other day I was like look you knew how I was before
you got with you that's right you're such a play man dude there's mad max let's go say hi
max was ah are you okay you look like you just saw ghost I got an epic english class my life is over
you're over it you need to lay off the books for a while and have some fun come on let's bounce
where are we going oh crap my dad's gonna go post when he finds out about this I'm gonna open the
can of what's on you if you don't come with me right now okay okay G
well Marco in the dialogue I heard one of the guys say what's up but he said it in a really
strange way didn't he yeah exactly he said what's up okay so what what's up with that so in the
90s it was popular instead of saying what's up you would just kind of double BS and just say what's up
and then it became very famous with a TV commercial for a certain beer and actually I remember
this commercial during the the Super Bowl they had this big commercial where everyone was saying what's
up in this really strange way right it's still used today informally between friends you'll go
hey hey what's up and what's up yeah yeah so that commercial made it actually quite cool and
in famous to talk like that actually in Spanish pod they have a show called getbasa which is like
the translation of what's up and they start each show with like saying getbasa but it's exactly the same
so maybe it will become popular in Spanish maybe but I guess only a time will tell yeah that's right
all right so really cool stuff and as we heard typical music from the 90s and another interesting
thing was the nicknames for eyes mad max very popular among young kids hmm so remember if you
have any questions about this language or anything else about this lesson come to our website at
englishpod.com right you can leave all your questions in comments there and we hope to see you guys there
so thanks for listening and until next time goodbye bye
you