Hello English learners welcome back to English pot my name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today we're bringing you part four of our romantic series called I'm sorry I love you
Yeah and today we've got some drama I don't we we got a lot of drama and we got a lot of useful
language yeah we're gonna learn some phrases we can use to describe a mistake and we're also going to
learn how we can comfort someone we can make them feel better okay exactly so in our dialogue today
Veronica and her boyfriend are on a break right so what does it mean to be on a break well it means you
stop having a romantic relationship for a short time so you can say we are on a break so we're not dating
we're not dating oh we don't date all right all right all right all right we could say let's take a break
so we've got the state on a break and the action take a break take a break okay let's take a break okay
so let's listen to our dialogue and it's gonna be a little bit fast and the girl I think she's crying
so it'll be a little bit difficult to understand but Marco and I will come back in a minute
and we'll talk about some of the difficult language here
so so I said let's take a break and since that night I've been waiting for him to call but I still
haven't heard from him you don't think he's seeing someone else do you come on don't be so dramatic
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine you think so oh no how could he do this to me
I'm sure he's cheating on me why else wouldn't he call but you two are on a break
theoretically he can do whatever he likes he's a love of my life
I really mess this up come on hun pull yourself together it's going to be all right
but I I still love him and it's all my fault I can't believe how immature and
self-result being I mean he is a firefighter it's not like he can just leave someone in the
burning building and meet me for dinner I'm totally messed this up you know what Veronica I
think you should make the first step I'm sure he'll forgive you no this is not going to happen I
I'm ruined everything hey do you hear something
I'm sorry it's your lovely firefighter
Wow that's a romantic boyfriend singing in the street yeah yeah that's amazing have you have you ever
done that for a girl um no have you have you ever sung to a girl and KTV I've sung to a girl and KTV
and karaoke karaoke yeah so but not so much as an undistrict with all the neighbors coming out to
see me well okay well I don't blame you all right let's take a look at the language that we saw in
our dialogue on language takeaway language takeaway all right so let's take a look at our first word
seeing someone seeing someone seeing someone seeing someone so if I'm seeing someone you're dating them
I'm dating them yeah I'm frequently going out with that person right so but it's not very serious
no it is serious but not really it's more of a casual thing it's not very exclusive so so if you
are seeing someone then you can also see another person maybe hmm well I think sometimes seeing
someone can mean actually they're your boyfriend or girlfriend like I'm seeing John he's my boyfriend
okay yeah see this is the difficult thing about seeing someone is that for some people it means it's
really serious well for other people it means it's more casual I guess it's important that
you and your boyfriend or girlfriend share the same view on the meeting of this word have to agree on
what seeing someone means okay well what's our next word Marco cheating on cheating on someone
cheating on me cheating on someone okay so if you're cheating on someone then you are like kissing
or even having sex with someone who's not your boyfriend or your husband or your girlfriend
or exactly so if I say she cheated on me that means that my girlfriend kissed her head sex with another guy
right but if I say she cheated me yeah that's different that's different maybe she sold you
something for a really high price she cheated me yeah or maybe she sold me something that was fake
or yeah or broken or broken yeah okay so cheated on is really different from cheated okay let's
take a look at our next word mess this up mess this up mess this up so Marco this is a phrasal
verb and that means we can sort of switch it around a little bit right exactly why don't we
listen to some examples and then we can come back and talk some more example one
I messed up on the exam and now I won't pass my class example two
when I'm cooking I always mess up and burn the rice okay so messed up it's pretty clear I think yeah
all right let's take a look at our next word immature immature immature immature so when someone is
immature they're acting really young really young right but it's not a very good thing to be
immature no it has a negative meaning right it's normal for children to be immature because
our children right but not an adult yes okay so we've got some examples that will help you to
understand this word a little bit better example one your toilet jokes are not funny stop being sorry
immature example two genie acts like she's 16 she's so immature
example three god you and your friends always act so immature
all right so immature now let's take a look at our next word selfish selfish selfish selfish
selfish so a selfish person is a person who only thinks about themselves okay so I only think about
me no one else yeah you don't care about other people's feelings okay so it's not a good thing to be
immature or selfish exactly okay so I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again we're
going to slow it down a little bit and this will help you to understand these phrases a little bit more clearly
so I said let's take a break and since that night I've been waiting for him to call but I still
haven't heard from him you don't think he's seeing someone else do you come on don't be so dramatic
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine you think so oh no how can he do this to me
I'm sure he's cheating on me why else wouldn't he call but you two are on a break theoretically
he can do whatever he likes he's the love of my life I've really messed this up
Come on hun pull yourself together it's going to be all right but I I still love him
and it's all my fault I can't believe how immature and selfish I was being I mean
he is a firefighter it's not like he can just leave someone in a burning building and meet me for dinner
I've totally messed this up you know what Veronica I think you should make the first step
I'm sure he'll forgive you no this is not gonna happen I I've ruined everything
hey do you hear something guess what it's your lovely firefighter
okay so we saw Veronica's friend trying to calm her down yeah trying to comfort her okay to make her feel
better let's take a look at some of the phrases she used in fluency builder fluency builder
okay so what was the first phrase that she said everything is going to work out just fine
everything is going to work out just fine everything is gonna work out just fine what does that mean
it's going to be okay it's going to be okay right yeah the problem will be solved okay so if
somebody's worried or somebody is crying you yeah you can say I don't worry everything is going to
work out just fine okay okay let's look at the next one pull yourself together pull yourself together
pull yourself together pull yourself together so what does that mean exactly it's kind of weird
I know I guess it just means stop crying relax and you know take a deep breath okay just like calm down
yeah get organized with your ideas and your thoughts yeah so you can think of maybe somebody who's got
tears down their face and everything is sort of in a mess if you pull it together they clean up
and they sort of relax okay all yourself together all right and the last phrase that we saw
it's going to be all right it's going to be all right it's going to be all right so it's going to be
all right means everything is going to be okay yeah it's going to be fine it's going to be fine
the problem will go away you'll feel better maybe you could even say it'll be all right yeah yeah
yeah these are three really helpful phrases that you can use when you want to say something nice
to a friend or a colleague who who has a problem okay exactly very useful language so let's
listen to some more examples example one don't worry everything is going to work out just fine
I'm sure he still loves you
example two
everything is going to be all right we'll find your puppy don't worry
okay great examples and I think it's clear now so let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll
come back and talk some more
so so I said let's take a break and since that night I've been waiting for him to call but I still
haven't heard from him you don't think he's seeing someone else do you come on don't be so dramatic
I'm sure everything is going to work out just fine you think so oh no how could he do this to me
I'm sure he's cheating on me why else wouldn't he call but you two are on a break
theoretically he can do whatever he likes he's a love of my life
I really messes up come on hun pull yourself together it's going to be all right
but I I still love him and it's all my fault I can't believe how immature and
salvage I was being I mean he is a firefighter it's not like he can just leave someone in the
burning building and meet me for dinner I'm totally messed this up you know what Veronica I think
he should make the first step I'm sure he'll forgive you no this is not gonna happen I
I
Hey, do you hear something
It's your lovely firefighter
Okay, yeah, I really like this dial like it's so romantic yeah, it's drama but at the same time romantic
So we want to know what you think will happen next yeah, well they get back together
Well they get married well they have a baby maybe they'll break up forever
Maybe she'll move halfway across the world
Anything could happen so let us know what you think will happen hmm come to our website at
English.com and leave your comments on the lesson page
Exactly and maybe you'll be right yeah you never know okay
So we're out of time for today. I hope you guys had fun and we'll see you next time until then it's goodbye