Hello everyone and welcome to English Padmai Names Marco.
Hi everyone, my name is Catherine.
What do you got Catherine for today?
It's a good question.
Well, we've got a little bit of a sign-feld situation.
So for those of you who are not familiar with this American TV show which by the way is one of my favorites,
a sign-feld is a TV show, a comedy about very awkward, very common situations that are taken to the
extreme.
Right, so it's a very popular show.
It was around for like 10 years.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
But it's not airing anymore.
Well, they're not making new episodes anymore.
Now you have to see them in reruns.
reruns, right?
So we have a situation that's very common.
And it was pretty funny on the show.
It's a guy trying to rent a car.
Okay, so he's probably at the airport or traveling and he's had a long flight and he wants to rent
a car, but of course there are some problems.
Right.
Now, I'll eventually level less and by the way, so keep that in mind as we listen to this dialogue
one time.
Hi, I made a reservation for a mid-sized vehicle.
The main is Jimmy Fox.
I'm sorry.
We have no mid-sized available at the moment.
I don't understand.
I made a reservation.
Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do.
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars, but the reservation keeps the car here.
That's why you have the reservation.
I know why we have reservations.
I don't think you do.
If you did, I'd have a car.
See, you know how to take the reservation.
You just don't know how to hold the reservation.
And that's really the most important part of the reservation, the holding.
Anybody can just take them.
But we do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
Fine.
I'll take the compact.
Alright, we have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
Would you like insurance?
Yeah, you better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
Alright, great.
So this actually happens a lot.
You make a reservation and either they lose it or they run out of cars.
It's such a common situation.
And it's not just cars.
Sometimes this happens at restaurants too and it really makes me angry.
Yeah, that happens a lot.
You show up and they're like, oh, we don't have a reservation.
And you're just like, well, then you have to keep yourself in check.
You can't really get angry.
But this guy does.
So let's take a look at the language.
Take a way to find out what are some of the words we're using here to describe renting
a car and what kind of car we're talking about.
Language take away.
Well, as you mentioned, at rental places, they have different size cars, right?
Different size vehicles, which by the way costs different prices.
Right.
So let's take a look at the size that they mentioned in dialogue.
And starting with the cheapest one, the least expensive and the smallest, it's a compact
vehicle.
Alright, compact.
So compact actually means small.
Small.
Right.
So compact car, you're going to hear a very often.
Even if you're buying a car, let's think of what's a compact car.
The VW Golf is a compact car, very small car.
So usually it's two doors or if it's a four door car, it's very small.
Not very long, right?
Right.
Exactly.
So maybe like a four focus could be a small car.
Also compact.
Now moving up in size a little bit, we would have a mid-sized vehicle.
Okay, mid-sized vehicle is, well, it's a giveaway here because mid-meads middle.
So it's kind of in the middle between the small and the large.
And this is your average four door sedan car.
Okay.
So as an example, you would have a four-taurus or maybe a Toyota Camry.
Yeah, Toyota Camry is maybe the most common car.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
That's kind of expensive, but it's still mid-sized, right?
Exactly.
And now a bigger car and probably one of the most popular cars in the United States
is an SUV.
Not anymore, Marco.
I know.
With the energy crisis and the gas prices.
Well, the economy as well.
People are not driving their SUVs anymore, but SUV is an acronym.
That means it stands for three different words.
S meaning sports.
You meaning utility.
V vehicle.
All right, thank you.
So SUV sport utility vehicle.
It means it can go maybe off road.
Right.
So an example of this would be a four-taurus or a...
Cherokee.
A Jeep Cherokee could be an SUV as well.
So right, those are three different types of cars.
Now obviously there are many more like a van or a limo, a limo, like a limousine.
But yeah, these are the most common ones that you would rent at a car rental.
Yes, definitely.
But what we have to do here is make a reservation.
Mm-hmm.
Now, interesting.
You make a reservation.
Yeah, you don't have it.
You don't do it.
You don't.
You make it.
Yeah, you make these are words that go together.
So we're going to keep them together.
I can call a restaurant.
So say for example, Marco or Cydra's friends.
I say hello.
I like to make a reservation for tonight.
Oh, okay, perfect.
Now if you show up at the restaurant, you say...
Where's my table?
I made a reservation.
Right.
And of course, I throw a fit because there's no other.
So you make a reservation.
And in this case, it was made before.
Okay, so you make a reservation.
Now, why was this guy angry at the rental car place?
Oh, long story short.
The company ran out of cars.
Okay.
Not all cars.
Just the car that he wanted.
Right.
The mid-size vehicle.
So they ran out.
So that doesn't mean they're actually running someone.
No, they have put it on.
They're running, choosing.
I'm going for a jog.
No, in this case, to run out, or in this case, we ran out means that they don't have
anymore.
You don't have anymore, exactly.
I think this word is a nice word for us to take a look at some other examples now.
Example one.
We're going to run out of gasoline.
You need to find a gas station soon.
Example two.
Can you buy some milk on your way home?
We ran out last night.
Example three.
My pen ran out of ink.
Can you lend me one please?
Oh, not a fun phrase.
But an important one in case you're ever in a restaurant or in a hotel or in a place
where you can purchase something or rent something and it's all gone.
All right.
So I think we've taken a look at a lot of great words here.
So let's listen to this dialogue again.
We're going to slow it down just a little bit and then we'll come back and explain some
phrases.
Hi, I made a reservation for a mid-sized vehicle.
The name is Jimmy Fox.
I'm sorry.
We have no mid-sized available at the moment.
I don't understand.
I made a reservation.
Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do.
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
But the reservation keeps the car here.
That's why you have the reservation.
I know why we have reservations.
I don't think you do.
If you did I'd have a car.
See, you know how to take the reservation.
You just don't know how to hold the reservation and that's really the most important part
of the reservation, the holding.
Anybody can just take them.
But we do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
Fine.
I'll take the compact.
All right.
We have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
Would you like insurance?
Yeah, you better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat the hell out of this
car.
And we're back.
So Marco, we've got a couple phrases here that deserve some attention.
So let's take a look at them in today's Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase that we want that I want to take a look at is when the agent says,
I'm sorry.
We have no midsize available at the moment.
Okay.
So do they or do they not have any?
Yes.
We have no midsize.
Okay.
So another way to say this is we haven't got any.
Uh-huh.
Oh, we don't have any.
Okay.
But in this case, you can just simplify it and say we have no.
Why wouldn't you say we have none?
Good question.
Why?
Because we need a thing here.
We have no cars.
We have no cake.
We have no food.
So this is a very common phrase in English and remember to put the thing at the end.
So, um, so for example, can I say, um, I have no money?
Absolutely.
I'm so sorry, Marco, but I'm not going to lend you.
I have no money.
Seriously, lend me something.
So we have no.
This is interesting because this is not a structure that is usually, uh, learned through textbooks,
right?
Usually say I don't have or we haven't got exactly this very spoken because you would
never say I go no.
Right, exactly.
Right.
We have to talk about something that we, uh, that has not been some things that we have.
So here I have no is very spoken, very common.
It's got another phrase.
Uh, that is also not taught so much in those textbooks that we were just mentioning.
So, uh, what's that phrase at the end?
Well, well, it's a threat.
It's a threat.
The guy is so angry.
He leans over the counter and he points his finger in the, uh, the agent's face.
I want to say.
He says, yeah.
You better give me the insurance.
You better.
All right.
So you better than me.
No, no.
It's not like better, like something is good, right?
You'd better is like a suggestion.
But very strong one.
All right.
Very strong.
This is a threat.
Yes.
You better eat your dinner or I'm going to send you to your room.
Exactly.
So as you can see, it says he says you better.
You better give me the insurance.
But the grammatically correct way would be you had better.
You had better.
So the contraction would be you'd better.
Exactly.
You'd you had better do this.
So this is a, it's a hypothetical situation.
You had better do this.
If you don't do this, bad things will happen.
So remember that here, we've got the grammatically correct form that you should write.
You'd better or the spoken form.
You better.
I think in this one, we should also listen to some other examples to get a better idea
of how we can use this very strong suggestion.
Example one.
You better go to the doctor before that cold gets any worse.
Example two.
You better watch out.
It's dangerous to go out this late.
Example three.
She better change her attitude or her boss is going to fire her.
So what is the threat?
You better give me insurance because what is he going to do?
He says I'm going to beat the hell out of this car.
Okay, so this future I'm going to.
I'm going to.
Right.
Beat the hell out of this car.
So this is very strong.
Right.
Yeah, it's very strong.
He's saying he is going to destroy the car.
So beat the hell out of.
So that means really just do damage to something.
So you can use it at toward the person.
Also it's like I'm going to beat the hell out of you.
And I'll arrest you.
The whole balance.
Right.
So it's a very strong phrase.
It shows anger and shows that you are threatening somebody.
So it's not obviously it's not polite.
And it might get you broken nose and a bar.
If you ever say this to someone or about someone.
So be very careful.
Right.
But you can use it to describe a situation.
He's like, yeah, we went to a bar yesterday and then beat the hell out of the bar tender.
Right.
Man.
So instead of just saying, then hit the bartender or then got into a fight, he
are saying he hit him and he just.
And he kept hitting and then kept hitting him.
So yeah, he beat the hell out of them.
Right.
All right, great.
So those are the phrases and words that we want to talk about today.
But I think it'd be good if we listen to this dialogue one more time just to get a good
feel for it.
We come back.
We talk a little bit more about the process of renting a car.
Hi.
I made a reservation for a mid-sized vehicle.
The name is Jimmy Fox.
I'm sorry.
We have no mid-sized available at the moment.
I don't understand.
I made a reservation.
Do you have my reservation?
Yes.
We do.
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars.
But the reservation keeps the car here.
That's why you have the reservation.
I know why we have reservations.
I don't think you do.
If you did, I'd have a car.
See, you know how to take the reservation.
You just don't know how to hold the reservation.
And that's really the most important part of the reservation, the holding.
Anybody can just take them.
We do have a compact or an SUV if you'd like.
Fine.
I'll take the compact.
All right.
We have a blue Ford Focus for you, Mr. Fox.
Would you like insurance?
Yeah.
You better give me the insurance because I'm going to beat
the hell out of this car.
You know, I heard that in Florida,
or in certain cities of California and Florida,
you can actually rent luxury cars.
Oh, yeah.
You can do that in most places.
You can rent like a Porsche or Lamborghini or a Ferrari.
Yeah.
Obviously it costs a lot of money.
But it gives you the opportunity to maybe drive
to maybe drive one of these cars that you obviously
wouldn't have the money to buy.
Yeah.
Especially if you're talking about those warm places,
like Florida, California, you want to be in the sunshine.
You get a convertible.
You got to get a convertible.
Yeah.
So I think the insurance premiums on those particular cars
are very high though.
So you're not only paying for the car,
but you're also paying for the insurance.
And possibly the speeding tickets.
Yeah, of course.
I can't imagine renting one of those cars
and not getting a speeding ticket.
Exactly.
So if any of you out there have experienced renting cars
or you have some questions about the specifics
that are involved in this process,
let us know on our website, engoshpod.com.
Right.
We're there to answer any questions or doubts.
And we'll see you guys there.
All right.
Until next time, everyone.