Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and today we've got a very, very useful lesson for all of the
out there.
That's right. We're bringing you part two of the What If series, which is a small series.
Small and it is kind of grammar focused, but it's very, very important because you often want
to talk about things that don't happen. We're calling these hypotheticals or conditional
statements. Right. So there are many different types of hypotheticals or conditional
statements. So today we're going to be looking at the third conditional, which is probably
the hardest one because it uses a little bit of a complex grammar structure. It's
complex. And we're actually talking about things that did not happen and that will not
happen, right? It's impossible to change. It's impossible to change these because there
are things that would have happened in the past, but didn't. Wow. That sounds confusing.
Uh, why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time and then we'll be back to
look at some phrases first.
This is the good life. We have a good don't you think? Yeah, of course. Although, don't
you ever wonder what could have been. What do you mean? Well, sometimes I think if
how things could have turned out, if I had done things a little differently. For example,
like for example, if I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I
wanted to. I see. Yeah, now that I think of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved
to this town and met Sally. You see, everything happens for a reason. We wouldn't even have met.
If I hadn't been in that car accident 10 years ago, well, I have no regrets. I'll drink to that.
All right, so two guys, you know, talking about life. These, I imagine these guys as being,
you know, middle, middle age, or a little bit older sitting on a porch drinking and beer,
talking about what could have been. Yeah, exactly. They're kind of thinking about the past and
the decisions they have made. Yeah, exactly. All right, so before we start in the grammar,
why don't we take a look at a couple of different phrases on fluency builder?
Well, Marko, this first phrase is a phrase you'll hear very often in English. It's a phrase
that even has full, soft vocal roots. Something we talked a lot about when we're studying
Socrates back in the end school, but this is the good life. The good life. We have the good life.
All right, have a good life. I have a good life is a very common phrase, but here the good life is an idiom.
So I'm living the good life. Means, you know, I have no complaints about my life.
Right, so pretty much you have all your necessities covered. And maybe you have a good,
a nice family and you have a good job and you're just happy. So this is the good life.
Very good. So you have the good life. Now moving on to another phrase that's kind of also a
philosophical, you know, it says everything happens for a reason. All right, so this phrase is,
well, it's also pretty common. People say this when bad things happen, but they also say this when
good things happen. Yeah. So basically, you're just saying that it's destiny. If this bad thing
happened to you, there is a reason for it. Maybe you don't see it now. Maybe not tomorrow, but maybe later
you'll see why. This often happens when people lose their jobs. Are you saying, well, you know,
everything happens for a reason. Maybe losing this job will allow you to find a better job.
Or maybe go back to school and study. Or maybe meet the man or woman of your dreams.
Right. So everything happens for a reason. Very good. And then the guy agrees and says, well,
I'll drink to that. Okay. So this is a way for people speaking English to say, listen, I agree with you.
I like that idea. And I will cheers. Cheers, right? Right. So this means we're going to touch our
glasses or touch our beer bottles. And we're going to, you know, think about how this is a nice thought,
you know, everything happens for a reason is positive. It's a way to say, listen, good things
going to happen from. Right. So he's saying, yes, I agree. Cheers. I'll drink to that.
I'll drink to that. All right. Well, pretty interesting phrases. You know, they're very
common, I guess, like, colloquial, right? So you can use them in every day conversation with a friend.
You can. And you know, oftentimes we say, for example, something really positive, like,
I'm really glad I have such great friends. And then everyone says, oh, I'll drink to that. Right. And so
this is something you'll hear when you're out with friends or with family. And they may sound funny
it first, but you will recognize them when you're speaking to people who's speaking English. All right.
So, all right. So let's listen to our dialogue again. And then we'll come back and explain the grammar.
This is the good life. We have it good. Don't you think? Yeah. Of course. Although,
don't you ever wonder what could have been? What do you mean? Well, sometimes I think of how
things could have turned out if I had done things a little differently. For example,
like, for example, if I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I wanted to.
I see. Yeah. Now that I think of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town
and met Sally. You see, everything happens for a reason. We wouldn't even have met. If I hadn't
been in that car accident 10 years ago. Well, I have no regrets. I'll drink to that.
Beep beep beep. All right. So now it's time for grammar breakdown.
Raman breakdown. So I'm grammar breakdown. We're going to look at the two main parts of these phrases
that allow us to talk about things that didn't happen. So we're talking about looking back at our
life and seeing what decisions and what actions we made. And in this case, we have a great sentence here.
If I hadn't studied architecture, I would have become an artist. All right. So let's look at the
first part before the comment. If I hadn't studied architecture. So now we have the conditional
if. So Mark, a big question. Did he study architecture? He did. He did. So if I hadn't studied
architecture, I mean, I did study architecture. But if I had not studied it, mm-hmm. Okay. So this is
if I could change the past, then what would I have done? I would have become an artist. Okay.
So he wanted to be an artist. But he didn't become an artist. He studied architecture instead.
Right. Okay. Very good. You can see the two parts here. We have one the condition. If I hadn't
done this thing. And then afterwards, we have the results. Then I would have become an artist. So this
is the hypothetical. Very good. And when we see the condition, you see the the structure of the
sentence is had plus verb in past participle. So if I hadn't studied architecture, and this is
called the past perfect. Mm-hmm. And then the result, as you said, would have become this is
the present perfect. Have her has plus verb in past participle. Let's look at another example.
I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town. Okay. So we've got the same idea here,
but we've got it flipped. We've got these two parts in different places. And so he's pretty much
saying if I hadn't moved to this town, then I wouldn't have gotten married. Mm-hmm. But what
did happen? He did move to this town. And he did get married. Exactly. So then yeah, like you say,
he changed the condition. And you can do this. You can put the condition in the beginning or at the end.
And again, the structure is the same. I would have gotten married. Right? Have gotten this is
present perfect. Have her has depending on the subject plus the verb in past participle.
And then the past perfect or the condition had plus verb in past participle hadn't moved to this town.
All right. That's a lot of grammar. It's a lot of grammar, but it's very, it's very easy once you just
start using it. Don't think too much about, okay, what do I do here? Just, you know, if you get the
rhythm and you start using it in the same way, then it kind of comes out naturally. And if you make
a little mistake, there's not a big deal because even we do it, you know? Exactly. Well, let's try a
couple of examples. Not the top of our heads first of all. If I hadn't moved to China,
I wouldn't have learned Chinese. Very good. So you did move to China and you did learn Chinese. Exactly.
So your turn. All right. If my parents hadn't spoken Spanish to me when I was a kid,
I wouldn't have become fluent in Spanish. Okay. So your parents did speak Spanish, do?
And you did become fluent in Spanish. So not bad. Right. As you can see, you can use it not only to
think about things in the past that you can't change anymore, but just also, you know, kind of
remember or say, you know, oh, if this hadn't happened, the results. Or if I hadn't opened my big
mouth, my best friend wouldn't have gotten so angry out. Exactly. So I said something stupid
and my friend did get angry. And now I feel bad about it. It happens. All right. Very good. So I hope
it's clear. It does sound a little bit complicated, but this is what our website is for, right? So if
you have questions or doubts, or you want to try and plant your own ideas, you can come to the website
and do it. Want to make some of your own sentences and practice some of these new things,
then come to our website, post some comments. And we're happy to correct and add our own
comments. Exactly. So before we go, let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
This is the good life. We have a good don't you think? Yeah, of course. Although, don't you ever wonder
what could have been? What do you mean? Well, sometimes I think if how things could have turned
out, if I had done things a little differently. For example, like, for example, if I hadn't
studied architecture, I would have become an artist like I wanted to. I see. Yeah, now that I think
of it, I wouldn't have gotten married if I hadn't moved to this town and met Sally. You see,
everything happens for a reason. We wouldn't even have met if I hadn't been in that car accident
ten years ago. Well, I have no regrets. I'm drink to that.
All right, we're back. So Catherine, any other regrets, maybe in your life, apart from opening your mouth?
Any other regrets? If my parents had spoken as managed to be as a kid, I would have learned.
But instead, I just learned English and that's all. Well, your mom is a half a Swedish, right?
Half Swedish, half-check. So, and she never spoke any of these languages here. She, no, she didn't
speak Swedish or check her parents spoke English as their common language, but she grew up speaking
Italian and German. But she didn't speak to me in those languages, and then as an adult, she
forgot some of them. And so, because my dad was, well, they're both Americans now. But my dad's
American. They're just booking the street. Wow. But now you speak Italian. So, do you ever try and
talk to your mom in Italian? Sometimes, my grandmother's Italian is much better. So,
my grandmother's completely fluent. So, I speak to her in Italian. And, um,
and German as well. She's fluent in German too. Nice body German at school. So, see, this is the
interesting thing. Now, so many people are speaking so many languages and before, if you spoke
another foreign language, it was a big deal. Oh, yeah. But now it's like a requirement. You have to
at least dominate your own native language and a foreign language, right? So, if your native language
is English, you at least have to speak Spanish or Chinese or some other language. Definitely true.
And I think there are a lot of people, um, a lot of our users that speak maybe two or three languages,
and English is just one more. So, you know, more power to them. This is a really great skill to have.
And I think it's really important to keep on going with it even though it's frustrating. Right.
And actually, once you've been able, and actually once you mastered a two or three different languages
than the fourth and fifth, just becomes easier. Actually, it's true. It sounds, it sounds funny when
you hear it because you're like, how could it be easier to learn more? But your brains start
to understand patterns, but, yeah. Right. And so it just becomes more natural for you.
Picks up patterns from the two or three other different languages that you dominate. So, it's a weird
it's strange how the brain works. Yeah. Yeah. All right, guys. So, that's all for today. Be sure to visit
our website, EnglishPod.com. As we said, any questions or comments, or you want us to correct your
grammar of this lesson, you can visit us there. And we'll see you guys next time.
All right. Bye, everyone. Bye.