Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco and my name is Catherine
and today we're going to be visiting one of my favorite places I must say.
Really, see you're a big meat eater.
I am. I have to have meat every day so that's why I usually go to the butcher.
Alright so vegetarians be warned today's dialogue is all about eating meat and where to go to
get meat so as Marco said that place is called the butcher's.
So we're going to be visiting the butcher and we're going to learn all the different types of meat
you can find there. Great so we don't have anything to preview but before we get started just
like to mention that you're going to hear a lot of different kinds of words and we're back
in a minute to talk about what they mean.
I'd like half pound of ground beef please.
Good choice. Our ground beef is extra lean if you know what I mean.
Could I also have half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of boneless chicken breast?
No, no, no chicken breasts at the moment but we have some nice chicken thighs.
No, that won't do. I'll take this smoked ham you have here.
Okay, is there anything else?
Is this salami and bologna you have here?
Yes, it's very fine meat made it myself.
Sounds good. Okay that's it.
Wait, we have tea bowl, ribeye, and sirloin sticks. They are very fresh.
Just came from the slaughterhouse.
No, that's okay really. I think that's all for today.
Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back so this butcher was kind of creepy in the beginning.
Very creepy in the beginning.
I think that's usually the conception that you have of butcher's because they always have a knife
and they're always covered in blood but it's not human blood.
Right like the movies, we need Todd.
Yeah like we need Todd.
What's your favorite street?
So but we actually took a look at a lot of different types of meat that the woman was ordering.
So why don't we take a look at these now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Okay so the first is a classic cut. This is something that we had at my house about once we
growing up it's called a pork chop pork chop.
So a pork chop comes from the animal the pork or pig.
Yeah we actually don't say pork to me the animal pork just means the kind of meat that comes from a pig.
So big difference there when we're talking about food we say pork.
Oh wow and what about a pork chop so what exactly is that?
Chop is usually just on the bone and oftentimes it's fried.
Or baked I guess but it's just a piece of pork on the bone and a chop you just imagine a knife chopping
something. All right so a pork chop very good and after pork chops we were ordering some ground beef.
All right so ground beef is another important one. Ground beef is beef that's been chopped up
and pushed through a machine that kind of pushes it out in very very small bits. Okay.
There's no bone. So ground comes from the verb to grind. So to grind up meat to make it very,
very small pieces. Right so if you want to make a spaghetti bowl on Yaze the kind of beef
you use is ground beef or even hamburgers. What are you exactly? So ground beef you ground up
beef. What are other things would you grind? Oh you could grind your teeth.
You can grind. Some people do that when they're sleeping and grind their teeth. You can grind
pepper grinders you know pepper sometimes come in balls you have to grind them to make them
smaller and broken down. Very good so that's ground beef and from the verb to grind.
Now we are buying some boneless chicken breasts. All right so boneless as you have
guests means without bones and chicken breasts are usually just a really nice juicy kind of tender
cut of meat from the chicken from the kind of underside of the chicken where obviously
yeah they have it. It's not a wing it's not a leg it's just a chicken breast. All right so boneless chicken
but now usually it is boneless right when you buy it at the supermarket. Yeah yeah. Next up we've got
some classic deli counter favorites these are our cold cuts. All right so cold cuts now this
means that they are cold. Oh well yeah they're cold but I think cold cuts the most important thing
to remember here is that they're mostly like kinds of salami or cured meats so these are salt
cured or their drive meats and you usually have them on sandwiches so like a salami sandwich.
So like cured meat you mean that meat has it hasn't been cooked. Oh no it's not been cooked but
it's treated in a way that allows it to last for a very long time. All right so they look like
long long tubes of meat or they look very dry. So they look very dry like a jerky for example.
All right so cured meat now for example we have salami and uh baloney.
baloney. Now it's interesting because baloney is actually spelled BOLOG and A so you
say balona balona or something like that. Well I think comes in the Italian balonia. All right but
it's definitely a change that happened in the English language when it came over from Italy but
baloney is a kind of meat that's yeah it's got a very funny looking name. Mm yeah so you're
more sophisticated than I am that's why you know this dude. I just speak Italian. All right so you have
salami baloney and uh pastrami. Pastrami what about ham is that is that considered a cold
cut? You can have ham in the cold cut section because ham sometimes comes in tubes that you slice.
Uh but ham is also just a normal kind of pork but ham is cured you know like a smoked ham.
Exactly we're smoked turkey one of my favorites. Mm very good and well now moving on from
the cold cuts we're going to concentrate on steaks. Ooh steak so there are a thousand kinds of steaks
in this world and every city seems to have its own kind but here we're only looking at three
the first of which is the teabone. All right the teabone steak I think is one of the most popular ones.
Definitely. Um it's a steak it's pretty big right? Yeah well yeah I can't be it. And it has a bone
inside that looks like a teabone. All right so um you're saying Marco that the teabone is named
after the shape and the look of this steak. Yeah teabone steak. All right and as well as our next one is
also a rib eye. Okay so the rib eye I think actually has a piece of the rib in it so the rib is the bone
and there's a circle which is kind of uh it's it's the piece of meat is sliced off the rib and the
circle is actually part of that rib so there's a little bit of bone in it but it's not as
burning as the teabone. Right so it does have one small bone that kind of looks like an eye because you
can see through it and our next steak has no bone and is the most tender and the best steak you
can have sirloin steak. So I think the sirloin is definitely the most expensive if you're in a restaurant
definitely the most tender I think of all those delicious and usually you can have like a big
sirloin steak like a half a kilo like a 400 grams sirloin steak. I'd have friend of it a full kilo
really sirloin steak for is it a competition or no there's a kind of steak called the
bistecca alafyorentina in Italy it's the the Florentine beef steak and it is it can be about a
kilo of meat. Wow. Yeah I bet you can't even move after that. No you're you fall asleep with your
head and your soup on the table. All right so that's all the the meat related words that we have
for you today. So why don't we move on now to Florentine builder where we're gonna take a look at some
of the phrases in this dialogue. Florentine builder. We're gonna look at the phrases if you know what I mean.
If you know what I mean. Now I love this phrase if you know what I mean. I do know what you mean.
Well it's I like it too. So you can use it for sarcasm. Yeah. Right or you can use it to kind of
insinuate something right. Exactly. Yeah so you're saying you're saying there's a double meaning
in what I want to say. So there's two things I could say and I'm not gonna say it outright but
you know this thing that we can't really say. So for example we can say she likes to go out if you
know what I mean. All right so you're insinuating that not only does she like to go out but maybe
she goes out a lot a lot. I don't mean she gets drunk or something like that. Yeah so it's kind of like a
double meaning but you're trying to be subtle. Yeah but it's not so subtle because you're actually
saying like this is that what I mean or um she's eating for two if you know what I mean. Oh there we go.
So you're insinuating that well you're not really insinuating you're telling me that. She's pregnant.
Eating for two is a common idiom and English that means that a person a woman has a well
is going to have a baby. So here I'm saying hey do you know this idiom? She's eating for two if you know
what I mean. Yeah. Inquinc Link. I'm wrinkly. So now why don't we take a look at some other examples
of how we could use if you know what I mean in different circumstances when you're trying to
insinuate something. Example one. She's eating for two now if you know what I mean.
Example two.
Example three.
All right we're back so um now that that's clear why don't we move on to our next phrase.
So this one is accounting phrase and for those of you who have heard the word doesn't before it
might not be so new the phrase is half a dozen half a dozen so that means half of a wealth.
So a dozen is 12 and it's I'm not really sure when this started being used in English but a
dozen is 12 and half a dozen is then six. Now there's another phrase or another saying that's very
common a dime a dozen. He's a dime a dozen. So that means you can get 12 of the same type of guys for
ten cents. Right so they're easy to find. They're easy to find. Yeah. The dime it doesn't. All right
very good and moving on to our last one. When they were talking they said something about the
meat being lean extra lean. Okay lean this is not mean lean on a door. Right. This is not like
resting on something. This is actually a kind of um weighted described food and so food is lean if it's
not got much fat. It's not fatty. Okay so if it's lean it doesn't have much fat. Exactly so I prefer
to eat lean meats so I often eat um birds and poultry so chicken I like it pretty lean and if it's
got fat on it I'll cut the fat off. Okay like the skin the skin is fat right. Yeah. All right so you
can have lean beef it doesn't have much fat around it. Yeah and in America actually on the the
packages at the supermarket it often says the percentage of meat that you have so it's 95% lean
or 98% lean. So that means you have 3% fat in there. Exactly. Right. My math skills are amazing.
All right so um now that we've finished with all of these words on fluency billet let's take a look at
a dialogue for the last time.
I would like half pound of ground beef please. Good choice. Our ground beef is extra lean if you know
what I mean. Could I also have half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of bonus chicken breast?
No no no chicken breasts at the moment but we have some nice chicken thighs.
No that won't do. I'll take this smoked ham you have here. Okay is there anything else?
Is this salami and bologna you have here? Yes it's very fine need made it myself. Sounds good okay that's it.
Wait we have tea room, ribeye and sourline sticks. They are very fresh just came from the slaughterhouse.
Hmm no that's okay really I think that's all for today.
Okay that'll be $34.50.
All right we're back so Catherine are you a big beef or meat eater? Definitely am it helps that my
partner and crime is from Kansas City and they have the best among the best sticks in our entire country
in Kansas City. Wow I actually miss um there was a back in California we had the
$6 burger from Carl's Jr it was just basically beef bacon cheese it was just like this huge
burger with full of meat and obviously a lot of calories. Okay but it was delicious I'm in
Ego to where we are very used to having some meat product every day with our food. Yeah well it
would be the same in the Midwest actually from where we're from um the it's the same in the Midwest
because people in the Midwest generally think that if you're not eating meat then you know what are you eating
bread? Right corn so uh so me this considered a healthy part of the day and you definitely eat it with your
meals. Yeah and I'm sure our vegetarian listeners might not appreciate this but you know it's just
kind of different diet some people eat for example rice every day. So we're in other countries you
wouldn't really have rice every day or for example when I was in Chile had a lot of potatoes.
Really? A lot of potato. Have you ever had an Argentine steak I hear they have the best beef in the
world? They are not only delicious but they are very inexpensive and it's amazing you can have a like a
complete steak buffet for like I don't know like it can't even remember it was just I sat there for
three hours and couldn't move and kept eating. Yeah was it is it true you can eat it with a spoon it's so soft.
Some of the meat is very very tender and not if it's grilled you can't really do that but in
other preparations it's almost like that. It's a nice butter sauce herbs. All right so uh thank you
me hungry. You've made me hungry I think we're gonna take off and have some uh burgers. All right so
if you have any questions any comments please come to our website at englishpod.com and
we're there to answer any doubts. And we'd love to know what your favorite foods are meat or
otherwise so post something on our website. Hope to see you there soon. Bye bye.