Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and today Marco you and I are talking about movies right?
We're talking a little bit about movies but mostly we're having a big argument.
Okay I kind of like arguments. Lots of great words and phrases for you to learn here in English
but we've got an upper intermediate level lesson with some people who are not getting along right
well. It's a couple. Guy and a girl and they're having a fight as couples do.
So we're going to be learning a lot of the different language that they are using in this very
heated debate. So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time and then we'll be right back.
Wow the terrible movie is finally over. Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want to
check flick. Well you should have picked in the end you always complain about everything.
Not everything just this film. Even the title is ridiculous and it's so long. Those are the
two and a half most wasted hours of my life. So much so that I'm thinking about asking them to
give me my money back. I'm thinking of taking you back home. I thought we could have a nice evening
but you're always so negative. I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have rented or bought
and then thrown in the garbage. You see that's what I'm talking about. I can't stand your
sarcastic jokes anymore. Next time go with your gay friend who is more in touch with his feelings.
Well he's more of a man than you are. At least he appreciates love stories. Love stories more like one
night stands. Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start on those fat drunk friends of yours. There
no saints. My friends fat. What about those whales you call friends? You're unbearable. You can walk
home. I'm leaving. Bye.
I think the guy was exaggerating a little bit. What do you think? I think they were both
exaggerating you know by the end of an argument. Both people are saying things that maybe they
don't mean. I think we'll talk a little bit more about this towards the end of the show but now
why don't we take a look at language takeaway? Language takeaway. All right on language takeaway
today we have four words and the first one that you probably saw in the very first sentence is a
chick flick. Chick flick. So first of all the word chick means a woman. It's slang and it's not very nice.
It's not very nice you know. Well I mean between guys you would use it and it's like all this
chick or that chick but you wouldn't really walk up to a girl in color it chick right? Now you wouldn't
say hey chick what's up? That's not something you want to say so chick is a a slang word for a
girl or a woman and that chick flick is a girl's movie. So a flick is a movie. Another slang word.
Exactly so this is the slang phrase for flick so hey Marka what flicks are showing at the movie theater?
All right so movies. So in the chick flick is usually a romantic movie a drama something that's very
like beaches beaches is a chick flick I don't know if they were seen that.
I'm also he's just not that into you is one of those new chick flick. Like how to lose a guy in
ten days. Yeah how to lose a guy in ten days or the devil wears Prada. Bright Wars. Bright Wars. Wow
lots of chick. I've actually never seen any one of these except how to lose a guy in ten days.
I've actually only seen that one. All right so chick flick is a girl's gormons movie and next up we have
a word is sarcastic where I'm a sarcastic jokes. So sarcastic jokes or somebody being sarcastic.
God Marka you're always so sarcastic. So what would sarcasm sound like?
Yeah he's really funny. All right so it's not really what you're saying it's kind of
how you're saying it. Right so it's kind of like by saying he's really funny. You're saying yeah
he's a funny guy but if I say he's really funny. I'm saying he's not funny he's these being mean
or he's a jerk. Yeah he's a jerk. So sarcasm is kind of one of those things that it's a little bit
difficult to learn how to do or to actually get it right especially in English right? Yeah Marco
great explanation. Exactly that's the way it goes. Oh yeah you're so funny. So you're amazing
you should go to you went to sarcasm school. So my parents would be really mean.
Have that. Sorry you're just kidding. All right so apart from being sarcastic you can criticize
someone. Like you're ever critical. All right so you're really into character right now.
All right so critical to criticize someone is to to complain about them or to say that the
things that they do are not very good. So you can criticize a person or a movie. Yeah so this
movie wasn't very good. It wasn't funny. The actors were bad. It was really long. These are criticisms.
Criticism. All right well and then moving on the girl was finally tired of the guy and his
complaints and she said he's unbearable. Gosh you're unbearable so the root of this word is to be able
to like to stand something to bear it and so if you're unbearable something is unbearable you just
can't stand it. All right so you're tired of it you can't stand it. She's she thinks he's so unbearable
she makes him get out of the car and she leaves. Yeah she said you can walk home. All right so that's
an unbearable person right. Okay so we took a look at those four main words here in order
dialogue. Let's move on now to some of the phrases that we found in fluency builder. fluency builder.
This first one's a common one especially when we talk about women and men and the relationship
between women and men we say about men that maybe they should be more in touch with their feelings
or their feminine side. Okay so if you're saying to be more in touch with your feminine side
what exactly are you saying? So the question well what you're saying is that you want to be able to
express your feelings more or you want to be able to understand more about your feminine side or
something like this. So to be in touch with is more about yourself it's about self reflection and
self understanding. So so you could say I'm a very serious person but I want to make some changes in my
life so I'm trying to be more in touch with my inner child. Your inner child. All right so to be in touch
with and it's usually related to feelings to something intangible to be heavier. To be heavier.
All right moving on now a heated phrase a one night stand. Oh I'll let you explain this one Marco.
All right so a one night stand is a casual and very quick temporal encounter that's usually
sexual encounter. It's romantic right so it can be between two different people they meet each other one night
they have a relationship for one night only and then they never see each other again so it's casual.
It's casual very good. So yeah you would see this you see this a lot in shows like you know sex
in the city and yeah they have a lot of one night stands in that show. All right so a one night stand
and well related to this the girl was criticizing his friends and she said they're no saints.
Okay so you could say this many different ways he's no saint. She's no saint or I'm no saint.
You're no saint. So a saint is a good person. It's a word that we use in religion to say
someone who's like mother Teresa or someone who's just really good and kind and doesn't commit any
exactly and so to say I'm no saint is to say well I do bad things or I say bad things. I'm not perfect. Okay so
he or they they're no saints they do bad stuff too. Yeah very good so that's the way that you would use
he's no saints they're no saints. All right so I think now we should listen to our dialogue for the last
time and we'll be right back.
You
Wow the terrible movie is finally over. Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want to end up seeing
it chick flick. Well you should have picked in the end you always complain about everything.
Not everything just this film even the title was ridiculous and it's so long. Those are the two
and a half most wasted hours of my life. So much so that I'm thinking about asking them to give
me my money back. I'm thinking of taking you back home. I thought we could have a nice evening but
you're always so negative. I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have rented or bought
and then thrown in the garbage. You see that's what I'm talking about. I can't stand your sarcastic
jokes anymore. Next time go with your gay friend who's more in touch with his feelings. Well he's
a man than you are. At least he appreciates love stories. Love stories more like one night stand.
Don't criticize Mario or else I'll start on those fat drunk friends of yours. There no saints.
My friends fat. What about those whales you call friends? You're unbearable. You can walk home. I'm leaving.
All right. Catherine, is this an argument that you would say is a typical among couples or maybe
people that are probably about to break up, right? Not couples that are happy. I would say but yeah
you definitely have people who are well I guess it's kind of the battle of the sexes, right? You
have people who are different genders and so they don't always understand each other. You know you
want to have your girlfriends as a girl and your girlfriends behave and talk in a certain way together
and guys do the same thing but with their friends and so sometimes you have these clashes these
interactions that are negative and you know when people are upset with each other they say mean things.
And especially I think in this case they don't really like each other's friends.
Exactly. That's a kind of a common thing like a guy doesn't like his girlfriend's friends
because maybe they gossip too much or something like that. And the same thing with the girl right
because a guy's friends maybe drink too much and play too many car games. So I think a lot of
times these these problems also have to do with the fact that like when a girl is with her girlfriend
she maybe acts differently or with when a guy's with his guy friends and so that's weird sometimes
for the relationship because you see your partner acting differently with other people. Right.
Do you like your boyfriend or girlfriend friends? Do you get in fights about this kind of stuff?
Or you know what the in-laws?
Ooh that's the whole number of situations. That's the whole number of situations.
Absolutely. All right so we want to hear from you and also if you have any questions or
comments suggestions come to EnglishPod.com and you can leave it on your lessons page or you can
email us at EnglishPod at PraxisLanguage.com. We hope to see another website in the near future please
get in touch with us. That's all for today. So bye bye. Bye.