Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine. So as usual we've got a great dialogue for you today.
And before we get going, I should mention what the topic is. So Marco, take it away.
We are actually having a small fight at the office.
Somebody or a coworker is annoying us. So you know, sometimes coworkers, you see them every day.
They're doing something that's maybe getting on your nerves.
And you practically live together because you're with each other for eight, nine,
ten hours every day. Exactly. So that's what we're going to be looking at today.
Some language related to this topic. So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
Hey, Mary, can you cut that out?
Cut what out? I'm not doing anything.
The tapping of your pen on your desk. It's driving me crazy.
Fine. By the way, would you mind not slurping your coffee every time you have a cup?
I don't slurped my coffee. And plus, how can you hear it when you're shouting into your phone all the time?
You've got to be kidding me. You're complaining about me talking on the phone.
When you go out for a cigarette break, ten times a day to shoot the breeze.
Look, we have a lot of accumulated anger from working in these conditions.
And it's probably okay to let off steam once in a while.
But it's probably not a good idea to keep it up. I'm willing to forgive and forget if you are.
Fine. Let's call it a truce. I'll try to be more considerate and keep the noise down.
Yeah, I'll try to do the same. So I was wondering,
do you want to go out to dinner Friday night?
All right, we're back. So yeah, I think this is a common situation, right?
So common, this might even be based on our own lives.
It is. You may not know, but Katherine, I get into fights all the time.
All the time. Not really.
All right. So I think there was some interesting words here, but mostly phrases.
So let's start with the words first on language takeaway.
All right. So the first word as you might have guessed has to do with eating and drinking.
This is called slurping. And it's some lurp to slurps.
So the noun, the thing is slurping. And it's very common with people who eat their food quickly.
Like soup. Yeah, soup or, you know, or when they're eating soup noodles.
Or sometimes when you have a drink and you're drinking it through a straw towards the end,
you're just like trying to get the very last part at the bottom. So yeah, the straw slurps.
Yeah, so slurping. Some people really can't stand it. And sometimes you don't even notice that you're doing it.
No, absolutely not. All right. So apart from slurping, what else do we have?
We've got a great word here, accumulated. So a lot of accumulated anger.
The word is a verb to accumulate. And what does that mean?
Means to kind of grow or to become more and more.
All right. So you're like saving it.
Or even it's like building up. You know, we say this will oftentimes in Chicago where it snows a lot in the winter
that there's a foot of snow accumulated on the ground. That means there's a lot of snow.
And every time it snows, it keeps getting bigger.
Yeah. So to accumulate.
So accumulated anger. Your anger is getting bigger and bigger.
Because you never tell anyone about your anger. So it keeps building and it keeps piling up.
All right. Well, towards the end, they said, well, let's call it truce. So they want to call it truce.
All right. A truce is another word for a piece. And so this is a way that you can stop fighting.
And say that you and I have been fighting for a long time. We may not come to a deal.
But we'll say truce from now on. We just won't fight.
We won't fight about it. Okay.
Brothers and sisters often call truce.
That's true. And well, if you're calling a truce, you're trying to be more considerate.
Okay. Consider it like you're saying is a way to be or a way to act and consider it.
Often has to do with how you act towards other people. So it's being nice to other people or thinking about other people's feelings before yourself.
All right. So if you're considered then you may be more polite.
You think about the other person's feelings before you do anything.
It's like, well, you just say nice little things like, please and thank you. And I'm sorry.
And these things are all ways of being considerate.
Very good. All right. So four great words on language takeaway. Why don't we move on now to fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right. So as we mentioned, this dialogue is very, very rich in a lot of different phrases.
So let's start with a couple of them. The very first one and the title of the lesson.
Cut it out. Cut that out. Hey, Mary, can you cut that out?
Right. So you're not actually saying to cut something with scissors or something?
No. This is it's a way of saying can you stop that? Stop it. Stop doing that.
Stop it. Quit it. Okay. Cut that out. Cut it out.
So if someone's doing something that's really annoying to you, it's not very nice to say, but you can say, hey, cut that out.
Or if someone's doing something mean to someone like my brother used to hit me, my mom would say, Peter, cut that out.
All right. So it is a good mom phrase as well.
All right. Moving on to our next phrase, the guy said that the tapping on the desk was driving him crazy.
It's driving me crazy.
All right. To drive someone crazy means to make someone just feel like they're going nuts or, you know, just it makes you kind of angry or frustrated or
tense. But it can also be used like in in a romantic sense, right? That girl drives me crazy.
It means like he can't even think about anything else.
All right. So in this case, what drives you crazy?
Uh, when I'll tell you what drives me crazy, when people clip their fingernails and toenails at the office.
Can't believe, well, it drives me crazy. Like, for example, when somebody or my brother leaves his clothes lying on the floor in the living room.
That's annoying to. Yeah. So that drives me crazy.
All right. So moving on to our third phrase, this is a pretty big one, but take it as a whole. You've got to be kidding me.
All right. So this is as you've said, a fixed phrase. These words usually go together and it is a perfect example of sarcasm.
So it's a way, the way you say it is very important. So I could say, you've got to be kidding me.
What's a good, what's a good situation for this? Maybe I get to the airport and I'm running late and I'm really happy that I get there on time.
And then I see the flight is delayed seven hours.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
Right. So it's a way of saying I can't believe it or seriously, this isn't what's happening.
What's happening? What bad luck. Right. So it is sarcastic phrase, but use it as a whole.
Usually you don't change the subject. You don't say you've got to be kidding him or it's always this.
You've got to be kidding me. All right.
Or you've got to be kidding me. See different meanings with different inflections and flex very good.
What's our next phrase?
Our next phrase is a good one because it doesn't mean what it sounds like.
Okay. So to shoot the breeze, all right.
Shoot means like you can shoot a gun and breeze is like the wind.
But here to shoot the breeze is to have a nice little conversation just to talk about nothing.
Okay. So I'm not really doing anything just talk a little bit.
Right. So if we think about this in the context of this sentence,
it's, you know, you go out for your cigarette break 10 times a day to shoot the breeze.
Okay. So this means you go outside and you just talk about nothing and whatever.
And it's almost like you're wasting time just talking. Okay. So shooting the breeze.
You can say, oh, we were just shooting the breeze.
This happened. It's a conversation. Nothing important.
Okay. And our last phrase for today.
Forgive and forget. Let's forgive and forget.
Let's forgive and forget. This is these words again like the last phrases.
Go together.
For given forget. So I could say this to you Mark. I say,
I know you've been fighting with your brother for 10 years. I say,
Finally, just forgive and forget. I mean, just put everything behind you and try and start again.
Okay. Let it go. Yeah. Forgive the person. Forget about it.
Move on. Okay. Forgive and forget. Very good. So very interesting phrases.
I think they're very useful. And this is very colloquial English, right?
Absolutely. This is stuff that you're going to hear all the time,
but maybe not all together, right?
Right. Right. The same time. Definitely though.
Very helpful for interacting with foreign friends and colleagues.
Very good. So let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back.
Hey, Mary, can you cut that out?
Cut what out? I'm not doing anything.
The tapping of your pen on your desk.
It's driving me crazy.
Fine.
By the way, would you mind not serving your coffee every time you have a cup?
I don't slurp my coffee. And plus, how can you hear it when you're shouting into your phone all the time?
You've got to be kidding me. You're complaining about me talking on the phone.
When you go out for a cigarette break, ten times a day to shoot the breeze.
Look, we have a lot of accumulated anger from working in these conditions.
And it's probably okay to let off steam once in a while.
But it's probably not a good idea to keep it up.
I'm willing to forgive and forget if you are.
Fine. Let's call it truce.
I'll try to be more considerate and keep the noise down.
Yeah, I'll try to do the same.
So, I was wondering, do you want to go out to dinner Friday night?
So, do you ever see the TV show full house when you were a kid?
I did. I did. It was a puppet.
With the all-saint winds and all those, right?
Yeah, and Bob Sagitt. So, there was an uncle on the show, Uncle Joey.
Mm-hmm.
And he always used to say, cut it out.
Oh, yeah.
And he had like hand motions for it.
And so, cut it out as a way to say, kind of stop it.
Quit it. You're killing me. It's like using two funny.
Right.
I've never heard of this phrase. I always think of that early 90s.
Very early 90s.
Yeah. Well, it this whole situation with the office as well.
I think there was a TV show called the office, right?
Yeah, there was the British office and then there was an American version.
And it's also something about office life and how colleagues get on each other's nerves
and they play pranks on each other and everyone's kind of weird.
And everyone drives everyone else crazy.
Exactly.
No, it's funny because once you start working in an office full-time,
I mean, everyone's maybe had a little bit of office experience,
but when it's full-time, you spend more time with your colleagues than you do with your family.
Yeah.
It's really strange.
Amazing.
What makes you crazy? What drives you crazy?
And what stuff does it matter?
So, this is an interesting topic.
We really want to hear from you guys.
Many of you probably work at an office, so tell us.
So, come and tell us what drives you crazy,
or maybe what colleague is driving you mad.
You don't have to use names. You can just use nicknames, anyone.
Right. So, we'll be waiting for you at EnglishPod.com.
Leave questions in comments and we'll see you guys next time.
Yep. Bye everyone.
Bye.