Hello English learners. Welcome back to English pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson talking about appearances.
That's right. We are going to change or somebody wants to change their appearance and they're going to have surgery.
Well before we get started let's look at what kind of surgery they're having in today's vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview.
All right, so today we're going to be talking about plastic surgery specifically.
Plastic surgery. So why plastic? I have no idea.
I don't either. No. Well basically plastic surgery is, you know, the surgery for your appearance.
Right. It's not really for health reasons. That's right. And sometimes they add things to you.
Sometimes they take things away, but they're not for your health. They're not for your heart or your lungs.
Right. It's for your appearance.
And also called cosmetic surgery. Right. And we'll be hearing that later. But cosmetic means
having to do with your appearance like cosmetics. Right. Exactly. All right. So we're going to be talking
about this. Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back.
What are you doing? Look at me. I'm look so old. I look as if I was 30. Come on.
Stop being so vain. You look great. You are beautiful. Yes, I am. But I think it's time for some plastic
surgery. I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin. See? I don't see any wrinkles or sagging skin.
You're 25. Stop being ridiculous. Besides, I think that people who get Botox have face lifts or
tummy tucks look weird. Doesn't look natural. Whatever, I think I'm going to get low-pace
suction and a nose job and some breast implants as well. I think you need to get brain surgery.
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery. You look amazing. I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this. I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to do that. You're fine the way you are and you have guys
all over you. Plus, plastic surgery hurts. Really? Yeah. When I got my nose job, I was black and
blue for a week.
All right, we're back. So yeah, they think this girl really wants to get this surgery.
But she doesn't seem to know why. She's just like, I'm in a bad mood. I want surgery.
That's the worst reason. And it's pretty painful for what I hear. Expensive and painful and
potentially dangerous. Yeah. We'll talk about that at the end. All right. So why don't we start with
the words that we saw that are all related to surgery in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. Okay. Well, this first one might be the reason for surgery, not in the
Sicily, a kind of surgery. If someone is vain. Okay. So if a person is vain, this is an
adjective. That means that they are very, they care too much about their appearance, right?
Right. And they care so much that they only care about themselves. So do I look good? I love my face.
My arm. I look so good. So a person who is vain thinks very highly of them. So. Okay. Very good.
And well, this person, I think, wanted to get surgery as well because she said she had wrinkles.
Okay. Rinkles are little lines on your face. So maybe on your forehead or next to your mouth.
And generally, when we get older, people get more and more of these. Right. So you would say you have
even you have wrinkly skin when you're in the bath. For too long and you look in your hands,
they look like raisins. You have wrinkly skin. That's right. Rinkles are a little lines in your skin.
All right. And well, you have wrinkles as you sit around your mouth and eyes. And sometimes
under your eyes, you also have some sagging skin. Or under your chin. Under your chin as well.
Yeah. That's right. So sagging means coming down means it's heavy. It's like hanging. Yeah.
So sagging, something sagged. It's heavy. It pulls down. But if you have sagging skin, that means your
skin is no longer tight. It's kind of loose in it hanging. Following off your face. Okay.
And a well, a new popular treatment that is not really surgery is this Botox. That's right.
So Botox is something that women and some men do every couple of months. I think and they have to
get shots. Right. They're like injections. That's right. And they tighten your skin. And so you
can get Botox in your your face or your forehead or your eyes. And it makes you look younger for a
couple of months. I've heard that they also put them in their lips to make them like fuller. Right.
That's right. And sometimes you can say that someone's had too much Botox because they can no longer
smile or they can't stop smiling. Exactly. And well, very related to this is also when people get a
face lift. Okay. A face lift. So that means that a doctor, a plastic surgeon will tighten the skin
on your face. So he'll pull your eyes and your the skin next to your ears to make your face look
younger. Right. So that's called a face lift. So it's kind of take away those wrinkles, right?
Or the sagging skin. Right. Lift means to pull up the opposite of sag. Very good. All right. So
this dialogue has a lot of rich vocabulary related surgery. So why don't we listen to our dialogue
again? And we'll be back with the second part of language. Take away to explain a little bit more.
What are you doing? Look at me. I'm look so old. I look as if I were 30. Come on. Stop being
so vain. You look great. You are beautiful. Yes, I am. But I think it's time for some plastic
surgery. I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin. See? I don't see any wrinkles or sagging
your 25. Stop being ridiculous. Besides, I think that people who get Botox have face lifts
or tummy tucks look weird. It doesn't look natural. Whatever, I think I'm going to get lipase
suction and a nose job and some breast implants as well. I think you need to get brain surgery.
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery. You look amazing. I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this. I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to do that. You're fine the way you are. And you have
guys drooling all over you. Plus plastic surgery hurts. Really? Yeah. When I got my nose job,
I was black and blue for a week. All right. We're back. So what other surgical procedure is in
store for us? Well, now the big ones. So we've left the face. I'm talking about the rest of the body.
All right. The first one is a tummy tuck. Okay. So a tummy tuck. What is that exactly?
Well, let's look at these two words by themselves because maybe tummy people have heard before
this is another way to say stomach. Usually children say tummy. Right. My tummy hurts. My tummy
hurts and doctors they'll say stomach. But the the name of this surgery is tummy tuck because
tuck means to to put in or to fold. And so my mom used to say tuck in your shirt. You know,
when your shirt comes out of your pants and that means you put it back in. Well, a tuck means
to fold your stomach under. It means to make your stomach look smaller and they put staples or I
think they they sell you up. Yeah. They sell you up. It's pretty painful, right? I've heard that.
Usually this is because somebody got a liposuction for example. And that's our next word.
Liposuction. Okay. Lipo. That's kind of fat, right? Yeah. And suction means to pull like a vacuum.
So that's basically what they do. They open the person up and kind of use a sort of vacuum type
device and suck all the fat out of the stomach or the balcony areas. You know, the love handles
that are also called. And this way they remove all this excess fat. And because they do this,
sometimes the skin since it's been stretched out because you were a little bit fat, they need to do
to they need to have a tummy tuck. That means to hide the extra skin, extra skin to kind of
that's very heighted. So these two words, these two procedures actually go hand in hand because maybe
if you're very fat, you get a liposuction, but that doesn't solve your problem because now you
have all these all this sagging skin of your stomach. That's right. So you have to have a tummy tuck.
Right. Well. All right. So yeah, very very dangerous procedure I've heard as well, right?
And they usually only do it with people who are very very fat that means dangerously fat because
if you do it on a skinny person, you could really hurt them. Yeah. Of course, fat is also necessary for
our bodies. All right. So now moving back up to the face again, a very common procedure. I think
one of the most common ones is a nose job. A nose job. And so nose job is very colloquial. You'll
hear this on the TV. Nose job means to fix someone's nose to change the shape or appearance of
their nose. And so oftentimes people with really big noses want smaller nose. Right. And so the
doctor will take some bone away and we'll put the skin back. Yes. And that's right. So this is
called a nose job or formerly known as like a nose surgery, right? That's right. Rhino Plasty is the
right. So plastic. And actually I've heard it's very painful because they have to break your nose
for they fix it. Exactly. Wow. I can't believe people do this. All right. And well,
the one of the very common ones among women most likely is our breast implants. That's right.
So breast implants. Am I allowed to say, boob job? Yeah, you can. Well, the very common phrase for this is
boob job. Right. Boob is a very colloquial term for breasts. Mm-hmm. And breast implants are
an implant is something that you put inside something. Mm-hmm. Okay. And so a breast implant is
a piece of silicone. Mm-hmm. So it's um it's it's like plastic, but it's more like a liquid plastic.
Yeah, just imagine like this big plastic bag with like gel right inside of it. And they put that
inside a woman's chest to make her breasts bigger. Right. And so these are very, very popular
surgeries breast implants. Right. Exactly. I guess many models and many, many types of different
types of women get breast implants. That's right. And the the verb there is to get. So she had, she got
breast implants. Right. Okay. Because they're things. Very good. All right. So I don't we listen to
a dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
What are you doing? Look at me. I'm look so old. I look as if I was 30. Come on. Stop being
so vain. You look great. You are beautiful. Yes, I am, but I think it's time for some plastic
surgery. I'm tired of these wrinkles and sagging skin. See? I don't see any wrinkles or sagging
skin. You're 25. Stop being ridiculous. Besides, I think that people who get Botox have facelifts
or tummy tucks look weird. Doesn't look natural. Whatever, I think I'm going to get low-pace
suction and a nose job and some breast implants as well. I think you need to get brain surgery.
I honestly don't think you need cosmetic surgery. You look amazing. I thought you were my friend
and would support me on this. I just want to feel better about myself and feel more attractive.
You don't need plastic surgery to do that. You're fine the way you are and you have guys
drooling all over you. Plus, plastic surgery hurts. Really? Yeah. When I got my nose job,
I was black and blue for a week.
All right, we're back. So as you mentioned, all of these surgeries are very painful and very expensive,
right? They are. The plastic surgery industry is huge. And I was just reading an article that said
Redus are becoming very popular. So there are doctors who perform redus. That means redo a surgery.
That's right. They're fixing other other surgeries. Because oftentimes, you know, people go in,
they say I want a nose job, they get a nose job and then it's not the nose, they want it.
And so they have doctors now who specialize in fixing former surgeries. Wow. Yeah, I've heard
also a lot about the plastic surgery tourism industry where people get offered a package, for
example, to go to countries like Argentina where they have good doctors and it's very inexpensive
compared to the states to get plastic surgery. And it's also a popular now in Asia, I believe they're
traveling to Hong Kong to get plastic surgery done. Interesting. Yeah, I know. It's one of those things
that, you know, if you have the money and you really feel that you want to improve your appearance,
then, you know. But isn't an improvement? I don't know. It is a little fake. Yeah, it is a
little bit fake. Like, for example, but it does help people with their self confidence, right?
Sometimes, for example, with the case of breast implants, a women feel very, very self-conscious about
them having smaller breasts. They want to get better breasts and they feel more confident, happier,
and, you know, stuff like this. So I guess if it helps and if you really want it, you know,
everyone's to their own. Well, I'm curious what our users think about this. Have you had
plastic surgery? Would you like to have plastic surgery? Let us know on our website EnglishPod.com.
Right. We'll see you guys there. Until next time. Bye. Bye.