Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco
and my name is Katherine and it's the holiday season so that means more Christmas songs for you guys
That's right and today we're going to be taking a look at a very famous song, very relaxed
but very beautiful song called Silent Night
Yeah this is one of those songs that you hear everywhere but unlike jingle bells which is like
jingle bells, jingle bells, not you know, vegetarian, uplifting and shopping music
This is more as Marco said calm, peaceful, almost church music so
Right we're going to find out what the words mean in this very classic song
Right it's classic and very religious because it has a connotation towards the Catholic religion
So why don't we listen to the song and then we'll be back to explain it
just
Silence
Not
Holy
With
round young virgin mother and child
holy infant, so tender and mild
sleep in the house
all right we're back so now let's take a look at this song line by line
so we're not going to do the standard format of picking out words
we're going to do it line by line to kind of get a good feel for this dialogue
so first of all some background, okay so the 24th the evening
Mary and Joseph are looking for a place to stay
Mary the virgin mother of God is going to give birth to a baby
right and they need a place to stay so finally they find a place
it's not a hotel it's not a house
it's like an inn
yeah well it's actually the steables for the end
and so what the song is celebrating is what happens afterwards after the baby
Jesus is born so that's where we are
all right so the first line says silent night holy night
right do you know it's holy that means it's religiously special it's important
okay all is calm all is bright
so we talk about bright light sometimes something is bright if it gives a lot of light off
and well the next line is very interesting because it says
round yon virgin mother and child now you see this first two words there
round yon what is round yon so round comes from around
okay yon means over there so around over there so over there we've got two people
okay we've over there we've got the virgin mother and her child
okay so the virgin mother is Mary right
and the child would be Jesus
exactly and this is holy infant so tender and mild okay so what is an infant
an infant is a baby some some some baby that's just been born so we can say
that infants are very very delicate you have to be very careful when you hold
an infant but in this case a holy infant is Jesus he's special for religious reasons
okay and when they say that he's tender and mild what does he mean by that
you talk about tender things when you're talking about things that are soft
okay delicate gentle or sweet
okay and something that is mild or someone that is mild is very quiet and calm
and gentle so not making much noise so the baby was is very sweet
very tender and wasn't crying or making a big you know fuss exactly
and then we have a sleep in heavenly peace sleep in heavenly peace
well the baby is quiet because the baby is sleeping so you're saying sleep and
heavenly peace that means you know may the peace of heaven because heaven is a very
peaceful place the most peaceful place may that peace be with you when you're sleeping
okay very good right and moving on we have silenite holy night again
but then they say shepherd's quake at the site so what is this shepherd
we know that there these are people that take care of sheep
that's right they make the sheep move from one place to another and but it says
they quake at the site so they quake at the site of what
well quake we often say quiver in one's boots or two quake means to shake
to win your nervous okay so you know when you're going to make a speech in front of many
many many people your hands start to shake that's called quaking okay to quake
alright so shepherd's quake they're nervous at the site
well the site is the noun for seeing something the site of Jesus the baby okay
glories stream from heaven a far so glories stream from heaven a far
okay the verb here the action word is too stream to stream okay that means to come
down okay so to come down and kind of big amounts so we have glory glory so
happiness and joy and glory and good things coming down from the heaven so
lots of positive good things coming down from heaven and where is heaven a far
a far so the key part of this is the word far it's far away right
a far is an old word we used to describe something that's far away so the
heavens a far the heavens that are far away are giving us all of this joy and happiness
okay and then the song says heavenly hosts sing aleluia so heavenly hosts those are
bodies or people or spirits and angels they're singing aleluia so aleluia is a
word that we often use in the Christian religion that comes from Greek actually
really yeah so aleluia's a Greek word and it means celebrate joy
amen okay aleluia it's something you're happy about aleluia aleluia and then they say
Christ the Savior is born now we have this the Savior what is it who is a Savior
what is a Savior it's a very good question the Savior is aware we only read
well we don't hear that often but you've heard the word to save before so for example
I fell into the water and Marco jumped in and saved me so I would be a Savior
Marco with my Savior he saved me but in this case Savior refers to the Bible and
the things that Jesus did later so we say in Christianity he saved people
the human kind so he is the Savior Christ the Savior alright and then our next
verse it says silent night holy night son of God loves pure light
radiant beans from thy holy face so we have radiant beams and then we have this word
thy so these beams that is like a beam of light right it's like a line of light
but you know how how light is clear so a beam of light is something that comes
down in a straight line so you can see it so for example when I turn on a
flashlight and there's a line of light that's a beam okay and radiant
it's very it means it's very bright it's very clear clear and it's strong and it's
coming out from that one place okay and what about this word thy it's very
popular like form old English right it's an old English form of saying you
you right so in the olden days in English we had different ways of saying
the word you okay and so thy is one of those words and you hear this
very often and so in this sentence we're saying radiant beams from thy holy
face we're now starting to talk to Jesus because we're referring to him you
radiant beams light is coming out of your face your whole day now I think you can
probably see this thy and thou in Shakespeare for example right exactly Shakespeare
the Bible prayers and all sorts of old books and poetry okay and then we say
with the dawn of redeming grace so what is to redeem to redeem is to find
value in something that didn't have value before okay so maybe I have a ticket
for some okay I want a small lottery ticket five dollars I go to the store to redeem
my money the paper is worthless but it's worth something when I redeem it okay
so Christ the Redeemer when he saves people he redeems them okay he gives
them value again very good so it's a very profound song right and it talks
about as we say about Jesus about angels and it's very very religious so it's a
great song and it's well it's a very popular song and well even if you don't
share the religious connotation that the song has is still is very popular in
North America many parts of the world so why don't we have a listen to the song
one last time
so when I was a little girl at school we had to sing this in German
so I know that there are some other countries that have the same song with words
so it's the same rhythm and everything but just in German and is it this pretty much the same idea
the same words yeah almost exactly the same just in the translated form so I'm maybe it came from
German I don't know that because it seems to be pretty old right but it is a very common
song during Christmas and even many times Christmas carolers will go around in an
old school and sing the songs in different places exactly and it's a really beautiful song
one of my favorites and I'm not a religious person so I don't really like it for the religious
perspective that it gave us but I do think that it's just one of those beautiful
classics on the season very warm music is nice and it's all right so an interesting
song and I'm sure we're going to have a lot of questions and comments about it so we expect
to see you guys on our website EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there
happy holidays and enjoy. Bye bye.