Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and we are your English language guides here in EnglishPod.
That's right and today we're going to be taking you to Christmas morning. It's Christmas day.
Oh, one of the best times of the year you wake up. You smell the good smell of delicious eggs and bacon and there's presents.
Hey, I guess that's when you're a kid. I guess when you're an adult, do you really get excited when you wake up for Christmas?
Hell yeah. Sure do. Yeah, I sure do. I love Christmas morning. Yeah, especially I think because of the special breakfast you get like pancakes, scrambled eggs.
But anyways, we're going to be taking a look at a situation here where a kid is opening Christmas presents and we are preparing a meal for Christmas because that day people are going to come over. So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time.
Dad Dad Dad, Wake Up. It's Christmas.
Wake up, it's Christmas!
To me, it's too early for this. Look, it's six in the morning. Go back to bed.
No way!
Santa already came and left all our presents. Can we go open them, please? Please?
Of course we can, honey. They'll come on get dressed.
Fine, not like Santa brought me any gifts.
They'll, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree. Awesome!
All right, Timmy, knock yourself out. We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right. It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
So everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes, ingredients for the gravy, and of course, yams.
My dad, off it to bring the egg yolk so we should be set.
All right, we're back, so there were a couple of different and interesting words there.
So let's take a look at them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, this first word is not a very happy word.
It's a word that we try not to use too much around the Christmas season, but sometimes you're just tired of people.
Because the holiday is all about people doing stuff.
Someone who's not being very happy, someone who's a little bit grumpy is called a grouch.
Okay, so a person that's not very happy, not very friendly is a grouch.
I don't want to open presents.
This is stupid.
Okay, that's a grouch.
Okay, so a person is a grouch or you can act like a grouch or be a grouch.
Don't be a grouch.
All right, and well, they were talking about heading to the market to buy something for dinner.
So to head to.
Okay, to head to is a way to say to go towards someplace or to go somewhere.
All right, so if I'm driving my car and you ask me where I'm going, I'm saying, oh, I'm heading to the bank.
All right, so to head to means, to be on your way somewhere, I'm going somewhere.
It's a way to say that you're in the process of going.
You can't say next year I will head to Alaska.
It doesn't make as much sense.
You usually say, I'm heading the bank or...
Let's head to the market.
OK.
And well, they were talking about heading to the market
because they are hosting Christmas dinner.
So, too host.
To host is a, well, it's a very important holiday term.
It's a verb.
You do it.
And it means that you are the person who has the special dinner
and your friend and family, they come to your house.
OK.
So we could say, this Christmas, I'm hosting the dinner at my house.
So I want everyone to come to my house and eat.
All right.
And it can also be a noun, right?
You can say, I am a host.
Exactly.
The host of this dinner.
Right.
And it doesn't have to be holidays either.
You could say, hey, Marco, how about you host a dinner next week?
Oh, come.
Right.
OK.
Offering wine.
All right.
So to host a dinner or to host a party, et cetera.
And our fourth word for language takeaway
is probably the most popular drink during the Christmas
season, egg, nug.
OK.
It sounds kind of disgusting.
Yeah.
A drink with egg.
But it's a very popular creamy, eggy drink.
It's very thick and it's cream colored.
And normally, you add a little bit of rum.
OK.
So make it up.
Yeah.
You drink it warm.
And it's kind of just a thick warm alcoholic beverage.
That's very, very popular.
And my dad loves it.
Very Christmas, right?
You don't have it.
Like, I am any other day.
No, you wouldn't want to.
It's too heavy.
But it's very, very popular.
Like, the days before Christmas and on Christmas.
OK.
So egg nug.
Very good.
So I think we should take a look at the dialogue again.
And we'll be back soon with Lizzy Builder.
Dad, dad, dad.
Wake up.
It's Christmas.
Timmy, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed.
No way.
Santa already came and left all our presents.
Can we go open them, please?
Please?
Of course we can, honey.
Bill, come on, get dressed.
Fine.
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
Bill, honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
Awesome.
All right, Timmy.
Knock yourself out.
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
So everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes.
Ingredients for the gravy and of course, yams.
My dad offered to bring the egg nog so we should be set.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at a couple of phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay, so this first phrases of phrase that I often heard as a child because I never
wanted to go to sleep.
So I'd go downstairs and my parents would say, Katherine, go back to bed.
Go back to bed.
Okay, go back to bed.
So this is just a very common colloquial spoken way of saying, go back to sleep.
Go to sleep.
Don't be awake.
So you can say go to sleep or you can say go to bed or if somebody has gotten out
of bed, you say go back to bed.
Exactly.
And so parents often use this with their kids because they want their kids to sleep.
You can also say to about someone who's up at night worrying and you say, come on, go back
to bed.
Relax.
Okay.
So then we also saw this phrase knock yourself out.
All right, Timmy, knock yourself out.
So what is this?
Knock yourself out.
Well, I'm not really sure where this phrase comes from.
I mean, to knock is like, to knock on a door, right?
But to knock yourself out, if I think about it, it probably means that you hate yourself
in the head and you fall over.
But the real meaning of this is go have fun.
Okay.
Have as much fun as you can have.
Have as much fun as you want.
Go knock yourself out.
So the parent is saying, hey, Timmy, go have as much fun as you want just go do it
and enjoy yourself.
Yeah, like go up in all these presence have all the fun you want.
All right.
And then we saw another phrase when they finished talking about dinner and all the things
they have to buy, they said, we should be set.
We should be set or we are set.
Well, this is funny because she says, well, my dad's going to bring the egg
knock so we should be set.
Which means we should have everything we need.
So we don't need anything else.
We're ready.
Everything is good.
Exactly.
So we can say we are set.
I'm set.
Are you set?
It's the way to say, are you ready?
Are you prepared?
Do you have everything you need?
Okay.
So I also need this one.
I'm going on a trip.
Right.
Are you set?
Did you pack everything?
Are you all set?
Yeah.
All right.
I finished packing.
I'm all set.
I'm ready to go.
All right.
What raises there as well?
Why don't we have a look at our dialogue for the last time?
Dad, dad, dad.
Wake up.
It's Christmas.
Tell me, it's too early for this.
Look, it's six in the morning.
Go back to bed.
No way.
Santa already came and left all our presents.
Can we go open them, please?
Please?
Of course we can, honey.
They'll come on, get dressed.
Fine.
Not like Santa brought me any gifts.
But honestly, you can be such a grouch sometimes.
Look at all these presents under the Christmas tree.
Awesome!
All right, Timmy.
Knock yourself out.
We should get ready and head to the market to buy everything for Christmas dinner tonight.
Yeah, you're right.
It's the first time we're hosting Christmas dinner at our house.
Everything has to be perfect.
I got the list right here.
Ham, turkey, mashed potatoes.
Ingredients for the gravy and of course, yams.
My dad offered to bring the egg yolk so we should be set.
All right, we're back.
So as you mentioned, Christmas morning is great.
You open presents and well, breakfast and it's time to be together with parents or family.
But as in this case, you can be a little bit of a grouch because you're just out of
kind of tired because you had Thanksgiving and November and then Christmas and now you're
having New Year's.
So you're kind of just like, yeah, the holidays season can be exhausting.
And I know a lot of families have a special dinner on the 24th.
That's Christmas Eve.
And then by the time it's Christmas Day, the 25th, you're exhausted.
You didn't get any sleep.
You might have had too much to drink last night.
And so it can be very tiring.
Also because the kids always get up way too early, like six o'clock.
Right, to open their presents, right?
And then they'll be playing with their toys all day and you'll be, you'll have a headache.
But it's a great season to spend time with the family.
And well, we want to know how you spend your Christmas Eve and your Christmas morning.
So why don't you come to our website, EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments
there as well.
We're looking forward to hearing from you again, happy holiday season.
Until next time.
Bye.