Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have another holiday lesson for you guys. It's an intermediate
level lesson but it's not about Christmas and it's not about New Year's. So what's this holiday
moment? It's like a afternoon Christmas but before New Year's.
Okay so let's look at this holiday and today's vocabulary preview.
Very cabbiery preview. All right so as you noticed in the title this is called boxing day.
Right so like fighting boxing.
Yeah kind of like boxes right it's more related to boxes.
Exactly so this is a this is a holiday that we don't actually celebrate in America.
It's celebrated in what are called commonwealth countries. That means countries that
used to be a part of Great Britain or that are a part of Great Britain so England.
Okay. Scotland, Canada, Australia and this is a day where well it's considered a holiday because
it's a bank holiday. That means all the banks closed. No one's at work. It's the day after Christmas.
So it's December 26th and it's traditionally a day when you give money or gifts to the poor.
Okay and so this is more or less what we're going to be talking about but
more modern right before it was like that but now it's kind of become this shopping thing right?
It has. It's a day when everyone goes to the sales after Christmas to return things or to buy new
things. So we're going to hear about this right away in today's dialogue and when we come back
we'll be talking about some of the phrases and words that you've heard.
What do you think of this one? Yeah so so. And this one? Two flashy.
Nah not two flashy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous?
Yes. Are you even listening? I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
And I'm trying to watch the game but you're yapping on about your new clothes.
Well I have to decide which gifts to keep in which to exchange for better ones when I go to the
box and day sales this afternoon. Well could you do me the favor of making this quick? It's the
third quarter you've been blabbering on since the first. Oh your precious game. You watch the same
game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at least three goals. Oh no you
didn't. You didn't just insult the sales where he seals did you? Why don't you just just go return all those
stupid clothes and not come back until his sales were over? I might just enjoy your stupid game
and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
All right great so we're back and interesting the the couple fighting right after Christmas.
Well I think it's very common to hear fights around the holidays. People are very stressed out
tired of of dealing with family and presence and all the stress right? Exactly. But we'll talk
about that a little bit later on right now. I don't we take a look at four key words in language take
away. Language take away. Okay these first two words are words that the wife uses in talking about
some of these clothes that she got as presents. So she says well she asks her husband is this too
flashy flashy. All right so you know flash like the camera flash right this big light. Now flashy
when you're talking about clothes or an object is it it's too noticeable right? It's too noticeable to
bright too loud. So for example a black shirt is not flashy. But an orange shirt. An orange shirt
with buttons and bells and black rhinestones diamonds that's flashy. All right okay flashy can also
mean something that is it's supposed to look expensive. Okay so that sweater was a little bit flashy
according to her. And but also she talked about another sweater being hideous. So hideous is an ugly
word and it means ugly. Ugly okay so I could say this sweater is hideous. That means it's not only
ugly it's really ugly. Okay it's more than ugly. All right a hideous sweater and moving on the guy
now was a little bit irritated and stressed out and he said you keep yapping on about your new clothes.
So what is this yapping on? Well Yapp is a sound like y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp y-yapp.
All right so yapping to yapp on about means to continue to talk and talk and talk about something.
Okay because he's watching the football game on TV and she's talking and talking and he's annoyed.
So this is rude to say stop yapping about this sorry stop yapping on about your game.
All right. It's very rude it means to stop talking I'm annoyed and well then he mentioned
another phrase that it's pretty much the same thing right blabbering on. To blabber to blabber on
about means to talk about something but to not really make sense okay so it's just worthless talk.
So you're just talking to talk you're not really saying anything interesting. Exactly and so
sometimes we make fun of people who blabber on about things because they're not important to us or they
sound stupid. All right okay so four key words there blabbering on yapping on why don't we
listen to them again in the dialogue.
What do you think of this one? Yeah so so. And this one? Too flashy.
Nah not too flashy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous?
I guess. Are you even listening I'm trying to have a conversation with you and I'm trying to watch
the game but you're yapping on about your new clothes. Well I have to decide which gifts to keep
in which to exchange for better ones when I go to the boxing day sales this afternoon.
Well could you do me the favor of making this quick it's the third quarter and you've been blabbering
on since the first. Oh your precious game you watch the same game every year and each year your
beloved hometown team loses by at least three goals. Oh no you didn't you didn't just insult the
sales where he seals did you? Why don't you just just go return all those stupid clothes and
not come back until his sales are over. I might just enjoy a stupid game and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas!
All right we're back so now we have a couple of different phrases that we want to look at on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. Okay so this first phrase is very closely related to the the days after
Christmas especially here I'm boxing day we've got someone who's talking about going to the stores
to the sales to exchange her gifts for better gifts. Okay it took change something for something better.
This is a very common construction it's an important phrase when talking about shopping.
So when we look at this construction you would say to exchange this sweater for a better one
of our larger one. Exactly so you can change the adjective the word that's describing it so you
can say it took change these shoes for bigger ones. I could also joke and I could say I'm going to
exchange my boyfriend for a better one. Right. He's being rude to me. Okay so to exchange
something for something else. Exactly. All right and then we saw another phrase that the husband
replied to when she offended him with his football team he said oh no you didn't.
Didn't what? I know I didn't what no you didn't what. All right so this like he said doesn't
make sense alone but some cultural context might help. In English we often say
say this phrase to me oh no you didn't just say that. Are you didn't just insult my team.
He's saying I can't believe you just said that. He's upset because what she said was rude or mean.
Okay okay so I could say you know Mark I think I could or sucks. Oh no you didn't.
I did just say I don't think so actually but it's usually a response right you have to
wait until somebody maybe says something mean or something that you know really hurts your
feelings or you don't agree with when you respond to this but you're usually very very offended right
when you say. Exactly it's always a response to a comment that has made you angry or upset.
Okay and our last phrase is when they finished talking and they were fighting she left and said
I might just just what? I know just what. See again these are common phrases but they don't seem
to make my sense alone. I might just so let's listen to this is a response again this is a response
to the line before it. Why don't you just just go and return all of those stupid clothes and not
come back until much later and she says I might just I might just do exactly what you just said.
Okay she's threatening him she's saying I might just go out and not come back for 10 hours.
All right I might just do that. Okay so that's a way to say what you said I might do that and I'm
threatening you. So again it's usually a response right or a threat as you said.
So I can say Marco why don't you just leave? All right I might just.
Oh what are they going to do in this studio now? All right so three interesting phrases there
why don't we listen to all the words and phrases again in our dialogue one last time.
What do you think of this one? Yeah so so. And this one two flashy.
Nah not too flashy. Oh and this sweater from my aunt isn't it hideous?
Yes. Are you even listening? I'm trying to have a conversation with you.
And I'm trying to watch the game but you're yapping on about your new clothes.
Well I have to decide which gifts to keep and which to exchange for better ones when I go to the
this afternoon. Well could you do me the favor of making this quick? It's the third
corner you've been blabbering on since the first. Oh your precious game. You watch the same
game every year and each year your beloved hometown team loses by at least three goals.
Oh no you didn't. You didn't just insult the sales where he seals did you?
Why don't you just just go return all those stupid clothes and not come back until a sales roll?
I might just enjoy your stupid game and Merry Christmas. Merry Christmas.
All right we're back so boxing day as you said is usually a commonwealth thing and the
United States you don't really have it right? We do not my family I don't know why but my family
sometimes celebrates that we have friends who come over and we have a nice boxing day meal but
I've been told that the tradition in commonwealth countries is to watch sporting events, local
sporting events and to go shopping for all these sales and bargains and exchange all those ugly
hideous annoying or bad gifts that you received at Christmas. Right so it's usually like the
after Christmas sales. Exactly so if you have any special boxing day traditions I'd be very curious
to hear them again not a holiday related to the sport boxing and spell the same way and it
looks the same but they're very different. No so if you have any stories or questions about the
things that we talked about today please do let us know on our website EnglishPod.com.
All right we'll see you guys there and until next time bye everyone.