Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson on about cell phones.
That's right. We're going to be buying a cell phone or also known as a mobile phone.
So before we jump into the dialogue, let's take a look at a specific type of phone on vocabulary
preview.
Very cablory preview. Well, the name of this phone is kind of funny. It's called a smart
phone. It's very popular these days. Things like the Apple iPhone or the HTC Hero.
These are examples of a smart phone. That's right. So basically a smart phone has additional
functions more than just a normal mobile phone. For example, you can check your email on a smart
phone.
Yeah. So the thing that makes a smart phone different from a normal mobile phone is that it's
like a small computer. You can do things like marcosets and emails or take photos
edit photos, use applications, things like that from your phone. Okay. So we're going
to be talking about smart phone. So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
Hello, sir. May I help you?
Yeah. I accidentally dropped my phone in the toilet.
I see. Well, you've come to the right place. We have over 100 models of more than 20
leading mobile phone manufacturers. Sounds good. I don't want it to be too expensive.
Maybe something mid range. We have this new HTC smart phone. It comes with the Android
OS so you can download applications. It also has a built-in camera, MP3 player and touch
screen. It works on the 3G network so you have fast access to the internet wherever you
are. What about Wi-Fi?
Of course. You can access the internet from any hotspot as well as from home. One last
thing. Is it waterproof?
All right. We're back. Now have you ever done this? Have you ever dropped your phone in
the water? Have you ever damaged the phone like that? Luckily, no, I'm not calm
wood, but I have a good friend who dropped his in the toilet and had to buy a new one.
Yeah. So this is not made up. It's actually more common than what people think. But we'll
get to that in a bit. Why don't we take a look at five key words in language takeaway?
Language takeaway. This first word is very important because in this particular
dialogue, we're talking about the HTC smart phone. This is a special kind of phone and it has
an Android operating system or OS. So Android is something that Google came up with and
they have this operating system that they're giving away for free. If you want to use it,
you can use it. You can make a whole new phone using this operating system. So the operating
system like Windows or what's the Mac one called? Tiger OS. Tiger OS. You have these
objects. Linux, yeah. Linux. These are these are like the interface that allows you to use
your computer and interact with it. And so they're different for different kinds of computers.
The same is true of a smart phone. Exactly. So that's what we're looking at today. If you
see this word Android, it's a proper noun and as Katherine mentioned, it's the name
of the OS or operating system developed by Google. So we're taking a look at a smart phone that
uses the Android OS. All right. Now this phone not only carried this operating system, but also
an MP3 player. That's right. So an MP3 player is a device that plays songs for you. So songs
can be stored as MP3s. A good example of an MP3 player is an iPod. An iPod, exactly. Or
and for many of you, you're listening to this podcast as an MP3 file through an MP3 player. So
that's a name we usually say MP3. Exactly. And another feature of this special smart phone is that
you can use it on the 3G network. What is a 3G network market? All right. So a 3G network
is a 3rd generation network, which allows more information to be sent. So not only can you send
voice like a normal cell phone network, but now you can send pictures or you can download information
like for example, your email. So this is a new 3G network that allows you to send more information
more data. Exactly. 3G, 3rd generation. And in addition to this, our customer wants to know about
Wi-Fi. Okay. Wi-Fi. You hear this a lot when you go to a hotel or a restaurant. They say we have
Wi-Fi access. Right. And Wi-Fi stands for wireless fidelity. So it's basically internet that has
no wires. You don't need to connect your computer to anything. You just log on and use the internet.
All right. So look out for that when you're in a cafe next time. Do they have Wi-Fi? Usually
there's a sign on the wall. And finally, this customer wants to know is this great phone water proof?
What's water proof? All right. So if you have a watch, for example, and you can take this
watch into a swing pool or the ocean, it means it's waterproof. So it resists water. It won't get
damaged if it gets wet. Great. So I could say that I have a waterproof jacket. Right. So that
means that when I go in the rain, my clothes don't get wet because they don't go inside the fabric.
Right. So and there are many things waterproof as watches or waterproof cameras. I've never really
seen a waterproof mobile phone though. That's a good invention, maybe. I would be. All right. So
those are five key words for language takeaway when we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back.
Hello, sir. May I help you? Yeah. I accidentally dropped my phone in the toilet. I see.
Well, you've come to the right place. We have over 100 models of more than 20 leading mobile phone
manufacturers. Sounds good. I don't want it to be too expensive. Maybe something mid range.
We have this new HTC smartphone. It comes with the Android OS so you can download applications.
It also has a built-in camera, MP3 player and touch screen. It works on the 3G network so you
have fast access to the internet wherever you are. What about Wi-Fi? Of course. You can access the
internet from any hotspot as well as from home. One last thing. Is it waterproof?
All right. We're back. So now we have three phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. This first phrase is a way of expressing something. So we're going to give you
a formula. The first word is leading. So leading mobile phone manufacturers. So when we use the word
leading, we're saying that it's leading an industry. That means the most important manufacturers in
a kind of industry. Right. So it's one of the biggest is one of the best. And if we want to change
the noun, we can say for example, the leading car manufacturer. Exactly. So in Japan, I wonder who the
leading car manufacturer is this is Toyoda. Toyoda. And we could also say that about clothing.
The leading clothing manufacturer in America is I have no idea cotton maybe. Cotton, right. So you can
use many other nouns. And well, if you want to drop the manufacturers, you can say the leading brand
in cosmetics or the leading supplier of medical equipment. So this means the person or the company
with the most that's the most important in an industry. Right. And going back to one of the features
of the mobile phone, we talked about the built in camera. Now this structure is interesting built in.
Well, we can say that things are built in when they are a part of something else. For example,
a built in camera is a part of a phone. It's not a camera and a phone to different devices. They're
put together. We can also say this about cabinets. You know, you can buy cabinets and you can
put them in your house and keep things in them. But we often have built-ins. That means that
they're stuck on the wall. You can't take them away. Right. So those are called built-ins because
they're part of the wall. So built in camera is a part of the phone. Right. So you can pretty much
use this structure with two products that are combined as one. For example, the cabinets that
Katherine mentioned or if your refrigerator has a television incorporated, right, you can say
this refrigerator comes with a built-in television. Or very common is the the laptop with built-in
speakers. So that means we don't have to bring speakers with us every time we want to use the laptop.
There's small speakers inside the computer. Right. Very good. And we have one last phrase. One last
phrase. One last thing. All right. So that's our phrase. One last thing. Oh, before you go one last thing.
So this is often said when someone's leaving a conversation. So I'm going to say, okay,
Marco, I've got to go running do something. I'll see you later. Right. Oh, really? One last thing.
Wait. What? Oh. Okay. So now I'll wait. So one last thing is a way to say, I know, wait. Hold on.
I have to tell you something. Something else. Mm-hmm. So yeah, as you say, you can use it as a fixed phrase.
One last thing or before I go one last thing. Can you take out the dog last thing? We have to talk about.
Right. And this was our last word. So why don't we listen to our dialogue at for the last time?
Hello, sir. May I help you? Yeah. I accidentally dropped my phone in the toilet.
I see. Well, you've come to the right place. We have over 100 models of more than 20 leading mobile phone
manufacturers. Sounds good. I don't want it to be too expensive. Maybe something mid range.
We have this new HTC smartphone. It comes with the Android OS so you can download applications.
It also has a built-in camera, MP3 player, and touch screen. It works on the 3G network so you have
fast access to the internet wherever you are. What about Wi-Fi? Of course. You can access the
internet from any hotspot as well as from home. One last thing. Is it waterproof?
Yeah.
All right. We're back. And I actually read somewhere that many girls have this accident because
they placed their mobile phones in their back pockets. So when they go to the bathroom,
they accidentally, the phone accidentally drops out and falls into the toilet.
I heard a different explanation with this common problem. Maybe not very appropriate.
Boys have this problem because they take their phone to the bathroom and they play with them when
they're using the bathroom. I've also heard this that you're maybe checking your messages or
checking your email when your bathroom. It falls. Just falls. Yeah. So I think boys and girls all have
this problem be careful with your phones. Those smartphones are still pretty expensive. Yes, they are.
All right. So if you have any questions, any doubts, you can contact us at EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see everyone there. Bye everyone. Bye.