Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about one of our favorite subjects, food.
That's right and in this occasion we are going to talk about Chinese food specifically, stir fry.
Okay this is a common dish in America and all over the world thanks to the many Cantonese
people who came over from Hong Kong or southern China and brought these delicious foods to our
cities.
So this is a very popular dish.
You'll be learning more about.
So let's jump right in and listen to today's dialogue and don't be worried if you don't
understand everything will be back in a moment.
Oh man I had the best supper last night.
My wife made a stir fry and it was amazing.
I love stir fry.
Crispy bite-sized vegetables covered in a mixture of soy sauce and oyster sauce, wilted
greens and fresh beans sprouts, throw in some onion and garlic in ginger.
It's almost lunch time.
I would die for a plate of stir fry right now.
Well you can keep the vegetables.
I'll take the meat.
The stir fry my wife made was really hardy with chunks of beef and slivers of bell peppers
and onion.
What?
You call that a stir fry?
More meat than vegetables?
It's the worst insult you could throw at a Chinese stir fry.
What a disgrace to the wok she fried it in.
What you had is equivalent to a fajita without the wrap.
Alright we're back so you've probably heard a lot of different vegetables and ingredients
in this dish.
So why don't we take a look at some of those now in language takeaway?
The first two phrases that we have actually are not words they're phrases are the names
of sauces that are very, very important to Chinese food.
The first one is soy sauce.
Okay soy sauce and it's this black sauce, right?
Very salty.
Very salty and it's made from soy beans.
Soy beans okay.
Soy so soy is a bean, a vegetable product but soy sauce is a thin black salty sauce.
Okay and it's very, very common to use it with Chinese dishes especially.
It's very related and usually have sushi with soy sauce.
Exactly so Japanese produce a lot of this too.
Alright and the other sauce that's not very common in our countries is oyster sauce.
Okay and oyster is an animal that lives in the sea.
It lives in a shell and we often eat oysters as a dish but oyster sauce is stinky, thick,
dark sauce that is very popular in Southeast Asian.
So Vietnamese food as well and Chinese food.
Okay so it's part of the ingredients of Chinese food.
It's really good.
It smells terrible but when you mix it with food and you cook it it smells as a very, very good flavor.
Absolutely.
Alright so that's the sauces.
Now apart from sauces we have some vegetables and some of those are bean sprouts.
Bean sprouts are very common vegetables especially in Asian food.
So you see a lot of these.
They're usually almost white, almost clear and they're crunchy and they have a little green
part at the end.
Right so they're like little straws with a little green point at the end.
So usually those go into your dish at the very end because they cook quickly.
Bean sprouts.
Okay.
Now if you're cooking stir fry what you need is the correct tools and the main tool that
you need is a walk.
That's right so a walk is actually a word that we take from like think Cantonese.
I'm not positive I don't speak Cantonese but in English we normally say frying pan.
But this is a special Asian frying pan that's very very large and very thin so foods
cook quickly in a walk.
Okay and it's not like the other pans where it has a big flat part.
It's very very round all over.
That's right it's almost like a bowl that sits on your stove and you cook quickly.
All right so that's a walk and well the guy compared his stir fry to a fajita.
Now fajita that's a that's not Chinese and it's not English.
Okay well it is English now it's actually the name of a food from Latin America.
So South America and Mexico and Central America I think more Mexican than anything and
it's like slivers of meat so thin strips of meat and vegetables that you eat in a tortilla
bread almost to take you is very thin corn or flour pancake.
Yeah so that that's a fajita.
It's kind of you've probably seen it a fajita or a or maybe what's commonly known as well
is a burrito which actually is also in American invention.
I don't think that exists in in Mexico.
No but they are delicious I think the word is Tex Mex.
Yeah Tex Mex Mex Mex Mex Mex Mex Mex.
All right so that's what we have for you on language takeaway.
So I don't we go back to our dialogue listen to it again and we'll be back shortly.
Oh man I had the best supper last night my wife made a stir fry and it was amazing.
I love stir fry crispy bite-sized vegetables covered in a mixture of soy sauce and oyster sauce
wilted greens and fresh beans sprouts throw in some onion and garlic and ginger.
It's almost lunch time.
I would die for a plate of stir fry right now.
Well you can keep the vegetables I'll take the meat.
The stir fry my wife made was really hardy with chunks of beef and slivers of bell peppers
and onion.
What?
You call that a stir fry?
More meat than vegetables?
That's the worst insult you could throw at a Chinese stir fry.
What a disgrace to the wok she fried it in.
What you had is equivalent to a fajita without the wrap.
All right we're back so now I think we should take a look at some of those phrases that
were used in this dialogue in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
The first phrase we have in fluency builder is a phrase that you will hear often when you watch
cooking shows.
So this is a term we say throw in to throw in.
Okay so throw in some vegetables or throw in some onion and garlic and that means to just
put it into the pan.
Put it into the pot.
That's right but it's very general or casual or easy.
You just add some.
If you want to be specifically can say please add one cup chopped onion.
Okay one cup of chopped onion but here's the throw in just means add casually.
Okay add some onion.
So we throw in all this ingredients and it sounds so delicious that the guy says I would
die for a plate of stir fry right about now.
So that means he wants some stir fry.
I would die for as a good thing.
It's a way to say I really want some.
It's an exaggeration.
It's not like you would actually die for it or you are dying to eat it.
It's just that it's an exaggeration means that you really really want it.
I would die for a new car.
My car is old and it never really works.
All right so you really want a new car.
Okay and well the guy obviously didn't really like what he was talking about and how
he cooked this stir frying he said what a disgrace to the walk she fried it in.
Okay this is a way to say that something is bad.
It's embarrassing so we can say that this food is a disgrace to Chinese food because
Chinese food is one way but this doesn't even look like Chinese.
So a disgrace a disgrace.
So the word disgrace means that something is bad or embarrassing to something else.
So a parent can say you're a disgrace to this family.
That means this family has a good reputation but what you did what you do these are bad
things they make us look bad.
They're embarrassing to us.
Okay so it's a very strong phrase.
This is a disgrace.
Okay a disgrace very good a strong phrase and you can use it if you ever want to talk
about someone or something in this way but remember it is pretty strong.
Right if you say somebody's a disgrace it's it's pretty insolent.
It's hurtful.
Okay so when we listen to our dialogue for one last time and we'll be back.
Oh man I had the best supper last night.
My wife made a stir fry and it was amazing.
I love stir fry crispy bite-sized vegetables covered in a mixture of soy sauce and oyster sauce.
Will the greens and fresh beans sprouts throw in some onion and garlic and ginger?
Mmm it's almost lunch time.
I would die for a plate of stir fry right now.
Well you can keep the vegetables.
I'll take the meat.
The stir fry my wife made was really hardy with chunks of beef and slivers of bell peppers and
onion.
You call that a stir fry?
More meat than vegetables?
That's the worst insult you could throw at a Chinese stir fry.
What a disgrace to the wok she fried it in.
What you had is equivalent to a fajita without the wrap.
All right so talking about Chinese food.
There are a lot of American inventions around
around Chinese food as well not only Mexican food.
For example it's very popular this dish chopped sui.
That's right chopped sui and I think I read somewhere that chop sui is actually.
Might have been a Cantonese dish that came from all of the leftovers and kind of garbage
in the kitchen where you would just fry it together and it was a cheap, easy meal.
So chop sui.
It kind of like an English.
It's like a pigeon English.
Well this dish is basically that right.
It's just a lot of meat.
Meat chunks mix with some vegetables and you have some chop sui.
Exactly.
And they're also this other thing that's very common people think about fortune cookies.
You think of Chinese restaurants and Chinese food.
You think of fortune cookies.
That's right but they don't have fortune cookies in China.
No, they do.
One of my biggest disappointments.
So fortune cookie is a small cookie with a message in that.
Message inside.
So you have a piece of paper.
So be careful when you're eating these.
You don't want to eat the paper.
But the paper sometimes says very strange things like you will have a
terrific number seven.
Right or something like that.
So that's why they're fortune cookies.
They usually talk about your future or what you're doing.
Beware of whales.
So but that's also an American invention that doesn't exist in China.
It doesn't really come from China.
Right.
Exactly.
So if you have any other information about food or we're always glad to hear it.
Because we're always hungry.
Or if you have a favorite Chinese food, please let us know our website is EnglishPod.com.
We can't wait to hear from you.
And we will talk you next time.
All right.