Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and welcome everyone. Today we've got an elementary level lesson for you.
It's all about sending things through the mail.
That's right. So maybe gifts, maybe letters. We're going to the post office. So why don't
we jump right into this dialogue? Let's listen to it for the first time and we'll be right back.
Hi, I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as well.
Very well. You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost?
Well, it depends. Do you want to send a via priority,
express or standard mail? What's the difference?
Well, standard mail can take up to 15 working days.
Priority is a bit faster and will arrive in about 5 to 8 working days.
Express is the fastest but it's also the most expensive.
It only takes 3 days and you can track your package online.
I see. Well, there's no rush. Please send it via priority mail.
Please be extra careful. The contents of the package are fragile.
Alright, it's a pretty simple dialogue. We want to send a package through the mail.
So why don't we take a look at some of those mail related terms in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
Alright, so the first item we're going to talk about in today's language takeaway is something
you can send. It's called a postcard. A postcard. Okay, so very popular among people who are
traveling and they want to send a postcard back home. That's right. So a postcard is something
that you usually buy at a tourist destination like Walt Disney World, for example,
and it has a picture on the front and some words on the back so you can write a letter on the
back of this picture. Uh-huh. So it's very simple. It's not really a letter. You don't put it in an
envelope. You just write whatever you want on the back of the postcard. But you do have to put a stamp
on it in order to send it. That's right. So stamp is our next word. A stamp comes in different
price ranges. That means that some stamps are more expensive than other stamps. This is like
money for the mail. So you have to buy the stamps and in order to prove that you have paid for the
letter that you want to send. You must place the stamps on the letter on the envelope or on the postcard.
Right? So depending on the size and weight it costs more. That's right. And usually you lick a stamp
to place it on the card so it doesn't fall off. True. That's right. You got to lick it. All right.
So as we talked about a package can be a letter at postcard. You place stamps on it and we need to
weigh the package to know how much money we have to pay. That's right. So sometimes a package is very
heavy if it's filled with books. For example, sometimes it's very light if it's filled with
clothes or feathers. And so to find out how much something weighs we have to weigh it. This is a verb.
Okay. So this is a verb, right? Two way. So you want to know how many kilos or how many pounds
this item has. Right. So we could say it weighs a lot or how much do you weigh? Okay. It's like this.
Very good. All right. Moving on. We have the different types of mailing speed, I guess.
Right. So we saw three via priority mail, express mail or standard mail. So let's go in part. So
let's go with the first one via priority mail. Priority is fast. It means priorities. Something
that's important. So I have many priorities at work. This means they're important. They're important.
So this letter has a certain importance. It's a little bit more important than for example the
other letters. That's right. But express is the most important the fastest. So to something that's
expresses fast like an express way is the fast highway. Express mail. Okay. So express mail is the fastest.
And now the normal cheapest mail is standard mail. Standard. So the word standard usually means
the average or the normal mail. And in this case it usually takes the longest. Mm. Okay. So
obviously standard mail is the cheapest express mail is the most expensive because it's the fastest.
That's right. So we've got all of those speeds now. Let's listen again to today's dialogue
and try and listen for the words we just talked about. And we'll be back in a moment to talk
about some important phrases. Hi. I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as
well. Very well. You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost? Well it depends. Do you want to send a via priority,
or standard mail? What's the difference? Well standard mail can take up to 15
working days. Priority is a bit faster and we'll arrive in about five to eight working days.
Express is the fastest, but it's also the most expensive. It only takes three days and you can
track your package online. I see. Well there's no rush. Please send it via priority mail. Please be
extra careful the contents of the package of fragile. All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at
three key phrases on fluency builder. Fluency builder. All right. So the first phrase today is one
that I like to use a lot. We say it depends. Okay. How much is this going to cost? Well it depends.
Okay. So the phrase could be it depends. So it depends. When do you usually use this?
Okay. If you ask me a question, I can have one answer, but maybe there's another possible answer.
For example, what are you going to wear tomorrow, Marco? It depends if it rains or not.
Okay. It depends. If it rains, I will wear a raincoat. If it's sunny, I will wear a normal coat.
So it depends means there is a situation or a circumstance that might change. And if it does,
my answer will change. Right. So it is a conditional it depends. For example, I can ask you what
are you going to eat tonight? It depends. If I exercise, I'm going to have a hamburger. And if I
don't exercise, I'll have a salad. Nice. Okay. So it depends. Now we have another phrase when they
were talking about how long it's going to take to mail something. He said standard mail can take up
two, 15 working days. So we have this little phrase there up to. Up to. So up to when you hear this,
two words together, that's an indication. It's a sign that we're talking about the maximum, the most.
Okay. So tomorrow, the temperature might go up to 24 degrees Celsius. Okay. So the temperature
maximum will reach 24. It could be maybe 22, 21, but not 25. That's 20. No, because up to means the top.
So you're usually dealing with numbers, right? For example, this coat can cost up to $150.
Wow. So the most I will spend is $150. So sometimes you have a number like this when we're talking
about sending a package. We can send packages that weigh up to 10 kilos, not more than 10 kilos,
though. Okay. Very good. And now for our last phrase to close off the dialogue, the guy said,
well, you know what? There's no rush. No rush. There's no rush. Okay. Well, the first word we
want to look at here is the word rush. And in this case, we're talking about sending a package
and the postcard, right? So does this person want it to arrive fast? He says, no. No. There's no rush.
Let's send it standard. It's cheaper. Okay. So maybe, so maybe your friend is like,
oh, we're going to be late. And you're like, no, there's no rush. There's no rush. We have one hour
before the movie starts calm down. Okay. So you're not in a hurry. No, there's no rush. Slow down.
It's okay. This is a good one to talk about with friends. If you're, or if you're working on a
project and work, you say, listen, there's no rush. Take your time. Okay. Very good. So let's go back to
our dialogue. Let's listen to it for the very last time. And we'll be back in a bit.
Hi. I would like to send this package to China and these postcards as well. Very well.
You will need some stamps for the postcards and I need to weigh that package too.
Great. How much is this going to cost? Well, it depends. Do you want to send it via priority,
express or standard mail? What's the difference? Well, standard mail can take up to 15
working days. Priority is a bit faster and will arrive in about 5 to 8 working days. Express is
the fastest, but it's also the most expensive. It only takes three days and you can track your package
online. I see. Well, there's no rush. Please send it via priority mail. Please be extra careful
the contents of the package of fragile. All right. We're back. So now, Catherine, do you
usually send postcards when you are abroad, when you travel? Yes. I love postcards. And actually,
I have some friends who have an amazing postcard collection. Oh, really? But it's not normal postcards.
No, whatever. They find the most ugly postcards and they buy them and they write silly notes
and they send them to themselves. Oh, really? I have the tradition of always sending my parents
and my grandparents a postcard when I abroad. That's so sweet. Yeah. So they have a collection of
all the places you've been there. Yeah. So all the time, wherever I am, the first thing that I try to
do if I'm in a cool place, I send them a postcard. And sometimes if I'm in a country in various cities
and there's some nice things in, for example, two or three cities, I'll send them three postcards.
That's awesome. So do they have a book at home with all of these postcards? Yeah, they do.
So, you know, I just send them a little thing. How I'm doing and how great it is and wish you could
be here, you know, little notes and then they have all the collection. It's really cool because
that way I've actually kept track a little bit of what year and what date I was in certain places.
Wow. Well, it's also nice because postcards you don't need to write a very long note. There's
no space. You just write a short note. You say hi. How's the weather? Miss you. Wish you were here.
Right. Okay. So that's all the time. We have for today, but let us know if you've had any
inconveniences at the post office. I actually hadn't won once. I couldn't send batteries through
the mail. Be great. They have acid apparently. Oh yeah. So it's very difficult to send. So maybe you've
had a situation like this before. Let us know EnglishPod.com. We'll see you guys there. Bye everyone.