Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very dramatic intermediate level lesson for you.
That's right. Today we're going to take a look at how a court works for example in the United
States. So you see that in movies and TV shows a lot, you know, the judge and all that.
That's right. Many of you have seen the movie The Firm or 12 Angry Men. These are classics
in, you know, courtroom drama as we say. So today we're in a courtroom and there are many
characters who are trying to determine if this person is innocent or guilty. So let's take a
lesson and find out what's going on.
Your honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury. My client Robert Malone has been accused of a
crime he did not commit. The prosecution has accused my client of being a pickpocket.
I know we have heard the testimony of many people here today. People who claim the defendant
my client stole their wallets. I feel sorry for these victims. I really do. But my client is innocent.
Let's look at the facts. Number one, these so-called witnesses did not actually see the
defendant steal anything. Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not have any of the stolen
wallets. There is no evidence. Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I ask you to think
carefully before giving your verdict. Look at the facts. Look at the evidence.
My client is innocent. Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, have you reached a verdict?
Yes, your honor. Albert, it is not guilty.
Thank you so much. You were great. Thank you for all your hard work.
You're welcome, Robert. I knew your innocent so my job was easy. Take care of yourself, okay?
Thanks once again. Hey, where's my wallet?
All right, we're back. So you've probably heard a lot of technical words that are
specifically related to the courtroom, to lawyers, and the laws. So why don't we take a look at some
of those now in language takeaway? Language takeaway. The first language takeaway we're looking at
today is all about people. So people you will find in a courtroom. Who's the first person on
our list of markets? So the top person would be the judge. Now you didn't really see this word judge
in the dialogue, right? You did hear, though, the phrase, you're honored. Your honor. So your honor.
So that's how you talk to a judge. You always add your honor before it or something. That's right.
So you know, we say Mr. President, when we're talking to Barack Obama, but if we're talking to a
judge, he's a special person in American society. So we call him or her, your honor.
Your honor. Okay. All right, your honor, the judge. That's our first person. Okay. Who else do we have?
So we have the judge. And now we have a group of 12 people who will ultimately decide if the
person is guilty or not. That's right. So these people are normal. They come from all different
parts of society, and they will decide what to do with this person is he guilty or is she innocent.
This group is called the jury. Okay. So the jury is a group of normal citizens who will
listen to both sides of the story and will then decide if the person committed the crime or
didn't commit the crime. That's right. A jury. And big question is who's fighting? We have two
sides. Someone who is upset and someone who is defending themselves. The person who is upset,
this is the prosecution. Okay. So the prosecution has a group of lawyers that are called the
prosecutors, right? That's right. And they're trying to prove that that person committed the crime.
For example, I say that Marco burned down my house. I go to court. I say I am the prosecution.
I want him to pay me for my house. So I'm the prosecution. Okay. So you're trying to not only prove
that I committed the crime, but also trying to get me to pay for the damage that I caused.
Exactly. So in this case, the prosecution says this man stole my wallet. He's a big pocket.
And who's the pick pocket or maybe the pick pocket? Who's the other side of this? The defendant.
Defend defendant. Think about the word here. To defend is to stand up for yourself.
To protect yourself. Right. So the defendant says, listen, no, that's not true. I am not a pick
pocket. I didn't do that. So we have the prosecution and the defense. Okay. And the person who
might be guilty, the person who did the thing or didn't do the thing, is called the defendant.
Okay. So in your example again about the crime that maybe I burnt your house down or I didn't,
I would be the defendant. And my lawyers would constitute my defense. Yeah. They are your defense.
Okay. So very technical words, but the important thing to remember here is defendant.
All right. Good. So now we have one key element that is also a person we have the witness.
All right. So the basic idea, like you said, is we have the tell a story. My story is that you
burned down my house. And you say, no, I didn't prove it. I say, I can. Someone saw you with a lighter.
Okay. So this person is my witness. That means that he or she saw what happened. So someone who
sees a crime is a witness to that crime. Okay. Very good. So a lot of people are in the court.
Room a lot of things are happening. So I think we should listen to the dialogue again.
And we'll be back to look at some more words on language takeaway part two.
Your honor. Ladies and gentlemen of the jury. My client Robert Malone has been accused of a
crime he did not commit. The prosecution has accused my client of being a pick pocket. I know we have
heard the testimony of many people here today. People who claim the defendant, my client,
stole their wallets. I feel sorry for these victims. I really do. But my client is innocent.
Let's look at the facts. Number one, these so-called witnesses did not actually see the
defendant steal anything. Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not have any of the stolen
wallets. There is no evidence. Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I ask you to think carefully
before giving your verdict. Look at the facts. Look at the evidence. My client is innocent.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury. Have you reached a verdict? Yes, your honor.
Avert it is not guilty. Thank you so much. You were great. Thank you for all your hard work.
You're welcome Robert. I knew your innocent so my job was easy. Take care of yourself, okay?
Thanks once again. Hey, where's my wallet?
I love what we do this. Somebody words. So much language to take away. That's right. So now we're
going to take a look at the second part of the language to take away. We have another set of four
words that we want to take a look at. Language takeaway. All right, the first is actually two words.
We have two opposites. Okay. She said earlier, the jury has to make a decision. The jury has to
decide is the defendant innocent or guilty. Okay. These are two important adjectives.
innocent. What does this mean? So if he is innocent, that means he did not commit the crime. He is
not responsible for what happened. He did not steal the wallets. Okay, so we often say babies are so
innocent. Right. They can't do anything. They can't do anything wrong. Right. So guilty would be the opposite.
That's right. So usually when someone is guilty, they're sad. They feel bad. You want them to pay
you and they go to jail. Yeah, in bad situations they go to jail. If you burn down my house, of course,
you're going to go to jail. All right. So guilty means you did a crime. You did a bad thing.
So we talked about the prosecution and the defense of the defendant and what happens is they also
present some key elements that will prove if the person is innocent or guilty. And those elements
are called evidence. That's right. So back to this idea, we tell a story. Maybe a witness can
help us tell our story. But as you say, evidence is stuff. It's things. So in the case of the house,
I could say you have matches and you smell like smoke and oil. This is evidence for me to use
to show that you are guilty. Right. So in this case, do we have any evidence? There's no evidence.
Says the defendant. Mm-hmm. Right. All right. So evidence is proof. It's proof.
It's proof. Yeah. And most of the times when you see movies or TV shows, they will find, uh,
I don't know, like maybe a fingerprint that's evidence or somebody's glasses, a cell phone. Exactly.
All right. So evidence. This is very important when you want to build a case. Finally, the end of
a trial we have a verdict. Now, what is a verdict? So a verdict is a final decision or a conclusion
when which the jury says, yeah, the person is guilty or he's not guilty. He's innocent. So we use
this word usually to reach a verdict. The jury reaches a verdict. Now it's interesting why we say
to reach because a jury is not just one person. A jury is many people. And so these people have to
decide together. They have to argue. They have to make a conclusion that everyone agrees on.
And this, this is to reach a conclusion to reach a verdict because they have to travel there. They
have to go together and figure it out. Right. That's very, very important. So the jury reaches a verdict.
And we did have one other phrase. It's very interesting. It doesn't quite fit with the other ones.
Uh, we heard this phrase from the defendant. The lawyer says, so these so-called witnesses didn't
actually see anything. Hmm. So he's so-called. So he's being sarcastic when he uses this phrase.
So called, right? That's why he's even his tone changes. These so-called witnesses. So it's a way
of expressing sarcasm. He's saying they say they're witnesses, but they're not really because they
didn't see anything. All right. So so-called means you say that they are, but they're not really.
Right. I could also say you're so-called lawyer thinks he can help you, but he can't.
Right. That means I don't think your lawyer is very good. I don't think he's a real lawyer.
Right. Or sometimes people say, my so-called friends stood me up last night.
Oh, so it's not really a friend. Not really a friend, exactly.
So called. All right. That's another good one. Let's listen to this dialogue one more time.
Really think about some of the words you heard today and we'll be back in a moment.
You're oner. Ladies and gentlemen of the jury. My client Robert Malone has been accused of
a crime he did not commit. The prosecution has accused my client of being a pick pocket.
I know we have heard the testimony of many people here today. People who claim the defendant,
my client stole their wallets. I feel sorry for these victims. I really do.
But my client is innocent. Let's look at the facts. Number one, these so-called witnesses did not
actually see the defendant steal anything. Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not
have any of the stolen wallets. There is no evidence. Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
I ask you to think carefully before giving your verdict. Look at the facts. Look at the evidence.
My client is innocent. Ladies and gentlemen of the jury. Have you reached a verdict?
Yes, your honor. All verdict is not guilty.
Thank you so much. You were great. Thank you for all your hard work. Your welcome Robert.
I knew your innocent so my job was easy. Take care of yourself, okay?
Thanks once again.
Hey, where's my wallet?
All right, we're back. So now at very interesting situation with the courtroom dramas
and I've heard that all the people in the jury have to agree in order for them to reach a verdict.
Right? So if one of them is not convinced that the person is for example guilty,
then they have to keep on deliberating. That's the word, right? That's right. So basically, the jury is
always alone in a room. Maybe they have a guard. But they're not supposed to talk to journalists or
friends of the defendant or anyone because their decision is supposed to be pure. So they talk.
And sometimes it takes 10 minutes. Everyone agrees. This person is guilty or if this person is innocent.
But sometimes they don't agree and it can be one day, two days, a week, two weeks.
A month trying to decide what to do. I remember in the OJ Simpson case, the jury took a
long time to figure out what they were going to do. And now we said that the jury are common
citizens. They're normal people. So what happens in their jobs? Like if they can't go to work
because they're doing this. Well, in America, this job is called jury duty. And so someone
will send you a letter and they say, listen, you need to come do jury duty. And you help be a part
of the jury. And your job, they can't make you come because this is a service for the government.
So it's above everything else. It's above you get your normal pay. There's no problem. You just
don't work. Okay. So they can't fire you if you're in jury duty for like five days or a month or whatever.
No, they can't. That's illegal. Wow. That's really interesting. But a lot of people I've heard
don't like to go to jury duty for some reason. It's, it's, it's, it's probably very boring. I've never
done it. But it's probably very boring. I would imagine so. All right. Well, that's a very interesting
topic. I'm sure in your countries, laws are handled differently. Maybe you don't have a court
room. Maybe you have like an England people where wigs and black robes. So let us know
how it works in your countries. We'll see everyone at our website English.com. And of course,
if you have any questions or comments, you can leave those there as well. See you on the website and happy
studies. Bye everyone.