Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and we're
shoe shopping again. That's right. We are going shoe shopping but this time it's a little bit more
complicated because we're getting women's shoes. That's right. So there are so many different kinds
of women's shoes. I'm not even sure I know them all myself but in this intermediate level lesson
we're going to cover some of the basics for you. That's right. So before we jump into this dialogue
we have a word that we want to preview with you today and let's take a look at it now on
vocabulary preview. Very cablory preview. Okay so we're shopping today for a certain kind of shoe.
It's not a sports shoe. It's a dress shoe. Okay that kind of doesn't make sense because a dress
is a noun. A shoe is a noun and so you're going to get a shoe that's a dress. No. A dress shoe
is a style of shoe. It means shoes that you wear when you're wearing fancy clothes. So it's kind
of like a formal shoe. A dress shoe is for a shoe that type of shoe that would go well with a dress.
That's right. Not sneakers but don't be fooled. This is not about dresses because men can
wear dress shoes too. That's right. It means shoes you would wear to a conference or to a wedding
or to church. So these are things that are a little bit fancier than everyday shoes.
Okay awesome so we're shopping for a dress shoe and there are so many types and styles of shoes
for women. So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a second.
Hi excuse me sir. I'm looking for a dress shoe. My usual pair that I've had for years have finally
been stretched out of shape. They didn't provide any support anymore. Sure. What kind of shoe
are you looking for? We've got strapy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps. If you're looking
for something a little more practical we've got Mary James, ballerinas. Show me some classic high heels.
Okay right this way. What color did you have in mind? Black classic. Of course we've got this
style here that is very popular because it's an open-to shoe you can wear it any time of the year.
It look great on everyone. Um too shiny and I wear pantyhose with my shoes so let's look for a
clothes to shoe. Okay these are very nice pair of leather shoes with a two-inch heel so they are
very comfortable. I don't like the pointed toes. Let me take a look at what else you have.
To high that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high in-step so I doubt
that one would fit properly. I don't want bows. I find slim backs very uncomfortable.
Those might as well be stillettos. Two modern, oh finally this is what I'm looking for.
Wood size. Seven and a half. Here we are. How does it fit?
Hmm not good. They're too tight. The length is right but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching
my toes and there'd be no room for my insoles. You know what? I don't think I have the patience for this
today. They just don't make shoes like they used to. I'll come back another time.
Have a nice day. MAM.
All right we're back so a lot of shoe styles as you noticed a lot of them are very, I don't know.
I don't even know what they are. So I don't we try and explain them now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So the first kind of shoe we've got here is very popular in the summer.
It's called a strappy sandal. A strappy sandal. So we know what a sandal is. It's kind of like
what you wear to the beach. It's a shoe that it doesn't really cover your whole foot just the bottom.
It's very open. And well what about strappy?
Strappy comes from the word strapp. So strapp is like a thin piece of fabric or leather that connects
other pieces. And so a strappy sandal means that it's it's got many of these different little
straps on it. Many lines everywhere that connect it. So it's very open. It's made of many different
thin pieces. Okay good. So we have a strappy sandal basically a sandal with many straps.
And well she went on to describe a sleek high heel. So this is a two-part thing here.
Sleek is an adjective which basically means really cool looking. Or more like it's it's pretty
and fancy and usually sleek things are also kind of simple like a Jaguar's very sleek car.
Okay. And so this is the adjective to describe the high heels. So we have high heels.
Okay. We have high heels that are kind of fancy shoe. Basically these are shoes that are not flat.
So the heel is very tall. That's right. So basically this is what a lot of women wear with dresses.
Basically the heel has a piece that kind of sticks out and makes the women look taller. So basically
it's like they're walking on the tips of their toes the entire time. Right and they make click,
click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click, click. But they're different kinds of heels.
Okay. High heels obviously means that they're tall. You can have low heels too. Those are shorter.
But high heels that are different kinds. One kind is pumps. Pumps. Okay. And the dialer. We actually
saw the salesman describe them as edgy pumps. So edgy what does edgy mean? Edgy means cool.
Core hip. So young people like to wear edgy clothes. Rock and roll kind of clothes. Not so much older people.
Okay. And pumps are a type of high heel you say. But what is the difference?
Well pumps basically are the kind of simple heel that a woman will wear with a pant suit or with a skirt to the
office. And so they usually have a closed toe and they're quite simple heels.
Okay. And the opposites or low maybe a little bit different from pumps would be the lettos.
So stilettos are a very special kind of heel. Stilettos. It refers basically to the difference in the
the back of the shoe where you have the heel. Because sometimes heels are kind of thick and heavy
they make the clunk sound. Right. But stilettos are very, very thin and very tall. Okay. So
stilettos heels. I think it's probably easier to walk with pumps rather than stilettos.
Stilettos are famous for being very, very hard to walk in. It's almost like the back of your
heel is a chopstick. Wow. I cannot imagine doing that. All right. So this is the classification of
our high heels. Why don't we move on now to Mary Jane's. Okay. So we've got high heels and heels.
We also have flats. These are flat shoes. So one important kind of flats is a Mary Jane. Sounds
a good name. Yeah. It is a name. Right. Mary Jane. Mary Jane. So what type of shoe is this? This is basically
a usually leather shoe but it can be different materials and it's round in the front and it has one
strap and they're very cute. Okay. Usually little girls wear Mary Jane's but they're pretty popular
these days with older people too. Okay. Okay. So they're round in the front. They are usually black
and they have one little strap that goes over the top of your foot. Mary Jane. Okay. All right.
So we've taken a look at Mary Jane's now moving on to I think it's a similar type of shoe.
Ballerina shoes. Well, ballerina shoes are similar because they're flat but that's about it.
Ballerina shoes are very, very thin. They're very, very weak. And usually they're
pretty simple. They're pink or white or black and they're almost like a slipper. Okay. So they
don't have the strap on top. No. They're stretchy and you just lie them onto your foot.
It's named after a dancer, ballerina's. You know the dancers who are pink and they put their
hair up and they spin around. And they're not hard on the bottom. They're usually quite soft and they're
always flat. So maybe these ballerina shoes. They're not the specific types of shoes for dancing
if you're a ballerina. But maybe they're more adequate for maybe walking around the house or
something you don't really go out hiking with ballerina shoes. No, you don't go out hiking.
But they're very popular to wear now to school or work. Okay. And the other type of shoes that we
had actually this was really confusing to me, a sling backs, sling backs shoes. Well, sling backs
can be hard because they can be heels. They could be pumps. But it basically refers to a part of the
shoe. So normal shoes, they cover the back of your foot. But sling backs have one strap in the back.
So maybe if I look at my foot in a sling back, I can see part of my heel. Right. Okay. So
sling backs have a little strap on the back of your heel since the shoe doesn't close in the back.
Right. Okay. But you also have high heels and women's shoes that don't close in the back.
But that you don't have a strap in the back either. Right. Those are open shoes.
So yeah, they're open in the back. But the sling back, there's one strap that keeps your shoe on.
Okay. A lot of different types of shoes we've just taken a look at. Why don't we go back?
Listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back shortly with fluency builder.
Hi, excuse me, sir. I'm looking for a dress shoe. My usual pair that I've had for years have
finally been stretched out of shape. They didn't provide any support anymore.
Sure. What kind of shoe are you looking for? We've got strapy sandals, sleek high heels,
edgy pumps. If you're looking for something a little more practical, we've got Mary Jane's.
Ballarinas. Show me some classic high heels, please. Okay. Right this way. What color did you have
in mind? Black classic. Of course. We've got this style here that is very popular.
Because it's an open-to-shoe. You can wear it any time of the year. They look great on everyone.
Too shiny. And I wear pantyhose with my shoes. So let's look for a closed toe shoe.
Okay. These are very nice pair of leather shoes with a two-inch heel. So they are very comfortable.
I don't like the pointed toes. Let me take a look at what else you have. To high,
that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high in-step. So I doubt that one would fit
I don't want bows. I find sling backs very uncomfortable. Those might as well be still letters.
Too modern. Oh, finally this is what I'm looking for. Wood size. Seven and a half.
Here we are. How does it fit? Hmm. Not good. They're too tight. The length is right, but the shoe is too
narrow and it's pinching my toes. And there'd be no room for my insoles. You know what? I don't think I
have the patience for this today. They just don't make shoes like they're used to. I'll come back
another time. Have a nice day. Ma'am. All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at five
key things on fluency builder. Fluency builder. Okay. Well, the reason we're shopping today is
because the woman needs a new pair of shoes because her old shoes can't be worn anymore. What's wrong
with the Marco? She said that they were stretched out of shape. Okay. So to stretch or to be
stretched out, this means that maybe they've been pulled and worn and they're stretched so much
that they don't have the original shape anymore. Right. So just imagine you have a new t-shirt.
And all of a sudden somebody takes you from your t-shirt and pulls you. Really hard. And usually what
happens is this t-shirt is going to be stretched out of shape. You pulled it so hard
that it loses its original form. So now maybe the neck is very low or the t-shirt is too long
on one side. Right. So that's what happens when you stretch something out of shape. Great. Okay.
So her old shoes are stretched out of shape and they don't provide support anymore. Okay. So to
provide support. Now what kind of support is she referring to? She's talking about foot support.
So for example, slippers are kind of shoe basically that don't provide support. They're very soft.
But can you walk around all day and slippers? No. It doesn't help your foot. But if you're trying
to find shoes that are really good for walking, you need to find ones that provide support. That
means that always support your foot, the bottom of your foot. Otherwise your foot gets too tired.
Not only the bottom but it could be also your ankle. For example, if you can't really go hiking
with shoes like these with sandals because obviously you're walking around rocks and it doesn't
provide support on your ankle. Maybe you can hurt your ankle if you don't have it. So maybe a hiking
boot will provide more support. Exactly. All right. And then the woman also mentioned that
will it's hard for her to find a shoe because she said I have a high-instep. Okay. So think about the
foot. You've got toes in the very front and a heel in the very back. But in the middle on top,
you have the in-step. So this is basically the top of your foot. Okay. So if she has a high-instep,
it means that her foot is kind of thick. That's right. Some people have thin feet. She has kind of a thick
foot. So fitting her foot into a shoe is sometimes hard. Right. We're not talking about the width of the foot.
We're talking about the height of the tall. Like the tall. How tall it is. From the bottom to the top of the foot.
Right. So that's what she means by high-instep. And well, they also mentioned different types of shoes.
She said she didn't want an open toe shoe. She wanted a closed toe shoe. That's right. So this is a
really important classification for women's shoes, especially. Open toe means that the toe of the shoe,
the very very front, has a hole or an opening. So you can see the toes. Right. A closed toe is the opposite.
So personally in the wintertime, I always wear closed toe shoes because I think open toe shoes are
too cold. Okay. So that's basically it. I guess men, we don't really have this type of shoe
between open toe and close toe. No, man. No, you don't really. But heels maybe you could have an open toe.
You can have an open toe shoe or close toe shoe. Right. Right. Okay. So a lot of interesting things.
This is useful for women out there. And also for boyfriends, maybe now you know what type of shoe
you're going to want. That's right. All right. So let's listen to this dialogue for the last time
and we'll be back shortly. Hi, excuse me, sir. I'm looking for a dress shoe. My usual pair
that I've had for years have finally been stretched out of shape. They didn't provide any support anymore.
Sure. What kind of shoe are you looking for? We've got strappy sandals, sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
If you're looking for something a little more practical, we've got Mary Jane's ballerinas. Show me
some classic high heels, please. Okay. Right this way. What color did you have in mind? Black classic.
Of course. We've got this style here that is very popular because it's an open toe shoe. You can
wear it anytime of the year. It look great on everyone. Um, too shiny. And I wear pantyhose with my
shoes. So let's look for a closed toe shoe. Okay. These are very nice pair of leather shoes with
a two inch heel. So they are very comfortable. I don't like the pointed toes. Let me take a look at
what else you have. To high, that one looks like the back would cut into my heel. I have a high
in-step so I doubt that one would fit properly. I don't want bows. I find slim backs very uncomfortable.
Those might as well be stillettos. Two modern. Oh, finally this is what I'm looking for.
Wood size. Seven and a half. Here we are. How does it fit?
Hmm, not good. They're too tight. The lead is right, but the shoe is too narrow and it's pinching
my toes and there'd be no room for my insoles. You know what? I don't think I have the patience
for this today. They just don't make shoes like they used to. I'll come back another time.
Have a nice day, ma'am.
All right, so talking about shoes. There's so many types and I think women are notoriously
famous for having a lot of shoes. Why is this? Some women are. Some women are. It depends on the
person, but part of the problem is he said earlier is that there's so many different kinds of women
shoes that now we expect women to have a different pair of shoes for every different occasion.
Hmm. Work shoes, hacking shoes, running shoes, wedding shoes. I don't know. Some are shoes,
when are shoes, fall shoes. So you need so many different kinds of shoes. You end up buying many
different kinds. I think that's true. And also basically women like to look nice. So that's why
you do your makeup, you have earrings, and they have nice bags. So I guess it's also part of it
is that you pay more attention to what type of shoe you're wearing that maybe goes well with the outfit.
I think maybe guys, not all guys obviously as well as not all women. But guys are a little bit
more generic. It's like jeans pretty much go well with any type of shoe as long as it's maybe
black or brown, right? Or something like that. True. Although I know a lot of guys who have many different
kinds of shoes. True. True. It takes up a lot of space in the glasses. It does shoes are hard to carry
around. And actually I find it kind of hard to get rid of my shoes. I think they have to be ripped
or just completely unwareable in order for me to throw a shoe away because otherwise it's,
you know, it's still, you can still wear it sometimes every weekend. That's true. Although I tend to
wear my shoes down. That means I wear them until they die. Really? Actually, I don't know.
I've had shoes that I've worn the the the souls down and then I just get it the soul change because I
like the shoe so much. Oh. Well let us know. Do you guys like to buy shoes? Do you have a lot of shoes?
Maybe you don't have that many shoes. We're curious to know about this in other cultures as well
because I know in the States in the United States, shoe shopping is very very popular. And
Holland they have a traditional wooden shoes. Yeah, they do. There's a clogs.
Clogs. So let us know. Maybe what type of shoes are also very unique to your country or culture.
We're at EnglishPod.com. We'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.