Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got a very special lesson for you all about time.
That's right. We're going to concentrate a little bit on some specific points of grammar this time
and we're going to talk about the morning routine, what you do in the mornings.
Well let's take a look first at the word routine. This is our vocabulary preview for today.
Very vocabulary preview.
All right. So a routine or the morning routine. What is a routine?
A routine is basically your habit for a certain period of time.
So for example, your routine in the morning is what you do when you wake up.
Right. Get breakfast and go to work. You can also have an evening routine.
It's what you always do before you go to bed.
Exactly. So everyone has a routine.
What they do in the mornings. Maybe what you do at night before going to bed.
So that's what we're going to talk about today.
That's right. You can also have an exercise routine. So basically anything with steps.
One, two, three, four, five.
You always do the same way. That's the routine.
Exactly. Right. So that's what we're going to take a look at today.
Why don't we jump right into our dialogue and listen to Stephanie's routine.
Stephanie, did you just get to school?
But you were up in a bout when I left the dorm this morning.
That was about an hour and a half ago. This happens all the time.
Why do you always take so long to get ready in the mornings?
It's a skill. What can I say? I don't know why.
I just have a long routine. Please explain because it makes no sense to me.
How can a girl's routine be so complicated? You get up. You shower.
You get dressed. You brush your teeth. You're out the door.
Half an hour tops. Jacob, you have the luxury of having a haircut that rarely
needs styling. I don't. I have to set aside about an hour and a half to get ready in the mornings.
Every day, I wake up and head straight for the shower. Every second day, I wash my hair.
If it's a hair washing day, I frequently need to wash my hair twice because it gets
really oily. Then I usually put in a conditioner and have to rinse that out too.
Because my hair is so long, I sell the manage to take a shower in under 20 minutes.
Afterwards, I often put on a pot of coffee and get dressed while I wait for it to brew.
I take a long time to get dressed in the morning. Every now and then, I remember to choose my
outfit the night before, but usually I do it in the morning. In all getting dressed takes about
half an hour. I wish time my hair is now semi dry so then I can have to sell my hair.
From time to time, I'll put my hair up, but oftentimes I blow dry it straight.
And then, because of the texture of my hair, I regularly have to fly iron it to keep it from freezing.
That's another 20 minutes or so. After that, I have my daily makeup routine.
True. I hardly ever see you without your hair done in your makeup on. Even when you're
so up to class and sweatpants, tell me, how long does it take you to choose that outfit in the morning?
Not funny.
All right, we're back. So obviously, she has a very complicated routine. I don't know if all
girls are like this. I'm not like this, but I think a lot of girls and some guys are really.
I don't want to be sexist here. I know some guys who take their time in the morning and are very
very, very particular. Really. I got the way that they look. Wow. Well, yeah, I imagine
everyone has their morning routine in different ways. And it was interesting to see how she described it.
So why don't we take a look at language takeaway? Language takeaway.
So today's language takeaway, like I said at the beginning of the podcast is all about time.
So we're going to look at some of these important time adverbs. That's right. These are called
adverbs of frequency. And basically, they are telling us how we do things. If we do something all
the time or if we never do something or everything in between. Exactly. So the first couple we have
today are a very, very common words. You're going to hear these a lot. The first one is frequently.
Okay, frequently. So if you do something frequently, consider it to be about 75% of the time.
Maybe a little bit more, almost 85% of the time. Right. So it's not always, but it's very often.
So for example, so I frequently forget to take my keys when I'm leaving the house, which is a
very big problem. Exactly. So considering out of seven days, maybe you forget your keys five days.
Hmm, that's a good. All right. So that's frequently. Now let's move on to another one.
It's actually a lot less. We talk about seldom. Well, Marco has told me that he seldom
forgets his keys. That means he almost always remembers them. Right. So seldom is a negative
adverb. It's saying that almost never. Okay. So if I say for example, I seldom go to the movies.
Not too bad. I like the movies. All right. Well, that means that I maybe go to the movie theater
once a month. Yeah, not very often. Not very often. seldom. All right. Now going back to a positive
adverb frequency, we have often. You, you described frequently as very often. That's right. So I could
also say, I often forget my keys or it often rains in tropical places. This means this is a common thing.
Exactly. So again, let's consider it to be about 70 to 80% of the time. Now with pronunciation,
some people like to pronounce often. Right. They'll kind of leave out the strong T sound. Well,
other people say often. That's right. Both forms are correct, right? Yes. They're both correct. So
you're safe using either of these. Right. Okay. And our third adverb of frequency, no,
our fourth. And our fourth adverb of frequency is also a positive one. And we say usually.
Usually means this is something that you do pretty consistently. I usually brush my hair before
I go to sleep. That means not always, but almost every day. Right. So let's consider that of seven
days you do it six times. Yeah. I usually do this. Okay. So usually is again very, very common.
And something in between maybe 60% of the time, 50% of the time we say regularly.
Well, I think of the word regularly as being very closely related to regular. So basically,
if I have a schedule, I do the same thing every day. I do it regularly. But sometimes there's a
special occasion. For example, I regularly run five kilometers after work when I go to the gym.
But sometimes when I want to go out with my friends, I don't run. So it's not always. But it is
pretty regular. Exactly. So regularly means you do it very often, but there are some exceptions.
Okay. Now, those are our adverbs of frequency, but we have a couple of other phrases that are
very similar. So we want to take a look at those as well. Let's go back to the beginning of
Stephanie's routine when he said that every day I wake up. Okay. So every day means 100% of the
time every single day. Monday to Sunday. Exactly. So obviously you wake up every day. Or I brush my
teeth twice every day. So that's 100% of the time. Now, if we say every second day, what does that mean?
That means Monday, yes, Tuesday, no Wednesday, yes. Thursday, no or any any day. So basically,
she says, I wash my hair every second day. That means one day I wash my hair. But the next day,
I don't the day after that, though, I wash it again every second day. Okay. So you can say every
second day. And I think you can also say every other day, right? Every other day. So every other day or
every second day. He calls his mother every other day. Very good. All right. And she also said that
every now and then I remember to choose my outfit. Okay. Well, this one's interesting. This is not
very frequent. This is basically saying sometimes. Sometimes. So now and then every now and then means,
I sometimes do it. I sometimes don't do it. Every now and then I really want to eat chocolate.
So I buy a candy bar. Okay. So maybe you want to eat chocolate twice in a month. Yeah, not very
off. Not very off. Okay. And another one that's very similar is from time to time. So Marco said
that he doesn't go to the movies very frequently. So he goes from time to time. Right. So I can say,
I seldom go to the movies or I can say, I like to go to the movies from time to time. That's right.
Or this girl is describing her appearance. She says, from time to time, I put my hair up.
So that means most of the time. That means sometimes it's down. Right. So as you can see,
there are many different ways of describing the frequency or how many times you do certain actions
or your routine. Right. So you can use this with a lot of things when you're describing.
And we encourage you to try some of these new ones because a lot of English learners use the same
time adverbs whenever they speak. So generally use some of these and challenge yourself. Exactly.
All right. So that's all we have for language. Take away when we move on now to fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. So using some of these ad verbs I could say, I can say, I regularly
make a pot of coffee in the morning. Okay. So a pot of coffee. You regularly make a pot of coffee. That
means you like to drink coffee every day. That's right. I always need my cup of coffee in the morning.
So I'm usually make it first thing. So a pot of coffee, we know what a cup of coffee is,
but a pot of coffee. What is a pot? A pot is basically the container that you use when you
brew coffee when you make it. So you put the coffee beans in the machine. And instead of having a cup
underneath, you have a bigger container that's a pot. You can also have a pot of tea. Exactly.
It's many cups. Usually eight or ten cups. All right. And remember that's verb to brew coffee.
I think it's a very nice kind of fancy way of saying making coffee. Brew a pot of coffee. I'm
brewing some coffee. All right. So a part from coffee and all of these things. Let's take a look at some
of the specific phrases that she used when she was talking about her hair because I think her hair
is very complicated. It is very complicated. Sometimes she washes her hair. Sometimes she doesn't
wash her hair. Sometimes she blow drys its straight. Okay. So to blow dry means that you use a blow
dryer. That's right. This is a machine that uses electricity to blow hot air on your hair so that
your hair will dry quickly. But you can blow dry your hair in many ways. Some people have curly hair.
And they have special tools for making their hair curly. But she says she blow dries its straight.
I mean she makes it straight with the hot air. Right. So I think the way you do this is you take the
blow dryer and a brush and you brush while you blow dryer. Yep. Making lines. See, I know a little
bit about this. Even though I don't have long enough hair for this. No, I guess well maybe you are
secretly one of those guys who has a routine like this woman. I don't think I can take this much
time in the shower and brushing my hair. But moving on actually I also know this next phrase.
To flat iron your hair. Okay. So flat iron is a noun and a verb. So I use a flat iron or I can
flat iron my hair. This is a tool that we use that's very very hot. Think of an iron. It's very,
very hot. And it basically presses my hair and makes it very, very thin and flat and straight. Right.
So I think people that have straight hair don't need to really flat iron their hair.
Nah. But if you have very curly hair, then you need it. So what's the difference?
Give us the insight here. Why wouldn't you just blow dry it straight? Why do you need to
flat iron it? Because a flat iron makes it more flat. It makes your hair
stick together more and it's much much hotter than a blow dryer. Okay. So I guess if you use a
blow dryer then you have puffy hair or like the next word that she described, frizzy hair.
Okay. So the adjective to describe this kind of hair is frizzy. For example, when it's very rainy,
my hair is frizzy. That means that it sticks out. It's very thick and not straight. Okay.
It's not curly, but it's messy. It kind of inflates. That's right. It's like a little balloon.
But the verb here is to frizz. So my hair is frizzing. Okay. And that means that it's getting like this.
Bigger or inflated. That's right. So usually girls who have this problem have it worse during
very humid or rainy days, not so bad when it's dry. Okay. So I actually have a little bit of a
frizzy hair. That's why I have to use some sort of hair gel, hair gel or moose. See, it's not because
I'm vain. It's just because if I don't use this, I'll come in looking like a lion.
I think I might have to insist that that happens sometimes soon. We can take a picture and put it
on our website English bot. Sure. Sure. All right. So why don't we go back and listen to the
dialogue one last time?
Stephanie, did you just get to school? But you were up in a bout when I left the dorm this morning.
That was about an hour and a half ago. This happens all the time. Why do you always take so long
to get ready in the mornings? It's a skill. What can I say? I don't know why. I just have
a long routine. Please explain because it makes no sense to me. How can a girls routine be so
complicated? You get up, you shower, you get dressed, you brush your teeth, you're out the door.
Half an hour tops. Jacob, you have the luxury of having a haircut that rarely needs styling.
I don't. I have to set aside about an hour and a half to get ready in the mornings.
Every day, I wake up and head straight for the shower. Every second day, I wash my hair. If it's a
hair washing day, I frequently need to wash my hair twice because it gets really oily. Then,
I usually put in a conditioner and have to rinse that out too. Because my hair is so long,
I sell the manage to take a shower in under 20 minutes. Afterwards, I often put on a pot of coffee
and get dressed while I wait for it to brew. I take a long time to get dressed in the morning.
Every now and then, I remember to choose my outfit the night before, but usually I do it in the morning.
In all getting dressed takes about half an hour. I wish time my hair is now semi dry so then I can
have to sell my hair. From time to time, I'll put my hair up. But oftentimes, I blow dry it straight.
And then, because of the texture of my hair, I regularly have to fly iron it to keep it from frizzing.
That's another 20 minutes or so. After that, I have my daily makeup routine.
True, I hardly ever see you without your hair done in your makeup on, even when you're
so up to class and sweatpants. Tell me, how long does it take you to choose that outfit in the
morning? Not funny.
Alright, so actually talking about morning routines and we've given you so many tools,
I think it would be a great idea if our users came to our site EnglishPod.com and posted
a part of their morning routine trying to use as many adverbs of frequency as possible.
That's a great suggestion and to get you all started, I could give you a little bit of my routine.
Alright, let's hear it.
Every morning, when I wake up, I turn off the alarm, which is very loud, and I take a shower.
I always brush my teeth and I usually brew a pot of coffee. Although sometimes I don't have
time to brew my coffee and I wait until I arrive at my office. I seldom choose the clothes I
will wear the night before. I almost always choose them during the morning.
And generally I ride my bike to work, but not always.
Okay, I think in the winter you seldom ride your bike to work.
Every once in a while.
Every now and then.
Alright, see? You have a perfect example there of more or less what we expect, but also it would be
interesting to see if you have any any other type of routine. I know some people
wake up in the morning and the first thing they do, they always walk their dog for example.
That's very nice. Other people are very hungry, so they almost always eat first.
Right, right when they wake up. I eat before I brush my teeth.
Oh, sorry, actually. Yeah. Alright, so we want to hear from you guys, come to EnglishPod.com.
We'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.