Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about sports and outdoor activities.
That's right. We are taking a look at a lot of different adventuresports.
So they're just not just the regular sports like tennis or soccer. These are more dangerous
sports.
That's right. So adventure sports is the topic. This is intermediate level. Let's check
out the dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Welcome to Adventure Tour. How may I help you? I want to book a tour with adventure sports.
Excellent. Our company has more than 10 years of experience in the adventure tourism
and sports field. Let me show you some options. This is our most popular choice. Our
river guides will take you on a white water wrapped in trip followed by a ride in a hot
air balloon. I don't really think I'm ready to throw myself down a river full of jagged rocks
and a rubber boat. Or go up in the air and a wicker basket held up by an oversized balloon.
What else do you have? Well, in that case we can take you hang gliding with one of our
experience instructors. It's the closest you can get to flying.
What? You mean strap myself to a flinzy kite? No, thank you. Next.
Okay. Well, why don't you tell me a little bit more about what you would like? We have
everything from mountain biking to rock climbing to street luge. I'm thinking something exciting,
but safer. I have the perfect option. This package will take you on a hiking trip
through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards there's a dog sledding journey. That's
more like it. All right. We're back. So obviously this tour agency or tour operator has a lot of
different options. A lot of them exciting. So why don't we take a look at some of those on language
takeaway? Language takeaway. So the first one has to do with water. This is called white water
rafting. That's right. So white water rafting. Now rafting means that you go in a raft. That's
right. It's a special kind of boat, not a wooden boat, not a big boat you see in the ocean. This is a
special boat for rivers maybe. That's right. It's an inflatable rubber boat. So he also described it
as an as a rubber boat. Okay. Rubber is the material it's made out of. That's right. So you go in
this boat in a river and it's called white water because it has, because it has rafids. So the river
is moving very quickly and you can see that it's a little bit dangerous to go swimming in a river
like this. That's right. So when the water goes really fast or when it hits some rocks,
it goes, the color changes from being blue or brown to white and that's why it's white water rafting.
That's right. And it's very, very scary and very dangerous. That's right. But very exciting. So that's
considered an adventure sport. And then the trip was followed by a ride in a hot air balloon.
Well everyone seen balloons before. Sometimes we give children balloons at the, at the
fair or maybe for their birthday. Balloons are basically rubber filled with air. But a hot air
balloon is a very special kind of mode of transportation actually. You can travel in a hot air balloon.
That's right. It's a big, big balloon that has a basket under it. And the person actually
described it as a wicker basket. A wicker is the material that's used in the basket, right?
That's right. You can have wicker furniture like wicker chairs. It's just a way to
to basically make furniture out of this kind of bark or natural material. So a hot air balloon is
a very big balloon and it's filled with hot air. Usually by some sort of fire that's under it.
And because it's filled with hot air, it goes up in the air. And as you say, you can use it as transportation,
uh, maybe to go very long distances carried by the wind because there's no real way of
a giving a direction or just for fun. That's right. It's another dangerous, but less dangerous,
kind of sport. Uh, but after that, we actually have one that I think you have some experience with
it's called hang lighting. That's right. Hang lighting is, it's another type of sport. And also
a type of flying sport. And basically you get on a hang glider. Okay. So if you've seen this
before, you'll know that it looks like someone is wearing wings. It's a big height that you
wear. Uh huh. It's a big, a kind of kind of looks like a triangle, like a kite. And you fly in it.
So it has no motor. It has, uh, not like the hot air balloon has no fire. Um, so you just basically
glide it. You just sail through the, the air, the atmosphere. Sounds very peaceful. It is.
But they say that you should go with an instructor. So what kind of instructor does this
tour company offer? That's right. The tour operator talked about taking you on a hang glider trip
with one of our experienced instructors. So experienced is the key word here. You want someone who has
done this many times before someone who knows what they are doing. That's right. So an experienced
instructor is a person that has, as you say, a lot of experience or is a professional. So that
an experienced instructor. Right. You could even say, you know, I want to take flying lessons
with an experienced pilot. Right. Or you can even talk about, uh, maybe a chef. He is a very
experienced chef. He's been a chef for a long time. That's right. So hang gliding. And our final
sport, very exciting as well. We are going dog sledding. Okay. So this is basically a winter sport
or a sport that you do in snowy places. You stand or sit on a sled and a team of dogs. So
that means many dogs pull you across the snow. That's right. So you go on a sled which is basically
usually made out of plastic or wood. And this is to go on top of the snow. And as you say,
a team of dogs pull you. I think you can see this in movies. This is kind of like the mode of
transportation in places where there are no roads. There are no other ways of getting places
that you just get pulled by dogs. Like Alaska or the Arctic Circle. Some are very, very far north.
Exactly. So a lot of great adventure sports. Very exciting. I think it's time for us to listen
to the dialogue again. And we'll be back in a bit with language takeaway part too.
Welcome to Adventure Tours. How may I help you? I want to book a tour with adventure sports.
Excellent. Our company has more than 10 years of experience in the Adventure Tourism and Sports
Field. Let me show you some options. This is our most popular choice. Our river guides will take you
on a white water wrapped in trip followed by a ride in a hot air balloon. I don't really think I'm
ready to throw myself down a river full of jagged rocks in a rubber boat. Or go up in the air
and a wicker basket held up by an oversized balloon. What else do you have? Well, in that case
we can take you hang gliding with one of our experienced instructors. It's the closest you can get to
flying. What? You mean strap myself to a flinzy kite? No, thank you. Next. Okay. Well, why don't you
tell me a little bit more about what you would like? We have everything from mountain biking to
rock climbing to street luge. I'm thinking something exciting but safer. I have the perfect
option. This package will take you on a hiking trip through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards
there's a dog sledding journey. That's more like it. All right. We're back. So now we're going to
take a look at three quick adjectives that we saw in this dialogue on language takeaway part two.
Language takeaway. This first adjective is something I am not a fan of. Let me just say if you
ever go rafting and you see rocks you want to avoid or you want to stay away from jagged rocks.
That's right. So the adjective jagged refers to maybe sharp or they can cut you, right? That's
right. So something that is jagged is not smooth. It's the opposite of smooth. That's right. So
maybe you've seen some rocks that have they're very pointy or that have things that can easily hurt
you or cut you. Those are jagged rocks. Broken glass can have jagged edges and that means you want to
avoid touching it because it can hurt you. Exactly. So jagged is a way of describing something that's
maybe sharp pointy or very dangerous that can cut you. And then moving on when we were talking about
the hot air balloon, this person very cleverly said that he doesn't want to go up in the air
in the basket held by an oversized balloon. Okay. So he's exaggerating like he said he's being clever
or silly. He's just afraid of the balloon. But basically he's saying an oversized balloon is a very,
very, very big or unnaturally big balloon. Right. So bigger than normal. So an oversized balloon
would be so a balloon that's bigger than normal or maybe I've seen an oversized in the early 1990s.
I remember a clothing trend. A lot of people like to wear oversized t-shirts. That's right. So t-shirts
that were way too big for you or maybe a naturally big. Those would be oversized t-shirts. Like xxxl.
Exactly. All right. And our final adjective when he was talking about hanglighting. He said that he's not
ready to go up in the air to strap to a flimsy kite. Okay. So the keyword here is flimsy.
We already talked about a kite. It's something that flies in the air. But something that's flimsy
is not very stable or sturdy. That's right. So it doesn't seem like it's very solid. So if you have
a kite. So a normal airplane is very sturdy. But a paper airplane is very flimsy. Exactly.
Then it moves around a lot. You can't control it. Exactly. So this not very solid. It's not
as you said sturdy. It doesn't really seem like it can stay up in the air for very long.
And it definitely can't support someone's weight. That's right. So you can even have a flimsy chair.
Maybe the chair is a little bit loose or doesn't seem like it's very strong. It feels like it might break.
That's right. So flimsy. That's the adjective. They're flimsy. So that's all the adjectives we have
for you today. Why don't we listen to the dialogue quickly one last time? And we're back to talk a
little bit more.
Down a river full of jagged rocks and a rubber boat. Or go up in the air and a wicker basket
held up by an oversized balloon. What else do you have? Well in that case we can take you
hang gliding with one of our experienced instructors. It's the closest you can get to flying.
What? You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite? No thank you. Next?
Hmm okay. Well why don't you tell me a little bit more about what you would like? We have everything
from mountain biking to rock climbing to street luge. I'm thinking something exciting but safer.
I have the perfect option. This package will take you on a hiking trip
through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards there's a dog sledding journey.
That's more like it.
Okay so Marco I know this is one of your favorite areas. Adventure sports.
You're a lot more daring than I am because I wouldn't do many of these things but what have you
done? I've actually haven't been in a hot air balloon. I don't really think that's very exciting.
It doesn't kind of work. Yeah you don't really go very fast. And I've never done a street luge
luge which is an interesting sport. Although it is pretty dangerous. It's basically
you're kind of riding on a type of skateboard right? Yeah basically it's a big skateboard and you lie
down on it. Your feet go down and your head is back. You're on your back and you go downhill
really fast. This is actually an Olympic sport and it's simply called luge and you can see this
with those big icy tracks that they have and they go downhill and they slide down on a bob sled
or luge would actually be the same thing but just one or two people on some type of skateboard
looking thing. Basically it's open. The the bob sled is closed so you see the people's heads
but the luge you just see their whole body and they're lying down on a piece of metal and they
go down very very quickly. They go very fast. I think in bob sledding and luge I think they can
reach speeds up to like 100 kilometers per hour. That's right and this year it was actually very
sad at the Olympics. A luge I think it was luge athlete died in practice. That's right. So
extreme sports or adventure sports they are as a name says full of adventure very exciting
but also obviously very dangerous. I think hiking is not really an adventure sport or very dangerous
unless you're hiking in dangerous territory with bears or something. Plus a bobble. Maybe you
guys should let us know what kind of sports do you do? Do you enjoy adventure sports? Our website is englishpo.com.
All right we'll see everyone there. Bye.