Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about, well kind of girly things.
That's right, we've talked about guys, shoes, women's shoes.
So now we're going to talk about another aspect of women's accessories.
We're going to talk about makeup.
Okay, so we're wearing makeup today. Actually we're buying makeup at the store.
I never even knew there were so many kinds of makeup.
So we're going to learn all about these in today's dialogue.
I'm hungry. Let's go grab a bite to eat. Yeah, me too. Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
I lost my makeup back at the airport and I want to pick up a few things.
Can we take long? No, five minutes. I promise.
Come on, we've been here for almost an hour.
I thought you said you're only going to get a few things.
How long does it take you to pick out a lipstick and some nail polish?
Are you crazy? You have no idea what you're talking about.
Just for my eyes, I have to get eyeliner and eyelash curler, eyeshadow and eyebrow pencil and mascara.
Then I need to get foundation, liquid foundation. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Are you nuts? How much is all this going to cost?
I'm looking at the price of each one of these little things and it's outrageous.
This is basically a crayon. What about you?
You spend as much money or more on your razors after shave,
colon and gel. Not to mention how much you spend on clothes and
find get the stupid $30 crayon.
Alright, we're back. So obviously, we're getting a lot of things for this girl. A lot of makeup.
So I think there are a couple of things that we may not know about. So let's take a look at them now on the
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So the first thing we're talking about today is a basic. Most women carry this around in their
purses. It's called lipstick. That's right. And as you say, this is a pretty basic thing.
It's the kind of like paint that you put on your lips. And it's called a lipstick because it
looks like a little stick. Right. And you turn it with your fingers and it comes up and then you turn it
again and it goes down. Basically keeping it from touching all of the things in your purse.
That's right. So lipstick. And well, apart from this, we also have nail polish. And this is also very
popular with the ladies when you paint your nails at a certain color. That's right. So polish is
basically anything that makes something shiny. It's something that you add to surfaces. So you could
add polish to wood on a table. But in this case, we're putting it on our nails. That is fingernails
or toenails. So it's nail polish. Alright, very good. And now we're getting into the specific things.
A lot of makeup that women use on their eyes. So for example, the first thing she said,
she needs to get an eye liner. Okay. So eye liner is basically a pencil. This is what the guy
is making fun of her about. He says it's just a pencil or crayon for your eye. And so basically
you use it to draw a line on the top or the bottom of your eye, your eyelid. Okay. So yeah,
it kind of looks like a marker. And it comes, I think black in different colors. And then
you paint little lines around your eyes to make them more pronounced. So it's called an eye liner.
Okay. And now we have an eyelash curler. And also, I think this is very important for the ladies.
Yeah. Well, not everyone uses this. It's a little bit of a scary instrument. It looks like it might
pop your eye out. It's something you use on your eyelashes. So those are the hairs that come off of your eye.
And basically, um, basically you use this to make them curly or to make them seem a bit longer.
And prettier. So an eyelash curler is something that it's like almost like a
oppress or something for your eyelashes. Okay. Very good. And well, now that we've got that covered,
we move on to eye shadow. And I think this goes on your eyelid, right? That's right. Some people
make it go further. They put it on their face above their eyelid. But that's a little bit crazy.
I think eye shadow generally goes like you said on your eyelid. And it can be in many different
colors. So blue, pink, red, whatever. People sometimes go crazy with eye shadow. Okay. And now what
about an eyebrow pencil. This is basically a pencil for filling in or for coloring your eyebrows.
Sometimes people like to make their eyebrows look darker or thicker. And so they use this pencil.
It's usually brown or black. And they use it on their eyebrows. So we picked up a lot of a
vocabular related to your eye. For example, in eyelash, your eyelid. Now we're talking about the eyebrows,
which are the hairs on top. More or less around your forehead. And now we also have another type of
makeup called mascara. This is another basics. So like we said earlier, lipstick is something you
almost always find in a woman's purse. Well, mascara is another one of those things. Almost
everybody wears mascara. This is kind of like a brush for your eyelashes. And it paints them
a different color. So most of them are in where black or brown. And it makes your eyelashes look really
long. Okay. Very good. So this is kind of like paint for your eyelashes. And now moving away from
your eyelashes, we're going to have rebuying also some foundation and liquid foundation. Okay. So
foundation is just a kind of base for your face. So foundation like a building is this is a very
bottom. Well, in this case, it's something that you put on your cheeks on your face and general on your
forehead. To kind of smooth your skin out and make it look all the same color or the same
the same texture. And so foundation can be like like we see here either a powder, which is kind of like
a dry substance. Or you can use liquid foundation, which is like it says liquid. It's almost like a
thick cream. All right. So foundation is as you said, I guess you just want to make your skin look the
same color, the same texture. Because obviously not everyone's skin is perfect. We'll have some spots
maybe or some different color on our face. You say we like you wear foundation too. Do you
or make up? Well, I mean, we as people, because you know, all right. No, no, no, no, none of this
make up for me. Although I have used an eyelash curler once. That's scary. Well, my friends
dared me to. So okay. And you love that. Of course. Now I use it all the time. No, no. But what I do
use is now things related to guys. So for example, the girlfriend was saying, well, you buy
razors and aftershave. So what are these things? Well, razors aren't just a guy thing. Everyone can
have a razor. It's basically a blade like a very sharp piece of metal that you use to cut hair.
So the hair on your legs, the hair on your face. These are these are things that you cut with a razor.
And that menus razors to shave their faces, shave their chins or above their lip.
All right. And well, actually after we shave our beard, we put on a little bit of aftershave,
which is basically kind of like alcohol that smells really nice. That's why because shaving can
actually hurt your skin or the hairs under your skin can become really itchy or irritated.
And so aftershave helps make everything feel better. Okay. And well, sometimes we also use a little
bit of cologne to smell nice. So women usually wear perfume, which is, you know, all the perfumes
like CK and we'll go boss and all that stuff as well as for guys. It's usually called cologne.
Okay. That's right. It's an important difference there because we don't say perfume for
guys and we don't say cologne for girls. So women wear perfume like you said, but men wear cologne.
And this word is very funny looking. It ends with, it's about COL OG and E. So you don't really
say the G. It's not collogna. Right. It's cologne. And it's something that you put on your neck or
your face smell really good if you're a man. Exactly. And finally, if you have long hair or maybe
you have very spike here like I do, you need to wear a little bit of gel to kind of give your
your head a little bit of shape. That's right. So gel is this actually the name of a kind of substance.
It's not liquid, but it's not hard either. And it basically thick like paste that you put in your
hair to keep it in one place. Yeah. It makes your hair become a little bit hard or it keeps your hair
style for a long time. That's right. All right. So a lot of vocab here, a lot of things that we've
picked up. Why don't we go back review all this great vocab on our dialogue for today.
I'm hungry. Let's look grab a bite to eat. Yeah, me too. Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
I lost my makeup bag at the airport and I want to pick up a few things. What do you take long?
No, five minutes. I promise. Come on. We've been here for almost an hour. I thought you said
I'd be really going to get a few things. How long does it take you to pick out a lip sick and some nail polish?
Are you crazy? You have no idea what you're talking about. Just for my eyes, I have to get
eyeliner and eyelash curler, eyeshadow and eyebrow pencil and mascara. Then I need to get foundation,
liquid foundation. Whoa, whoa, whoa, are you nuts? How much is all this going to cost? I'm looking
at the price of each one of these little things and it's outrageous. This is basically a crayon.
What about you? You spend as much money or more on your razors after shave,
colon and gel. Not to mention how much you spend on clothes and find get the stupid $30 crayon.
All right, we're back. So now we're going to take a look at three short phrases that we've picked out for you on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So this first phrase is something that we always, almost always say with our friends
or family when we're hungry, we're shopping, you know, some of the time it's your outside and you just
really want to eat, you say, hey, let's grab a bite to eat. That's right. So this is a very natural
colloquial way of saying let's go get something to eat. Let's go eat something. So it could be small
it could be a snack like a nice cream but it can also be dinner. So hey, do you want to go grab
bite to eat some time? That means, hey, you want to go have lunch or dinner sometime? Very good. So the
phrases grab a bite or go grab a bite to eat. So a bite can be a noun like a thing like a piece of food that you eat
but it could also be a verb to bite like, you know, the dog bites the man. And so you have to
care about this one. In this case, it's a noun. Okay, very good. And well, she wanted to first go to the
store and she said, I want to pick up a few things. Well, usually when you pick something up,
you take it from a table or from the ground. But in this case, it means to buy something because
you can't just pick something up in a store and then walk away. You have to pay for it. Right. So for
example, you can say, when you come home, can you pick up a carton of milk? So that means, can you
buy some milk on your way home? It doesn't mean can you take some from someone else or steal some?
Exactly. All right. So to pick something up to buy to go and get, but obviously you have to pay.
All right. And he used this very interesting phrase when she was getting all these things for her.
She said, whoa, whoa, whoa, are you nuts? Okay. So nuts is the important word here. It means crazy
or out of your mind. That's right. So it's another way of saying crazy. So if you call someone nuts,
or you say he's nuts, that means, yeah, like don't talk to him. He's nuts. Or he always says really
dangerous things. He's nuts. So he's a little bit crazy. So it's an adjective as to describe someone
that's a little bit crazy or a little bit adventurous maybe. But in this case, he's not actually saying
she's a crazy person. He's saying listen, this is so much stuff. Are you crazy or he's basically
saying, do you really want to do this? This seems like a bad decision. Exactly. So that's why he used the
phrase, are you nuts? Okay. So a lot of great stuff there. Why don't we go back, listen to our
dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a bit. I'm hungry. Let's look grab a bite to eat.
Yeah, we too. Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast? I lost my make up bag at the airport and I
want to pick up a few things. Can we take long? No, five minutes. I promise.
Come on. You've been here for almost an hour. I thought you said you're only going to get a
few things. How long does it take you to pick out a lipstick and some nail polish? Are you crazy?
You have no idea what you're talking about. Just for my eyes, I have to get eyeliner and eyelash
curler, eyeshadow and eyebrow pencil and mascara. Then I need to get foundation, liquid foundation.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, are you nuts? How much is all this going to cost? I'm looking at the price of each
one of these little things and it's outrageous. This is basically a crayon. What about you? You spend
as much money or more on your razors after shave, cologne and gel. Not to mention how much you
spend on clothes and get the stupid $30 crayon.
All right, so talking about makeup. A lot of things here. Maybe I didn't mention a couple of
things. I don't know. We took a look at the most important things, I think, right? But you also mentioned
something, for example, cover up. There's something such makeup called cover up. Yeah, so cover up.
It could be a couple of different things in English. For example, something that you
you wear to cover your body when you're at the beach. You don't want to walk around and everyone can
see you and your bathing suit. But when we're talking about makeup, a cover up cover up is a thing
that we use to hide blemishes or zits or pimples. So you know when you get a really small red dot
on your face and you're embarrassed and it's ugly and you don't want anyone to see it. Well,
cover up is a kind of makeup you use that looks like your skin color and you put it on top
and you can't see the red anymore. Okay, so you cover up your pimple. Yeah, or you use cover up.
It's a noun too. Okay, and I've also seen that well, many girls don't really wear too much
lipstick anymore nowadays. They use this thing called lip gloss. Okay, lip gloss. Remember
we were talking about polish earlier? Well, gloss is a similar word. It means something that
makes another thing shiny. And so lip stick can be very dry, can be very flat, can be very flat.
But lip gloss is something that makes things look wet, makes things look shiny. Okay, and actually
one last thing before when we talked about gel, I guess guys use gel but women use this thing called
moose. Or they could use gel too. I don't think it's gender specific, but a lot of people use
moose. I know some men who use moose as well. Moose is kind of like a foam. You know, it comes in a can it goes
yeah, and it inflates this white substance. Yeah, it looks it looks like, I don't know, like whipped cream.
Like whipped cream. Yeah, and you put it in your hair and it's very fluffy and it's actually less strong.
It's not like gel because if you put it in your hair, your hair won't look hard, but it will help shape your hair if you
want to keep your hair in one place. A lot of things here, I think in beauty and cosmetics,
we have a lot of a lot of things and probably we didn't even touch on half of the things that are out there.
So if you have any questions or if you want to ask us anything at all about this lesson or anything else,
you could always come to EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments there.
So we'll see you at EnglishPod and until next time. All right, good.