Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have a very dangerous lesson for you guys.
That's right today we're going to talk about guns or specifically about weapons.
So yeah we're talking about kinds of guns. There are more than I think I ever knew and we're
going to discuss about six today but before we get going, Mark we've got a phrase in a vocabulary
preview. That's right so today on vocabulary preview we're going to take a look at shooting range.
Have you ever been to one of these places? Yes a shooting range. It's a place like you say
and it's a place where you can fire your weapons or you can use guns safely. So you don't
kill anyone or you don't hurt someone. Now basically yeah it's a place to practice shooting.
So maybe for example if you want to practice how to shoot guns you go to this place and they
have special things to help you improve your shooting abilities. Usually these are very
very secure. They have guards and things because you don't want to give the guns out to anybody.
Let's listen to today's dialogue about a shooting range and find out what kinds of guns they have.
Hey Nick, what are you up to? Not much. Just had no over to the shooting range. You want to come?
Seriously? You mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man. Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm
pistol that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's really fun too. They have
big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim. Yeah that would be cool.
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun. Maybe even a rocket
launcher or an anti-tag missile or what about a flame thrower? Whoa take it easy there Rambo.
Don't get carried away. These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them properly.
There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe. For example never handle a weapon
that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber and never
put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot. Wow I didn't know. It always looks
so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know running and firing a weapon is
a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
Alright we're back so obviously this guy was very excited about using these weapons and you may have
heard that we're using this word weapons. It's basically all of these things I guess anything that
can be used in defense or hurt someone. Yes anything that can be used to hurt someone as a weapon.
So a knife can be a weapon not just guns. Guns are kind of weapon. That's right so taking a look at
our first type of gun or our first type of weapon we have a 9mm pistol. Okay so the weapon is the
pistol and the pistol is basically a handgun but it comes in different sizes so that's with the
9mm first. That's right that's the size of the projectile that will come out of the weapon and
a pistol as you say it's a handgun. It's usually small and it can fit in your hands so you can use
just one hand to use this weapon. Okay so there's a similar handgun that's a little bit bigger that's
called a revolver. That's right a revolver so this one has a revolving chamber so you kind of see
this in the old Western movies when they're having six bullets right? Yeah like swing their guns into
their side holsters. Yeah well yeah that's right the revolver refers to the well to revolve it
means to move around to spin. That's right. And so the the place with the bullet basically spins
after you shoot the gun. That's right so that's why it's called a revolver unlike the pistol
the pistol will usually not really have a revolver it will have a magazine. Okay now moving on to
our next type of weapon we have the very famous machine gun. That's the one that shoots off really fast
and so basically it's called a machine gun because it's it's automatically releasing all of these
bullets at once. You just pull the trigger and many many bullets come out. That's right so in a
pistol or in a revolver usually you have to press the trigger and once and it shoots only once but in
the machine gun you can keep it pressed and all of these bullets will start flying out. Very, very dangerous.
Very dangerous. Okay so now moving on to the next one we also took a look at a shotgun. Okay this is
well this is not the biggest gun we're going to talk about today but it's a very large gun very long
and you have to use two hands to hold it. This is what you usually use when you go hunting right?
That's right so as you said it's very long and it's very loud and it doesn't really shoot
bullets. It shoots little pellets, little cartridges that are filled with little rocks for example
and that's what it shoots and this is why it's not very precise like a machine gun or a handgun
but it does a lot of damage. Absolutely and what's something else that does a lot of damage?
Our next gun will do that. Well this guy got a little bit excited and he said he wanted to use a
rocket launcher. Okay so you know what a rocket is? A rocket is something that's basically a
projectile that goes into the sky and can it can basically blow up big buildings or cars.
That's right and that's what a rocket launcher is. Now maybe you've heard of the word bazooka.
A bazooka is a type of rocket launcher. It's very very wide and it's circular and you usually see it in
movies like Rambo. We talked about where the Rambo will hold it on one shoulder. It's so big and the
rocket shoots out and can destroy huge buildings. That's exactly right so that's why it's called a rocket
launcher. Now for our last type of weapon we have a flame thrower. Okay well a flame refers to fire.
So fire has flames those are the parts that kind of come up on a fire that read and orange.
And a flame thrower is a device that's a weapon that will shoot flames. Not bullets. Exactly.
It was very popular back in in world war two to actually shoot the flame thrower into bunkers
into holes because then you know this is how you can get people out of there. And I think flame
throwers are used now to some sort of degree like to fumigate sometimes or to burn weeds when
you're in a field. Right they're not really used as weapons anymore. Although I think I've seen
a number of them in action movies. Really. Yeah. In action movies of course. So we have a lot of guns.
A lot of different types of weapons. Why don't we go back to the dialogue? Let's listen to it again
and we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
Hey Nick. What are you up to? Not much. Just had no over the shooting range. You want to come?
Seriously? You mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man. Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol
that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's really fun too. They have big targets
of the range that we could use to practice and improve your aim. Yeah that would be cool.
Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun or a shotgun. Maybe even a rocket
launcher or an anti-tag missile. Or what about a flame thrower? Whoa take it easy there Rambo.
Don't get carried away. These weapons are not toys and you must first learn how to handle them
properly. There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe. For example never handle
a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure there isn't anything in the chamber
and never put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot. Wow I didn't know.
It always looks so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know. Running and firing
a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at our phrases that we've picked out for you on
Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. So this first phrase comes from the beginning of today's
dialogue when Nick is saying well I'm not doing much. I'm just heading over to the shooting range.
That's right so we know what shooting range is but when he says I'm heading over to the shooting range.
Well this can be confusing because to head over has nothing to do with the head on your body.
Right. It means I'm going towards some place. I'm going to this place.
So it's just another way of saying going to right. So for example you can say I'm heading over to
my friend's house this afternoon. That's right so I'm going to my friend's house this afternoon.
But remember that this is a pretty relaxed, pretty informal way of saying something.
See you wouldn't say I'm heading over to work. Do you say hey I'm heading over to his house to hang out
I'm heading over to the pizza restaurant to grab a bite to eat. That's right. Okay so now obviously
we saw that one of the guys got very excited about the idea of using all these cool weapons.
And his friend said whoa take it easy their rambo. Don't get carried away. I love this phrase.
This phrase is something you say to someone who is maybe too excited about something.
Hmm that's right. It means don't go crazy. Don't exaggerate.
Right so maybe at the shooting range they'll have a revolver. They'll have a pistol but they're
probably not going to have a rocket launcher or as he said an anti tank missile. These are crazy
weapons from movies. And so the friend is saying no you're exaggerating. Don't get carried away.
Now for example maybe you go to the mall and you go shopping and maybe you got a little bit
carried away and you spent too much money. That always happens to me doing holidays. Like it
carried away and I buy way too much stuff. That's right so that's the way that you would use
carried away. And now for our last phrase he was actually explaining a couple of rules of weapon
weapon handling and he said that there are some rules that he has to abide by.
Okay so this is a fixed phrase we use the verb to abide with word like the rules. So to abide
by the rules or we must all abide by the rules. This is a fancy way of saying to follow the rules
or to recognize the rules and that's right. So you have to abide by the rules
of your school or maybe you have to everyone has to abide by the law. Right or some people can say
there are rules in the Bible that other people abide by. That's right. Okay so a lot of great stuff.
I think we've taken a look at a lot of different types of weapons and phrases. So pretty interesting
stuff. Why don't we listen to it for the last time?
Hey Nick, what are you up to? Not much. Just had no over to the shooting range. You want to come?
Seriously? You mean to fire a real weapon? I don't know man.
Yeah it will be fun. I have a 9mm pistol that's really easy to shoot. I also have a revolver that's
really fun too. They have big targets at the range that we could use to practice and improve your
brain. Yeah that would be cool. Maybe I can also have a try at other weapons like a machine gun
or a shotgun. Maybe even a rocket launcher or an anti-tag missile. Or what about a flame thrower?
Whoa take it easy there Rambo. Don't get carried away. These weapons are not toys and you must
first learn how to handle them properly. There are basic rules that you must abide by in order to be safe.
For example never handle a weapon that you haven't inspected yourself. Always make sure
there isn't anything in the chamber and never put your finger to the trigger unless you are ready to shoot.
Wow I didn't know. It always looks so cool and easy in the movies. The reality is different you know
running and firing a weapon is a lot harder than in the movies. So are you ready? Let's do it!
Alright we're back so I'm talking about weapons and pistols and all this has ever used
one of these heavy-roaches. I have I have been to a couple shooting ranges and have fired a
couple of guns. I've never fired a shotgun. They don't usually well sometimes they have a shotgun.
But I've shot pistols before and did you like it? I like it. It's an interesting activity. I don't know
how I feel about using guns on people but I understand why hunting is an enjoyable sport because
there is a sport aspect to it. You really have to control your body and
you can improve. You can get better like darts but with loud guns. It's very hard to
aim actually to hit something. People think it's very easy like in the movies.
Well and I think it's particularly hard with handguns because some of them can be very powerful and so
there's a kick and you don't realize it the first time you shoot a gun you're like oh oh that was way
harder than it looks. I bet you're a good shot right? Yeah yeah yeah I've always really enjoyed
weapons and my aim is alright although my eyesight kind of I need to use glasses so it can be a
little bit tricky sometimes especially when you shoot a weapon sometimes it's very you just clean
it so it has a lot of oil and it'll kick out into your face and get your glasses wet. Well that's why
we use goggles at the shooting ranges that I could do but I'm curious to know have you guys ever shot
a gun before have you ever been to a shooting range or shooting range is legal in your country?
Yeah some places are not. Yeah so let us know our website is englishpod.com.
Alright we'll see you guys there. Bye.