Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson all about going shopping.
That's right today we are going with a guy to a shop and he's buying a new suit.
Okay so lots of great words for men or for buying clothes for your husband or brother.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
Hello Sarah what can I do for you today?
Hello I need a new suit. I have an important interview next week so I really need to look sharp.
No problem we have a broad selection of suits all tailor made so it will fit perfectly.
Great. I want a three piece suit.
Preferably made from talent cashmere or wool.
Very well sir. Would you like to have some shirts made also?
Sure. I also take some silver cufflinks and a pair of silk tie.
It is. Very good. Now if you will accompany me we can take your measurements and choose the patterns for your suit and shirts.
Alright we're back so a very simple dialogue about a guy needing a suit and he talked to the
tailor apparently about a couple of things now.
Why don't we take a look at some of those words in language takeaway?
Language takeaway
Well first of all a tailor is a person who makes clothes. So in this case a man who makes suits.
And the first thing that we have to talk about is the kinds of suits that he has.
He says we have a broad selection of suits.
Okay so this adjective broad. What does that mean?
It means wide. You know you can have a very broad street. That means many cars can fit across it.
But in this case we're talking about a selection. So that means a broad selection of suits
very very many suits to choose from. Okay so for example if you go to a music store where they sell
CDs and stuff like that they might they will have a broad selection of music so you can have
wrap and hip hop and R&B etc. That's right or the iTunes store has a broad selection of music.
You can choose basically anything. That's right okay. So we have a broad selection of suits and
he said well great. I actually need a three piece suit.
Okay so there are different kinds of suits. Some just have two pieces like pants and the jacket.
But the kind that the man wants is a three piece suit. So that means there's a jacket.
Pants or trousers. Some people might say and the vest.
Okay so yeah you've probably seen this that they look very nice. Basically under or over your shirt
you wear a vest and so if you wear a vest with the suit it's called the three piece suit.
You know who I'm thinking of right now who always wears three piece suits. He's very famous.
A football player actually. Beckham? Yes really. David Beckham. I don't know if you guys
watched the World Cup but in the World Cup David Beckham was always wearing a three piece suit.
Wow and that he's that's amazing. Okay so we have a three piece suit now. We don't have a four
piece suit do we? I don't think so. I don't know. I don't think so. Maybe a
touch. You have like the the in your match the cumberbund. Oh cumberbund that's what it's called.
Okay well that's for a tuxedo. Now moving on we talk about the materials of the suit and he said
well I preferably want something made from Italian cash, mere or wool. Okay so Italian is an
adjective that describes things that come from Italy and Italy is very famous for its fabrics and silk.
And so in this case we're talking about Italian wool. Cashmere is a very expensive, very soft kind of wool.
Okay and wool is basically a sort of material that comes from the from the sheep,
from the hair of the sheep. That's right and so different sheep, different animals have different kinds
of wool and these have different prices so some are more expensive and some are cheaper. Cashmere is
very expensive. Okay very good and so he also is offered some shirts and he's like yeah sure I'll take
some shirts and I also need some silver cuff links. Okay so when you close your shirts by your wrist
you usually have a button or in some cases something a little bit more fancy and when it's more fancy
it's called a cuff link. Yes you've probably seen it it looks like a small metal button
that you can remove from your shirt so it looks a lot better it's kind of hard to explain but just
imagine on your wrist you have a small metal button that you can close your shirt at the wrist.
That's right and some people have very very fancy ones with special pictures so you could have for
example a car if you love cars or you know a diamond cuff link but a diamond on it. That's right
in this case he wants a cuff links made of silver and also he wants a pair of silk ties. Okay so
a pair of means two he wants two different silk ties and the tie is basically a is something that
you you put around your neck men wear these usually to the office and once that are made of silk
are usually more expensive. That's right so a silk tie and okay so we've pretty much covered
everything that he needs he wants a very nice suit with a lot of great accessories why don't we
listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Hello sir what can I do for you today? Hello I need a new suit.
I have an important interview next week so I really need to look sharp.
No problem we have a broad selection of suits all tailor made so it will fit perfectly.
Great I want a three piece suit. Preferably made from Italian cashmere or wool.
Very well sir would you like to have some shirts made also? Sure. I also take some silver
cuff links and a pair of silk ties. Very good now if you will accompany me we can take your
measurements and choose the patterns for your suit and shirts.
Some fluency builder today we have three very useful phrases that you can say when you're with
the tailor at the at the store buying a suit. The first one is to look sharp. That's right he says that
he has a job interview and he wants to look sharp. Okay so to look means to have the appearance of
but sharp what does this mean? Basically take it as a chunk or as a phrase and if you look sharp
it means you look smart you look good you look clean you look very nice. So this is normally something
we say to men. You look really sharp today or I want him to look sharp I'm going to buy him a nice silk
tie. That's right so to look sharp as I said to look very nice very clean very handsome.
Okay so looking sharp and well when we were talking about the suit the person mentioned that all the
suits are tailor made. This is a very important phrase if you want to go shopping for clothes that
are made for you. So something is tailor made if the sizes are made only for fitting you. That's right.
If you go to the department store and you buy a suit off of the shelf for the rack it's not tailor made
but if the tailor makes it he soows it to your size then it's tailor made. That's right. You know
wedding dresses are tailor made special suits are tailor made so this is usually an expensive kind of clothing.
Okay so it basically means the tailor the person made it especially for you. That's right. And the
opposite as you said would be off the rack. Off the rack and this means that when you go to the
store you pick something you like it and you buy it. There's no one going no one is going to sew it
to make it fit you. That's right so this is actually how most of us get our clothes you go to the
department store you get a pair of jeans a t-shirt obviously all that stuff is off the rack. It's not
tailor made for your size. That's right. Okay but if you want to if you really want to get something
tailor made you need to be able to talk to the tailor about it and so he will usually say let me
take your measurements. This is our next phrase. That's right. The tailor mentioned that he wants to
take them over there and take his measurements. So when the tailor says I want to take your measurements
or I need to take your measurements what does that mean? That means I need to measure parts of your
body to help make the suit. So he'll normally measure your shoulders your waist your hips and how
long things will be so your arms and your legs and these are all important measurements to know
how big or how small to make the suit. That's right you want the tailor to take your measurements
or you can also say you have to get measured. That's right so to get measured or to take someone's
measurement these are key phrases for buying a tailor made suit. Very good. Okay why don't we listen to
it like one last time and we'll be back to talk some more.
Hello sir what can I do for you today? Hello I need a new suit. I have an important interview
next week so I really need to look sharp. No problem we have a broad selection of suits all
tailor made so it will fit perfectly. Great. I want a three piece suit,
preferably made from talent cashmere or wool. Very well sir. Would you like to have some shirts made also?
Sure. I also take some silver cufflinks and a pair of silk ties. Very good.
Good measurements and choose the patterns for your suit and shirts.
So do you have any tailor made suits Marco? I actually don't. I haven't
here to the office I'd never wear suit. We don't really need to wear suits all fancy and they're
there have been very few occasions where I've needed a suit so I actually don't have a suit at the
moment. Not even one. I left them I left them all at home and I just haven't used them and
probably they wouldn't fit anymore. This is the problem with getting things tailor made as well.
The thing is that with a tailor made suit usually it's made to get bigger or smaller so
maybe the shoulders and the arms are the same but if you gain weight or you lose weight the tailor can
make those small, small changes. That's right. Actually I had a friend who got some tailor made jeans
and I think that would be nice because sometimes I don't know jeans for me they don't fit well.
Yeah I mean either. There's a very famous company that does tailor made jeans that I was thinking
about going to because I hate buying jeans off the rack. Yeah they usually don't fit either. They're
the waist is too if I need a bigger waist but then everything is too baggy and it's it just doesn't
look right or everything is too small so I think this is a very interesting thing although I
don't know how expensive it would be because getting tailor made clothes is relatively expensive.
It can be very expensive although that's usually in America or in Europe in places like India
and China I think it's much more common to have things made to fit you. This is a very interesting
subject and actually we are wondering if maybe you know a tailor you are a tailor or you've
gotten things tailor made for you. Maybe you got married recently and you had a tailor made
tuxedo or a tailor made wedding dress. That's right so let us know we can be found at Englishpod.com
we hope to see you there. All right bye guys. Bye.