Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have part two of a very important and very valuable series
about giving presentations.
That's right. As you well know, we started this series. It's a ten-part series and today we're
going to talk about sales and charts and graphs and more or less explaining maybe a PowerPoint
presentation. That's right. So you're going to learn some wonderful ways of talking about
changes in markets and marketing. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to talk about what you've heard.
As all of you are well aware, competition and laptop computer sector is intense. We continue
to fight with our competitors for market share and this is the case both in the developed
markets and the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa. You may
ask yourself why is this market so cut-throat? Well the answer is simple. There is a huge
untapped potential market out there with a huge untapped potential for profit. If I bring
up the first graph here it shows the increase in terms of number of computer owners across
the globe. As you can see in the 1980s computer ownership amounted to around 0.5% of the total
world population. Since the 1990s computer ownership has risen dramatically. In the new millennium
we saw an even larger explosion in computer owners with figures rising to around 4% to 5%
and increase of 1,000% compared with the 1980s. If we move on to discuss the figures for
China specifically we can see in chart B that the overall figure for computer ownership
stands at around 60 million which represents a huge increase in a very short time period.
Now of course 60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you compare the total population
and this is a key reason why the personal computer market is such a hot market.
For us at Alpha and of course for all of our competitors as well we have millions of potential
customers who are looking to join the internet generation. If we do this right we really can
repude rewards in a very short time frame. I now like to move on to discuss the X420 brand itself
and compare and contrast with some of our key competitors.
All right we're back so now let's start with language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay so in the first part of what Mr Ford is saying he mentioned something
called market share. Now Margot what is market share? That's right everyone is competing for market
share and this is basically a small portion of your available market. So for example if you
sell perfumes, women's perfume then your market share is maybe women who are 18 to 35 years old
in your city or in your town or in your country. I see right so when we're talking about market
share because we're sharing a piece of this big pie we're going to talk about that in terms of a
percentage so 30% or 15%. That's right I think maybe one of the clearest examples is Coca-Cola has
I think maybe a 60% market share of the carbonated beverages market. Interesting so you could say
that Apple has a 50% market share of the personal computing industry. That's right very good so
this is what we refer to as market share. Now as we continue to talk about markets we have
two very interesting words when we refer to a developed market and a developing market.
Okay so a developed market is something that has been polished and grown over time perhaps
we talk about the developed world being Western Europe and America but then we have developing
markets and those are markets that are still trying to figure out kind of what's going on they're
growing they're usually growing much faster than a developed market. That's right so again when
we're talking about maybe computers we consider for example the United States a developed market many
people already have a computer or expressed a desire by one and so maybe a developing market are
some of the African countries where they're still growing and so now they're beginning to purchase
more and more computers. Okay so developed and developing two different ways to describe markets.
That's right. Now after that we hear this phrase cut throat so someone asks why is this market so cut
throat. What does this mean? A cut throat business or a cut throat industry. It means that it's
very very competitive. Okay so cut throat we're actually talking about maybe having a knife and
cutting someone else's throat but it's just a metaphor it's a way of saying yes this is very
competitive so you're not actually cutting someone's throat. Everyone is fighting for that market
share so it's very cut throat everyone is is fighting very very hard but you're not literally
killing someone or cutting their throat. And you could even use this to talk about a sporting event
you could say you know it was a cut throat game. That's right that's right so anything that's very
competitive or very close. So to finish off language takeaway when Mr Ford was towards the end of
his presentation he said that the rewards could be very very big in a very short timeframe.
So when we say the word timeframe we mean period of time it's not like you know two PM it's like
from from May to June we have this short timeframe it's only two months long. That's right. So time frame
is a window or a period. That's right so this is what he is referring to is that in the very short
period or in this period of time they could make a lot of money a time frame. Right but how long
would a long time frame be maybe a couple of years? Alright so you can have a short time frame and a
long time frame. That's right okay why don't we take a look at our dialogue again and we'll be
back shortly with fluency builder. As all of you are well aware competition and laptop computer
sector is intense we continue to fight with our competitors for market share and this is the case
both in the developed markets and the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa.
You may ask yourself why is this market so cut throat? Well the answer is simple there is a huge
untapped potential market out there with a huge untapped potential for profit. If I bring up the first
graph here it shows the increase in terms of number of computer owners across the globe. As you can
see in the 1980s computer ownership amounted to around 0.5% of the total world population. Since
the 1990s computer ownership has risen dramatically. In the new millennium we saw an even larger
explosion in computer owners with figures rising to around 4% to 5% and increase of 1,000% compared
with the 1980s. If we move on to discuss the figures for China specifically we can see in chart
B that the overall figure for computer ownership stands at around 60 million which represents a huge
increase in a very short time period. Now of course 60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you
compare the total population of China. And this is a key reason why the personal computer market
is such a hot market. For us at Alpha and of course for all of our competitors as well we have
millions of potential customers who are looking to join the internet generation. If we do this
right we really can repude rewards in a very short time frame. I now like to move on to discuss the
X420 brand itself and compare and contrast with some of our key competitors.
Alright we're back so now we've picked out a couple of different phrases for you. Let's check
those out now on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. So in today's dialogue we heard Mr. Ford talk
about some numbers he's talking about growth and change in the market and he says with figures
2 around 4 to 5 percent we've got an overall increase of 1000 percent. That's right so this phrase
an increase of very very common when you're talking about growth of maybe revenue or when you're
talking about the growth of a company or sales for example. So it's important to remember here that
this is a fixed phrase we say an increase of 10 percent or an increase of 30 percent. But you can
use the same phrase with with drops in percentages or money so you can say a decrease of 10 percent
that means that you go down 10 percent or a decrease of 100 percent. That's right. So a very useful
phrase when talking about incrementing someone or as you said decreasing a decrease of 5 percent.
Now Mr. Ford used a very interesting phrase when referring to the Chinese market obviously it's a
very big market and he says that the computer ownership stands at around 60 million. But of course
60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you compare it to the population of China. That's right.
So what does this mean? It's a big percentage or a small percentage. Very very small.
All right so what the what he's saying here is it's like a drop of water in an ocean. So a drop of
water is so small you don't even notice it you don't even see it because the ocean is so big and so
you can use this in many different ways you can say hey you know five dollars is just a drop in the
ocean. Right. It's not really important because it's very little money. That's right that's right.
So it's sort of like a metaphor saying you know what it's very insignificant. It's just a drop
of just a drop of water in an ocean. It's not really something you can notice. That's right just a drop
in the ocean. And now at the very end of today's speech we heard the phrase to compare and contrast.
So we're talking about the X420 computer brand itself. Now what is what is Mr. Ford mean when
he says to compare and contrast. So when we mentioned the word compare we are basically trying to
determine how they are similar in many ways the characteristics of how they are similar. And to contrast
is how they are different right? That's right. So let's let's use an example perhaps we could say
Pepsi and Coca Cola let's compare and contrast. So they're both carbonated beverages. They are both
sweet and they're both they're pretty much the same color. That's right and they're also fairly
cheap. They have about the same price. But I would say that Coca Cola is tastes more like prune.
So that would be a contrast in characteristic of Coca Cola is that maybe it tastes a little bit sweeter.
It does and you could also say it's easier to find Coca Cola. Pepsi is less easy to find sometimes.
That's right. Another way that they're different. So basically to compare and contrast
is to point out how two things are similar and how they're different. That's right. So we've had
a lot of interesting phrases there. I think very useful if you're talking about business and
marketing and sales. So why don't we listen to our dialogue one last time?
As all of you are well aware, competition and laptop computer sector is intense. We continue to
fight with our competitors for market share and this is the case both in the developed markets
and the West as well as more developing markets in Asia and Africa. You may ask yourself,
why is this market so cut throat? Well the answer is simple. There's a huge untapped potential
market out there with a huge untapped potential for profit. If I bring up the first graph here,
it shows the increase in terms of number of computer owners across the globe. As you can see in the
1980s computer ownership amounted to around 0.5% of the total world population. Since the 1990s computer
ownership has risen dramatically. In the new millennium we saw an even larger explosion in computer
owners with figures rising to around 4% to 5%. In an increase of 1,000% compared with the 1980s.
If we move on to discuss the figures for China specifically, we can see in chart B that the overall
figure for computer ownership stands at around 60 million which represents a huge increase in a
very short time period. Now of course 60 million is just a drop in the ocean if you compare
the total population of China. And this is a key reason why the personal computer market is such a
hot market. For us at alpha and of course for all of our competitors as well, we have millions of
potential customers who are looking to join the internet generation. If we do this right, we really
can repute rewards in a very short time frame. I now like to move on to discuss the X420 brand itself
and compare and contrast with some of our key competitors.
Alright we're back so as we mentioned this is just a part of our presentation series.
We're going to keep on talking with Mr. Ford as he discusses business and a lot of other
very interesting and useful skills for talking in public. That's right. So the goal of this series
is to help you feel better when you're giving a presentation in English. We all know it's very
very hard to talk in English when you're still learning but it's even harder to talk alone to give
us speech or presentation. And so the point of this series is to really give you those skills
and to help teach you some of the key phrases and words that you'll be using in your presentations
in the future. That's right. So if you have any questions or any doubts, we are always available
at English.com and we'll see everyone there. Bye. Bye.