Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got another episode in our series about giving a presentation.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about some key elements of the topic that we're talking about.
We're talking about a laptop computer. So we're going to give some more details and characteristics about the computer and what makes it so special.
So let's take a listen to what Mr. Ford has to say about what makes this company's computers very special.
How did you get this video?
It's not a good question.
Now a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates the new X420 line with our previous models?
And also of course with some of our competitors. In other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the others?
This is a key question and is something I'd like to explore in a little depth.
Firstly, the X420 has a range of USBs that really make it a cut above the rest.
The first thing to mention is that the X420 is the first in a new generation of ultra light laptop computers.
It is only two pounds which compares very favorably with all our key competitors.
In terms of computer performance for such a light machine, it's very powerful.
4GB of RAM with an ultra fast processor. The most advanced video in sound cards on the market are installed with a crystal clear 15-inch LCD display.
The X420 really stands out as an ex-generation laptop.
Compared with our previous X540 range, it really is in a league of its own.
Now, if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420, we can see that sales revenue for 2010 is expected to hit at least $20 million.
Now this is really a conservative estimate. If our marketing campaign is successful, I'm confident that we could see a doubling of this figure at the very least.
Now, please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production. I'm certain that in the coming three years,
the X420 will actually overtake all our existing products, both in terms of sales and revenue.
Okay, now let's move on to discuss our marketing concept and look more closely at our key competitors.
Alright, we're back. So we obviously heard a lot of vocab here, a lot of interesting things regarding the computer.
Why don't we take a look at some of the words that he used on language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
So the first word that is pretty challenging is to differentiate. It's a verb. So Mr. Ford says,
ask yourself what it is that differentiates this new computer line with other ones.
That's right. So two differentiates. That means what makes it different. What is so special about it, right?
That's right. So you can ask a question like this. What differentiates Apple computers from other computers?
That's right. So you're asking what makes it so different. That's right. Okay. So then he
refrazes the question and he says, well, in other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the other computers?
Alright, so this is a verbal phrase to stand out. It's very similar to the one that we just mentioned to differentiate.
This means what makes this computer special? Why is it unique? That's right. So we're basically saying,
why is this one more noticeable than the rest? That's to stand out. So maybe if everyone in the office is wearing white
P-shirts today, but somebody comes in wearing a red T-shirt. That person is going to stand out.
Actually, Mark, I think today that's you. You're wearing a red T-shirt today. So you stand out.
Okay. So now as he continued to talk about the computer, he used this prefix before an adjective.
That was very interesting. He said this computer is ultra light and then he said it's ultra thin as well.
And that it has an ultra fast processor. Okay. So ultra like ultra fast ultra thin.
This is a way of saying very, very. That's right. So that's what he's saying. He's saying it's very light.
It's very thin. So that's pretty much the structure. You can add ultra before an adjective to
emphasize that it's very something. That's right. So when I think of cool actors,
I think of James Dean. He was ultra cool. Ultra cool. Very cool. That's right. Okay. So you can do it with
pretty much all adjectives, but you know, you can't really exaggerate and use it all the time.
That's what the key is to remember. This is an exaggeration. So yeah, you don't want to use it all
a time. But if you want to make sure you say that something is, if you want to emphasize that something
is special or that it's very, very something. You use the word ultra. That's right. Okay.
As you continue to talk about the characteristics of the laptop computer, he made reference to the
LCD display, the screen of the computer. And he said that it's a crystal clear 15 inch LCD display.
What does he mean by crystal clear? Well, crystal is a very special kind of glass. Right. And so
it's expensive. It's what some people have as their special glassware, you know, wine glasses,
drinking glasses. And so crystal is very special because it's so it's so clear to see through.
So transparent. It's transparent. Like goes through it. You can see everything. And so to say
something is crystal clear to it's to say that it's very, very clear. It's extremely clear.
It's as clear as crystal. Okay. So basically, like the the screen of this computer, you can see
very, very well everything that's on the screen, everything that's happening. All the colors,
all of the words. Okay. And then moving away from the characteristics of the computer,
he talked about projected sales and he expected $20 million. But he said that that is a very
conservative estimate. Okay. So an estimate is like a guess. It's how much we think we will earn
in a year or how much we think will happen. But in this case, a conservative estimate means that
it's a low estimate. You know, we might make $20 million next year. That's conservative.
Another estimate is we will make $40 million. So that's not conservative. That's right. Okay. So
as you said an estimate is we are more or less guessing how much it would be. And conservative.
So what would what would be the opposite of a conservative estimate? You could say a generous estimate.
That means you're giving a lot. Okay. So a generous estimate is our revenues will be at around
$60 million next year. Okay. Very good. So I think we've taken in a lot. Why don't we take a break?
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with fluency builder.
Now a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates the new X420 line with our previous
models? In also of course with some of our competitors. In other words, what makes the X420 stand out
from all the others? This is a key question and it's something I'd like to explore in a little depth.
Firstly, the X420 has a range of USPs that really make it a cut above the rest. The first thing
to mention is that the X420 is the first and a new generation of ultra light laptop computers.
It is only two pounds which compares very favorably with all our key competitors. In terms of
computer performance for such a light machine it's very powerful. 4GB of RAM with an ultra fast
processor. The most advanced video in sound cards on the market are installed with a crystal
clear 15-inch LCD display. The X420 really stands out as an ex-generation laptop.
Compared with our previous X540 range it really is in a league of its own.
Now, if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420 we can see that sales revenue for 2010
is expected to hit at least $20 million. Now this is really a conservative estimate.
If our marketing campaign is successful I'm confident that we can see a doubling of this figure
at the very least. Now please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production.
I'm certain that in the coming three years the X420 will actually overtake all our existing products.
Both in terms of sales and revenue. Okay, now let's move on to discuss our marketing concept
and look more closely at our key competitors.
All right, we're back with Fluency Builder. Let's take a look at some key phrases now.
Fluency Builder. All right, so our first phrase is a very important phrase when you're trying to
differentiate different products or things. We say this is really a cut above the rest.
Okay, so if something is a cut above the rest it means that it's in a different category
from everyone else. It's a lot better. It is a lot better. So you can say that we
saw many, many applicants who wanted to come for a job at our company, but John, he was a cut above
the rest. He was much better than all of the other candidates. Okay, very good. So a cut above the rest.
Now when we talked about this computer he also made reference saying that, you know, it's in
a league of its own. The computer is so powerful. It's so new. It's so fantastic that it's in a league of
it's own. Okay, so a league is like a category in this case. We have good computers. We have great
computers, but this computer is so good. It's an entirely new category. It's awesome. It's amazing.
It's mind blowing. So we often say this with new things, you know, this is great, but nothing
before it can compare. There's just not as good. So it's in a league of its own. Okay, very good.
So you can make reference to products or also people, right? A person can be in a league of his own.
That's right. So, you know, there are a lot of good singers in the world. But this singer,
he is in a league of his own. Okay, very good. And to finish off, Lluency Beller towards the end of his
dialogue, he said, to please bear in mind that this is only the first year of production.
Okay, so we're talking about making these products. You know, there's there's going to,
it's going to take time to make money. And Mr. Ford would like us to bear something in mind to bear
in mind this fact. So to bear something in mind means to remember or to consider. Okay.
So he's asking us to please consider that it's only the first year of production. So we can't really
expect too much. That's right. So you could say this about a number of different things.
I could say, you know, Marco, here's, here's my report. Please look over it. Please bear in mind.
This is only a first draft. Okay. So I will make some edits. I will make some changes.
It's not perfect. And I know that. So please bear this in mind. Okay. So you're kind of warning
you're kind of letting me know to consider the fact that it's not the final report. And there
might be some mistakes. Exactly. So to bear in mind, that this saying this is kind of like a warning
that things are not perfect yet. But, you know, I still want your opinion. Okay. Very good.
So when are we listened to the dialogue again? And we're back in a bit.
It's not the important question. Now, a key question you might ask yourself is what differentiates
the new X420 line with our previous models? And also, of course, with some of our competitors.
In other words, what makes the X420 stand out from all the others? This is a key question
and is something I'd like to explore in a little depth. Firstly, the X420 has a range of
USBs that really make it a cut above the rest. The first thing to mention is that the X420 is the
first in a new generation of ultra light laptop computers. It is only two pounds, which compares
very favorably with all our key competitors. In terms of computer performance, for such a light
machine, it's very powerful. 4GB of RAM with an ultra fast processor. The most advanced video
and sound cards on the market are installed with a crystal clear 15 inch LCD display.
The X420 really stands out as an ex-generation laptop. Compared with our previous X540 range,
it really is in a league of its own. Now, if we go on to look at projected sales for the X420,
we can see that sales revenue for 2010 is expected to hit at least $20 million.
Now, this is really a conservative estimate. If our marketing campaign is successful,
I'm confident that we could see a doubling of this figure at the very least.
Now, please bear in mind that this is only for the first year of production. I'm certain that
in the coming three years, the X420 will actually overtake all our existing products,
both in terms of sales and revenue. Okay, now let's move on to discuss our marketing
concept and look more closely at our key competitors.
We're back. Now, you've probably saw this acronym in the very first part of the dialogue
when he said that the X420 has a range of USBs that really make it a cut above the rest.
All right, so this is a very special acronym for the business world. And it stands for U,
Unique, S, selling, and P, point, Unique, selling point. That's right. So as the name says,
a unique selling point are characteristics that are unique to the machine that
allow it to be more competitive and to persuade people to buy it or to sell itself.
All right, so the new iPhone has a very interesting Unique selling point. It has two cameras,
one on the front and one on the back. So that really differentiates it from other phones on the market.
That's right. So that is what a USB is or a unique selling point. As we said, it's an acronym in
the business world, but next time that you find the opportunity to use it, I'm sure it's going to
sound amazing. Yes, very professional. USB Unique selling point. All right, so that's all the time we have,
be sure to check out the next part of our series next week. And of course, if you have any questions
or comments, you're always welcome at EnglishPod.com. We will see you there. Bye.