Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you guys.
Now Marco what are we talking about today?
That's right today we're going to try to buy a new car. So we're going to the car dealer and we want
to try and see if we can get a new car. Okay so lots of great vocabulary for buying that car.
Let's check out today's dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
I see. You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale. It is a perfect
time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year. Perfect. I like this one. That is the Ford
focus. A very light but powerful vehicle. It comes with dual-side airbags, power steering and power
windows. Tinted windows and your choice of either automatic or manual transmission. Sounds like a good
car. How many miles to the gallon? It is a very fuel efficient vehicle giving you about 34 miles in the
city and 40 on the highway. That is really convenient especially now the fuel prices are so high.
What's under the hood? A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine. Trust me this car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question. What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest
for the first year. You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back. Great. Let's do it.
All right. We're back. So now we're going to take a look at some of that Vokab especially the one
that the salesman used on language takeaway. Language takeaway. All right. So at the beginning of this
dialogue we hear a lot of features that this car has. The first one is trade in actually this is
something that the man says when he goes to the car lot. That's right. He says he has an old car.
He has a Ford Pinto and he wants to trade it in. He wants to trade in his old car.
So this is something that you do in America or other other places when you have a car already
but you want a new car. And so the car lot, the place where you can buy the cars they usually
give you some money for your old car and you can spend that money on your new car. That's right.
So basically you give them your old car plus some extra cash and then you can get a new car.
So that's basically what a trade-in is. And well as you said we had a lot of features on this car
of the Ford Focus. First of all, dual-side airbags. Okay so dual-side is pretty simple. It
means that you have them on both sides. The left and the right dual means two. But our airbags are
what's important in this phrase airbags do what exactly Marco. They protect you from hitting
the front part of the car. So maybe out of the steering wheel, a bag will inflate if you crash.
So it will prevent you from hitting the steering wheel and getting hurt. It's like a big balloon
and it protects you from damaging your body. That's right. So it has two airbags with
for the passenger and for the driver. All right so after that we also heard about a number of things
that are power, power steering power windows. So what is power steering do? Power steering
are also called assisted steering. It allows you to turn your car with less effort. So maybe
you've driven a car that didn't have power steering and so you really have to struggle when you're
turning the car especially if you're parking. So if the turn the wheel and turn it turn it turn
it to turn but a power steering makes it more automatic. That's right. So it's very easy to turn
left or right. That's right. And the same thing goes for power windows. So maybe your car doesn't have
electric windows. So you have to do it manually with a little lever. It's a turn it around that
around that around. But instead with power windows you just push a button and the window goes down
or up. That's right. And actually as well another feature for the windows we have tinted windows.
Now these are sometimes very popular. I don't think I've ever had tinted windows on my car but
tint means something is darker. It's protected from the sun. So tinted sunglasses for example
can be very dark. But tinted windows on a car are black. They don't let much sunlight in. So you
don't get blinded by the sun or so other people can't see you from outside. Usually limousines.
You will see all limousines have tinted windows. Politicians like to drive around in cars with
tinted windows. That's right. Okay. So a lot of features. There are a lot of Vokab regarding the car.
Why don't we take a break? Let's listen to the dialogue again. And we'll be back to talk some more.
Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
I see. You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale. It is a perfect
time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year. Perfect. I like this one. That is the Ford
Focus. A very light but powerful vehicle. It comes with dual-side airbags, power steering and
power windows. Tinted windows and your choice of either automatic or manual transmission. Sounds like a good
car. How many miles to the gallon? It is a very fuel efficient vehicle giving you about 34 miles
in the city and 40 on the highway. That is really convenient, especially now the fuel prices are so high.
What's under the hood? A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine. Trust me. This car is fast.
Now for the most difficult question. What is the price tag for this lovely vehicle?
Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and no interest
for the first year. You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
Great. Let's do it.
All right. We're back. So now let's start again with language takeaway. Now let's take a look at part two.
Language takeaway. All right. So a very very key phrase that we heard in the dialogue is
automatic or sometimes manual transmission. So automatic transmission, manual transmission. This is
very important when we talk about cars. That's right. So basically the car has a lot of gears and
with an automatic transmission, the car will basically change gears by itself. Right. So you can
start in park and you go to drive and you can go to reverse park drive reverse. That's right. This
controls kind of the way the car moves. But with a manual transmission, this means you have to do it
by yourself using your hand. So we have what gears. We have 1, 2, 3, 4 and sometimes 5. That's right.
So that's a manual transmission. You have to change the gears manually. It's a lot of work.
Now talking about another feature of the car, the client asked, well how many miles to the
gallon does the car get? And the salesman said that the car is very fuel efficient.
Okay. So this is a very important phrase right now as gas is very expensive in some parts of the world.
And we're concerned about the environment, right? So a fuel efficient car is a car that uses gas very
well. That means that I can go very, very far on one tank of gas. I don't need to keep putting gas
into my car. That's right. So usually for example sports cars are not fuel efficient.
Hummers are not fuel efficient. That's right. So fuel efficient is a key thing to look for these days.
But the customer also wanted to know what's under the hood. So this phrase under the hood is very,
very common when we're talking about cars. That's right. The person said what's under the hood?
And basically what we're seeing is what is under the hood, which is that metal cover and the
front part of the car. So you lift that in there. You can have access to the engine. So basically that's the
question. What kind of an engine does this car have? Oftentimes when your car stops or you have a problem
like it's broken, someone like a mechanic will say, hey, let's have a look. Let's look under the hood.
He wants to know, let's look at the engines so we can find the problem. But in this case,
it's not a problem. He just wants to know what kind of a car is this? Is it powerful? Or is it not so
powerful? That's right. That's exactly right. So that's why we want to know what's under the hood.
And well, he goes on to explain all the features about the engine. But then when we talk about the
payment, how much the car costs, the salesman said, you know what? It's not expensive. And on top of that,
you can drive it out today with 0% down payment. Okay. This is important to down payments are
payments that you often make with very, very big ticket items, a house, a car, things like this. So
a down payment is what you have to pay to get the thing to begin using it, but not all of the payment.
Right. So it's a percentage. So if the car is $10,000 and the man says, there's a 0% down payment.
How much do I have to pay? Mark 0. 0. I don't pay anything today. I pay in a month, a little bit.
And then next month, a little bit. But if the payment is a 10% down payment, then I have to pay $1,000. That's right.
That's right. So as you said, it's usually about things that have a big price tech that are very expensive.
A house, a car, these types of things usually you need to give a down payment. That means that you're
committing to buying it. That's right. So a lot of interesting things going on in today's lesson.
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again? And we'll be back to talk some more.
Hi there. I am looking for a new car. I have this old Ford Pinto that I would like to trade in.
I see. You are in luck this month because all of our 2010 models are on sale. It is a perfect
time to buy a new car since it's the end of the year. Perfect. I like this one. That is the Ford
Focus. A very light but powerful vehicle. It comes with dual-side airbags, power steering and power
windows. Tinted windows and your choice of either automatic or manual transmission. Sounds like a good
car. How many miles to the gallon? It is a very fuel efficient vehicle. Giving you about
34 miles in the city and 40 on the highway. That is really convenient, especially now the fuel prices
are so high. What's under the hood? A very powerful 2.5 liter turbocharged engine. Trust me,
this car is fast. Now for the most difficult question. What is the price tech for this lovely
vehicle? Very affordable, man. You can take it out of this lot today with zero down payment and
no interest for the first year. You can test drive it now and we can sign the papers when we get back.
Great. Let's do it.
All right. So buying a new car can always be tricky. What do you prefer though for example in these
types of features of the car? For me, a car must be very fuel efficient. Because number one,
cars are all bad for the environment. So I want a car that's less bad for the environment.
But also I really like manual transmission because number one, manual transmission is
more fuel efficient than automatic. And also I like to have more control when I'm driving. I feel
safer in a manual transition car because when you do manual, you actually pay more attention to
your driving. You have to concentrate. But automatic, you can think about other things,
listen to the music and touch. So I think that that's a safety issue. What do you look for?
I know you're really really into cars. Yeah, I actually prefer manual transmissions as well.
Most importantly because of the way that the car drives, especially a sports car, it's definitely
something for me is nice to have a manual transmission. But also you know a little nice features like
and the exterior, like the rims, like nice rims, or maybe a nice paint job. Tinted windows,
I'm not a very big fan of tinted windows. But yeah, I don't know. Some cars nowadays even for
as you said politicians, they even sell them bulletproof. That's right. They have bulletproof
glass. Very, very secure. Well for me, I don't think I need bulletproof glass, but a good stereo
is a good sign. But that's right. Yeah. You want to have good speakers and the connector iPod to the
stereo now. Exactly. Exactly. So a lot of great things with cars and actually the model that
they mentioned, the Ford Pinto is a very popular but very bad car. It was cheap. It was cheap,
but it wasn't very good. And the 1970s and 80s, this was a very common car and it's its famous for
being a small cheap car. That's right. That's right. Like the Volkswagen Beetle. Yes, exactly.
So maybe you can come to our website, english.com and you can tell us if you have a car, what was your
first car? And did you buy a new car or a used car? Hmm. That's right. Second hand cars.
So let us know. And of course, if you have any questions, we're always there on the website
English.com. And we'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.