Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today's show is a continuation of our series about giving a presentation
in English. So we're talking about a special line of computers here.
That's right and on this occasion we're going to compare two companies so we're going to try
to tell everyone what the differences between our company and the competitors.
All right so we learned a lot of great phrases and words for making comparisons in last week's
show. You're going to hear some of these again. Let's listen to the dialogue.
Now of course with all this cutting-edge technology there must be a catch. You might ask yourself,
about the retail price will be too much for most consumers you might say. Well you'd be wrong.
Yes of course the X420 is aimed at the luxury market but if you compare the price of our
leading competitors the X420 represents incredible value for money. At only 15,000 RMB it is far more
affordable and far more attractive than almost every leading brand in model. So what differentiates
us from our competitors? Well if we compare oranges luxury MP40 range then we can really highlight
some of the differences. Now of course orange has an enviable record for producing revolutionary
and top class products and I must admit the MP40 is a breathtaking machine. However for most consumers
the MP40 is simply far too expensive to consider. Compared with the X420 it is more expensive
and there's no doubt that considering the quality and workmanship that goes into the X420 we
really win hands down on value for money. Also if you compare the after sales service we offer I think
we can proudly boast the best customer service facilities in the whole laptop sector.
As opposed to most of our rivals we guarantee quality we guarantee service and we guarantee reliability.
The questions we must ask ourselves are what does the alpha brand stand for and also how can we
set ourselves apart from our competitors? The answer to both of these questions is the same my friends.
Alpha stands first and foremost for quality for excellence and for service. If we always stick to
this philosophy then I'm confident that we will really be able to expand our market share
significantly. Okay let me move on now to give you an idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at these phrases on language takeaway.
Our first phrase comes from the very first sentence of today's dialogue we heard this phrase
cutting edge technology now Marco what does cutting edge mean? Okay so as you see in the dialogue
we're talking about technology and if technology is cutting edge it basically means it's new it's
very modern it's the newest you can get it's the most advanced perhaps that's right. So
what's an example of a current cutting edge technology can you think of something? So for example when we
talk about mobile phones that can now connect to the internet you can send emails
have many features even two cameras and touch sensitive screens this is a type of cutting edge
technology. Okay it's the most new technology the newest that's right. So after that we heard another
phrase this is a bit different this is more of a this is more of a business phrase we have this
retail price I bet the retail price will be too much. So what is a retail price and how is it
different from a regular price? Okay so the retail price is basically the amount of money that you pay
for something at the store. Exactly so if I go to a store and I buy a computer for $1,000 I know that
the store they bought the computer for less money otherwise they don't earn any money it's about
it's a bad business. That's right. So the retail price is higher than the actual price the cost of
production. So retail price just basically means exactly what you said Marco how much you would spend
on something how much and then costs in a store. That's right that's why they're called retail stores.
Exactly. Now moving on when we're discussing the X420 this computer Mr. Ford says that it's aimed
at the luxury market. That means that this company would like to sell the computer in the luxury
market the luxury market is not the normal market it's the market for very expensive very
beautiful very nice things luxury items luxury brands are very expensive. That's right so for example
a car such as Mercedes Benz might be aimed at the luxury market whereas a car like a Honda Civic
is aimed at maybe more of a middle class market. Exactly or in clothing you could say Gucci is a
luxury brand. All right whereas the gap or something is a regular consumer brand. That's right.
So this is what we talk about when we refer to a luxury market. Now moving on to the description
of the X420 Mr. Ford says that it's amazing quality and that the workmanship is very very good.
So workmanship is related to the word work and now workmanship means how something is made.
Generally when we talk about luxury goods we expect the workmanship to be very very high quality.
That means that the way that these things are made is the best. That's right. It's not going to
break in one day. Usually I think when you talk about workmanship or luxury items like this
maybe they're part of it is made by hand. So this is what we talk about workmanship is how
skilled that that person is or how skilled his hands are to make this great piece of luxury good
exactly. So a very good example in the world of music is the stratavarius violin. So stratavarius
violins are very very expensive because the workmanship is the best quality in the history of
world music. That's right. Very good. So that's what we talk about workmanship. You can apply it
to many different things but moving on to our last word for language takeaway today. Another nice
business phrase that we talk about specifically in sales is market share.
Now Marco described to me market share because I know what a market is. It's where things are bought
and sold but what is a share market share. So in this case we're talking about computers. So a
market share is how much a company owns in the market or how much they sell in this market. So for
example if we have a city of a thousand people and everyone there buys computers. If we sell
computers to 500 people of that city that means we own a 50% market share. Okay so a market share
is usually like a percentage right it's a piece of this big pie. That's right. So everyone is always
fighting for more market share. Whoever sells more has bigger market share. So in the world of
televisions would you say that Sony has a large market share and in televisions? Probably although
I think maybe Samsung has bigger yeah market share or LG. I don't know see this is the thing
with market shares that there are so many brands in a certain industry that everyone has maybe a
little piece of the pie or maybe one has a bigger piece. I see. All right well that's it for language
takeaway. I hope you guys have learned something there. We're going to be back in a moment with fluency
builder. Now of course with all this cutting edge technology there must be a catch. You might
ask yourself about the retail price will be too much for most consumers you might say. Well you
would be wrong. Yes of course the X420 is aimed at the luxury market but if you compare the price of
our leading competitors the X420 represents incredible value for money. At only 15,000 RMB it is far
more affordable and far more attractive than almost every leading brand and model. So what differentiates
us from our competitors? Well if we compare orange's luxury MP40 range then we can really highlight
some of the differences. Now of course orange has an enviable record for producing revolutionary
and top class products and I must admit the MP40 is a breathtaking machine. However for most consumers
the MP40 is simply far too expensive to consider. Compared with the X420 it is more expensive
and there's no doubt that considering the quality and workmanship that goes into the X420 we really
win hands down on value for money. Also if you compare the after sales service we offer I think we can
proudly boast the best customer service facilities in the whole laptop sector. As opposed to most
of our rivals we guarantee quality we guarantee service and we guarantee reliability. The questions
we must ask ourselves are what does the alpha brand stand for and also how can we set ourselves
apart from our competitors? The answer to both of these questions is the same my friends.
Alpha stands first and foremost for quality for excellence and for service. If we always stick to
this philosophy then I'm confident that we will really be able to expand our market share
significantly. Okay let me move on now to give you an idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder
So the first phrase I would like to look at in Fluency Builder is very important for consumers. I
mean people who buy things are very interested in this thing. We call it value for money.
Hmm that's right when Mr Ford was talking about the X420 it's he said it represents
incredible value for money at only 15,000 RMB. Okay so 15,000 RMB sounds like a lot of money to me
but he's saying that the value of the product is very good considering the price. That's right
and that's what the phrase value for money is as you said the quality and how much you are
getting for this product compared to how much you're paying for it is very very good. So the idea is
it should be more expensive. But it's not so the value considering considering the price is actually
very good. So maybe I could say that you know this computer this this Apple computer it's expensive
it's $1,500 but the value for money is great because I'll have this computer for five years.
That's right. Another computer might break and I have to buy a new one. And also you can describe
value for money is something good or bad. For example the same computer you can say it doesn't
represent good value for money. So maybe you pay more than what you're actually getting.
There was a bad deal. It was a bad deal that's right. Great. Well the next phrase is an interesting
one. It's in the sentence where we talked about workmanship. So semester four was describing
the x420 and he said it really wins hands down on a value for money. That's right. So the
phrase that we're going to take a look at is hands down. So what does he mean when he says that
workmanship for the x420 wins hands down? So this is a very spoken English phrase and it has nothing
to do with your hands. It means, well I guess it could hands down. I'm not really sure what the
literal meaning is but when we say it we mean that something is without competition. So there is no
doubt in my mind. This is absolutely the best in value for money. And so maybe if I say
over there are two or three computers they're all nice nothing is hands down. But if I say listen
this IBM computer is hands down the best on the market. That means there's no other competition.
It is the best. So you can't really argue with that. It's the best no arguments there.
No arguments. Exactly hands down. He is hands down the best baseball player I've ever seen.
Okay very good. Okay so now moving on to our next phrase when Mr. Ford again was talking about
now the company he said that the alpha brand is what does it stand for and he said that it stands
first and foremost for quality. Okay so this means you think about first and foremost this means
above everything else. So alpha means a lot of things. They make good computers. They're strong
company. But first and foremost it means quality. It means that more important than any other thing
that alpha brand does quality is the most important. Okay so basically we're seeing the first
thing and the most important thing is quality. So that's what you mean when you say first and foremost.
So you can say for example when I'm looking for a car price is the first and foremost important quality.
Okay so we're talking about you know for Marco the most important factor the most important
part of buying a car is the price. That's right. So moving on to our last phrase now when Mr. Ford
was ending this part of his speech he said that we always stick to this philosophy. To stick to.
So stick is a verb and a noun if you're familiar with the noun it's different from what we're
talking about today. To stick to remember that is a phrase to stick to something. So to stick
to means to continue doing it. Okay you're going to hear this a lot when you talk about sports
or even in the office. I could say listen Marco I don't want you to quit. I really want you to stick
to this project. Okay so to continue doing to not give up. Don't give up right. So you can say this
to a child also you know I know you want to quit playing soccer but I think you should stick to it
to stick to it. That means to continue playing not to quit. Okay very good so it's a very nice
and maybe spoken English phrase which means continue doing to not give up to be persuasive.
Right to stick to something. I want to stick to it. You should stick to this. Okay very good.
So a lot of phrases here I think we've taken a look at a lot of things here. Maybe we should go back.
Let's review one last time the dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
Now of course with all this cutting edge technology there must be a catch. You might ask yourself
about the retail price will be too much for most consumers you might say. Well you'd be wrong.
Yes of course the X420 is aimed at the luxury market but if you compare the price of our
leading competitors the X420 represents incredible value for money. At only 15,000 RMB it is far more
affordable and far more attractive than almost every leading brand and model. So what differentiates
us from our competitors? Well if we compare oranges luxury MP40 range then we can really
highlight some of the differences. Now of course Orange has an enviable record for producing
revolutionary and top class products and I must admit the MP40 is a breathtaking machine.
However for most consumers the MP40 is simply far too expensive to consider. Compared with the
X420 it is more expensive and there's no doubt that considering the quality and workmanship
that goes into the X420 we really win hands down on value for money. Also if you compare the
AfterSale's service we offer I think we can proudly boast the best customer service facilities
in the whole laptop sector. As opposed to most of our rivals we guarantee quality we guarantee
service and we guarantee reliability. The questions we must ask ourselves are what does the
Alpha brand stand for and also how can we set ourselves apart from our competitors? The
insert of both of these questions is the same my friends. Alpha stands first and foremost for quality.
For excellence and for service. If we always stick to this philosophy then I'm confident that we
will really be able to expand our market share significantly. Okay let me move on now to give you
an idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
All right so that's all the time we have for today on this series. Be sure to check out the next
part next week where we're going to continue talking about presentations and as you can see it's
very business oriented but you can apply everything that you learn to other situations as well.
Exactly these phrases like hands down and to stick to these aren't business phrases these are
words you can use in business but I use these in my everyday life and I think that with a little
bit of practice you guys can sound really really fluent in English and these phrases are good
place to start. That's right so if you have any questions any doubts or comments you can visit our
website EnglishPod.com where we'll be there. See you guys soon. Bye.