Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have an elementary level lesson in which we're going to talk about
small talk. That's right, today we're going to talk to an old friend and so we're going to give you
some of the words and phrases you need to talk about your past or talk about how you have been.
So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to discuss it.
I hate coming to high school reunions. It'll be great honey. We will get to see your old
classmates and catch up to see how they've been doing. Ah yeah I guess so. Oh look there's Robert
Matthews. Rob. Hey Bill wow great to see you. Likewise it's been a long time. This is my wife Dorsey.
The ledger to meet you. So Bill how have you been? Can't complain. We have two children who are in
college and my business is going well. How about you? Ah you know me I'm a dedicated bachelor.
I never married although I do have a beautiful daughter with Mary. You remember her? We were
high school sweetheart's. It didn't really work out between us but I really can't complain either.
That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping you would come tonight.
You didn't hear? Frank passed away last year. Are you serious? Man just drinking your chain.
He'll be here soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
All right we're back. So now let's get started with our language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The first phrase we have here in language takeaway is a very important one
because it is the setting for today's dialogue. We are at a high school reunion. That's right so
everyone knows what high school is but a high school reunion is when you go back to your high school
for a party maybe five years or ten years after you graduate. So then you meet all your old friends
from high school you talk about you know how you have been and just meet up with everyone that
maybe you haven't seen in a very long time. Exactly so a reunion usually happens every
five years, ten years or 20 years. It can happen at different times but this is important because
you can have many different kinds of reunions like a college reunion or high school reunion.
I've even heard of some people who had an elementary school reunion. Really wow. Imagine seeing
your classmates when you were maybe ten years old. I couldn't imagine. All right so we're at a
high school reunion and we are there because we're going to meet our old classmates and to catch
up and see how they have been. Okay so this is exactly what you do at a reunion. You catch up
with people that you maybe lost touch with. To catch up means to find out about what people have
been doing since the last time you talked. So maybe Marco and I were classmates in high school
and we haven't talked in ten years. As a Marco I want to catch up. I want to learn about what you do
who you married where you work, things like that. Right so when two people get together the catch up
maybe it doesn't even have to be a very long time. Maybe you haven't seen your friend for a week
and so you want to get together have a cup of coffee and catch up and see how the relationship has
been going or how it's work so you want to catch up. So you can say this in a very simple way. Let's
catch up or it's been nice to catch up. That's right. All right moving on to our next word. This guy
built meets up with Robert Matthews and they're saying, hey wow great to see you and he answers
by saying likewise. So it's good to see you likewise. Right. That means it's good to see you too.
So you don't have to repeat everything that person just said for example if I just meet someone new
and I say it's a pleasure to meet you you can say I could say likewise. Likewise. Because I don't want
to say it's a pleasure to meet you too. That's so many words. So likewise is a very short way to say
all of those things. That's right. So we were finding out about Robert Matthews and he says that
well he is a dedicated bachelor. So a dedicated bachelor what is a bachelor Marco? So a bachelor is a
person who is not married a person who is single. A man a woman cannot be a bachelor. So a bachelor
is specifically a man and he's not married and we often have a stereotype that means we have an idea
of what a bachelor lives like right now. He has only beer and his refrigerator and he has
has many relationships and no wife. So that's right. So a dedicated bachelor is a person who is not
married and doesn't really seem to want to get married or any of this. He wants to space single.
Exactly. Okay. And well to finish off this guy Robert lied a little bit to Bill saying that
Frank had passed away. That's really mean but this phrase to pass away is very important and
something we should talk about. So what does it mean to pass away? It's another way of saying
he died. So that's nicer. Yeah it's a lot more subtle and nicer. So instead of saying
Frank died, you say Frank passed away. So you could say last year my grandmother passed away.
That's the way of saying that my grandmother died last year but again it's a lot nicer way to say.
Right because the word died can be a little bit too direct into harsh. So maybe saying my
grandmother passed away last year. It's a nicer way of saying it. Okay. So that's all the language
tickle you have. Let's take a look at our dialogue again and we'll be back.
I hate coming to high school reunions. It'll be great honey. We will get to see your old
classmates and catch up to see how they've been doing. Yeah I guess so. Oh look there's Robert Matthews.
Rob. Hey Bill wow great to see you. Likewise it's been a long time. This is my wife Dorothy.
Blasher to meet you. So Bill how have you been? Can't complain. We have two children who are in
college and my business is going well. How about you? You know me I'm a dedicated bachelor.
I never married although I do have a beautiful daughter with Mary. You remember her?
We were a high school sweetheart. It didn't really work out between us but I really can't complain either.
That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping he would come tonight.
You didn't hear? Frank passed away last year. Are you serious? Man just drinking your chain.
It'll be your soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
Alright let's move on now to 4 key phrases on fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So the focus of today's fluency builder is small talk. These are phrases you can use when you're
at a reunion or dinner. Especially with people you don't know very well. So let's jump in and
look at this first phrase. Great to see you. That's right. So he says hey Bill wow great to see you.
So this is a nice little opening phrase saying wow I'm really excited to see you. I'm really happy to see
you. Exactly. I mean I'm happy. Look at you. You know great to see you. You say this
at the beginning of a conversation. That's right. And actually Bill responded by saying
the likewise. So we talked about this. He's saying wow great to see you too. Then he continues by saying
it's been a long time. This means that these two people they have not seen each other in a very
long time. You can also say it's been so long or it's been a long time. That means it's been a long
time since we last saw each other. That's right. So Robert goes on to ask Bill. He says well you know
how have you been? How are things? Bill answers by saying can't complain. Okay so this is not
grammatically correct. Normally you need a subject. Right. I can't complain. But when we're
speaking in English and we're having a conversation like this it's okay to to say just can't complain
as a phrase. So he's saying have you been well I can't complain. Right. Can't complain. That means
nothing bad has happened. Things are okay. Right. You're saying that things are good. They're not
fantastic. But they're not bad either. So you can't really complain. So it's just a phrase where
very directly you can say oh can't complain. Everything's great. So you could even say this about
about other things like you know I asked John how his job was and he said can't complain. Right.
It's not great but it's not bad. Right. Exactly right. All right and obviously we saw how
Robert lied to Bill by saying that they're good friend that they're good friend of Frank
had passed away and he said are you serious? No I'm just yanking your chain. Okay so this might
sound very strange to a lot of you because a chain is something that doesn't really seem to fit in this
conversation. Right. But yanking your chain remember this as a phrase it means I'm just joking.
Right. I'm not serious. Kidding. I'm lying to you I guess right. So but how can you use this in
another context? Okay I could say you know Marco I have something I have to tell you.
And I say what? I'm leaving which part I quit. Are you serious? No I'm just yanking your chain.
Okay or no I'm just kidding. Right. So you're kind of teasing someone when you do this right?
Mm-hmm. I'm just yanking your chain. I'm just lying to you. I'm teasing you. I'm
making you believe something that isn't that isn't true. Exactly. So this is something you can
use after you tell someone that you were just joking. So you know I'm just yanking your chain.
I'm just joking with you. That's right. So don't try to translate it directly or
literally because it's not gonna make sense. So just remember this as a phrasal verb or a phrase in
general. Exactly. All right let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
I hate coming to a high school reunion. It'll be great honey. We will get to see your old classmates
and catch up to see how they've been doing. I yeah I guess so. Oh look there's Robert Matthews.
Rob. Hey Bill. Wow. Great to see you. Likewise it's been a long time. This is my wife Dorsey.
But pleasure to meet you. So Bill how have you been?
Can't complain. We have two children who are in college and my business is going well.
How about you?
You know me. I'm a dedicated bachelor. I never married although I do have a beautiful daughter
with Mary. You remember her? We were a high school sweetheart. It didn't really work out between us
but I really can't complain either. That's good. Have you seen Frank? I was hoping he would come
tonight. You didn't hear Frank passed away last year. Are you serious?
Man just janking your chain. He'll be yours soon. I saw him last week. He told me he would show up.
All right so we're back and talking about high school reunions these are very popular in the
United States right? They are very popular and I think people often have them every five,
10, 15, 20 years. But most people don't go to the high school reunion until either 10 or 20 years
after their high school graduation. I think at five years is very soon. 10 years is nice because
you haven't seen people but 20 years is really I think shocking because people can be completely
different or they could be the same but it's been you know you were 18 when you graduated
high school. Now you're 38 years old. You have this whole life that you've had and so I think it's
much more interesting. Yeah it's very interesting and I guess people go to these things half because
they do want to maybe meet up with old friends that they haven't kept in touch with. I think especially
this was very popular before the whole internet revolution. Now everyone's in touch and Facebook and
emails and it's just so much easier to keep in touch but before you have to remember that you know
it was basically by telephone or by mail. So actually seeing a person 10 years or catching up with
them was very difficult back then. Yeah we all see photos and videos now of our classmates.
So it's not quite as surprising when we bump into them later but I think it is still
interesting though because at least on my social networking websites there are a lot of people
that I don't have connections to and so I look forward to my high school reunion when I get to see
some of these people and kind of find out what they've been doing for the past 10 or 15 years.
It's actually very interesting I guess when you see how your classmates have changed how maybe
the the one that used to be the nerd or maybe not to not very attractive all of a sudden is really
attractive and has like a super model as a wife or how these things work out. Or the high school
football captain is now kind of sad and so yeah these are the types of surprises that people
look forward to when they go to high school reunions. So a very interesting subject let us know on
our website English.com if you're high school and the place where you live do they have high
school reunions or maybe even elementary school reunions. Yeah let us know we hope to find out more about
you guys' experiences and until next time bye.