Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we have part 7 of our series all about giving a presentation in English.
That's right so obviously not every presentation is going to go perfectly. Sometimes we do have some problems.
In this occasion we're going to take a look at tech problems and how to handle them.
That's right so you're going to learn some great ways to discuss and to explain technical problems.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert.
Please note that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over. Let's see if this
results the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael. There might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and start again.
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time don't they?
But it's not a huge problem. In the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that I can talk a little bit
more about the advertising concept and what we're looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
All right so we're back and now let's take a look at five key words that we've picked out for you
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay so we have some phrasal verbs today. The first one is to kick off.
That's right Mr. Ford started out by saying that we can kick off the first TV advert.
So this phrasal verb to kick off what does it mean?
It means to start something okay so to kick it off means to start.
So I can say tonight we're kicking off the party at 8 o'clock.
That's right or let's kick off this new product with a big party.
That's right okay so the phrasal verb to kick off you've probably also seen it in sports.
I think in soccer you have the kick off which is the same thing.
That's right except it's in noun so be careful with that one.
The kick off is the very beginning of the game.
Okay very good. In that same paragraph towards the end we see Mr. Ford saying okay so I just
need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Pop up. Right. I like this verb actually because it makes me think of that but when you're
using a computer and you have these little windows or these little icons, those little pictures
when something changes they appear quickly and that means in computer talk it means to pop up.
That's right you obviously maybe heard of this already you have annoying pop ups maybe
visit a website and all of a sudden these new windows start to open.
They're all advertisement. Do you buy this by this by this by this by this?
Right. There are pop ups but also you can have a pop up in a chat window for example.
In this case we also use it as a verb it should pop up so to pop up to appear to appear.
Very good. Obviously it didn't work something was happening with the projector and Mr. Ford
was going through maybe some of the problems and he said let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay. Connection is a very important noun especially when we're talking
about technical things like computers you can have an internet connection. This means how you
are able to use the internet but in this case we're talking about a projector which makes things bigger
and a computer and so those things need to need to have a connection they need to have a
cord or something that you plug into one and to the other so that they can talk to each other.
That's right. So as you notice we are using it as a noun they need to have the computer and the
projector needs to have a connection so you have the verb to connect but then you have the noun
a connection. All right and let's move on to another possible solution Mr. Ford suggests
rebooting the system. Okay so the verb here to reboot is another special computer word that means
to turn off and turn on again to restart. So if I say reboot that I'm using the prefix they
re which means a repetition or to do it again if I just say boot can I say just I need to boot
the computer. I need to boot up the computer. Okay boot up. That's right so in this case
you would be talking about a computer that is off and you want to turn it on so I would say
hey Marco can you boot up the computer for me? Now about using the word reboot or to boot up
it's usually for electronic things electric things you wouldn't say to reboot your car or to boot
up your car. No this is for for computer specifically electronics for example. Oh man my iPhone just
froze. I need to reboot it. Okay very good. All right and for our last phrase or verb for today
on language take away we have the towards the end of the dialogue towards the end. Towards the end
of the dialogue Mr. Ford apologizes and says you know what I'm sorry but technical problems do
crop up sometimes. Okay so this verb to crop up means to appear or to happen but not all the time.
So unexpectedly or occasionally. That's right so these things do crop up sometimes it means
every once in a while this problem will happen. So can I use this for a person if you say oh you
scared me you cropped up on me. No the creeped up on me creeped up very good so we can't confuse those
too but they sound very similar. They do sound similar but to crop up is usually a problem or an event
or a thing that happens and it happens not very often. Okay very good so I think we've taken a look at
a lot of words here specifically phrasal verbs so let's review those let's listen to our dialogue again.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert. Please note
that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally. Hmm.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over. Let's see if
this resolves the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael. There might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and
start again. I'll call IT support to come over right now.
Okay guys unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time. Don't they?
But it's not a huge problem. In the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that
I can talk a little bit more about the advertising concept and what we are looking to achieve over
all with this campaign.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So this first phrase we have is very important to especially when we're using
video or a projector in a presentation. We say let's dim the lights. That's right so we have the
verb to dim. So to dim something is to make it darker. But not turn it off completely. No it means
it means maybe to lower the lights. We could actually see this on a computer also when the screen
is very very bright because it ought to bright. I need you to dim it a little. Make it a little bit
darker. Okay so you can use this verb to dim to make it a little bit darker or to make it lower
in intensity. That's right dim the color dim the lights. All right very good. Now Mr Ford when he was
talking about the advert he said well it's new and it's not ready yet completely so it might seem
a bit rough around the edges. Okay this is a very very popular phrase that means that something is
incomplete. Maybe it's not perfect yet. It needs some work. Okay so if maybe you're designing
a new website and it's maybe 50% done. So you say the website is almost finished but it's still
rough around the edges. We need to make some changes to fix it. That's right so rough around the edges
as a phrase that is the opposite of the word polished. Something is polished if it's perfect
and ready to go. Okay and well when the technical problem started Mr Ford was a apologizing and said
he looks I'm sorry and he also used this interesting phrase bear with me bear with me a second.
Okay so this is interesting because it's not the animal the bear. Right right. This is different. This
means you know excuse me please be patient I have to do something and you have to wait. So this is
a very very polite way of asking some people or some person to wait for you. To tolerate. Yes.
So both the animal bear and to bear with me are spelled the same way. It looks exactly like the
animal but we're not talking about the animal. Now we're asking someone to tolerate something that's
annoying or frustrating. So for example I'm trying to show you a file in my computer Marco.
My computer is not working. I say please bear with me a second. I have to reboot my computer.
I have to wait here. Okay very good. Now towards the end of the dialogue when we talked about
to crop up the second part of that Mr Ford said unfortunately technical problems do crop up
from time to time. So we already discussed cropped up what is time to time me from time to time.
Okay think of this as a set phrase because we said already that you could also say sometimes.
So from time to time means every once in a while or occasionally. Occasionally. So it's an
adverbial phrase it's a it's a way of telling people how often something happens but in this case
it's not very common. So for example you can say I like to go to the movies from time to time.
That's right so maybe once or twice a month you like to go to the movies.
But what if I come to work every day do I come to work from time to time? No. Right. That's okay.
So from time to time is rarely or occasionally not very often. Exactly. All right very good.
So now let's listen to our dialogue one last time and review everything we've just learned.
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert. Please note that we're
still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
Okay so I just need to click this in the advert should pop up on the screen.
Sorry about this spare with me a second. It seems to be a problem with the projector.
Let me see. Jonathan could you lend a hand a second?
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer. Let me check the connection a second.
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
Okay sorry guys obviously a problem with the system. Let's just reboot and start over. Let's see if this
resolves the issue.
Right let's try again. No still nothing Michael. There might be a technical issue with the projector.
I think maybe the projector has overheated. We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and
start again. I'll call IT support to come over right now. Okay guys.
Unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time don't they? But it's not a huge
in the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that. I can talk a little bit more about the
advertising concept and what we are looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
All right so this was part seven of our presentation series and actually these type of
problems occur very very often specifically with with the laptop and the projector and sometimes
it doesn't work, it doesn't recognize it and so this is a nice way of handling it.
This is and we hope that these are phrases that you can use in your daily life as well.
Maybe you're working with your colleagues and you're having some technical problems
or if you're having a problem and someone gives you instructions for how to solve that problem.
Like I often get this from my technical team. I say listen I have a problem and they say hey just
reboot your computer and it'll be okay so these are very very common issues that I think that
you can learn how to describe an English with today's lesson. All right very good and of
course if you guys have any questions or any doubts about this or any of our lessons please come to our
website EnglishPod.com on the lessons page you can leave your comments and questions and we'll see you
guys next time. Bye.