Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and this is our 300th
lesson here at EnglishPod so it's a special lesson but today we're talking a little bit about dating.
That's right today we're going to talk about dating now in a little bit of a less conventional way
a new type of dating very modern with using technology. Using technology that's right so let's listen to
today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow? Oh I can't have a date. Really? Wow with who?
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months. She's really cool and she's driving
over here this weekend. Wait a minute. You mean you met her online? Yeah I sent up for a website called
Match.com and it's great. You fill in all your details and preferences like if you are a smoker or
if you have any pets then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them
or chat. That's kind of weird. What if she's a psycho or something like that? It's the same as meeting
people anywhere and dating them. I'm just tired of going to bars being set up for dates by my friends.
I think this is a really cool alternative especially if you are a bit shy. I guess it does seem logical.
I'll have to check it out. All right we're back so now let's take a look at some of these
keywords with that we've picked out for you on language takeaway. Language takeaway.
So the first word is a word that you're going to hear English speakers say all the time, especially
if they're Americans. So cool is our first word. Right this guy described this girl that he is
seen as really cool. She's really cool. So what does that mean if I describe someone as a cool person?
A cool person is someone who you like. It's a good thing. So someone who is cool I think of as
relaxed and interesting and someone who maybe had lots of ideas or things to say.
Okay so if you say that a person is cool you're saying that you like that person. Now what if you say
something is cool like Paris is really cool. Paris is cool. It's a cool city. That means it's an
interesting city. It's something that you like. Maybe you're trying to recommend someone to go there.
You can also say that movie was really cool. So again it means you liked it. Yeah.
Okay so talking about dating this friend it was a bit surprised when he said that he met this girl
online. That's right so online where is this place online? It's cyberspace. All right so online
means on the internet and we often use this when describing things. So English pod is an online
English learning site. That's right so anything that is in the internet in cyberspace you say that
is online. So our website is online or maybe you have pictures online. I have many photographs
online or I like to meet people online. Okay so continuing on we talked about a website that
obviously that's online where you find people and talking about preferences. You mentioned that you
can stay to whether you are a smoker or if you have pets. So what is a person that's a smoker?
Well many of you have probably heard the the term to smoke before. I smoke cigarettes. I smoke.
But a smoker is a person who smokes cigarettes and so I could say that I want a non-smoker
if I'm looking for a boyfriend because I don't want someone who smokes. But maybe if you do
smoke you can say I'm looking for a smoker. Someone who does smoke. Okay so his friend was a little bit
concerned saying well that's weird why did this girl is a psycho or something like that? All right a
psycho now maybe you've heard of the movie psycho but psycho is something that we use in English to
say that someone is really crazy almost scary crazy. It comes from the word psycho path right?
That's right and a psychopath is someone who is crazy but also very dangerous. Right so obviously when
we use this word we're describing someone as being a little bit strange or maybe even a little bit
dangerous. That's right so we don't want any psychos to come and talk to us online right? That's right.
So he went on to explain how dating is just the same online as it is offline and that he thinks
it's a really cool alternative even if you're shy. So something is an alternative if you have
different options maybe dating by going to a bar and meeting someone is what normal people do
but an alternative to that would be dating online. That's right. I mean it's another option.
So the word alternative is a second option and another option. Right for example if I want to
go have a Thai food tonight but you don't want to I'd say hey Marko well can you give me an alternative
idea? That is the other option. All right great so a lot of words in this very interesting
dialogue stay with us will be right back where we'll take a look at Fluency Builder.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow? Oh I can't have a date. Really? Wow with who?
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months. She's really cool and she's driving
over here this weekend. Wait a minute you mean you met her online? Yeah I send up for a website
called Match.com and it's great. You fill in all your details and preferences like if you are a
smoker or if you have any pets then you find people that have similar characteristics and you
can email them or chat. That's kind of weird what if she's a psycho or something like that?
It's the same as meeting people anywhere and dating them. I'm just tired of going to bars
being set up for dates by my friends. I think this is a really cool alternative especially if you are a
bit shy. I guess it does seem logical. I'll have to check it out.
All right we're back and we've picked out five key phrases for you let's check those out on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. All right the first phrase we've got here is one that we often use in English
spoken English to talk about seeing our friends. Okay so the first person says do you want to hang
out tomorrow to hang out? That's right so let's hang out. We never hang out anymore what does that mean?
Well it's a hang out is it's hard to define because you can do many things when you're hanging out.
But basically it means friends being together. So watching a movie listening to music chatting these are
all examples of hanging out. So maybe if you get together with your friend that's just sitting
in the living room and talk you're hanging out. That's right or you could go drive a card
together in your hanging out you're talking. So to hang out is to be social is to talk to your friend.
So spend time together and you said wait oh I can't because I have a date.
Okay to have a date so a date is a romantic appointment with someone that you you want to go out with
but you have a date this is something you have. I have a date that night. So this is actually
a very important part because as you said it's a romantic appointment. So if you have to go to the doctor
and he's not your boyfriend or anything like this you don't say I have a date with the doctor.
No you say I have an appointment with the doctor. Okay. But if it's romantic you say oh I want to
get my hair done because I have a date tonight. Right I have a date. I want to look nice for my date.
Okay and then he goes on to explain that this date that he has is with a girl that he has
been chatting with. Okay so the verb here is to chat with chat. Chat just means talk to talk to.
But in internet terms to chat with means to talk to on the internet. So maybe you use a program
like MSN or Google G chat to talk to somebody online that's called chatting. That's right. So I think
everyone has done this at one point or another when you are online chatting via MSN messenger or any
of these chat clients. So very very common thing. But remember to add the chat with. I am chatting
with my friends. Yeah I don't like to chat with people while I'm at work. They're excited.
Right on the internet. Now this guy explained about the website match.com and he said that he signed
up for this website. Okay another really key verb when you're talking about internet things.
So for example if you want to come to EnglishPod you can sign up for a
free trial. That means provide your information. Right. Start to use. That's right. So it applies
for things online and offline. You for example in the real world or offline you can sign up for
a cooking class. That's right or last week I signed up for a dance class so I can learn how to dance.
Very good. Okay and then to finish off the guy explained that he's tired of meeting people at bars
that his friends set up dates for him. Okay so he doesn't like to be set up. To be set up remember
that be to be set up. That means someone else is doing this to you. So Marco I want to set you up
with my friend. That means I want to take you and my friend and make you have a date. Right exactly.
So this is exactly what it means to set someone up or to be set up is to have them go on a date with
someone else. All right so I don't like to be set up because I like to know the person I will have a
date with before we go out but when you're set up someone else makes a decision for you so it's a little
bit difficult. That's right. Okay so a lot of interesting things here why don't we take a look at our
dialogue one last time and we'll be right back.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow? Oh I can't have a date. Really? Wow with who?
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months. She's really cool and she's driving
over here this weekend. Wait a minute. You mean you met her online? Yeah I sent up for a website called
Match.com and it's great. You fill in all your details and preferences like if you are a
smoker or if you have any pets then you find people that have similar characteristics and you
can email them or chat. That's kind of weird. What if she's a psycho or something like that?
It's the same as meeting people anywhere in Dayton. I'm just tired of going to bars
being set up for dates by my friends. I think this is a really cool alternative especially if you
are a bit shy. I guess it does seem logical. I'll have to check it out.
All right so talking about setting up this is another word that comes to mind when your
friends set you up for a date is a blind date. Okay so a blind date is not a date with two
blind people. Right. A blind date is a date that you go to when you don't know who the other
person is before you go. That's right. So for example my friend's mother loves to set people up
on blind dates. She's a match maker. She makes these makes couples. So she will call one person and
call the other person and then she'll make them have a date. She sets them up and then they have
this date a blind date. A blind date that's right. And actually what you're doing with this
technology now that you can use a website to find and meet people who are also looking for romance.
It's very interesting. It's very modern obviously because now we have the technology to do it.
And many people actually have very successful or very great love stories of how they met online
chatting or while playing a video game online or many different things like this. Well the
thing that I like about it and I have to say I've never done it. So what I like from hearing about it
is that like a mask.com you you save a lot of time. It seems that way because you get to tell the
person hey I don't want I don't like people who smoke I don't like who have pets but I really like
people who play video games. And so you find people who are like that and then you can you know
get to know that person better. But I think it's hard when you're going on dates especially
you know your friends they set you up and you have nothing in common. You have no interests that
are in common and that can that can be really frustrating. So it seems like online dating is a new
type of efficient way of dating because you preliminary already filter out everyone or everything
that you don't like about a person and you find someone that has your same or similar likes.
But that's that's modern date right? That's right a lot of people I now have data using these
websites and have been very successful. Really been married. Wow it's amazing. So actually this is a
great thing let us know if you have any friend who's a founder significant other husband or wife
via online dating or if you've tried it maybe you can let us know how it is. Our website is Englishpod.com
don't forget to sign up if you don't have an account and we'll see you there. All right bye guys. Bye.