Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about fear.
That's right. Today we're going to talk about phobias. Different types of fears that that you have.
Many people that have many people are scared of different things and that's what we're going to talk about today.
Okay so let's listen to today's dialogue and find out what the people in our dialogue are very, very afraid of.
Are you excited about your trip next month?
Yes and no. I can't wait to go to Europe but at the same time I'm terrified.
Why?
Well I have aerophobia. I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh really? I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying.
It's not that bad though. I mean it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air
700 miles per hour. I actually have a rack in phobia.
You scared of spiders. I actually have two more phobias.
Acrophobia and glossophobia.
I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying but public speaking is not that bad.
Are you kidding? When I get on stage my palms start to sweat. I get really nervous and I can hardly speak.
Well I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic. I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds.
We are such weirdos right?
All right we're back so let's take a look at those phobias on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first phobia that we have is called arrow phobia.
That's right arrow phobia and that means that you are scared of flying.
Okay so we can tell because phobia means a you know fear of something but it's not just a fear.
It means that if you go on an airplane you get very very upset.
Right. You think that you're going to die.
That's right. Okay and so phobia is a very serious fear.
But arrow like arrow plane is the prefix. So arrow phobia is a fear of going on airplane.
That's right and another phobia that we have is a rack no phobia. So again as you see in the prefix
a rack no is related to a spider. That's right so this comes from the origins of English.
I'm not sure if it's Greek or Latin but a rack no phobia like a rack nid has to do with spiders.
So I'm afraid of spiders if I'm if I have a rack no phobia. That is right and now taking to look at
two more types of phobias here we have acro phobia and gloss phobia. So let's take a look at the
first one acro phobia. So acro phobia acro has to do with heights. So I don't like to be on tall
buildings. I don't like to maybe look down from heights. That means I'm afraid of heights.
That's right. You're afraid of being in a very high altitude acro phobia. Now gloss phobia is an
interesting one because this one you are scared of public speaking or you get very nervous when
you're in front of a group of people. Right so this is actually a very very common fear.
But if it's a if it's a serious fear it's a phobia. So gloss phobia means that when you go in front
of people you get very very anxious upset your stomach hurts you have wet hands. So that's a very
serious fear. That's right and for our last phobia we have claustrophobia. I think is one of the most
common ones if you have claustrophobia you're afraid of smaller tight spaces. That's right. So people
see her the word claustrophobic. People who are claustrophobic or people who suffer from claustrophobia
don't like to be in small tight places like elevators for example. Or tunnels. So now you brought
up an interesting point. Our last phobia we said claustrophobic and now we must make the difference
between for example claustrophobia and being claustrophobic. So phobia you hear the word I
hear the ending I a phobia claustrophobia is a noun okay that means I can talk about I have it I have
this fear but when you're talking about the adjective something that describes you you would have to
use the iq ending. I'm claustrophobic he is acrophobic they are aerophobic. Okay so that's
the adjective form. So if I say I have a rachnophobia it means I have this fear or I can say I am a rachnophobic.
Great so this can be used for all other kinds of phobias so when you learn those words remember
that there's two different kinds there's the ia there's the ia phobia which is the noun and iq
which is the adjective. All right let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with fluency builder.
Are you excited about your trip next month? Yes and no I can't wait to go to Europe but
at the same time I'm terrified. Why? Well I have aerophobia I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh really I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying. It's not that bad though I mean it is
pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air at 700 miles per hour.
I actually have a rachnophobia. You're scared of spiders I actually have two more phobias.
Acrophobia and glossophobia. I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying but
public speaking is not that bad. Are you kidding? When I get on stage my palm start to sweat.
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak. Wow I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds. We are such weirdos right?
All right so we've picked out a couple of different phrases today let's take a look at those now on fluency
builder. Fluency builder. So in the beginning of today's dialogue the character said I cannot wait
to go to Europe but at the same time I'm terrified so at the same time. So in this case we're saying
that we are happy but also we are scared so two things at once at the same time. Right so this is a
little bit different from when we talk about I can do two things at the same time I can walk and
chew gum. More talking about feelings or emotions you say you know I'm happy but at the same time
I'm also scared. Right. That means that I have these two feelings and actually they're opposite feelings.
Right exactly usually they are opposite feelings so like you say you're happy but at the same time
you're nervous. Like saying on the other hand. Exactly. All right now when we talked about all these
fears we're afraid of flying we are afraid of spiders we describe them as a chronic fear.
Okay so this adjective chronic is very important because it has to do with time. Okay so I have
a chronic fear of heights that means this is a fear I've always had and I will always have.
Right. You can also say she has chronic back pain. Mm-hmm. Okay that means it comes back again and
again it's not just one time it's all it's it's some person's whole life maybe not every day but
it comes back. Right. Okay so that's if you say you have a chronic something you're explaining
that you've had it for a while or you will always have it. Something usually very serious also.
And going back to one of the phobias we mentioned Goloso phobia and the other person said well you
know public speaking is not that bad it's not it's not something to be so afraid of and the other
person replied by saying are you kidding? Are you kidding? So this is actually a way of showing some
sarcasm when you're talking because public speaking is not that bad the person wants to say no it is
that bad it is awful so are you kidding is a way to say no I totally disagree. Right so you're being
a little bit sarcastic but at the same time you're also acting a bit surprise like I can't believe
you said that or like I said I really like the twilight movie is Marko are you kidding? Those
ones are terrible. All right so Marko does not agree with my opinion. All right now when we're talking
about public speaking we mentioned that you get on stage so this is very important because this is
the action to get on stage and speak. Okay so if you have a stage or maybe even you don't have a stage
but you're talking about performing in front of other people like a speech or play you say you get
on stage and it's important to remember this as a phrase. So whenever I get on stage I start to
sweat. Now you may want to add the there you want to say to get on the stage but it's not necessary
it's not incorrect but the usual or let's say more correct form would just be used of phrase to
get on stage. When I get on stage I get very nervous you don't have to say when I get on the stage.
Or she's normally very shy but when she gets on stage she opens up and becomes very
very very talkative. That's right. All right so that's all the phrases we've picked out for you.
Let's listen to her dialogue one last time and we'll be right back.
Are you excited about your trip next month? Yes and no I can't wait to go to Europe but
at the same time I'm terrified. Why? Well I have Airophobia. I have a chronic fear of flying.
Oh really? I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying. It's not that bad though I mean it is
pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air at 700 miles per hour.
I actually have a rack inophobia. You scared of spiders. I actually have two more phobias.
Acrophobia and glossophobia. I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying but
public speaking is not that bad. Are you kidding? When I get on stage my palm start to sweat.
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak. Well I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds. We are such weirdos right.
All right so talking about all these phobias. Now one of these phobias was actually made into a
movie I think in 1990. A rack no phobia. This very chronic fear of spiders. That's right and
I remember when I was younger and this movie came out everybody started talking about how they were
a rack no phobic. Had this horrible fear of spiders. Did you ever see that movie? Of course of course
they terrifying. It was supposedly some South American spider that made its way into the United States
on a box in a crate or something. Now many people handle phobias differently. Are you have any phobia?
Are you claustrophobic? Are you a rack no phobic? I don't have any phobias and I'm not really afraid
of anything so I'm pretty lucky that way but I know a number of people who are afraid of heights
and acrophobic and so that's pretty common. And actually if you look it up you will find
an dictionary maybe hundreds of phobias people who are afraid of open spaces people who are afraid
of close spaces or people who are afraid of marriage they even have a phobia uh determined for this
type of person. So it's very interesting now this is going to be a challenge why don't you look
up a couple of different phobias and share with us maybe some of the craziest ones or the funniest ones
or maybe the strangest ones you can find. That's right so look them up share them with us
our website is engoshpad.com. All right we'll see you guys there. Bye.