Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about someone who's very very dirty.
That's right and actually not only are we talking about something being dirty but also that we
want to clean everything. Okay so you'll learn how to call someone who likes clean things in English today.
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
The End of the Video
This bathroom is a pig's die. Helen, why do you keep slushing a toilet? What's wrong?
I just can't stand it. It's really gross in here. There's a state on the toilet seat and the floor
was wet and slippery so I cleaned it. You did what? Helen, I know it's gross but I've seen
many public washrooms that are much worse. Why are you cleaning the countertop? Are you out of
your mind? I can't help myself. It's just so disgusting in here. Helen, this is not like your
own bathroom. Just leave it to the cleaners. Okay? Hang on. I'm just going to quickly wipe
this sink and sleep the floor. Feel sucked and neat freak. I'm out there.
Alright we're back so this girl was very much of a neat freak and we're going to take a look at
that word a little bit later on. Why don't we go back to the very beginning and take a look at
some vocab on language takeaway? Language takeaway. The first word we have here on language
takeaway today is pig's die. Right? This bathroom is a pig's die. Okay so pig's die is a place
where pigs live. Okay so now this obviously the bathroom is not really a place where pigs live. So
if you call something a pig's die you're saying that it's very dirty. You're saying it's disgusting.
It's very very dirty like a pig's die. So actually if you go to a farm and you see where all the pigs
are that is actually called a pig's die. Right? There's mud and dirt. Yeah that's a pig's die.
So someone who is very very dirty you can also call a pig. Okay now she was saying that the
bathroom is so dirty and it's really gross in here. Okay so gross means something is she doesn't
like it. It's really dirty and you know makes her uncomfortable. So something that doesn't taste good.
You can say it's gross. That's right so I don't like to eat snake. I think eating snake is gross.
Okay very good. So something that is gross is something that's not really nice. Maybe a taste bad
or it smells bad. Something that is bad in general. That's right. Okay so she went on to talk
about the toilet seat and that there was a stain on the toilet seat. Okay a stain is usually a bad
thing. It means that there's a color or a mark that's permanent or maybe can be washed away
on something. So in this case the toilet seat has a mark on it. Okay. Maybe it's brown or yellow.
But I can also say I was drinking wine and I spilled the wine on my shirt and it left a stain.
Right. So now there's a there's always this red red part on my shirt. Okay I won't go away. Okay so
a stain is a mark that usually won't go away. Okay so then she went on to describe the bathroom
as being disgusting. So I guess this is very similar to gross. That's right. Something that is gross
is usually also disgusting. I can say ugh this food is awful. It's just disgusting. Okay but I
can also say in this case your room is disgusting. You need to clean it. It's so dirty or bad or unappealing.
So something that is gross something that is disgusting is something negative. Yes. Okay and then
we have our keyword and the title of this lesson for today they need freak. Her friend says you're
such a neat freak. That's right. So a neat freak is someone who likes things to be very clean.
And so a neat freak does not live in a pig's die. Right. A neat freak does not like to be in
pig's die. A neat freak likes things to be in order and organized and clean. So maybe somebody that's
cleaning all the time or that's very very organized you can say that that person is a neat freak.
He is a neat freak or she is a neat freak. Now it's not necessarily a good thing to be a neat
freak but it's not terrible either to call somebody a neat freak. You can say hey are you a neat freak?
Right. I mean are you really concerned about cleanliness? Uh huh. Okay. Very good. So a lot of great
vocab when we take a look again at our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
The bathroom is a pig's die. Helen why do you keep sloshing a toilet? What's wrong?
I just can't stand it. It's really gross in here. There's a stain on the toilet seat and the floor
was wet in slippery so I cleaned it. You did what? Helen I know it's gross but I've seen many
public washrooms that are much worse. Why are you cleaning the countertop? Are you out of your mind?
I can't help myself it's just so disgusting in here. Helen this is not like your own bathroom.
Just leave it to the cleanliness okay? Hang on I'm just going to quickly wipe this sink
into the floor. Feel sucked and neat freak. I'm out there.
All right we're back so now let's take a look at Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder.
So the first thing we want to talk about today is this phrase I can't stand it. So this is our
need freak talking. She says I just can't stand it. I just can't stand it. So if you can't stand
something that means that you can tolerate it. That's right it means I don't like it. I don't want
it anymore. I need to change it. Okay so for example if a bar is too loud you say I have to
leave I can't stand it. It's too loud in there. That's right or if you are next to me all
then you do tap tap tap tap tap with your pen I say Marco stop it. I can't stand it anymore.
Okay very good and then she went on to explain or to justify why she was cleaning the public
restroom and she said I can't help myself it's just too disgusting in here. I can't help myself.
So this means that I cannot control my actions. Okay I cannot control what I do.
And so in some cases like with a neat freak the person really needs everything to be clean.
And so she says I can't help myself. I have to clean. Okay so it's a phrase like this. Don't
try to separate it. Don't try to separate it and try to define what help and help yourself.
It's more of a phrase saying I can't control myself. I can't control my actions. I can't help myself.
Or in the case of another person you say she can't help herself.
He can't help himself. Right so maybe you like to smoke and you're smoking all the time and
you say stop smoking you say I can't help myself. I have to smoke. Yeah I have to smoke. Okay.
And for our last phrase she said hang on I'm just going to quickly wipe the sink and sweep the floor.
Hang on this means wait wait a moment yeah so this is a really common phrase we hear in English.
It's something that you'll hear all the time you know pretty relaxed environment not maybe in
school but if someone says okay I'm going to go see you later and the other person wants to say
something to you. You say hang on. Hang on wait a moment so I have to tell you this thing.
So you wouldn't really use it with your boss or a customer you wouldn't say hang on a second.
No you would say that with a friend or family member things like that. Okay so it's a very
informal way of saying wait a moment wait a minute. That's right so the formal way is please wait.
Please wait and the informal way is hang on hang on or hang on a sec which is hang on a second.
All right that's all the words we have for today when we review our dialogue one last time.
This bathroom is a pig's die. Helen why do you keep slushing a toilet? What's wrong?
I just can't stand it it's really gross in here there's a state on the toilet seat and the floor
with wet and slippery so I cleaned it. You did what? Helen I know it's gross but I've seen many
public washrooms that are much worse why are you cleaning the count to top are you out of your mind?
I can't help myself it's just so disgusting in here. Helen this is not like your own bathroom
just leave it to the cleaners okay hang on I'm just going to quickly wipe this sink and sweep the floor.
Go suck a neat freak I'm out here.
All right so talking about cleanliness and being neat what type of person are you? Do you usually
are you a neat freak do you keep everything very clean and ordered? I'm not a neat freak but I'm also not
a pig not a slob I like things to be very organized okay but I'm not really concerned about
leaning so much I'm too lazy so there's a difference for me I in my house I know where everything is
but maybe there's clothes on the floor and there's books in the bathroom I mean so I'm in the
mill what about you are you a neat freak? No I'm not really a neat freak per se but I do like
everything to be very clean on the other hand so I can't really stand it when things are if things
are out of order a little bit that's okay but if things are dirty that really gets to me but I'm not
the type of person that has you know folders with all my bills and in one folder or labels or even
when I was in school I didn't have my notebooks in order really but yeah so we're the opposite
yeah exactly but I hate things that are dirty. Uh huh interesting well let us know are you a neat freak
our website is englishpod.com you can talk about yourself all over that that lesson comments area
that's right and if you have any other suggestions or comments we're always there as well and we'll see
you guys next time bye bye