Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about going out for a drink.
That's right, we're going to a bar and we're going to order cocktails.
So we're going to learn all about the different types of cocktails and a little bit more
language that you can use at a bar.
Exactly. So let's take a listen to today's dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
What can I get you?
I'll have a cosmo please.
Dude, you can't order a cosmo. That's a ladies drink. You're embarrassing me.
Why are you talking about? It's a good drink.
It's too soft. Order something with a little more kick to it.
Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach.
You have got to be kidding me.
Come on, it's delicious. Especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it. I'm ordering for you. I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a man
hat and put it on my top.
Here. Now this is a real drink.
It's strong. This is going to get me wasted.
That's the idea.
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at some of those drinks on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So in language takeaway today we're going to focus on the names of drinks.
So we heard four of them in today's dialogue. What was that first one? Marco?
The first one was a cosmo or also called a cosmo palette.
Okay, so this is something if you watch the TV show sex in the city you will have heard before
because the girls always order cosmos.
Now a cosmo palette is served in a martini glass, right?
You've seen the martini glass. It kind of looks like a triangle.
And it's very easy to spill.
Yeah. That's right. So what does a cosmo have?
Because obviously a cocktail is a combination of different liquors or alcohol with maybe juices
and stuff like that. So what does a cosmo have?
That's a good question. Cosmo is a vodka drink I believe and it's served in a martini glass.
But it's generally considered a drink for ladies for women.
Why is that?
Because it's a weaker drink but also because it's popular in the media and in movies and stuff
as a women's drink. So that's how I got that every time.
I see. All right, very good. So that's what a cosmo is now.
If we move on to another very popular drink a little bit more tropical. I think everyone always has it
when the Caribbean or when they're on vacation at the beach.
It's called a sex on the beach.
Okay, this name might make you laugh because a sex on the beach. It's very descriptive.
But it's actually a very common drink.
Right. And in the dialogue he talks about how he likes to have this drink served in a pineapple
or a coconut. So that means it's very fruity and I think the rum drink.
Yeah, and it usually has either coconut juice in it or maybe some pineapple juice.
Very fruity. Very fruity. I think even they, I think they add a little bit of vanilla or even ice cream
like a milk or something like that. So it's very fruity. It's kind of like a milkshake with liquor.
Weird. Yeah, I don't know that I've ever had one. But this is the part of the dialogue where his
friend says, come on. You need to buy something that's more manly. He orders a scotch on the rocks instead.
Okay. So a scotch is a type of liquor. It's a whiskey. That's right. Scotch whiskey comes from
Scotland and it's a whiskey drink and basically scotch on the rocks means scotch poured over ice.
Ice. So in this case rocks means ice. And you'll hear this often.
Often do you want that on the rocks? Do you want that on ice? Right. So you don't say I want whiskey
with ice or you don't say I want scotch with ice. You can just say on the rocks.
Scotch on the rocks. So it may be if you're ordering a rum drink and you don't want it mixed with anything
you can say rum on the rocks. On the rocks. Very good. And not only are we ordering a scotch
on the rocks, but we're also ordering a Manhattan. So what does a Manhattan have?
All right. A Manhattan is a very strong cocktail. It has bourbon, which is a kind of whiskey.
American whiskey. It has vermouth, which is also very strong ingredient. It has bidders.
What is bidders? Bitter is another kind of ingredient that is often used in cocktails to make
things bitter. Okay. So it's not a sweet drink. No, no, no. It's not a sweet drink. Although they
sometimes put a little bit of lemon or orange rind in the drink and that's the skin.
Okay. So both these drinks are pretty strong. They're very interesting.
All the ones that we've seen, the Cosmo, the Sex on the Beach. They're all called cocktails.
And a cocktail has the characteristic that it usually has alcohol. That's right. So cocktail is a mix
of different ingredients, but it's an alcohol-based drink. Okay. You can also get non-alcoholic
cocktails. So there is that option. All right. Very good. So when we take a break, let's listen to
the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
What can I get you? I only have a Cosmo please. Dude, you can't order a Cosmo. That's a lady's drink.
You're embarrassing me. Why are you talking about? It's a good drink. It's too soft. Or do
something with a little more kick to it? Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach. You have got to be
kidding me. Come on. It's delicious, especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it. I'm ordering for you. I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a
man hat and put it on my tap. Here. Now this is a real drink. It's strong. This is going to get
wasted. That's the idea. All right. We're back. So now let's talk a little bit more about these
drinks on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder. So Marko, there are many different ways to talk about
drinks, but the most important ones that we often discuss, especially with cocktails is weak drinks,
versus strong drinks. That's right. Week drinks versus strong drinks. Now, usually the Cosmo
or maybe the sex on the beach, it's considered to be a weak drink. That's right. So it's not
it's not very strong because there's less alcohol. Like a Cosmo has fruit juice, like cranberry juice.
And the sex on the beach is very fruity. So it makes it less alcohol-y. That's right. And actually
those two also have one type of alcohol. So it's not very strong whereas maybe a Manhattan
has all these mix of bourbon and other drinks as well. So it will be strong, a strong alcohol
drink. Yeah and Scotch on the rocks is also very strong because it's just Scotch. Right. You're not
mixing it with anything. No, there's just some ice and some Scotch. So that's a strong drink.
Okay. So obviously his friend was saying that all those drinks are too weak. He should order
something with a little more kick to it. So in this context kick means strength. So alcohol.
He wants a drink that's not weak, that's strong. So a strong drink has more kick than a weak drink.
So can we use this with food or with other situations? You can but with food that usually means
spice. So Indian food tends to have a lot of kick to it. That means it's very spicy.
Okay. So with alcohol it's strong with food. It's usually spicy. If this rice has a kick to it,
it means it's a little spicy. That's right. So just think about the kick as meaning that something
is strong or has a strong flavor. Okay. Very good. Now when they were ordering they didn't pay
immediately because she said, put it on my tab. All right. So to put something on a tab, this is
really important when you're going to a bar or a restaurant and you want to order drinks.
A tab is a bill that you don't pay immediately. Right. You the bartender will write down all
the drinks that you have and all of their prices and you pay when you leave. Mm-hmm. Okay.
So if you put something on your tab, you'll pay it later or when you leave. That's right.
So normally at a bar in America, you say, I want to start a tab. That means I want to start a
bill and you give the bartender your credit card and he will keep your credit card until you leave.
Oh really? So he keeps your credit card into it because obviously maybe you start a tab and then
you want to leave and you don't want to pay then it's more people get a little bit drunk and they
forget they have to pay so bartenders now keep your credit card so that even if you forget to pay
they can charge you. Oh wow. Okay. Very interesting and now for our last phrase, he was a little
bit concerned because this drink is so strong. He said, this is going to get me wasted.
Okay. So to be wasted or to get wasted means to get very, very drunk.
Uh-huh. To drink too much. So if you say I'm wasted, it means I'm very drunk. I'm very drunk.
You could say, oh look at those those boys over there they're all wasted. They're all, you know,
being drunk and sick and yeah. Okay. So it's a very informal, very casual kind of a colloquial way of
saying being drunk or being intoxicated. That's right. So it's something we often use with friends or
as, you know, with young people, but it's not something you want to use in your English class because
it's not a good thing to be. It's not a good thing to be wasted. Okay. Very good. So now let's take a break
and listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
What can I get you? I want to have a cosmo please. Dude, you can't order a cosmo. That's a
ladies drink. You're embarrassing me. Why are you talking about? It's a good drink. It's too soft.
Order something with a little more kick to it. Fine. I'll have a sex on the beach. You have
got to be kidding me. Come on, it's delicious, especially when served with a pineapple or a coconut.
Forget it. I'm ordering for you. I'll have a scotch on the rocks and my friend here will have a
man hat and put it on my top. Here. Now this is a real drink. It's strong. This is going to get me
wasted. That's the idea. All right. So about cocktails, liakers. What is your favorite cocktail
when you go out? I almost always order gin and tonic. That's my cocktail. So gin is another type of
liquor. That's right. Gin is another type of liquor like vodka or whiskey. It has a very unique taste.
And tonic is a kind of water but it has a certain flavor to it. It has a flavor to it. So gin and tonic
usually has some gin, some tonic water and some lime. But the tonic water is kind of bubbly.
That's right. It's bubbly. So that's I like bubbly drinks.
It's a selection of pain and stuff like that. Yes. Exactly. I see. What's your favorite?
I am a whiskey guy and so I usually order something like this scotch on the rocks or so I never
like to mix it with anything else. And especially I really don't like mix having sweet drinks.
So you're a purist. Kind of it's just that you know when the sweet alcohol and things that
are sweet I don't really think go that well together. No I think I agree. Although there are some
sweet alcohols. Our Italian friends will be familiar with limon cello which is that it's a dessert
the core which tastes like lemon or also calua calua which is very sweet. It's kind of like
a coffee alcohol. Right. So many people like to put calua in their coffee to have Irish coffee.
That's right. So actually the alcoholic world is very vast and actually many people don't
drink alcohol. Many people may have it occasionally. But the other interesting thing is that
usually countries have a national alcoholic drink. So for example the Mexican
national alcoholic drink would be tequila. That's right. Or Russian or Eastern European.
What's gotten vodka? So in your country maybe you have a local or a national alcoholic drink.
We would be very interested to know about. That's right. Let us know our website is englishpod.com.
We'll see you guys there. All right guys. See you. Bye. Bye.