Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about something that I think a lot of people
experience, especially with certain things like peanuts and cats. So what are we talking about?
That's right. Today we are talking about allergies. So that means that we have a problem with maybe
cats. They make us sick or with certain foods. Like a lot of people who are allergic to milk,
actually that's right. So we're going to talk about a couple of these allergies and symptoms.
So why don't we have a listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
I feel terrible. I keep sneezing and my eyes are all watering. What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are you? Looks like you have a cold. You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk. Maybe we should
put you into quarantine. Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy. An allergy? I never
thought about that. I don't think I'm allergic to pollen though and I'm discented as the
bee steings after being stung so many times. Hmm. Oh, why did you chuck that peanut at me?
Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts, I guess not. Not funny. I could have gone into
anaphylactic shock. Okay, my bad. How about dust? This office is full of it. Yes, the whole office is
dusty yet I only feel affected near desks. You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles birthday today. I didn't want him to be alone on his special day.
Ah, put it away! I guess we found the problem. You're allergic to cats.
All right, so now let's take a look at Vogue cab on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so Mark, we have a number of things that might happen if you're feeling like you're
allergic to something. The first one is my eyes are all watery. Okay, so your eyes get watery.
And that means you start to have a lot of water a lot of tears in your eyes. That's right, but you're
not sad. You're not crying. It's just that you have this reaction that you cannot control and the
water may become stomp from your eyes. Right, usually it gets your eyes get wet in watery, itchy, red.
Yeah, there's another thing too. This happens a lot. You feel like you can't stop sneezing
to sneeze. That sneezes something you do when the air comes out of your nose.
I don't know. You know that if you're a mouth that of everyone. Yeah, and you can't control it.
And sometimes it's very, very strong. You move your head, but it's something that you do
when you're allergic to something like cat or flower, but also maybe when you smell something
some some spice like a pepper. Hot pepper? Yeah, yeah, or when you're sick when you have a cold.
That's right. And so his friends says that maybe they should put him into quarantine. All right,
now this is a joke. If you have allergies, you don't have to go to quarantine. But quarantine is very
serious. It's a place where people go when they have a dangerous or very infectious disease. Right.
And quarantine means that no one else can come in and you cannot go out. Right, exactly. So I think
when they had the pig flu, the swine flu, many people were put into quarantine to make sure they
didn't give it to someone else. That's right. So usually in quarantine, you have to wait until you
can prove that you're not sick anymore and you get to leave. That's right. All right. So they were
talking about maybe the options of what he's allergic to. She says, I'm not, I don't think I'm allergic
to pollen. So what is pollen? Where does it come from? All right. Now pollen is actually a very
common allergy and pollen comes from flowers. It's kind of like a special dust,
a special kind of thing that you see on flowers that gets blown away. So when it's springtime,
many people suffer from allergies because there's a lot more pollen in there. So it's that little
dust. Usually sometimes yellow that you can find on flowers. And this is actually what butterflies
and bees look for. That's right. Okay. And then he talked about, well, he's not allergic to bees.
And his friend threw a peanut at him, but he, he said it in a very strange way. He said,
why did you chuck that peanut at me to chuck? To chuck. Now this is a very spoken English way of
saying something to chuck means to throw. So like Marco, why did you chuck that pillow at me? That was
mean. All right. So to chuck is to throw, but usually to throw something strongly. So as you said,
it's very spoken English. It's not really proper to actually write it or say it to someone in a
formal occasion. Yeah, that's right. So you wouldn't say this in your English example. You could say
this with your friends. Okay. So to chuck something. So that's all the vocab we have for you when
we go back and listen to the dialogue again.
Oh, I feel terrible. I keep sneezing in my eyes row watery. What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are you? Looks like you have a cold. You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk. Maybe we should
put you into quarantine. Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy.
An allergy? I never thought about that. I don't think I'm allergic to pollen though, and I'm
descentitized to bee steings after being stunned so many times. Hmm.
Oh, why did you chuck that peanut at me? Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts. I guess not.
Not funny. I could have gone into anaphylactic shock. Okay, my bad. How about dust? This office is full of it.
Yes, the whole office is dusty yet I only feel affected near desks.
You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles birthday today. I didn't want it to be alone on a special day.
Put it away! I guess we found the problem. You're allergic to cats.
All right, we're back so now it's time for Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder.
All right, now we heard a very difficult word later on the dialogue. Jim said,
not funny. I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Right. All right, so this phrase, to go into shock is very important. Go into shock. And now,
what does it mean to go into shock? Well, shock is something, especially anaphylactic shock,
which means that I think you can stop breathing because your body basically shuts down and you can't,
you know, you're throat titans you can't breathe. But to go into shock means that your body will kind of
stop doing its normal functions. For example, if you fall in very, very cold water,
your body goes into shock. Right. And this is something that is a physical reaction.
You see it all the time in movies, I think, when a nurse or a doctor or someone yells,
he's going into shock. Right. That's right. They have to get the paddles on feet. Right,
you know, exactly. So that's what it means when you go into shock. But you use this verb,
you go into shock. He's going into shock. That's right. Dr. He's gone into shock.
And well, he said, okay, I'm sorry. My bad. He said, my bad. What is my bad?
All right. My bad is another phrase that comes from spoken English to be careful with how you use it.
This is something you can use with your friends. My bad is the way of saying, my fault or excuse me,
you know, that I mistake. My mistake. So if you do something wrong, and you say, oh, I'm sorry,
that was my mistake. You can just say, my bad. That's right. Or, you know, Jerry can we go outside for a second.
I have to talk to you. I mean, Marco, my bad. Right. Exactly. I mean, I'm, you know,
my fault. I'm sorry. I made a mistake. So, but this is very colloquial. And I think it's very juvenile.
Right. I think younger people use this my bad. My bad. Yeah. It's younger. Yeah. That's a younger. All right.
And for our last phrase when Jim was talking about maybe being allergic to pollen,
or he said, I'm desensitized to be things. All right. So, de-sensitized, you should know
automatically that prefix D means not. All right. So it's negative. I'm desensitized means that
I'm not sensitive to. All right. That means that, you know, if I get stung by B, like me,
it gets big and red and it hurts. Right. But this person, he doesn't have a reaction. He's de-sensitized.
So, there's no reaction. There's no red. There's no swelling. I think you see it a lot for people
that maybe live in an area where there are a lot of mosquitoes. And if we go there, we're going to
get bitten and you can see it. It's going to be itchy. But people who live there, they've been
bitten so many times that they probably don't even feel it or probably don't even get bitten
in or they desensitized. That's right. Or you could say that I'm desensitized to loud noises.
Okay. I live in a city and there's a metro near my apartment. I can hear it. It's very loud.
And so I'm desensitized to the noise. I mean, I don't really notice it anymore. It doesn't bother me.
Right. Very good. So that's all the vocab and phrases we've prepared for you today. Let's listen
to the dialogue one last time.
Oh, I feel terrible. I keep sneezing on my eyes row watery. What's wrong with me?
Wow, you're not dying. Are you? It looks like you have a cold. You should take some medicine.
I don't think it's a cold. I feel fine if I move a few feet away from my desk.
Maybe we should put you into quarantine. Jokes aside, I think you might have an allergy.
An allergy? I never thought about that. I don't think I'm allergic to pollen though,
and I'm desensitized to bee steings after being stung so many times.
Oh, why did you chuck that peanut at me?
Just checking if you're allergic to peanuts, I guess not.
Not funny. I could have gone into anaphylactic shock.
Okay, my bad. How about dust? This office is full of it.
Yes, the whole office is dusty. Yet I only feel affected near our desks.
You brought your cat into the office?
Yeah, it's Mr. Snuffles birthday today. I didn't want him to be alone on a special day.
Put it away!
I guess we found the problem. You're allergic to cats.
All right, so speaking about allergies, we always talk about the common ones like
pollen dust.
You also mentioned about food.
Like somebody who cannot drink milk, they're allergic to milk.
That's right, we have a special name for this actually.
Someone who cannot drink milk or dairy products like ice cream is called lactose intolerant.
So if your lactose intolerant, it means that your stomach is very upset after you have dairy products.
This lactose is basically dairy.
And there are some people also who are allergic to seafood, for example fish or shrimp or any type of
seafood. That's right, and also people who are allergic to gluten.
Now gluten is a very common product that is found in breads and cereal.
Things like that. And so people who have an allergy to gluten actually have to change their diet
quite a bit.
Yeah, they have to look for things that are gluten-free, which is very hard because apparently
it's in everything.
That's right, so if you have one of these allergies, you can find dairy free on a box or gluten-free
on the box, and specialty food stores will have these labels.
And so are you allergic to anything?
No, not really. Sometimes in here, in China, I feel like I'm a little bit allergic when
I have allergies when the season's change.
But at home, no, I have no allergies.
No, there's no meaning. I can, I'm very lucky, I think, because I can't imagine if I had an allergy
like a tapina or to seafood, which not only would be a shame because you can't have these foods,
but if you accidentally have it, it could be life threatening.
That's right, like my dad who was allergic to bees would go into anaphylactic shock if he
were stunned. And so you have to be very careful because you never know when you'll have an
accident like that. Exactly. So this is an interesting topic. Maybe you guys want to share
if you are allergic to anything, maybe you're allergic to maybe you are allergic to certain types
of foods, chemicals, some people are allergic to certain types of shampoo, for example.
Or fabrics like cotton. So if you want to share with us, let us know at our website EnglishPod.com.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.