Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we have another episode in our series about small talks.
So small talk, Marco is what exactly?
Quick little conversation that you have maybe with a colleague or friend or even with a stranger,
maybe in the elevator, just about the weather, some small little topic.
So you're not talking about the meaning of life, you're talking about the weather or food.
So let's check out today's dialogue and we'll be back in a minute to talk more about what's going on.
Oh dear miss, you are soaked. Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
Yes, it sure is. I had to run here from work. I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please, why don't you go ahead of me in line?
I'm in no hurry. Oh, that's so nice of you. Thank you very much.
My pleasure, miss. Actually, could you recommend what to eat here I've never been here before?
Sure. Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice. I usually get that.
Also, the milkshakes are the best milkshakes in town.
Well, thanks for the suggestions. Well, don't mention it.
All right, we're back. So as we saw in this dialogue, it's a small talk conversation with two
strangers who are actually buying some food. So this is something that could happen if you are
waiting in line at a supermarket, if you're at the bank or even at a shop like in this case.
Exactly. This kind of conversation happens all the time. So let's take a look at some words and phrases
in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right. So the first word that we have for you today is the gentleman, the older person.
Notice how wet the girl what she said you are soaked. All right. So it's raining outside and he says,
oh dear, miss, you are soaked. All right. This is an adjective. It describes what she looks like.
So if you are soaked, it means that you are a little bit wet. Very wet. Very wet. You know,
you can say that someone is a little wet, but if they're soaked, it means they're shoes,
they're pants, they're shirt, they're hat. Everything is very wet. Okay, you are soaked. And so
it's an adjective, even though it has an ED ending, it may look like a verb or in the past,
but it's not, it's an adjective with an ED ending. That's right. So it's raining outside. This woman
is very wet. She's soaked. She's wet. And she says, I have to rush. I have to hurry because of what?
Because I'm on my lunch break. She's on her lunch break. Okay. So during work, we might have something
called a break. This is a short time when we don't have to work. Mm-hmm. Five minutes, 10 minutes.
And the break that we have at lunch, when we get to eat is a little bit longer. So we call this a lunch break.
That's right. So usually people have their lunch break. Let's say at noon or one o'clock. And it's usually
an hour like you say. That's right an hour. Okay. So she's on her lunch break. And that's why she's
in a hurry. And so the other guy led her go in front of him. And he asked her for some suggestions.
What is good here? What is what do you recommend to eat? That's right. So he's not familiar with
the food, but the woman is. And she says, well, the avocado sandwich is delicious. Now let's talk
about this fruit. Because it is a fruit, right Marco? Mm-hmm. It's a fruit and avocado.
It's a, you see this. It looks like a big green pear, more or less. That's right. Well, it's green
on the inside. And it's dark on the outside. So to eat it, you have to take off the skin. Yeah, that's right.
And inside, it's kind of a buttery, almost. You kind of, it's not hard like a banana or an apple.
It's kind of more very, very soft. You can take it out with a spoon. That's right. It's very,
very delicious. And it's very common in a lot of Latin cooking where you have, for example, guacamole
in Mexican cooking, which is made primarily of avocado. That's right. So she recommends the avocado
sandwich. And then she goes on to describe some of the food. And now here, we're going to take a look
at some adjectives, but in a superlative form. For example, she said, it's the healthiest thing
on the menu, this sandwich. Okay. So this is a really important point, Marco and I'm glad you brought
it up. I can say that this food is healthy. That means it's good for my body. But if I say that
healthy, it's the healthiest. What does that mean? How is that different from healthy?
Basically, you're saying that it's the on the list of things that are at the restaurant, maybe
that are healthy. This is the most healthy. But you don't say most healthy. You say healthyest.
Healthyest. Okay. So is chocolate cake the healthiest thing on the menu? No, probably not.
To probably the least healthy. So on top, we have the healthiest thing on the menu. We also have
another superlative. We heard the word tastiest. Right. This comes from the adjective
tastiest. Something is delicious. It's tastiest. It tastes good. But here we're saying that it's
the thing that tastes the best, the tastiest choice. Okay. So I think that the avocado sandwich is
the tastiest. That means I think it's the best thing you can eat. And that's another one actually.
Best is another superlative. But it's a little bit different because it's not an isseastest. Right.
It's not like tastiest or healthiest. It's just best. Right. You're saying that it's
the number one. So the best milkshake in town like in this dialogue. Or you say the best
soccer player in the world is so-and-so. All right. So this comes from the adjective good. So we have
good, which is not bad. And the best, which is the most good, right? Yeah, exactly. But you don't
say the most good. You say the best. He's the best. So maybe Ronaldo is the one of the best
soccer players in the world. Exactly. All right. So now let's take a break. Let's take a look at
everything again and we'll be right back with Fluency Builder.
Oh dear, Miss. You are soaked. Wow. It's really raining heavily outside. Yes, it sure is.
I had to run here from work. I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please. Why don't you go ahead of me in line? I'm in no hurry. Oh, that's so nice of you. Thank
you very much. My pleasure, Miss. Actually, could you recommend what to eat here? I've never been here
before. Sure. Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice. I usually get that. Also, the milkshakes
are the best milkshakes in town. Well, thanks for the suggestions. Well, don't mention it.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a look at three phrases we picked out on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. So have a great phrase here. Something that we often hear in conversation
polite conversations. The older man says, I'm in no hurry. Now what does this mean? Does this mean
he needs to go somewhere? No, he says, you know what? I really don't have to go anywhere fast.
That's why he let her the girl get in front of him in line at the shop. All right. So basically,
it means I can wait. I can wait. Yeah. So if somebody says, oh, I'll be right back. Please wait a moment.
You can say, I'm in no hurry. Take your time. Okay. So I'm in no hurry. I mean, it's not that
important. I don't have to go fast. Right. But if you change the no and you say, I'm in a hurry,
then that means that you have to go fast. Come on, Marco, speed it up. I'm in a hurry. In a hurry.
Okay. So just changing those two words that gives you a completely different meaning.
And well, the girl Michelle, she said, oh, that's so nice of you. Thank you very much. And he says,
my pleasure. All right. So this is an alternative to the phrase, you're welcome. Okay. This is a
very polite way to say you're welcome. And so when we hear her thinking for something, you know,
thank you for letting me go ahead of you. He says, my pleasure. This is a great, great phrase for
you guys. Exactly. So now you have another alternative instead of saying you're welcome or no
problem or don't mention it. Now you have it's my pleasure. This is a little bit more formal,
but you can use it in any circumstance. That's right. And as I said, another option here is the
is the phrase, don't mention it, which means exactly the same thing. You're welcome. That's right.
So the older gentleman says, thanks for the suggestions, thanks for your help. And what is the
young woman say? Don't mention it. Don't mention it. So this is more colloquial. This is a little
bit more spoken language. She's saying, no problem. You're welcome. That's right. So you have your
welcome, no problem. My pleasure. Don't mention it. All ways of saying the same thing. All right. So let's
take another listen to our dialogue. We'll be back in a moment.
Oh dear, Miss, you are soaked. Wow, it's really raining heavily outside. Yes, it sure is.
I had to run here from work. I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please, why don't you go ahead of me in line? I'm in no hurry.
Oh, that's so nice of you. Thank you very much. My pleasure, Miss. Actually, could you recommend what's
each here I've never been here before? Sure. Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious, and it's the
healthiest thing on the menu. Personally, I think the beef salad is the tastiest choice. I usually
get that. Also, the milkshakes are the best milkshakes in town. Well, thanks for the suggestions.
Yeah, don't mention it. All right, we're back. So talking about the superlatives. I know it's
a complicated subject because grammar wise. It can be a little bit difficult to determine when
do you say, for example, beautiful? Do you say more beautiful? Or do you say beautiful? List?
And you say more beautiful? Right. Well, I don't really have a hard and fast rule for everyone.
It's one of those things that you learn while you're studying English, and you just have to
remember. Yes, there are some exceptions, but usually you can guide yourself by adjectives that
have usually three or more syllables. You probably have to use most or more. Amazing. Right. You don't
say amazing. Mist. Most amazing. Most amazing or more amazing. What a funny funny. So then you say
funny year or funniest or sad. You can say saddest. All right. So sad, funny. These are one and two
syllables. Sad, funny. Sad, just funny. You can use this ending. But with the words like beautiful or
amazing, there are three syllables. They're long. You have to say most amazing, most beautiful. Yeah.
And there are some exceptions to the rule. You may find them, but usually if you see an adjective
that's a little bit long like this, you can just say you can just use more for the comparative
or most for the superlative. All right. So lots of stuff there. I recommend that you guys go check
out the dialogue and expansion sentences we have for today. Our website is Englishpod.com. All right. We'll see
you guys there. Bye. Bye.