Hello everyone and welcome to English Mod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and it's the holiday season. Today we have a lesson all about a special
December holiday. That's right. We are getting close to Christmas and of course today we are going
to talk about Christmas in the United States and some of the typical traditions that you see over
there. That's right. So we're going to be looking at a family as they wait for Christmas morning
to arrive. If you don't know what that is, don't worry. You'll hear us talk about it in a
moment, but first let's listen to our dialogue.
What are you doing awake? I can't sleep. But it's almost midnight.
Exactly. I'm too excited for Christmas morning. Also, I thought I heard Santa. Really? How do you
know what Santa? Well, I heard that naughty boys and girls get cold and they're stockings.
So I thought I'd be nice and make Santa cookies. I even left out some milk. I heard someone
in the kitchen eating the cookies so I came downstairs. Hmm, well I know that Santa won't come
down the chimney with you hiding behind the tree spying on him. Really? Really? Let's go back
upstairs and get back to bed. That way we can let Santa do his job. Then when you wake up,
it will be Christmas already. Okay. Hey, honey, is that you? Don't eat all the cookies.
I want some too. All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay, I just said it, but here's that phrase again. Christmas morning.
That's right. So Christmas morning is December 25th in the morning, right? That's right. Okay.
Okay. So the tradition is that small children will wake up early and run downstairs and they will
find Christmas presents under the Christmas tree. And so this is the Christmas morning tradition.
Okay. Many countries, they celebrate Christmas on Christmas Eve, the 24th, right? All right. So Christmas
Eve is December 24th Christmas day or if it's in the morning Christmas morning is December 25th.
And as you said, kids come downstairs or go to the where the Christmas tree is to look for their
presents that Santa came in and left for them. That's right. So the idea, the story is that Santa
comes at night late at night and brings presents for the children and when the children wake up,
they see the presents, but Santa has already gone. So Santa is a man. He's kind of a
mythical figure with a big white beard and a red outfit and a red hat. Right. So his name is Santa
Claus or just Santa. There are many, many different names for the for Santa different cultures in
different countries. Yeah, some people like to call him Saint Nick or Saint Nicholas. But most people
will call him Santa in America. That's right. So this is what happens. Part of what happens during
Christmas Eve and Christmas Day. And usually also boys and girls will find our stockings that
will be filled with candy or small toys as well. That's right. Stockings are basically socks.
But these are special socks that you don't wear. You hang them and a lot of people like to put them
on the fireplace, the hang them from the fireplace. And like you said, Marko, they're filled with
sweets. The story says that boys and girls who are nice get good things like sweets and toys
and boys and girls who are naughty get cold. Cold. That's that black material that we used to
make a barbecue for example. Yeah, exactly. It's very dirty and it's not something you want in
your stocking. Okay. That's right. So that's what we get in our stockings. And now when the small
boy and his father were talking they were saying that, you know, he should go back to bed and not hide
behind the tree. So if they're in the living room or they're downstairs in the house, what tree do they
have? We're not talking about a big real tree outside. We're talking about the Christmas tree.
But you know, it's a long phrase. The Christmas tree. We don't have to say it that way. When we have
a Christmas tree inside the house, we can just call it the tree. Okay. And a Christmas tree,
as many of you may have seen already, is a pine tree usually and you put decorations on it and the
present scope under it. That's right. So you might hear this phrase. There are presents under the tree
or there are many nice presents under the tree. That means there are lots of nice presents under
the Christmas tree. That's right. And well, the kid wanted to stay behind the tree and spy
on Santa Claus. That's right. So this is a verb to spy. This means to watch someone,
but to watch them while they don't know that you're watching them. So you're hiding, but looking at
someone else. Right. You're spying. This is where the the the noun comes a spy like James Bond.
James Bond spies. He is a very famous spy. That's right. But in this case, the boy does not want
Santa Claus to see him. So he is spying on Santa Claus. All right. Very good stuff. Why don't we
listen to the dialogue again and review this book?
What are you doing awake? I can't sleep. But it's almost midnight. Exactly. I'm too excited for Christmas
morning. Also, I thought I heard Santa. Really? How do you know what Santa? Well, I heard
that naughty boys and girls get cold and they're stockings. So I thought I'd be nice and make
Santa cookies. I even left out some milk. I heard someone in the kitchen eating the cookies.
So I came downstairs. Hmm. Well, I know that Santa won't come down the chimney with you hiding
behind the trees spying on him. Really? Really? Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
That way we can let Santa do his job. Then when you wake up, it will be Christmas already. Okay.
Hey, honey, is that you? Don't need all the cookies. I want some too.
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at three phrases on fluency builder.
All right, so Marco, there's another great phrase in here that we often use to run Christmas.
What is it that Santa Claus does? Well, the way Santa Claus leaves presence for boys and
girls is that he will come down the chimney and we saw that when the dad said, well, Santa
Claus won't come down the chimney if you're here hiding behind the tree. All right. So the
chimney is a part of the fireplace. Fireplaces where you have a fire in your house to keep warm
and the chimney is where the smoke goes to come outside. But Santa Claus goes the other way. He comes
down the chimney from the roof into your house. That's right. And then he leaves the presence.
So the father said, all right. So stop spying on Santa. Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
All right, get back to bed. This is a phrase that you're going to hear parents say a lot to their
children. So if the children are awake or walking around, you say, get back to bed. That means
go back to sleep. Go back to sleep. That's right. And we want the kids to go back to sleep.
So we can let Santa do his job. All right. Like that last phrase, this is a phrase that you can
use in other ways. It's not just for Christmas, but we said, you know, let Santa do his job. Let
Santa leave his presence. Let's not bother Santa. But we can change Santa with any other name.
Right. So you can say, I don't know, maybe your your dad is working in the office and your
mom will tell you, you know, come out here. Let dad do his job. I mean, don't bother dad. Don't
distract him. Let him work. Right. Okay. So that's the way that you use those phrases. Very good
stuff here when we review one last time. What are you doing awake? I can't sleep. But it's almost midnight.
Exactly. I'm too excited for Christmas warning. Also, I thought I heard Santa. Really? How do you know
what Santa? Well, I heard that naughty boys and girls get cold and they're stockings. So I thought
I'd be nice and make Santa cookies. I even left out some milk. I heard someone in the kitchen eating
the cookies. So I came downstairs. Hmm. Well, I know that Santa won't come down the chimney with
you hiding behind the tree spying on him. Really? Really? Let's go back upstairs and get back
to bed. That way we can let Santa do his job. Then when you wake up, it will be Christmas already.
Okay. Hey, honey, is that you? Don't need all the cookies. I want some too.
All right. So these Christmas traditions are, as we said, they're typically American,
but many other cultures share similar traditions like this. That's correct. So obviously,
traditions are different in every family, not everyone celebrates Christmas. Morning,
some people celebrate Christmas Eve. But most people will, will be familiar with Christmas stockings,
Christmas trees, and Santa who comes down the chimney. That's right. So it also depends, I guess,
on the culture and religion, some religions celebrate Christmas differently, or not at all. So
it's actually a very interesting time of the year. But if you look or if you can see any American
movies like I remember this one called the Santa Claus. Yeah. It's very, you can see the typical
American Christmas snow and trees and presents and Santa Claus a lot of things. That's right. So
a good way to end this of you to say have a very merry Christmas. That means you know,
have a have a nice holiday and joy Christmas. If you're not going to celebrate Christmas for whatever
reason, you can just say happy holidays. Happy holidays. That's right. And of course,
you can go to our website, english.com where we want to know if you celebrate Christmas or what are
the Christmas traditions in your country. That's right. We're very curious to hear those. So we'll see you soon
on english.pod.com. All right. We'll see you guys. Bye.