Hello everyone and welcome to English part. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about a very, well it's pretty important part
of your child's education. That's right something that many schools do is they have a conference
between the teacher and the parent. So you know they can talk about how the child is doing.
That's right. So this is something very common in American schools and it's important to learn some
of the words that you will hear. So let's take a listen to our dialogue and when we come back we'll be
talking about what some of these words and phrases mean.
Thank you for coming tonight, Mr. Weber. As a teacher it's great seeing the kids parents
assist our parent teacher conference night. Of course I'm very interested to know how my child is
doing and also gets some insight from you as to how he can improve. Well Alan is a great student.
He's a hard worker and very well behaved. However he does struggle a bit with math.
I guess he gets that for me. I never did well in math when I was a kid.
What can I do at home to compliment what he is learning in the classroom? Well it's important
that you sit with him and review his homework assignments and help him with math. I would also
recommend he stay after school twice a week for tutoring sessions. It will really help a lot.
Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that. Is there anything else?
Yes. Here's a notice from our financial department. Seems your child's tuition is overdue.
Oh yes I...
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
First up in language takeaway we have the key phrase here which is parent teacher conference.
That's right so it's a parent teacher conference, a parent teacher conference and it's basically
a meeting between the parent of the child and the teacher of the child and they talk about
how well he is doing or she is doing or where she needs or he needs to improve. That's right so
this is something that can happen maybe twice a year, maybe four times a year it depends on the
school but it's just a meeting between the parents or parents of the child and his or her teacher.
That's right so it's very common with schools in order to make sure that the parent knows
how the child is doing in school and can improve maybe. And one of the goals is to
write the parent with insight into how to help the child learn more. Okay so insight is kind of like
a better understanding of things. More clear picture yeah so I could say you know what Marco
I just don't get that woman's Cindy can you provide some insight into why she made that decision?
That's right so you want some more information or some type of explanation as to why she made
that decision. Exactly and so the teacher will then provide this insight by describing
what he or she thinks about the student. That's right and well the teacher went on to say that
Allen is a great student hard worker very well behaved. So he is a hard worker that means
he is this is not an interesting this is now he is a hard worker she is a hard worker.
He is very well behaved. Now this is a way to describe him he is not naughty he is well behaved. That
means he doesn't start fight he doesn't talk in class he doesn't cheat. Okay so what would be the
opposite you say a child or a person is well behaved what would be the opposite? I would say the child
who is not well behaved is naughty. Okay so you say he is not well behaved or just he is naughty.
He's very naughty he always starts fights in class. Okay now the student is having a little bit of
problems with math and so the parent asks what he can do to complement what he is learning in the
classroom. Okay so to complement you might have heard this a verb before but here it means something
special it means to add to all right so okay the boy Allen he's learning a lot in school but
maybe he's not learning enough because his math scores just aren't good enough. So the father wants
to know what can he do in addition to school. Right you know what can he do extra to help his boy so
that will it will complement his studies. That's right so we have two compliments someone as to say
oh you look nice today or this in this situation this verb we are saying to provide more support
or extra help to something. That's right so I feel really good about accounting but I want to take
an extra math class to complement my accounting studies because I'm just not very confident in my
math. Very good exactly. All right so and towards the end well we're talking about how the child's
tuition is overdue that teacher says the child's tuition is overdue. What is tuition Marco?
Well the tuition is the fees that you have to pay for school. Okay so maybe a private school will
have a tuition so high school or an elementary school but you often hear this in regards to college
or university so college tuition in America are very expensive. That's right and when a tuition is overdue
it means that it hasn't been pageant and so the payment is late. The payment is late now a lot of
things can be overdue that means they've passed their due date a bill can be overdue. That's right so
you should have paid your bill already but you haven't so it's overdue. Okay so a lot of
vocab there when we listen to our dialogue again.
Thank you for coming tonight Mr. Weber as a teacher it's great seeing the kids parents
assist our parent teacher conference night. Of course I'm very interested to know how my child is
doing and also gets some insight from you as to how he can improve. Well Alan is a great student
he's a hard worker and very well behaved however he does struggle a bit with math. I guess he
gets that for me. I never did well in math when I was a kid. What can I do at home to compliment
what he is learning in the classroom? Well it's important that you sit with him and review his
homework assignments and help him with math. I would also recommend he stay after school twice a week
for tutoring sessions. It will really help a lot. Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that.
Is there anything else? Yes. Here's a notice from our financial department.
Seems your child's tuition is overdue. Oh yes I...
Alright we're back so now we've prepared three key phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right the first phrase here on fluency builder is to struggle with. So Alan is a
great student but he does struggle with math. That's right so to struggle with something means
that you are having a hard time it's difficult for you. It is difficult so when I was a student in
elementary school I struggled with science. Is there anything you struggled with Marco? I struggled
with... I struggled a little bit with history. I'm doing so for Marco history was hard for me science was hard
but you can also use it for your work right you can say I'm struggling a little bit at work.
I'm struggling with my new schedule. I have too much to do. Okay so after the teacher said that
Alan is struggling with math the parent actually said I guess he gets that from me. I never did
well in math when I was a kid so what is the parent saying? He gets that from me or she gets that
means that the child has the same problems the parent has. So when the parent was little he had a
hard time with math. He struggled with math and now his child struggles with math so it's something
that maybe he inherited or he got from his father. He gets that from me. Right so sometimes you will
hear that maybe somebody is stubborn and you say well you know I get that from my dad. Yes I'm
very talkative I get that from my mother. That means my mother is talkative and I have the same
characteristic. So we're basically saying that you kind of genetically inherit the same
characteristics. Exactly. All right and the teacher said that well in order to improve Alan should
attend tutoring sessions. Tutoring sessions now this is important you might have heard the word
tutor before I have a math tutor but a tutoring session is actually the time you spend together
with your tutor practicing something or studying something. Right so you don't have a class with your
tutor you have a tutoring session. That's right class is for a teacher and many students but a
tutoring session is one on one it's two people together a tutor and a student. Uh-huh a learner.
So the the word tutor can be a noun you have a tutor which is a person that helps you or you can
tutor someone to tutor which means to teach or to help. That's right so in college I had a tutoring
session with a math tutor two times a week that means my math tutor helped me learn math
outside of school. After school. Very good. All right so a lot of great stuff there let's
the dialogue one last time.
Thank you for coming tonight Mr. Weber. As a teacher it's great seeing the kids parents
assist our parent teacher conference night. Of course I'm very interested to know how my child is
doing and also gets some insight from you as to how he can improve. Well Alan is a great student.
He's a hard worker and very well behaved. However he does struggle a bit with math.
I guess he gets that for me. I never did well in math when I was a kid.
What can I do at home to compliment what he is learning in the classroom?
Well it's important that you sit with him and review his homework assignments and help him with math.
I would also recommend he stay after school twice a week for tutoring sessions. It will
really help a lot. Thanks a lot. I will definitely do that. Is there anything else?
Yes. Here's a notice from our financial department. Seems your child's tuition is over due. Oh yes I...
All right so parent teacher conferences a very common thing, a very common thing and I think sometimes
even a little bit scary for the kid because you know your parent is going to go talk to your
teacher and maybe your teacher is not going to say great things about you. Yeah this is always very
nerve-wracking for children because maybe you didn't tell your mom and dad what you got on your
test in science last week and then your teacher will tell your parents and your parents will be angry.
Right so this is the time when the parents can be honest with the teacher and the teacher can be honest with
the parents. That's right because sometimes teachers will have a file with maybe your test scores
and they will show them to your parents so not only what you get on your poor cards but then you
actually see the tests and it could be like you say a little nerve-wracking. I've also heard though
it can be nerve-wracking for the teacher because sometimes teachers have to tell parents things that
they don't really want to know about their kids. If the teacher says hey your boy Allen he's not
very good at math, maybe Allen's dad gets angry and says yo no that's not true he's very good at math.
Right right. So it can be hard for everyone but I think generally they're very positive they really
helped the students. Right well it's it's interesting and actually I haven't really seen
parent teacher conferences to be that common outside of the United States so maybe if you're a parent
you have attended a parent teacher conference or maybe when you were a kid your parents went to your
parent teacher conference and if you don't have teacher conferences in your country what do you
have how do parents and teachers talk let us know our website is english.com. All right we'll see you
guys there bye.