Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
Hi everyone, my name is Katherine and today, Marco, we're talking about money.
That's right, we're going to take a look at another lesson about money, but this time,
we're going to learn a little bit more about coins in the United States.
That's right, different coins, so different sizes and shapes.
They have different names because they represent different amounts of money.
So today we're going to learn the names of those coins and we're also going to learn a little bit about British money.
So let's check out the dialogue.
How'd we organize these coins?
That's a lot of money.
What'd you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to go to the bank and change it for bills.
But first, I have to separate them into little piles.
Okay, all find all the quarters and dimes while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great, then we can add everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins that are not from here.
Oh yeah, those are from a trip to the London.
I have like 90 pens, but it all won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change these coins for you?
Hopefully.
Alright, we're back, so let's take a look at some of this language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So first up, Marko, we have this funny phrase, break the piggy bank.
What is a piggy bank?
That's right, a piggy bank.
Now, you may have seen this, it has the shape of a little pig.
It's usually made out of plastic or ceramic.
And it has a little hole at the top where you can put in coins,
it just basically save your money there.
Alright, so this is a pig-shaped bank.
But it's a bank you keep in your room, mostly children have these, right?
Yeah, so if you want to save your change or you want to save some of your coins that you have
or teach your children about saving money, then usually they have a little piggy bank
where they can store their money.
So when you break the piggy bank, usually these were made of ceramic.
So to spend the money, you have to decide when it's very, very special or important.
So you have to break the entire bank.
And that's when you take all the coins you've been saving.
Exactly, because they didn't really have a little hole where you could take it out from.
So when you wanted to take your money out, you literally had to break it.
Great, good.
Alright, so that's a piggy bank.
But what do we store inside a piggy bank?
We don't store bills, do we?
That's right, no, we sort of coin.
So this is an interesting word bill, like the name bill,
Bill Clinton, for example, bills are the paper money that we use.
Alright, but not capitalized like a name because this is a normal common noun.
Bills represent all paper money.
So I could ask for change.
Could I have the change in bills, please?
That's right.
And if I'm at a store, they'll give me bills, maybe a $5 bill, $10 bill.
There's also counts for other currencies.
So if I'm in China, I might get my Rm and B, my UN in bills.
So it's just a general name for paper money.
That's right.
So, but what we store in the piggy bank are coins.
Now talking specifically about the types of coins or the different amounts that these represent.
Let's take a look at those more in detail.
Alright, so first up we've got quarters.
Now this should be pretty easy if you know your time.
Because a quarter is one fourth of something.
So if we're talking about money, it's a quarter of a dollar or 25 cents.
That's right.
So 25 cents or a quarter of a dollar or one fourth of a dollar,
we just call it a quarter.
So, you know, most machines or pay phones, you need to insert quarters.
That's right.
So you can recognize the quarter because it's the biggest coin.
It has a big eagle on one side.
And on the other side it has George Washington.
George Washington, that's right.
Now the next in line or the next coin that we're going to take a look at are dimes.
Dimes.
Now these are also recognizable because they're the smallest coins.
But that does not mean they're the smallest amount.
Right.
Dimes are actually the second largest.
They're 10 cents or one tenth of a dollar.
So you can say they're 10 cents or you can say dime.
So do you have, I don't know if you have a 10 dimes that means you get a dollar.
That's right.
10 dimes equal one dollar.
And the face on the dime is, oh, Jeff or Sally Alexander Hamilton.
I don't know.
No, he was the first, well, he created basically the department of the treasury.
But Thomas Jefferson is on another coin.
And that's what we're going to look at next.
That's right.
The nickel.
The nickel is like the metal, you know, nickel.
And yeah, so this one is a little bit bigger than the dime, but not as big as the quarter.
Right.
I think it's a little bit thicker maybe.
It is thicker, but it's not as much money.
Mm-hmm.
A nickel is five cents.
Five cents.
So one 20th of a dollar.
That's right.
One 20th of a dollar.
So this is what we call a nickel.
So you would call this coin.
You would say, hey, do you have any nickels?
Dimes and nickels usually go together.
I don't know why.
It's a little bit more than a nickels and dime.
Nickels and dime.
He's catching his nickels and dime's.
Means he doesn't have very much money.
That's right.
So yeah, and then on this coin, you have the face of Thomas Jefferson.
Okay.
And finally, we have the only coin that's not silver colored.
It's actually more of a copper color.
Mm-hmm.
That would be the penny.
The penny.
That's right.
One cent or one penny is the smallest of the coins.
And actually, you need one hundred of these to make one dollar.
That's right.
So this is very unique because it's a different color.
It's the smallest amount.
And the face on this coin, do you know this one?
Yes.
This one is Abraham Lincoln.
Correct.
All right.
So we've got all these important people.
All of them were presidents actually except for Alexander Hamilton.
That's right.
And actually, I think Alexander Hamilton looks good better than the rest.
He was a pretty handsome one.
Actually, now he was had to be very funny looking.
Yeah.
So actually, all of these coins, you can call them by these names and everyone will recognize them,
especially in the US.
Now, I don't really think they apply to any other country as we saw later on, for example, money in England or the United Kingdom.
But usually in the US, if you say, hey, do you have any spare change or do you have any nickels and dimes?
Or can I borrow a penny?
Can I borrow a penny?
Actually, in the US, they have these little things called take a penny, leave a penny, right?
Or give a penny, take a penny.
Yeah.
You see these because pennies are not worth very much money.
And oftentimes, people will leave a penny.
And if you have, it may something cost 26 cents, but you only have a quarter, you can take a penny and then spend that.
So they're basically free pennies.
Right.
You might see in a store.
But if you get change, you don't want to carry those pennies around or that change.
So you just leave that there.
And then, you know, it's kind of a way of recycling this small amount of money, which is very interesting.
It is very interesting.
But we're going to actually take a look at some British currency.
So let's take another listen to the dialogue and when we come back, we'll explore that.
Help me organize these coins.
That's a lot of money.
What'd you do? Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to go to the bank and change it for bills.
But first, I have to separate them into little piles.
Okay.
I'll find all the quarters and dimes, while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great.
Then we can add everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins that are not from here.
Oh, yeah. Those are from a trip to the London.
I have like 90 pens, but it all I won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change these coins for you?
Hopefully.
Alright, we're back.
So let's take a look at these British words on language takeaway part two.
So here we've got British currency.
The pound, right, is the name of the currency.
So in America, we have the dollar in Britain.
We have the pound.
Is it the sterling pound?
Yeah, pound sterling.
The pound sterling.
I think that has to do with weight.
I'm sure.
But here we've got to divide it into small and large quantities.
So where we have coins, we might have pens.
Sounds like sense.
Right, exactly.
And I think actually the penny might come from from the British term pens.
I'm sure it does.
They're very similar and the meaning is basically 100th of a pound.
Right, exactly.
And the pound is basically what you would say in the US dollar.
A pound is the currency of England.
But actually, you know, how in the United States people would say, you know, 100 bucks, which
be a hundred dollars, over there they say 100 quid.
Quid.
So yeah, this is actually important slang.
In America, I would spend five bucks at the movies in Britain.
I would spend five quid.
And now that's a slang term for one pound.
That's right.
And actually I've heard also like 50p, which I think means 50 cents.
Yeah, pens.
Yeah, so 50p.
So you could say this stick or this pack of gum costs 50p.
So 50p.
That's right.
Half of a pound.
So as you can see, obviously the currencies are different.
But also it is interesting to learn the way that you would say locally.
So, you know, next time if you're in Britain or you're talking to an English person, then you'd
know if they say, you know, 50 quid, you understand they're talking about 50 pounds.
Exactly.
So, but they don't use the euro over there.
No, they don't not in Great Britain.
They do use the euro on the consonants of France, Italy.
And the euro is the name of that currency.
Okay.
All right.
So a lot of great stuff.
And now lastly, although we saw at the beginning of the dialogue, let's talk about what this person
wants to do.
He wants to change these coins into bills.
That's right.
So the verb when you need to exchange money is to change money.
So let's say if I go to England and all I have is dollars, I would say I want to
change money.
Okay.
You could also say exchange.
But when we're speaking to one another, we normally just say change.
Right.
Because even the places are sometimes called money changes.
You know, they say that or something like that.
Exactly.
And so if I want to change money, that means I want to maybe change dollars for euros or
dollars for pounds.
But this also can mean I want to change a dollar for some quarters.
Right.
Because I need quarters for like a laundry machine or telephone.
And I've heard also the term is to break.
So if you have a $10 bill and you need maybe a $5 bill, but you don't have like you
ask the person to break that money.
So you say can you break this bill?
Yeah.
That actually makes sense because it bill normally you break something that's big into smaller
pieces.
So if you think about it, if I break a glass, it becomes many pieces.
Well, if I break a $5 bill, I want maybe $1.
I get five of those.
There's one piece and then it breaks into many pieces.
Mm-hmm.
So to break means to ask for smaller change.
That's right.
So maybe next time you guys need change, you can go up to someone and say excuse me, can you
change this $5 bill for me or can you break this $5 bill on straight?
All right.
So a lot of interesting language.
Very useful stuff.
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
How'd we organize these coins?
That's a lot of money.
What'd you do?
Break the piggy bank?
Yeah, I'm going to go to the bank and change it for bills.
But first, I have to separate them into little piles.
Okay.
I'll find all the quarters and dimes while you sort the nickels and pennies.
Great.
Then we can add everything up and take it to the bank.
I found some coins that are not from here.
Oh, yeah.
Those are from a trip to the London.
I have like 90 pens, but it all won't add up to one pound.
Are you sure the bank will change these coins for you?
Hopefully.
All right.
Coming back to the topic now.
You seem to know a lot about this stuff.
Let's test your knowledge here.
On the $100 bill, who do we find?
But president or one person?
Benjamin Franklin.
That's right.
But he was in a president, right?
He was not.
He was a very important figure in American history.
Many people are familiar with the story of Benjamin Franklin and the kite with the key out.
Right.
So he discovered electricity.
He was a very important inventor and also an important person when it comes to the creation
of America.
That's right.
Now the smaller of the bills would be the $1 bill.
And actually now you have a $1 coin as well.
But on the $1 bill, do you know who's on there?
I think George Washington.
I think so.
Yeah.
So he's like the quarter and on the $1 bill.
We like to recycle our presidents.
The $20 bill, then would be Abraham Lincoln, right?
That's right.
So he's there actually on.
He's sort of unfair though.
Favorite president in the United States.
So yeah.
But they haven't changed over time.
Like in other countries, you see that they change according to the important person that's in government
or maybe you know like for example in China, you know you have a German mal on there, which before you did
into or in England you have a queen Elizabeth before was the previous ruler, which I think was King George the sixth.
So but in the US guys flat out a hundred years ago these guys haven't changed them since then.
Well I think what's America likes to celebrate its creation.
And we're just still very young country, right?
Right.
1776 so it's only been what 240 years.
So yeah, the idea is basically that we celebrate the founding, so the beginning of the Republic.
And the men who are involved in that, they're called the founders.
George Washington James Madison Alexander Hamilton all in Brent Benjamin Franklin.
These people are very important in the history of America.
And that's why we celebrate them on our money.
The one exception of course is Abraham Lincoln.
He was from the 1860s.
Right.
So he was president.
Yeah.
He was he was very important because of the civil war.
And a lot of the changes that later happened to our constitution.
And so he's another person who's maybe added on.
So he's basically the last guy you guys kind of celebrate because you don't have, we don't know if you're a Franklin Delano,
Rosa.
Right.
Or you know Bill Clinton or something like that.
Not yet.
Right.
So I guess we got to wait a while.
But that's very interesting.
The this history aspect of current season is actually very very interesting.
It is.
And one thing I like I'd like to add about quarters is that in the 2000s, so from 2000, I think on.
The United States started to make state quarters.
So you'll see often times these quarters with the picture of a state new Hampshire, Maryland,
Illinois, California and a special symbol of that state.
And so these are special quarters from the last maybe 10 years or so.
Yeah.
I remember seeing these because usually on the other side of the quarter one, once that you had George Washington,
on the other side, you had the the eagle, the the the emblem of the flag, I guess.
Not the flag, but the national public.
And so you know, the public.
And but now you have these states and it says, you know, Delaware and it has a little maybe,
I don't know, flower or something that's represented with these states.
So that was actually very nice.
It was a collector's type thing as well, right?
People were collecting that.
That's right.
You can collect all 50.
Some people did that.
And you still see them in use.
So those are the state quarters.
And those generally are in our new work quarters.
Okay.
Interesting.
All right, guys.
So we're at a time.
But if you guys have any questions or doubts, you could find us at English.com.
And we'll see you guys there.
Bye.