Hello everyone and welcome to English Mod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about something that is well not so fun when it happens.
That's right today we're going to talk about those situations where people are trying to take advantage of us.
Alright they're lying to us so they can take our money.
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and when we come back in a moment we'll be talking about some of these words and phrases that you're about to hear.
I got an urgent email from Tom. He said he's in London and got robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel.
What? That sounds really dodgy to me.
No way Tom is an honest person he wouldn't lie to me.
No I mean it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent that out.
I mean think about it. Why would he email you instead of calling you?
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money?
For sure. There's so many con artists out there you never really know.
Alright we're back so let's take a look at some language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
In language takeaway Marko one of the first things we hear is that I got an urgent email from Tom.
That's right so this is an adjective something that is urgent.
It's urgent that means it needs to be looked at immediately it's very important.
That's right so you can have an urgent email that means it's very important email or something
in a situation can be urgent. Yeah like an emergency.
The urgent care we talk about at the hospital it's something that needs to be
looked at by a doctor immediately urgently. That's right urgently that would be the adverb.
Now we go on to say that the email is urgent because it's from Tom and the email said that he is in
London and he got robbed.
Alright he got robbed. Alright so to rob is the verb R.O.B.
But here it's important to look at the verb got. This means that whatever's happening it happened
to him to the friend by someone else. That's right. So someone robbed him.
Alright he got robbed that means someone took his money right. That's right.
So the verb would be to get and robbed it would be an adjective ending.
But we also have the verb to rob and if you rob someone that means that you are stealing his or her
money. Yeah if I rob Marco means I take Marco's money from him but if I got robbed by Marco
means he took my money. That's right so remember if you use the verb to rob by itself that means
that you are doing the action or someone is stealing from another person but if you get robbed or
a person got robbed that means he or her got money taken from him. Now the friend got robbed someone
took his money and we've been asked to wire him some money. Okay to wire money. That's right to wire
money and this basically means to send money. It's a very old way or form of sending money.
Basically you're sending money electronically. You don't actually buy an envelope and put some
money in it and send it in the mail. You go to a bank or a Western Union and you transfer the money
electronically. That's right. So to send an electronic transfer of money we usually say you wire
someone some money. Yeah I'll wire it to you. That's right. Alright now continuing on we the main
topic about today's lesson is about people trying to scam other people. All right here
the verb to scam means to lie or to be dishonest with someone so that you can take their money or
to take advantage of them. That's right so to scam means to take advantage of someone to lie to
someone but you also have a scam a noun which is a situation where people are trying to take your
money. So a very famous scam might be people in a big city like Paris saying oh I'm a tourist
I'm lost can you help me can you give me some money to go to the train station and really these
people they're not lost they just want you to give them money. That's right. So this is called a scam
and what they're doing is they are trying to scam you. That's right and so we actually have a word
for these type of people. We say they are con artists they are conning you. A con artist okay so
we know what an artist is an artist is a person who maybe paints pictures or you know makes
something creative but a con is someone who breaks the law. All right so a con artist is someone who
creatively breaks the law. That's right so these are basically thieves or people who take advantage
of other people or steal from other people in a very creative way so there are situations where
they may sell something that doesn't even really belong to them. That's right so the thing to remember
here with a con artist is that there's almost always a story you know you have to they give you
this story they make you believe them and then you give them money or you give them some help
that they don't deserve and that that way they take it away from you. That's right. All right so
we're taking a look at a lot of language here let's take a break listen to the dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit. I got an urgent email from Tom he said he's in London got robbed and
needs us to wire him some money for his hotel. What? That sounds really dodgy to me. No way Tom is an honest
person he wouldn't lie to me. No I mean it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent
that out. I mean think about it why would he email you instead of calling you? Do you really think
someone is trying to scam people into sending money? For sure there's so many con artists out there
you never really know. All right we're back let's take a look at 4 key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So we've got two friends who are talking one friend says that they got an
urgent email from Tom and the other says wow that sounds really dodgy to me. That's right so if
something sounds dodgy or something is dodgy it means it doesn't really sound believable or
correct or legal. That's right so maybe I can't trust it. Right. I something is dodgy if it doesn't
sound like something I would want to trust and I think you can you can say it about a situation so
this robbery it sounds quite dodgy. You can also say it about food right? Right this food is
looks kind of dodgy it means it doesn't really look safe. Yeah maybe I'll be sick if I eat it.
So it's it's quite dodgy looking. Right or even a person can look dodgy so maybe that person is not
really someone you want to trust. A con artist doesn't always look dodgy but if if a con a
person looks dodgy and they ask you for money probably shouldn't give it right. Any money. Exactly.
All right so that's dodgy now the person answers by saying no way you know Tom is an honest person
he wouldn't lie to me he's not dodgy. No way. Right. Now this is a really popular thing to say and it
means basically that's not possible. I don't agree with you. I disagree and it's pretty forceful
actually you're expressing your opinion so if I say the Chicago white socks are the best baseball
team in the world. No way no you're wrong I think the Yankees are the best. Oh.
Like we could go back and forth. No way. Right exactly. But basically you're disagreeing.
That's right. Now the situation evolves around the fact that someone may have hacked
Tom's email account and send out that email. All right so the phrase he would be to hack an account
or to hack a website. It's important to remember that the the verb to hack is pretty recent we
talk mostly about computers and the internet when we talk about hacking. Right and it means to
gain access. All right to go into some buddies account without permission. Right so maybe illegally
or like you said without permission. So if your email account gets hacked it means someone else
accessed it without your permission or illegally. So when someone has access to your account they hack it
usually they send out an email with your name. So your friends think it's you but really it's
someone who is maybe a con artist or or someone who's not trustworthy. That's right that's exactly
right. So that's the word to hack or maybe the noun the person that hacks is called a hacker.
Now moving on to our last phrase when we agree with someone forcefully like we said no way was to disagree
when we do agree we say for sure. That's right this is basically the opposite.
In this situation we were thinking well do you really think someone is trying to hack his account?
The answer was for sure. I mean definitely absolutely. That's right so for sure it's another way
of agreeing strongly agreeing with someone or with what someone said for sure. For sure.
All right so that's all we have for today. Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
I got an urgent email from Tom. He said he's in London and got robbed and needs to
wire him some money for his hotel. What? That sounds really dodgy to me. No way Tom is an honest person.
He wouldn't lie to me. No I mean it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent
that out. I mean think about it. Why would he email you instead of calling you? Do you really think
someone is trying to scam people into sending money? For sure. There's so many con artists out there you never really know.
All right we're back so talking about scams and con artists in China there is actually a very,
very, very famous scam involving tea. That's right and this is something that you might experience in
Beijing or Shanghai or any big city. I hope you don't. But basically as a tourist you're traveling around
you go to a major tourist site like Tiananmen or the people square in Shanghai and some other
tourists some Chinese tourists they come to you and they say hello. Where you from are you
traveling here we're traveling to and then after about half an hour maybe one hour of talking they say hey
we were thinking about going to have some tea. There's a tea festival. Would you like to come with us?
Right and you go and you drink some tea and you chat and you think wow I've made some nice new
friends. These people are very nice and then you get the bill. Right and it's like $200 which is
pretty crazy for tea. So exactly it's a scam. These people are con artists. They build trust they
make you trust them. They make you think wow I have nice new friends and then they steal your money.
They steal your money that's right. It's a very popular scam in China. So and basically if you do come
here just be aware of it. It's usually young people they say they're university students or they say they
from another city and like you say they build trust you they invite you to have tea and you
think well why not you know to learn more about the culture to learn more about the country you're visiting
and they turn out to try to scam you. That's right and another popular one is the artists.
I'm a local artist I would like to show you my newest work and then they take you and the work is very
expensive and they make you buy it. So speed be aware I think what you said is true Marco that
you know you just have to be careful and have to have to recognize that not everyone wants to be your
friend. Exactly yes so be careful when you're traveling and I'm sure it happens in many other
countries maybe you have some stories that you've experienced or maybe some local types of scams
that you may know about in your country. That's right let us know our website is englishpod.com
trying use those new words con artists and scam. We'll be around answering your questions let us know
in englishpod.com. We'll see you there. Bye.